{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Technical reference: conditional access to Azure AD apps | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With Conditional access control, Azure Active Directory checks the specific conditions you pick when authenticating the user and before allowing access to the application.",
      "pos": [
        121,
        292
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once those conditions are met, the user is authenticated and allowed access to the application.",
      "pos": [
        293,
        388
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Technical reference: conditional access to Azure AD apps",
      "pos": [
        697,
        753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Services enabled with conditional access",
      "pos": [
        758,
        798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conditional Access rules are supported across various Azure AD application types.",
      "pos": [
        799,
        880
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This list includes:",
      "pos": [
        881,
        900
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Federated applications from the Azure AD application gallery",
      "pos": [
        904,
        964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Password SSO applications from the Azure AD application gallery",
      "pos": [
        967,
        1030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Applications registered with the Azure Application Proxy",
      "pos": [
        1033,
        1089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Developed line of business and multi-tenant applications registered with Azure AD",
      "pos": [
        1092,
        1173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Visual Studio Online",
      "pos": [
        1176,
        1196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Remote App",
      "pos": [
        1199,
        1215
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable access rules",
      "pos": [
        1220,
        1239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each rule can be enabled or disabled on a per application bases.",
      "pos": [
        1241,
        1305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When rules are <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ON<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> they will be enabled and enforced for users accessing the application.",
      "pos": [
        1306,
        1398
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When they are <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OFF<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> they will not be used and will not impact the users sign in experience.",
      "pos": [
        1399,
        1492
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Applying rules to specific users",
      "pos": [
        1497,
        1529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rules can be applied to specific sets of users based on security group by setting <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply To<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1530,
        1625
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply To<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> can be set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All Users<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Groups<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1626,
        1681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All Users<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> the rules will apply to any user with access to the application.",
      "pos": [
        1682,
        1772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Groups<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option allows specific security and distribution groups to be selected, rules will only be enforced for these groups.",
      "pos": [
        1773,
        1905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When deploying a rule it is common to first apply it a limited set of users, that are members of a piloting groups.",
      "pos": [
        1909,
        2024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once complete the rule can be applied to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All Users<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2025,
        2080
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will cause the rule to be enforced for all users in the organization.",
      "pos": [
        2081,
        2155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select groups may also be exempted from policy using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Except<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option.",
      "pos": [
        2157,
        2232
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any members of these groups will be exempted even if they appear in an included group.",
      "pos": [
        2233,
        2319
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "“At work” networks",
      "pos": [
        2324,
        2342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conditional access rules that use an “At work” network, rely on trusted IP ranges that have been configured in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        2345,
        2465
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These rules include:",
      "pos": [
        2466,
        2486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Require multi-factor authentication when not at work",
      "pos": [
        2490,
        2542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Block access when not at work",
      "pos": [
        2545,
        2574
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Trusted IP ranges can be configured in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>multi-factor authentication configuration page<ept id=\"p1\">](../multi-factor-authentication/multi-factor-authentication-whats-next.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2576,
        2742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conditional Access policy will use the configured ranges on each authentication request and token issuance to evaluate rules.",
      "pos": [
        2743,
        2868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The inside corpnet claim is not used since it is not available for longer lived sessions, such as refresh tokens in mobile applications.",
      "pos": [
        2869,
        3005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Per-application rules",
      "pos": [
        3010,
        3031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rules are configured per application allowing the high value services to be secured without impacting access to other services.",
      "pos": [
        3032,
        3159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conditional access rules can be configured on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the application.",
      "pos": [
        3160,
        3247
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rules currently offered:",
      "pos": [
        3250,
        3274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Require multi-factor authentication",
      "pos": [
        3280,
        3315
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All users that this policy is applied to will be required to authenticate via multi-factor authentication at least once.",
      "pos": [
        3321,
        3441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Require multi-factor authentication when not at work",
      "pos": [
        3448,
        3500
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this policy is applied, all users will be required to have performed multi-factor authentication at least once if they access the service from a non-work remote location.",
      "pos": [
        3506,
        3679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If they move from a work to remote location, they will be required to perform multifactor authentication when accessing the service.",
      "pos": [
        3680,
        3812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Block access when not at work",
      "pos": [
        3819,
        3848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When users move from work to a remote location, they will be blocked if the \"Block access when not at work\" policy is applied to them.",
      "pos": [
        3855,
        3989
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They will be re-allowed access when at a work location.",
      "pos": [
        3991,
        4046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Related topics",
      "pos": [
        4052,
        4066
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Securing access to Office 365 and other apps connected to Azure Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        4071,
        4151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Article Index for Application Management in Azure Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        4196,
        4262
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "\n<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Technical reference: conditional access to Azure AD apps | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"With Conditional access control, Azure Active Directory checks the specific conditions you pick when authenticating the user and before allowing access to the application. Once those conditions are met, the user is authenticated and allowed access to the application.\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"femila\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\" \n    ms.date=\"03/30/2016\"\n    ms.author=\"femila\"/>\n\n# Technical reference: conditional access to Azure AD apps\n\n## Services enabled with conditional access\nConditional Access rules are supported across various Azure AD application types. This list includes:\n\n- Federated applications from the Azure AD application gallery\n- Password SSO applications from the Azure AD application gallery\n- Applications registered with the Azure Application Proxy\n- Developed line of business and multi-tenant applications registered with Azure AD\n- Visual Studio Online\n- Azure Remote App\n\n## Enable access rules\n\nEach rule can be enabled or disabled on a per application bases. When rules are **ON** they will be enabled and enforced for users accessing the application. When they are **OFF** they will not be used and will not impact the users sign in experience.\n\n## Applying rules to specific users\nRules can be applied to specific sets of users based on security group by setting **Apply To**. **Apply To** can be set to **All Users** or **Groups**. When set to **All Users** the rules will apply to any user with access to the application. The **Groups** option allows specific security and distribution groups to be selected, rules will only be enforced for these groups.\n\n  When deploying a rule it is common to first apply it a limited set of users, that are members of a piloting groups. Once complete the rule can be applied to **All Users**. This will cause the rule to be enforced for all users in the organization.\n\nSelect groups may also be exempted from policy using the **Except** option. Any members of these groups will be exempted even if they appear in an included group.\n\n## “At work” networks\n\n\nConditional access rules that use an “At work” network, rely on trusted IP ranges that have been configured in Azure AD. These rules include:\n\n- Require multi-factor authentication when not at work\n- Block access when not at work\n\nTrusted IP ranges can be configured in the [multi-factor authentication configuration page](../multi-factor-authentication/multi-factor-authentication-whats-next.md). Conditional Access policy will use the configured ranges on each authentication request and token issuance to evaluate rules. The inside corpnet claim is not used since it is not available for longer lived sessions, such as refresh tokens in mobile applications.\n\n## Per-application rules\nRules are configured per application allowing the high value services to be secured without impacting access to other services. Conditional access rules can be configured on the **Configure** tab of the application. \n\nRules currently offered:\n\n- **Require multi-factor authentication**\n - All users that this policy is applied to will be required to authenticate via multi-factor authentication at least once.\n \n- **Require multi-factor authentication when not at work**\n - If this policy is applied, all users will be required to have performed multi-factor authentication at least once if they access the service from a non-work remote location. If they move from a work to remote location, they will be required to perform multifactor authentication when accessing the service.\n \n- **Block access when not at work** \n - When users move from work to a remote location, they will be blocked if the \"Block access when not at work\" policy is applied to them.  They will be re-allowed access when at a work location.\n\n\n## Related topics\n\n- [Securing access to Office 365 and other apps connected to Azure Active Directory](active-directory-conditional-access.md)\n- [Article Index for Application Management in Azure Active Directory](active-directory-apps-index.md)\n"
}