{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect sync: Best practices for changing the default configuration | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provides best practices for changing the default configuration of Azure AD Connect sync.",
      "pos": [
        140,
        228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect sync: Best practices for changing the default configuration",
      "pos": [
        550,
        626
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The purpose of this topic is to describe supported and unsupported changes to Azure AD Connect sync.",
      "pos": [
        628,
        728
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The configuration created by Azure AD Connect works “as is” for the majority of environments that synchronize on-premises Active Directory with Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        730,
        883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, in some cases, it is necessary to apply some changes to a configuration to satisfy a particular need or requirement.",
      "pos": [
        884,
        1009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Changes to the service account",
      "pos": [
        1014,
        1044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect sync is running under a service account created by the installation wizard.",
      "pos": [
        1045,
        1137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This service account holds the encryption keys to the database used by sync.",
      "pos": [
        1138,
        1214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is created with a 127 characters long password and the password is set to not expire.",
      "pos": [
        1215,
        1303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>unsupported<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to change or reset the password of the service account.",
      "pos": [
        1307,
        1384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Doing so will destroy the encryption keys and the service will not be able to access the database and will not be able to start.",
      "pos": [
        1385,
        1513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Changes to the scheduler",
      "pos": [
        1518,
        1542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect sync is set to synchronize identity data every 3 hours.",
      "pos": [
        1543,
        1615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During installation a scheduled task is created running under a service account with permissions to operate the sync server.",
      "pos": [
        1616,
        1740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>unsupported<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to make changes to the scheduled task.",
      "pos": [
        1744,
        1804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The password for the service account is not known.",
      "pos": [
        1805,
        1855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>changes to the service account<ept id=\"p1\">](#changes-to-the-service-account)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        1856,
        1925
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1928,
        2006
      ],
      "content": "It is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>unsupported<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to synchronize more frequently than the default 3 hours."
    },
    {
      "content": "Changes to Synchronization Rules",
      "pos": [
        2011,
        2043
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The installation wizard provides a configuration which is supposed to work for the most common scenarios.",
      "pos": [
        2045,
        2150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In case you need to make changes to the configuration, then you must follow these rules to still have a supported configuration.",
      "pos": [
        2151,
        2279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The only supported change to an out-of-box sync rule is to disable it.",
      "pos": [
        2283,
        2353
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any other change might be lost in an upgrade.",
      "pos": [
        2354,
        2399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need to make any other change to an out-of-box rule, then make a copy of it and disable the original rule.",
      "pos": [
        2402,
        2515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Sync Rule Editor will prompt you and help you with this.",
      "pos": [
        2516,
        2576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Export your custom synchronization rules using the Synchronization Rules Editor.",
      "pos": [
        2579,
        2659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This provides you with a PowerShell script you can use to easily recreate them in the case of a disaster recovery scenario.",
      "pos": [
        2660,
        2783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.WARNING]</ph> The out-of-box sync rules have a thumbprint.",
      "pos": [
        2786,
        2846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you make a change to these rules, the thumbprint will no longer match and you might have problems in the future when you try to apply a new release of Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        2847,
        3018
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only make changes the way it is described in this article.",
      "pos": [
        3019,
        3077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete an unwanted Sync Rule",
      "pos": [
        3083,
        3111
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Do not delete an out-of-box sync rule; it will be recreated during next upgrade.",
      "pos": [
        3112,
        3192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In some cases the installation wizard has produced a configuration which will not work for your topology.",
      "pos": [
        3194,
        3299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example if you have an account-resource forest topology but you have extended the schema in the account forest with the Exchange schema then rules for Exchange will be created for the account forest as well as the resource forest.",
      "pos": [
        3300,
        3534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case we need to disable the Sync Rule for Exchange.",
      "pos": [
        3535,
        3594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Disabled sync rule",
      "pos": [
        3598,
        3616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the picture above the installation wizard has found an old Exchange 2003 schema in the account forest.",
      "pos": [
        3731,
        3836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This was added before the resource forest was introduced in Fabrikam's environment.",
      "pos": [
        3837,
        3920
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To ensure no attributes from the old Exchange implementation are synchronized the sync rule should be disabled as shown.",
      "pos": [
        3921,
        4041
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Change out-of-box rules",
      "pos": [
        4047,
        4070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need to make changes to an out-of-box rule then you should make a copy of the out-of-box rule and disable the original rule.",
      "pos": [
        4071,
        4202
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then make the changes to the cloned rule.",
      "pos": [
        4203,
        4244
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Sync Rule Editor will help you with this.",
      "pos": [
        4245,
        4290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you open an out-of-box rule you will be presented with this dialog box:",
      "pos": [
        4291,
        4367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Warning out of box rule",
      "pos": [
        4371,
        4394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to create a copy of the rule.",
      "pos": [
        4508,
        4552
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cloned rule is then opened.",
      "pos": [
        4553,
        4584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cloned rule",
      "pos": [
        4588,
        4599
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On this cloned rule, make any necessary changes to scope, join, and transformations.",
      "pos": [
        4704,
        4788
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Do not flow an attribute",
      "pos": [
        4794,
        4818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two ways to not flow an attribute.",
      "pos": [
        4819,
        4863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first is available in the installation wizard and allows you to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>remove selected attributes<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom.md#azure-ad-app-and-attribute-filtering)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4864,
        5049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option works if you have never synchronized the attribute before.",
      "pos": [
        5050,
        5120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However if you have started to synchronize this attribute and later remove it with this feature, then the sync engine will stop managing the attribute and the existing values will be left in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        5121,
        5321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to remove the value of an attribute and make sure it will not flow in the future, you will need create a custom rule instead.",
      "pos": [
        5323,
        5460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At Fabrikam we have realized that some of the attributes we synchronize to the cloud should not be there.",
      "pos": [
        5462,
        5567
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We want to make sure these attributes are removed from Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        5568,
        5632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Extension Attributes",
      "pos": [
        5636,
        5656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a new inbound Synchronization Rule and populate the description",
      "pos": [
        5774,
        5844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Descriptions",
      "pos": [
        5847,
        5859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create attribute flows of type <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Expression<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and with the source <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>AuthoritativeNull<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5974,
        6062
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The literal <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AuthoritativeNull<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> indicates that the value should be empty in the MV even if a lower precedence sync rule tries to populate the value.",
      "pos": [
        6063,
        6213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Extension Attributes<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration/syncruletransformations.png)</ph>",
      "pos": [
        6214,
        6352
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save the Sync Rule.",
      "pos": [
        6355,
        6374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Start <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Synchronization Service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, find the Connector, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Run<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Full Synchronization<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6375,
        6475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will recalculate all attribute flows.",
      "pos": [
        6476,
        6518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify that the intended changes are about to be exported by searching the connector space.",
      "pos": [
        6521,
        6612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Staged delete",
      "pos": [
        6615,
        6628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        6744,
        6754
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6755,
        6857
      ],
      "content": "Learn more about the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure AD Connect sync<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-whatis.md)</ept> configuration."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6859,
        6978
      ],
      "content": "Learn more about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Azure AD Connect sync: Best practices for changing the default configuration | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Provides best practices for changing the default configuration of Azure AD Connect sync.\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"andkjell\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"11/11/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"markusvi;andkjell\"/>\n\n\n# Azure AD Connect sync: Best practices for changing the default configuration\n\nThe purpose of this topic is to describe supported and unsupported changes to Azure AD Connect sync.\n\nThe configuration created by Azure AD Connect works “as is” for the majority of environments that synchronize on-premises Active Directory with Azure AD. However, in some cases, it is necessary to apply some changes to a configuration to satisfy a particular need or requirement.\n\n## Changes to the service account\nAzure AD Connect sync is running under a service account created by the installation wizard. This service account holds the encryption keys to the database used by sync. It is created with a 127 characters long password and the password is set to not expire.\n\n- It is **unsupported** to change or reset the password of the service account. Doing so will destroy the encryption keys and the service will not be able to access the database and will not be able to start.\n\n## Changes to the scheduler\nAzure AD Connect sync is set to synchronize identity data every 3 hours. During installation a scheduled task is created running under a service account with permissions to operate the sync server.\n\n- It is **unsupported** to make changes to the scheduled task. The password for the service account is not known. See [changes to the service account](#changes-to-the-service-account)\n- It is **unsupported** to synchronize more frequently than the default 3 hours.\n\n## Changes to Synchronization Rules\n\nThe installation wizard provides a configuration which is supposed to work for the most common scenarios. In case you need to make changes to the configuration, then you must follow these rules to still have a supported configuration.\n\n- The only supported change to an out-of-box sync rule is to disable it. Any other change might be lost in an upgrade.\n- If you need to make any other change to an out-of-box rule, then make a copy of it and disable the original rule. The Sync Rule Editor will prompt you and help you with this.\n- Export your custom synchronization rules using the Synchronization Rules Editor. This provides you with a PowerShell script you can use to easily recreate them in the case of a disaster recovery scenario.\n\n>[AZURE.WARNING] The out-of-box sync rules have a thumbprint. If you make a change to these rules, the thumbprint will no longer match and you might have problems in the future when you try to apply a new release of Azure AD Connect. Only make changes the way it is described in this article.\n\n### Delete an unwanted Sync Rule\nDo not delete an out-of-box sync rule; it will be recreated during next upgrade.\n\nIn some cases the installation wizard has produced a configuration which will not work for your topology. For example if you have an account-resource forest topology but you have extended the schema in the account forest with the Exchange schema then rules for Exchange will be created for the account forest as well as the resource forest. In this case we need to disable the Sync Rule for Exchange.\n\n![Disabled sync rule](./media/active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration/exchangedisabledrule.png)\n\nIn the picture above the installation wizard has found an old Exchange 2003 schema in the account forest. This was added before the resource forest was introduced in Fabrikam's environment. To ensure no attributes from the old Exchange implementation are synchronized the sync rule should be disabled as shown.\n\n### Change out-of-box rules\nIf you need to make changes to an out-of-box rule then you should make a copy of the out-of-box rule and disable the original rule. Then make the changes to the cloned rule. The Sync Rule Editor will help you with this. When you open an out-of-box rule you will be presented with this dialog box:\n\n![Warning out of box rule](./media/active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration/warningoutofboxrule.png)\n\nSelect **Yes** to create a copy of the rule. The cloned rule is then opened.\n\n![Cloned rule](./media/active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration/clonedrule.png)\n\nOn this cloned rule, make any necessary changes to scope, join, and transformations.\n\n### Do not flow an attribute\nThere are two ways to not flow an attribute. The first is available in the installation wizard and allows you to [remove selected attributes](active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom.md#azure-ad-app-and-attribute-filtering). This option works if you have never synchronized the attribute before. However if you have started to synchronize this attribute and later remove it with this feature, then the sync engine will stop managing the attribute and the existing values will be left in Azure AD.\n\nIf you want to remove the value of an attribute and make sure it will not flow in the future, you will need create a custom rule instead.\n\nAt Fabrikam we have realized that some of the attributes we synchronize to the cloud should not be there. We want to make sure these attributes are removed from Azure AD.\n\n![Extension Attributes](./media/active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration/badextensionattribute.png)\n\n- Create a new inbound Synchronization Rule and populate the description\n![Descriptions](./media/active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration/syncruledescription.png)\n- Create attribute flows of type **Expression** and with the source **AuthoritativeNull**. The literal **AuthoritativeNull** indicates that the value should be empty in the MV even if a lower precedence sync rule tries to populate the value.\n![Extension Attributes](./media/active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration/syncruletransformations.png)\n- Save the Sync Rule. Start **Synchronization Service**, find the Connector, select **Run**, and **Full Synchronization**. This will recalculate all attribute flows.\n- Verify that the intended changes are about to be exported by searching the connector space.\n![Staged delete](./media/active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration/deletetobeexported.png)\n\n## Next steps\nLearn more about the [Azure AD Connect sync](active-directory-aadconnectsync-whatis.md) configuration.\n\nLearn more about [Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory](active-directory-aadconnect.md).\n\n\n"
}