{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "For applications that need to scale compute resources out and in, scale operations are implicitly balanced across fault and update domains.",
      "pos": [
        2,
        141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For an introduction to VM scale sets refer to the recent <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure blog announcement<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/azure-vm-scale-sets-public-preview/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        142,
        295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Take a look at these videos for more about VM scale sets:",
      "pos": [
        297,
        354
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Mark Russinovich talks Azure Scale Sets",
      "pos": [
        360,
        399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual Machine Scale Sets with Guy Bowerman",
      "pos": [
        497,
        541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating and managing VM scale sets",
      "pos": [
        649,
        684
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM scale sets can be defined and deployed using JSON templates and <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>REST APIs<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt589023.aspx)</ept> just like individual Azure Resource Manager VMs.",
      "pos": [
        686,
        863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Therefore, any standard Azure Resource Manager deployment methods can be used.",
      "pos": [
        864,
        942
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about templates, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Authoring Azure Resource Manager templates<ept id=\"p1\">](../articles/resource-group-authoring-templates.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        943,
        1081
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A set of example templates for VM scale sets can be found in the Azure Quickstart teamplates GitHub repository here:",
      "pos": [
        1083,
        1199
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1201,
        1354
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates)</ept> - look for templates with <bpt id=\"p2\">_</bpt>vmss<ept id=\"p2\">_</ept> in the title."
    },
    {
      "content": "In the detail pages for these templates you'll see a button that links to the portal deployment feature.",
      "pos": [
        1356,
        1460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To deploy the VM scale set, click on the button and then fill in any parameters that are required in the portal.",
      "pos": [
        1461,
        1573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're not sure whether a resource supports upper or mixed case it is safer to always use lower case parameter values.",
      "pos": [
        1574,
        1695
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is also a handy video dissection of a VM scale set template here:",
      "pos": [
        1696,
        1767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM Scale Set Template Dissection",
      "pos": [
        1770,
        1802
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scaling a VM scale set out and in",
      "pos": [
        1895,
        1928
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To increase or decrease the number of virtual machines in a VM scale set, simply change the <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>capacity<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> property and redeploy the template.",
      "pos": [
        1930,
        2068
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This simplicity makes it easy to write your own custom scaling layer if you want to define custom scale events that are not supported by Azure autoscale.",
      "pos": [
        2069,
        2222
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are redeploying a template to change the capacity, you could define a much smaller template which only includes the SKU and the updated capacity.",
      "pos": [
        2224,
        2376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An example of this is shown here: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/master/201-vmss-scale-in-or-out/azuredeploy.json<ept id=\"p1\">](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/master/201-vmss-linux-nat/azuredeploy.json)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2377,
        2640
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2642,
        2860
      ],
      "content": "To walk through the steps that create a scale set that is automatically scaled, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Automatically Scale Machines in a Virtual Machine Scale Set<ept id=\"p1\">](../articles/virtual-machines/virtual-machines-windows-ps-vmss-create.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitoring your VM scale set",
      "pos": [
        2865,
        2893
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is currently recommended you use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Explorer<ept id=\"p1\">](https://resources.azure.com)</ept> to view VM scale sets.",
      "pos": [
        2895,
        3012
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM scale sets are a resource under Microsoft.Compute, so from this site you can see them by expanding the following links:",
      "pos": [
        3013,
        3135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM scale set scenarios",
      "pos": [
        3288,
        3310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This section lists some typical VM scale set scenarios.",
      "pos": [
        3312,
        3367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some higher level Azure services (like Batch, Service Fabric, Azure Container Service) will use these scenarios.",
      "pos": [
        3368,
        3480
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RDP / SSH to VM scale set instances<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - A VM scale set is created inside a VNET and individual VMs in are not allocated public IP addresses.",
      "pos": [
        3485,
        3627
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is a good thing because you don't generally want the expense and management overhead of allocating separate IP addresses to all the stateless resources in your compute grid, and you can easily connect to these VMs from other resources in your VNET including ones which have public IP addresses like load balancers or standalone virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        3628,
        3978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Connect to VMs using NAT rules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - You can create a public IP address, assign it to a load balancer, and define inbound NAT rules which map a port on the IP address to a port on a VM in the VM scale set.",
      "pos": [
        3983,
        4188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "E.g.",
      "pos": [
        4189,
        4193
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4199,
        4331
      ],
      "content": "Public IP->Port 50000 -> vmss\\_0->Port 22\n Public IP->Port 50001 -> vmss\\_1->Port 22\n Public IP->Port 50002-> vmss\\_2->Port 22",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "   ",
        "   "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Public IP-&gt;Port 50000 -&gt; vmss\\_0-&gt;Port 22",
          "pos": [
            0,
            41
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Public IP-&gt;Port 50001 -&gt; vmss\\_1-&gt;Port 22",
          "pos": [
            43,
            84
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Public IP-&gt;Port 50002-&gt; vmss\\_2-&gt;Port 22",
          "pos": [
            86,
            126
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4337,
        4649
      ],
      "content": "Here's an example of creating a VM scale set which uses NAT rules to enable SSH connection to every VM in a scale set using a single public IP: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/tree/master/201-vmss-linux-nat<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/tree/master/201-vmss-linux-nat)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4655,
        4885
      ],
      "content": "Here's an example of doing the same with RDP and Windows: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/tree/master/201-vmss-windows-nat<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/tree/master/201-vmss-windows-nat)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Connect to VMs using a \"jumpbox\"<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - If you create a VM scale set and a standalone VM in the same VNET, the standalone VM and the VM scale set VMs can connect to one another using their internal IP addresses as defined by the VNET/Subnet.",
      "pos": [
        4890,
        5130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you create a public IP address and assign it to the standalone VM you can RDP or SSH to the standalone VM and then connect from that machine to your VM scale set instances.",
      "pos": [
        5131,
        5306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You may notice at this point that a simple VM scale set is inherently more secure than a simple standalone VM with a public IP address in its default configuration.",
      "pos": [
        5307,
        5471
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5477,
        5815
      ],
      "content": "For an example of this approach, this template creates a simple Mesos cluster consisting of a standalone Master VM which manages a VM scale-set based cluster of VMs: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/mesos-vmss-simple-cluster.json<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/mesos-vmss-simple-cluster.json)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Round robin load balancing to VM scale set instances<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - If you want to deliver work to a compute cluster of VMs using a \"round-robin\" approach, you can configure an Azure load balancer with load-balancing rules accordingly.",
      "pos": [
        5820,
        6046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also define probes to verify your application is running by pinging ports with a specified protocol, interval and request path.",
      "pos": [
        6047,
        6182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example which creates a VM scale set of VMs running IIS web server, and uses a load balancer to balance the load that each VM receives.",
      "pos": [
        6188,
        6334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It also uses the HTTP protocol to ping a specific URL on each VM: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/vmss-win-iis-vnet-storage-lb.json<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/vmss-win-iis-vnet-storage-lb.json)</ept> - look at the Microsoft.Network/loadBalancers resource type and the networkProfile and extensionProfile in the virtualMachineScaleSet.",
      "pos": [
        6335,
        6714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deploying a VM scale set as a compute cluster in a PaaS cluster manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - VM scale sets are sometimes described as a next-generation worker role.",
      "pos": [
        6719,
        6868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's a valid description but it also runs the risk of confusing scale set features with PaaS v1 Worker role features.",
      "pos": [
        6869,
        6986
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In a sense VM scale sets provide a true \"worker role\" or worker resource, in that they provide a generalized compute resource which is platform/runtime independent, customizable and integrates into Azure Resource Manager IaaS.",
      "pos": [
        6987,
        7213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A PaaS v1 worker role, while limited in terms of platform/runtime support (Windows platform images only) also includes services such as VIP swap, configurable upgrade settings, runtime/app deployment specific settings which are either not <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>yet<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> available in VM scale sets, or will be delivered by other higher level PaaS services like Service Fabric.",
      "pos": [
        7219,
        7569
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With this in mind you can look at VM scale sets as an infrastructure which supports PaaS.",
      "pos": [
        7570,
        7659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I.e.",
      "pos": [
        7660,
        7664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PaaS solutions like Service Fabric or cluster managers like Mesos can build on top of VM scale sets as a scalable compute layer.",
      "pos": [
        7665,
        7793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example of a Mesos cluster which deploys a VM Scale Set in the same VNET as a standalone VM.",
      "pos": [
        7799,
        7902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The standalone VM is a Mesos master, and the VM scale set represents a set of slave nodes: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/mesos-vmss-simple-cluster.json<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/mesos-vmss-simple-cluster.json)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7903,
        8167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Future versions of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Container Service<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/azure-container-service-now-and-the-future/)</ept> will deploy more complex/hardened versions of this scenario based on VM scale sets.",
      "pos": [
        8168,
        8378
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM scale set performance and scale guidance",
      "pos": [
        8383,
        8426
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During the public preview, do not create more than 500 VMs in multiple VM Scale Sets at a time.",
      "pos": [
        8430,
        8525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Plan for no more than 40 VMs per storage account.",
      "pos": [
        8528,
        8577
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Spread out the first letters of storage account names as much as possible.",
      "pos": [
        8580,
        8654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The example VMSS templates in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Quickstart templates<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/)</ept> provide examples of how to do this.",
      "pos": [
        8656,
        8804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If using custom VMs, plan for no more than 40 VMs per VM scale set, in a single storage account.",
      "pos": [
        8807,
        8903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will need the image pre-copied into the storage account before you can begin VM scale set deployment.",
      "pos": [
        8905,
        9010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the FAQ for more information.",
      "pos": [
        9011,
        9044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Plan for no more than 2048 VMs per VNET.",
      "pos": [
        9047,
        9087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This limit will be increased in the future.",
      "pos": [
        9089,
        9132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The number of VMs you can create is limited by your Compute core quota in any region.",
      "pos": [
        9135,
        9220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You may need to contact Customer Support to increase your Compute quota limit increased even if you have a high limit of cores for use with cloud services or IaaS v1 today.",
      "pos": [
        9221,
        9393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To query your quota you can run the following Azure CLI command: <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>azure vm list-usage<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept>, and the following PowerShell command: <bpt id=\"p2\">_</bpt>Get-AzureRmVMUsage<ept id=\"p2\">_</ept> (if using a version of PowerShell below 1.0 use <bpt id=\"p3\">_</bpt>Get-AzureVMUsage<ept id=\"p3\">_</ept>).",
      "pos": [
        9394,
        9609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM scale set frequently asked questions",
      "pos": [
        9614,
        9653
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q.",
      "pos": [
        9657,
        9659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How many VMs can you have in a VM scale set?",
      "pos": [
        9662,
        9706
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        9710,
        9712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100 if you use platform images which can be distributed across multiple storage accounts.",
      "pos": [
        9715,
        9804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you use custom images, up to 40, since custom images are limited to a single storage account during preview.",
      "pos": [
        9805,
        9916
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9918,
        9975
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> What other resource limits exist for VM scale sets?"
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        9979,
        9981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You are limited to creating no more than 500 VMs in multiple scale sets per region during the preview period.",
      "pos": [
        9984,
        10093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The existing <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Subscription Service Limits/<ept id=\"p1\">](../articles/azure-subscription-service-limits.md)</ept> apply.",
      "pos": [
        10094,
        10200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q.",
      "pos": [
        10204,
        10206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Are Data Disks Supported within VM scale sets?",
      "pos": [
        10209,
        10255
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        10259,
        10261
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not in the initial release.",
      "pos": [
        10264,
        10291
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your options for storing data are:",
      "pos": [
        10292,
        10326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure files (SMB shared drives)",
      "pos": [
        10330,
        10361
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "OS drive",
      "pos": [
        10365,
        10373
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Temp drive (local, not backed by Azure storage)",
      "pos": [
        10377,
        10424
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "External data service (e.g. remote DB, Azure tables, Azure blobs)",
      "pos": [
        10428,
        10493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q.",
      "pos": [
        10497,
        10499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Which Azure regions support for VM scale sets?",
      "pos": [
        10502,
        10548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        10552,
        10554
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any region which supports Azure Resource Manager supports VM Scale Sets.",
      "pos": [
        10557,
        10629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q.",
      "pos": [
        10633,
        10635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How do you create a VM scale sets using a custom image?",
      "pos": [
        10638,
        10693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        10697,
        10699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Leave the vhdContainers property blank, for example:",
      "pos": [
        10702,
        10754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q.",
      "pos": [
        11243,
        11245
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If I reduce my VM scale set capacity from 20 to 15, which VMs will be removed?",
      "pos": [
        11248,
        11326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        11330,
        11332
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual machines are removed from the scale set evenly across upgrade domains and fault domains to maximize availability.",
      "pos": [
        11335,
        11456
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q.",
      "pos": [
        11460,
        11462
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How about it if I then increase the capacity from 15 to 18?",
      "pos": [
        11465,
        11524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        11528,
        11530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you increase to 18, VMs with index 15, 16, 17 will be created.",
      "pos": [
        11533,
        11598
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In both cases the VMs are balanced across FDs and UDs.",
      "pos": [
        11599,
        11653
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q.",
      "pos": [
        11657,
        11659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using multiple extensions in a VM scale set, can I enforce an execution sequence?",
      "pos": [
        11662,
        11748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        11752,
        11754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not directly, but for the customScript extension, your script could wait for another extension to complete (for example by monitoring the extension log - see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/blob/master/201-vmss-lapstack-autoscale/install\\_lap.sh<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/blob/master/201-vmss-lapstack-autoscale/install_lap.sh)</ept>).",
      "pos": [
        11757,
        12134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q.",
      "pos": [
        12138,
        12140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Do VM scale sets work with Azure availability sets?",
      "pos": [
        12143,
        12194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A.",
      "pos": [
        12198,
        12200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes.",
      "pos": [
        12203,
        12207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A VM scale set is an implicit availability set with 3 FDs and 5 UDs.",
      "pos": [
        12208,
        12276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You don't need to configure anything under virtualMachineProfile.",
      "pos": [
        12277,
        12342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In future releases, VM scale sets are likely to span multiple tenants but for now a scale set is a single availability set.",
      "pos": [
        12343,
        12466
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "\n\nFor applications that need to scale compute resources out and in, scale operations are implicitly balanced across fault and update domains. For an introduction to VM scale sets refer to the recent [Azure blog announcement](https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/azure-vm-scale-sets-public-preview/).\n\nTake a look at these videos for more about VM scale sets:\n\n - [Mark Russinovich talks Azure Scale Sets](https://channel9.msdn.com/Blogs/Regular-IT-Guy/Mark-Russinovich-Talks-Azure-Scale-Sets/)  \n\n - [Virtual Machine Scale Sets with Guy Bowerman](https://channel9.msdn.com/Shows/Cloud+Cover/Episode-191-Virtual-Machine-Scale-Sets-with-Guy-Bowerman)\n\n## Creating and managing VM scale sets\n\nVM scale sets can be defined and deployed using JSON templates and [REST APIs](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt589023.aspx) just like individual Azure Resource Manager VMs. Therefore, any standard Azure Resource Manager deployment methods can be used. For more information about templates, see [Authoring Azure Resource Manager templates](../articles/resource-group-authoring-templates.md).\n\nA set of example templates for VM scale sets can be found in the Azure Quickstart teamplates GitHub repository here:\n\n[https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates) - look for templates with _vmss_ in the title.\n\nIn the detail pages for these templates you'll see a button that links to the portal deployment feature. To deploy the VM scale set, click on the button and then fill in any parameters that are required in the portal. If you're not sure whether a resource supports upper or mixed case it is safer to always use lower case parameter values. There is also a handy video dissection of a VM scale set template here:\n\n[VM Scale Set Template Dissection](https://channel9.msdn.com/Blogs/Windows-Azure/VM-Scale-Set-Template-Dissection/player)\n\n## Scaling a VM scale set out and in\n\nTo increase or decrease the number of virtual machines in a VM scale set, simply change the _capacity_ property and redeploy the template. This simplicity makes it easy to write your own custom scaling layer if you want to define custom scale events that are not supported by Azure autoscale.\n\nIf you are redeploying a template to change the capacity, you could define a much smaller template which only includes the SKU and the updated capacity. An example of this is shown here: [https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/master/201-vmss-scale-in-or-out/azuredeploy.json](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/master/201-vmss-linux-nat/azuredeploy.json).\n\nTo walk through the steps that create a scale set that is automatically scaled, see [Automatically Scale Machines in a Virtual Machine Scale Set](../articles/virtual-machines/virtual-machines-windows-ps-vmss-create.md)\n\n## Monitoring your VM scale set\n\nIt is currently recommended you use the [Azure Resource Explorer](https://resources.azure.com) to view VM scale sets. VM scale sets are a resource under Microsoft.Compute, so from this site you can see them by expanding the following links:\n\n    subscriptions -> your subscription -> resourceGroups -> providers -> Microsoft.Compute -> virtualMachineScaleSets -> your VM scale set -> etc.\n\n## VM scale set scenarios\n\nThis section lists some typical VM scale set scenarios. Some higher level Azure services (like Batch, Service Fabric, Azure Container Service) will use these scenarios.\n\n - **RDP / SSH to VM scale set instances** - A VM scale set is created inside a VNET and individual VMs in are not allocated public IP addresses. This is a good thing because you don't generally want the expense and management overhead of allocating separate IP addresses to all the stateless resources in your compute grid, and you can easily connect to these VMs from other resources in your VNET including ones which have public IP addresses like load balancers or standalone virtual machines.\n\n - **Connect to VMs using NAT rules** - You can create a public IP address, assign it to a load balancer, and define inbound NAT rules which map a port on the IP address to a port on a VM in the VM scale set. E.g.\n\n    Public IP->Port 50000 -> vmss\\_0->Port 22\n    Public IP->Port 50001 -> vmss\\_1->Port 22\n    Public IP->Port 50002-> vmss\\_2->Port 22\n\n    Here's an example of creating a VM scale set which uses NAT rules to enable SSH connection to every VM in a scale set using a single public IP: [https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/tree/master/201-vmss-linux-nat](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/tree/master/201-vmss-linux-nat)\n\n    Here's an example of doing the same with RDP and Windows: [https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/tree/master/201-vmss-windows-nat](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/tree/master/201-vmss-windows-nat)\n\n - **Connect to VMs using a \"jumpbox\"** - If you create a VM scale set and a standalone VM in the same VNET, the standalone VM and the VM scale set VMs can connect to one another using their internal IP addresses as defined by the VNET/Subnet. If you create a public IP address and assign it to the standalone VM you can RDP or SSH to the standalone VM and then connect from that machine to your VM scale set instances. You may notice at this point that a simple VM scale set is inherently more secure than a simple standalone VM with a public IP address in its default configuration.\n\n    For an example of this approach, this template creates a simple Mesos cluster consisting of a standalone Master VM which manages a VM scale-set based cluster of VMs: [https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/mesos-vmss-simple-cluster.json](https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/mesos-vmss-simple-cluster.json)\n\n - **Round robin load balancing to VM scale set instances** - If you want to deliver work to a compute cluster of VMs using a \"round-robin\" approach, you can configure an Azure load balancer with load-balancing rules accordingly. You can also define probes to verify your application is running by pinging ports with a specified protocol, interval and request path.\n\n    Here is an example which creates a VM scale set of VMs running IIS web server, and uses a load balancer to balance the load that each VM receives. It also uses the HTTP protocol to ping a specific URL on each VM: [https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/vmss-win-iis-vnet-storage-lb.json](https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/vmss-win-iis-vnet-storage-lb.json) - look at the Microsoft.Network/loadBalancers resource type and the networkProfile and extensionProfile in the virtualMachineScaleSet.\n\n - **Deploying a VM scale set as a compute cluster in a PaaS cluster manager** - VM scale sets are sometimes described as a next-generation worker role. It's a valid description but it also runs the risk of confusing scale set features with PaaS v1 Worker role features. In a sense VM scale sets provide a true \"worker role\" or worker resource, in that they provide a generalized compute resource which is platform/runtime independent, customizable and integrates into Azure Resource Manager IaaS.\n\n    A PaaS v1 worker role, while limited in terms of platform/runtime support (Windows platform images only) also includes services such as VIP swap, configurable upgrade settings, runtime/app deployment specific settings which are either not _yet_ available in VM scale sets, or will be delivered by other higher level PaaS services like Service Fabric. With this in mind you can look at VM scale sets as an infrastructure which supports PaaS. I.e. PaaS solutions like Service Fabric or cluster managers like Mesos can build on top of VM scale sets as a scalable compute layer.\n\n    Here is an example of a Mesos cluster which deploys a VM Scale Set in the same VNET as a standalone VM. The standalone VM is a Mesos master, and the VM scale set represents a set of slave nodes: [https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/mesos-vmss-simple-cluster.json](https://github.com/gbowerman/azure-myriad/blob/master/mesos-vmss-simple-cluster.json). Future versions of the [Azure Container Service](https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/azure-container-service-now-and-the-future/) will deploy more complex/hardened versions of this scenario based on VM scale sets.\n\n## VM scale set performance and scale guidance\n\n- During the public preview, do not create more than 500 VMs in multiple VM Scale Sets at a time.\n- Plan for no more than 40 VMs per storage account.\n- Spread out the first letters of storage account names as much as possible.  The example VMSS templates in [Azure Quickstart templates](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/) provide examples of how to do this.\n- If using custom VMs, plan for no more than 40 VMs per VM scale set, in a single storage account.  You will need the image pre-copied into the storage account before you can begin VM scale set deployment. See the FAQ for more information.\n- Plan for no more than 2048 VMs per VNET.  This limit will be increased in the future.\n- The number of VMs you can create is limited by your Compute core quota in any region. You may need to contact Customer Support to increase your Compute quota limit increased even if you have a high limit of cores for use with cloud services or IaaS v1 today. To query your quota you can run the following Azure CLI command: _azure vm list-usage_, and the following PowerShell command: _Get-AzureRmVMUsage_ (if using a version of PowerShell below 1.0 use _Get-AzureVMUsage_).\n\n## VM scale set frequently asked questions\n\n**Q.** How many VMs can you have in a VM scale set?\n\n**A.** 100 if you use platform images which can be distributed across multiple storage accounts. If you use custom images, up to 40, since custom images are limited to a single storage account during preview.\n\n**Q** What other resource limits exist for VM scale sets?\n\n**A.** You are limited to creating no more than 500 VMs in multiple scale sets per region during the preview period. The existing [Azure Subscription Service Limits/](../articles/azure-subscription-service-limits.md) apply.\n\n**Q.** Are Data Disks Supported within VM scale sets?\n\n**A.** Not in the initial release. Your options for storing data are:\n\n- Azure files (SMB shared drives)\n\n- OS drive\n\n- Temp drive (local, not backed by Azure storage)\n\n- External data service (e.g. remote DB, Azure tables, Azure blobs)\n\n**Q.** Which Azure regions support for VM scale sets?\n\n**A.** Any region which supports Azure Resource Manager supports VM Scale Sets.\n\n**Q.** How do you create a VM scale sets using a custom image?\n\n**A.** Leave the vhdContainers property blank, for example:\n\n    \"storageProfile\": {\n        \"osDisk\": {\n            \"name\": \"vmssosdisk\",\n            \"caching\": \"ReadOnly\",\n            \"createOption\": \"FromImage\",\n            \"image\": {\n                \"uri\": [https://mycustomimage.blob.core.windows.net/system/Microsoft.Compute/Images/mytemplates/template-osDisk.vhd](https://mycustomimage.blob.core.windows.net/system/Microsoft.Compute/Images/mytemplates/template-osDisk.vhd)\n            },\n            \"osType\": \"Windows\"\n        }\n    },\n\n\n**Q.** If I reduce my VM scale set capacity from 20 to 15, which VMs will be removed?\n\n**A.** Virtual machines are removed from the scale set evenly across upgrade domains and fault domains to maximize availability.\n\n**Q.** How about it if I then increase the capacity from 15 to 18?\n\n**A.** If you increase to 18, VMs with index 15, 16, 17 will be created. In both cases the VMs are balanced across FDs and UDs.\n\n**Q.** When using multiple extensions in a VM scale set, can I enforce an execution sequence?\n\n**A.** Not directly, but for the customScript extension, your script could wait for another extension to complete (for example by monitoring the extension log - see [https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/blob/master/201-vmss-lapstack-autoscale/install\\_lap.sh](https://github.com/Azure/azure-quickstart-templates/blob/master/201-vmss-lapstack-autoscale/install_lap.sh)).\n\n**Q.** Do VM scale sets work with Azure availability sets?\n\n**A.** Yes. A VM scale set is an implicit availability set with 3 FDs and 5 UDs. You don't need to configure anything under virtualMachineProfile. In future releases, VM scale sets are likely to span multiple tenants but for now a scale set is a single availability set.\n"
}