{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Diagnosing issues with an Microsoft Azure cloud service requires collecting the service’s log files on virtual machines as the issues occur.",
      "pos": [
        1,
        141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the AzureLogCollector extension on-demand to perfom one-time collection of logs from one or more Cloud Service VMs (from both web roles and worker roles) and transfer the collected files to an Azure storage account – all without remotely logging on to any of the VMs.",
      "pos": [
        142,
        421
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        424,
        597
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph>Descriptions for most of the logged information can be found at http://blogs.msdn.com/b/kwill/archive/2013/08/09/windows-azure-paas-compute-diagnostics-data.asp."
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two modes of collection dependent on the types of files to be collected.",
      "pos": [
        599,
        681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Guest Agent Logs only (GA).",
      "pos": [
        684,
        717
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This collection mode includes all the logs related to Azure guest agents and other Azure components.",
      "pos": [
        718,
        818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All Logs (Full).",
      "pos": [
        821,
        837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This collection mode will collect all files in GA mode plus:",
      "pos": [
        838,
        898
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "system and application event logs",
      "pos": [
        904,
        937
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "HTTP error logs",
      "pos": [
        945,
        960
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "IIS Logs",
      "pos": [
        968,
        976
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Setup logs",
      "pos": [
        984,
        994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "other system logs",
      "pos": [
        1002,
        1019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In both collection modes, additional data collection folders can be specified by using a collection of the following structure:",
      "pos": [
        1021,
        1148
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1152,
        1270
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The name of the collection, which will be used as the name of subfolder inside the zip file to be collected."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1274,
        1363
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Location<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The path to the folder on the virtual machine where file will be collected."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SearchPattern<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The pattern of the names of files to be collected.",
      "pos": [
        1367,
        1436
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Default is “*”",
      "pos": [
        1437,
        1451
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1455,
        1530
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recursive<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: if the files will be collected recursively under the folder."
    }
  ],
  "content": "\nDiagnosing issues with an Microsoft Azure cloud service requires collecting the service’s log files on virtual machines as the issues occur. You can use the AzureLogCollector extension on-demand to perfom one-time collection of logs from one or more Cloud Service VMs (from both web roles and worker roles) and transfer the collected files to an Azure storage account – all without remotely logging on to any of the VMs.\n> [AZURE.NOTE]Descriptions for most of the logged information can be found at http://blogs.msdn.com/b/kwill/archive/2013/08/09/windows-azure-paas-compute-diagnostics-data.asp.\n\nThere are two modes of collection dependent on the types of files to be collected.\n- Azure Guest Agent Logs only (GA). This collection mode includes all the logs related to Azure guest agents and other Azure components.\n- All Logs (Full). This collection mode will collect all files in GA mode plus:\n\n  - system and application event logs\n  \n  - HTTP error logs\n  \n  - IIS Logs\n  \n  - Setup logs\n  \n  - other system logs\n\nIn both collection modes, additional data collection folders can be specified by using a collection of the following structure:\n\n- **Name**: The name of the collection, which will be used as the name of subfolder inside the zip file to be collected.\n\n- **Location**: The path to the folder on the virtual machine where file will be collected.\n\n- **SearchPattern**: The pattern of the names of files to be collected. Default is “*”\n\n- **Recursive**: if the files will be collected recursively under the folder.\n\n"
}