{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure App Service plans in-depth overview",
      "pos": [
        28,
        69
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how App Service plans for Azure App Service work, and how they benefit your management experience.",
      "pos": [
        89,
        193
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure App Service plans in-depth overview",
      "pos": [
        598,
        639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>App Service plan<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> represents a set of features and capacity that you can share across multiple apps in <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure App Service<ept id=\"p2\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=529714)</ept>, including Web Apps, Mobile Apps, Logic Apps or API Apps.",
      "pos": [
        642,
        875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These plans support 5 pricing tiers (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Free<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Shared<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Basic<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Premium<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>) where each tier has its own capabilities and capacity.",
      "pos": [
        876,
        1030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Apps in the same subscription and geographic location can share a plan.",
      "pos": [
        1031,
        1102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All the apps sharing a plan can leverage all the capabilities and features defined by the plan's tier.",
      "pos": [
        1103,
        1205
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All apps associated with a given plan run on the resources defined by the plan.",
      "pos": [
        1206,
        1285
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if your plan is configured to use two \"small\" instances in the standard service tier, all apps associated with that plan will run on both instances and will have access to the standard service tier functionality.",
      "pos": [
        1286,
        1511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Plan instances on which apps are running on are fully managed and highly available.",
      "pos": [
        1512,
        1595
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this article we'll explore the key characteristics such as tier and scale of an App Service plan and how they come into play while managing your apps.",
      "pos": [
        1597,
        1750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Apps, and App Service plans",
      "pos": [
        1754,
        1781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An app in App Service can be associated with only one App Service plan at any given time.",
      "pos": [
        1783,
        1872
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both apps and plans are contained in a resource group.",
      "pos": [
        1875,
        1929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A resource group serves as the life-cycle boundary for every resource contained within it.",
      "pos": [
        1930,
        2020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource groups enable you to manage all the pieces of an application together.",
      "pos": [
        2021,
        2100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The ability to have multiple App Service plans in a single resource group allows you to allocate different apps to different physical resources.",
      "pos": [
        2102,
        2246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, this allows separation of resources between dev, test and production environments.",
      "pos": [
        2247,
        2342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A scenario for this is when you might want to allocate one plan with its own dedicated set of resources for your production apps, and a second plan for your dev and test environments.",
      "pos": [
        2343,
        2526
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this way, load testing against a new version of your apps will not compete for the same resources as your production apps, which are serving real customers.",
      "pos": [
        2527,
        2686
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Having multiple plans in a single resource group also enables you to define an application that spans across geographical regions.",
      "pos": [
        2688,
        2818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a highly available app running in two regions will include two plans, one for each region, and one app associated with each plan.",
      "pos": [
        2819,
        2961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In such a situation, all the copies of the app will be associated with a single resource group.",
      "pos": [
        2962,
        3057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Having a single view of a resource group with multiple plans and multiple apps makes it easy to manage, control and view the health of the application.",
      "pos": [
        3058,
        3209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a new App Service plan vs. use an existing plan",
      "pos": [
        3214,
        3268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When creating a new app, you should consider creating a new resource group when the app you are about to create represents a brand new project.",
      "pos": [
        3270,
        3413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, creating a new resource group, plan, and app is the right choice.",
      "pos": [
        3414,
        3493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the app you are about to create is a component for a larger application, then this web app should be created within the resource group allocated for that larger application.",
      "pos": [
        3495,
        3671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Regardless of the new app being a altogether new application or part of a larger one, you can choose to leverage an existing App Service plan to host it or create a new one.",
      "pos": [
        3673,
        3846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is more a question of capacity and expected load.",
      "pos": [
        3847,
        3901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this new app is going to be resource intensive and have different scaling factors than the other apps hosted in an existing plan, it is recommended to isolate it into its own plan.",
      "pos": [
        3902,
        4085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating a new plan allows you to allocate a new set of resource for your web app, and provides you with greater control over resource allocation, as each plan gets its own set of instances.",
      "pos": [
        4087,
        4277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Having the capacity to move apps across plans also allows you to change the way resources are allocated across the bigger application.",
      "pos": [
        4280,
        4414
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Finally, if you want to create a new app in a different region, and that region doesn't have an existing plan, you will have to create a new plan in that region to be able to host your app there.",
      "pos": [
        4417,
        4612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create an App Service plan",
      "pos": [
        4617,
        4643
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4645,
        4765
      ],
      "content": "You can create an empty <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>App Service plan<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>App Service plan<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> browse expireince or as part of app creation."
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=529715)</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>NEW<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, then select <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Web + mobile<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, then select <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Web Apps<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Mobile Apps<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Logic Apps<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>API Apps<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4767,
        4967
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can then select or create the App Service plan for the new app.",
      "pos": [
        4988,
        5055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a new App Service Plan, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>+ Create New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, type the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>App Service plan<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> name and select an appropriate <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Location<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5076,
        5208
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pricing tier<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and select an appropriate pricing tier for the service.",
      "pos": [
        5210,
        5288
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>View all<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to view more pricing options, such as <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Free<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Shared<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5289,
        5371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you have selected the pricing tier, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button.",
      "pos": [
        5373,
        5443
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Move an app to a different App Service plan",
      "pos": [
        5450,
        5493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can move an app to a different app service plan in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://portal.azure.com)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5495,
        5595
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Apps can be moved between plans as long as the plans are in the same resource group and geographical region.",
      "pos": [
        5596,
        5704
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To move an app to another plan, navigate to the app you want to move.",
      "pos": [
        5706,
        5775
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the settings menu look for <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change App Service Plan<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5776,
        5834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will open the App Service Plan selector.",
      "pos": [
        5837,
        5882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At this point, you can either pick an existing plan, or create a new one.",
      "pos": [
        5883,
        5956
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only valid plans (in the same resource group and geographical location) are shown.",
      "pos": [
        5957,
        6039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that each plan has its own pricing tier.",
      "pos": [
        6054,
        6099
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, when you move a site from a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Free<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tier to a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tier, your app will be able to leverage all the features and resources of the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> tier.",
      "pos": [
        6100,
        6269
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Clone an app to a different App Service plan",
      "pos": [
        6274,
        6318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to move the app to a different region, one alternative is app cloning.",
      "pos": [
        6319,
        6401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Clone will make a copy of your app into a new or exisiting App Service plan or App Service environment in any region.",
      "pos": [
        6402,
        6519
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6538,
        6587
      ],
      "content": "You can find <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Clone App<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>tools<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> menu."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6590,
        6712
      ],
      "content": "Clone has some limitatiations, you can read more about it <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-web/app-service-web-app-cloning-portal.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Scale an App Service plan",
      "pos": [
        6717,
        6742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are three ways to scale a plan:",
      "pos": [
        6744,
        6781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Change the plan’s <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>pricing tier<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6785,
        6820
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a plan in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Basic<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tier can be converted into a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Premium<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> tier and all apps associated with that plan will be able to leverage the features offered in the new service tier.",
      "pos": [
        6821,
        7029
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Change the plan’s <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>instance size<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, as an example a plan in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Basic<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tier using <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>small<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> instances can be changed to use <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>large<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> instances.",
      "pos": [
        7032,
        7180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All apps associated with that plan will be able to leverage the additional memory and CPU resources offered by the larger instance size.",
      "pos": [
        7181,
        7317
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Change the plan’s <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>instance count<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7320,
        7357
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> plan scaled out to 3 instances can be scaled to 10 instances, and a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Premium<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> plan can be scaled out to 20 instances.",
      "pos": [
        7358,
        7505
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All apps associated with that plan will be able to leverage the additional memory and CPU resources offered by the larger instance count.",
      "pos": [
        7506,
        7643
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can change the pricing tier and instance size by clickin on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Scale Up<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> item under settings for either the App or the App Service Plan.",
      "pos": [
        7645,
        7789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Changes will apply to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>App Service Plan<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and affect all Apps hosted by it.",
      "pos": [
        7790,
        7870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Summary",
      "pos": [
        7894,
        7901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service plans represent a set of features and capacity that you can share across your apps.",
      "pos": [
        7903,
        7998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service plans give you the flexibility to allocate specific apps to a given set of resources and further optimize you Azure resource utilization.",
      "pos": [
        7999,
        8148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This way, if you want to save money on your testing environment you can share a plan across multiple apps.",
      "pos": [
        8149,
        8255
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also maximize throughput for your production environment by scaling it across multiple regions and plans.",
      "pos": [
        8256,
        8369
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What's changed",
      "pos": [
        8374,
        8388
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8392,
        8560
      ],
      "content": "For a guide to the change from Websites to App Service see: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure App Service and Its Impact on Existing Azure Services<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=529714)</ept>"
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Azure App Service plans in-depth overview\" \n    description=\"Learn how App Service plans for Azure App Service work, and how they benefit your management experience.\" \n    keywords=\"app service, azure app service, scale, scalable, app service plan, app service cost\"\n    services=\"app-service\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"btardif\" \n    manager=\"wpickett\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"app-service\" \n    ms.workload=\"na\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"03/15/2016\" \n    ms.author=\"byvinyal\"/>\n\n#Azure App Service plans in-depth overview#\n\nAn **App Service plan** represents a set of features and capacity that you can share across multiple apps in [Azure App Service](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=529714), including Web Apps, Mobile Apps, Logic Apps or API Apps. These plans support 5 pricing tiers (**Free**, **Shared**, **Basic**, **Standard** and **Premium**) where each tier has its own capabilities and capacity. Apps in the same subscription and geographic location can share a plan. All the apps sharing a plan can leverage all the capabilities and features defined by the plan's tier. All apps associated with a given plan run on the resources defined by the plan. For example, if your plan is configured to use two \"small\" instances in the standard service tier, all apps associated with that plan will run on both instances and will have access to the standard service tier functionality. Plan instances on which apps are running on are fully managed and highly available.\n\nIn this article we'll explore the key characteristics such as tier and scale of an App Service plan and how they come into play while managing your apps.\n\n##Apps, and App Service plans\n\nAn app in App Service can be associated with only one App Service plan at any given time. \n\nBoth apps and plans are contained in a resource group. A resource group serves as the life-cycle boundary for every resource contained within it. Resource groups enable you to manage all the pieces of an application together.\n\nThe ability to have multiple App Service plans in a single resource group allows you to allocate different apps to different physical resources. For example, this allows separation of resources between dev, test and production environments. A scenario for this is when you might want to allocate one plan with its own dedicated set of resources for your production apps, and a second plan for your dev and test environments. In this way, load testing against a new version of your apps will not compete for the same resources as your production apps, which are serving real customers.\n\nHaving multiple plans in a single resource group also enables you to define an application that spans across geographical regions. For example, a highly available app running in two regions will include two plans, one for each region, and one app associated with each plan. In such a situation, all the copies of the app will be associated with a single resource group. Having a single view of a resource group with multiple plans and multiple apps makes it easy to manage, control and view the health of the application.\n\n## Create a new App Service plan vs. use an existing plan\n\nWhen creating a new app, you should consider creating a new resource group when the app you are about to create represents a brand new project. In this case, creating a new resource group, plan, and app is the right choice.\n\nIf the app you are about to create is a component for a larger application, then this web app should be created within the resource group allocated for that larger application.\n\nRegardless of the new app being a altogether new application or part of a larger one, you can choose to leverage an existing App Service plan to host it or create a new one. This is more a question of capacity and expected load. If this new app is going to be resource intensive and have different scaling factors than the other apps hosted in an existing plan, it is recommended to isolate it into its own plan.\n\nCreating a new plan allows you to allocate a new set of resource for your web app, and provides you with greater control over resource allocation, as each plan gets its own set of instances.\n \nHaving the capacity to move apps across plans also allows you to change the way resources are allocated across the bigger application.\n \nFinally, if you want to create a new app in a different region, and that region doesn't have an existing plan, you will have to create a new plan in that region to be able to host your app there.\n\n## Create an App Service plan\n\nYou can create an empty **App Service plan** from the **App Service plan** browse expireince or as part of app creation.\n\nTo do this in the [Azure Portal](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=529715), click **NEW**, then select **Web + mobile**, then select **Web Apps**, **Mobile Apps**, **Logic Apps** or **API Apps**. \n![][createWebApp]\n\nYou can then select or create the App Service plan for the new app.\n  \n ![][createASP]\n\nTo create a new App Service Plan, click **+ Create New**, type the **App Service plan** name and select an appropriate **Location**.  Click **Pricing tier** and select an appropriate pricing tier for the service. Select **View all** to view more pricing options, such as **Free** and **Shared**.  After you have selected the pricing tier, click the **Select** button. \n \n## Move an app to a different App Service plan\n\nYou can move an app to a different app service plan in the [Azure Portal](https://portal.azure.com). Apps can be moved between plans as long as the plans are in the same resource group and geographical region.\n\nTo move an app to another plan, navigate to the app you want to move. In the settings menu look for **Change App Service Plan**.\n \nThis will open the App Service Plan selector. At this point, you can either pick an existing plan, or create a new one. Only valid plans (in the same resource group and geographical location) are shown.\n\n![][change]\n\nNote that each plan has its own pricing tier. For example, when you move a site from a **Free** tier to a **Standard** tier, your app will be able to leverage all the features and resources of the **Standard** tier.\n\n## Clone an app to a different App Service plan\nIf you want to move the app to a different region, one alternative is app cloning. Clone will make a copy of your app into a new or exisiting App Service plan or App Service environment in any region.\n\n ![][appclone]\n \nYou can find **Clone App** in the **tools** menu. \n\nClone has some limitatiations, you can read more about it [here](../app-service-web/app-service-web-app-cloning-portal.md)\n\n## Scale an App Service plan\n\nThere are three ways to scale a plan:\n\n- Change the plan’s **pricing tier**. For example, a plan in the **Basic** tier can be converted into a **Standard** or **Premium** tier and all apps associated with that plan will be able to leverage the features offered in the new service tier.\n- Change the plan’s **instance size**, as an example a plan in the **Basic** tier using **small** instances can be changed to use **large** instances. All apps associated with that plan will be able to leverage the additional memory and CPU resources offered by the larger instance size.\n- Change the plan’s **instance count**. For example, a **Standard** plan scaled out to 3 instances can be scaled to 10 instances, and a **Premium** plan can be scaled out to 20 instances. All apps associated with that plan will be able to leverage the additional memory and CPU resources offered by the larger instance count.\n\nYou can change the pricing tier and instance size by clickin on the **Scale Up** item under settings for either the App or the App Service Plan. Changes will apply to the **App Service Plan** and affect all Apps hosted by it.\n \n ![][pricingtier]\n\n##Summary\n\nApp Service plans represent a set of features and capacity that you can share across your apps. App Service plans give you the flexibility to allocate specific apps to a given set of resources and further optimize you Azure resource utilization. This way, if you want to save money on your testing environment you can share a plan across multiple apps. You can also maximize throughput for your production environment by scaling it across multiple regions and plans.\n\n## What's changed\n\n* For a guide to the change from Websites to App Service see: [Azure App Service and Its Impact on Existing Azure Services](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=529714)\n   \n[pricingtier]: ./media/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/appserviceplan-pricingtier.png\n[assign]: ./media/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/assing-appserviceplan.png\n[change]: ./media/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/change-appserviceplan.png\n[createASP]: ./media/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/create-appserviceplan.png\n[createWebApp]: ./media/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/create-web-app.png\n[appclone]: ./media/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/app-clone.png\n"
}