{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect: Custom installation | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        82
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This document details the custom installation options for Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        101,
        176
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom installation of Azure AD Connect",
      "pos": [
        506,
        545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following documentation provides information on using the custom installation option for Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        548,
        658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use this option if you have additional configuration options or need optional features that are not covered in the express installation.",
      "pos": [
        660,
        804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Related documentation",
      "pos": [
        809,
        830
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you did not read the documentation on <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect.md)</ept>, the following table provides links to related topics.",
      "pos": [
        831,
        1028
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first three topics in bold are required before you start the installation.",
      "pos": [
        1029,
        1107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Topic",
      "pos": [
        1111,
        1116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Download Azure AD Connect",
      "pos": [
        1152,
        1177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Download Azure AD Connect",
      "pos": [
        1183,
        1208
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hardware and prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        1263,
        1289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect: Hardware and prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        1295,
        1339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Accounts used for installation",
      "pos": [
        1393,
        1423
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect accounts and permissions",
      "pos": [
        1429,
        1470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install using Express settings",
      "pos": [
        1529,
        1559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Express installation of Azure AD Connect",
      "pos": [
        1563,
        1603
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upgrade from DirSync",
      "pos": [
        1661,
        1681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upgrade from Azure AD sync tool (DirSync)",
      "pos": [
        1685,
        1726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After installation",
      "pos": [
        1792,
        1810
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify the installation and assign licenses",
      "pos": [
        1814,
        1857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install required components",
      "pos": [
        1912,
        1939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you install the synchronization services, you can leave the optional configuration section unchecked and Azure AD Connect will set everything up automatically.",
      "pos": [
        1941,
        2105
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This includes setting up a SQL Server 2012 Express instance and creating the appropriate groups and assigning them permissions.",
      "pos": [
        2107,
        2234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you wish to change the defaults you can use the table below to understand the optional configuration options that are available.",
      "pos": [
        2236,
        2367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Required Components",
      "pos": [
        2371,
        2390
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Optional Configuration",
      "pos": [
        2473,
        2495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        2499,
        2510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server Name",
      "pos": [
        2543,
        2558
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Allows you to specify the SQL Server name and the instance name.",
      "pos": [
        2561,
        2625
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose this option if you already have a database server that you would like to use.",
      "pos": [
        2627,
        2711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Account",
      "pos": [
        2712,
        2727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default Azure AD Connect will create a local service account for the synchronization services to use.",
      "pos": [
        2730,
        2834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The password is generated automatically and unknown to the person installing Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        2835,
        2929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you use a remote SQL server you need a service account in the domain and know the password.",
      "pos": [
        2930,
        3024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In those cases, enter the service account to use.",
      "pos": [
        3025,
        3074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure the user running the installation is an SA in SQL so a login for the service account can be created.",
      "pos": [
        3075,
        3185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure AD Connect accounts and permissions<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md#custom-settings-installation)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        3186,
        3315
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permissions",
      "pos": [
        3318,
        3329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default Azure AD Connect will create four groups local to the server when the synchronization services are installed.",
      "pos": [
        3332,
        3452
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These groups are: Administrators group, Operators group, Browse group, and the Password Reset Group.",
      "pos": [
        3454,
        3554
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you wish to specify your own groups you can do so here.",
      "pos": [
        3556,
        3614
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The groups must be local on the server and cannot be located in the domain.",
      "pos": [
        3615,
        3690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User sign-in",
      "pos": [
        3698,
        3710
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After installing the required components you will be asked to specify how the single sign-on method that users will use.",
      "pos": [
        3711,
        3831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The table below provides a brief description of the available options.",
      "pos": [
        3833,
        3903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a full description of the sign-in methods, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>User sign-in<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-user-signin.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3904,
        4014
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User Signin",
      "pos": [
        4018,
        4029
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Single Sign On option",
      "pos": [
        4105,
        4126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        4129,
        4140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Password Sync",
      "pos": [
        4173,
        4186
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users will be able to sign into Microsoft cloud services, such as Office 365, Dynamics CRM, and Windows InTune, using the same password as they use when logging into their on-premises network.",
      "pos": [
        4188,
        4380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The user's password is synchronized to Azure via a password hash and authentication occurs in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        4382,
        4486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Password synchronization<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-implement-password-synchronization.md)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        4487,
        4610
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Federation with AD FS",
      "pos": [
        4611,
        4632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users will be able to sign into Microsoft cloud services, such as Office 365, Dynamics CRM, and Windows InTune, using the same password as they use when logging into their on-premises network.",
      "pos": [
        4633,
        4825
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The users are redirected to their on-premises ad fs instance for signing in and authentication is done on-premises.",
      "pos": [
        4827,
        4942
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Do not configure",
      "pos": [
        4943,
        4959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Neither feature will be installed and configured.",
      "pos": [
        4961,
        5010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose this option if you already have a 3rd party federation server or another existing solution in place.",
      "pos": [
        5012,
        5119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect to Azure AD",
      "pos": [
        5126,
        5145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the Connect to Azure AD screen, enter a global admin account and password.",
      "pos": [
        5146,
        5223
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure this account does not have multi-factor authentication enabled.",
      "pos": [
        5224,
        5297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will cause it to fail authentication.",
      "pos": [
        5299,
        5341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This account is only used to create a service account in Azure AD and is not used after the wizard has completed.",
      "pos": [
        5342,
        5455
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User Signin",
      "pos": [
        5459,
        5470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pages under the section Sync",
      "pos": [
        5548,
        5576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect your directories",
      "pos": [
        5582,
        5606
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To connect to your Active Directory Domain Service, Azure AD Connect needs the credentials of an account with sufficient permissions.",
      "pos": [
        5607,
        5740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This account can be a regular user account because it only needs the default read permissions.",
      "pos": [
        5742,
        5836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, depending on your scenario, you may need additional permissions.",
      "pos": [
        5838,
        5911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure AD Connect Accounts and permissions<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md#create-the-ad-ds-account)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        5913,
        6059
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User Signin",
      "pos": [
        6063,
        6074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Uniquely identifying your users",
      "pos": [
        6153,
        6184
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Matching across forests feature allows you to define how users from your AD DS forests are represented in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        6186,
        6305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A user might either be represented only once across all forests or have a combination of enabled and disabled accounts.",
      "pos": [
        6307,
        6426
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User Signin",
      "pos": [
        6430,
        6441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Setting",
      "pos": [
        6512,
        6519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        6522,
        6533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "My users are only represented once across all forests",
      "pos": [
        6567,
        6620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All users are created as individual objects in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        6704,
        6760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The objects are not joined in the metaverse.",
      "pos": [
        6765,
        6809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Mail attribute",
      "pos": [
        6811,
        6825
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option joins users and contacts if the mail attribute has the same value in different forests.",
      "pos": [
        6921,
        7020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is recommended to use this option when your contacts have been created using GALSync.",
      "pos": [
        7021,
        7109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ObjectSID and msExchangeMasterAccountSID",
      "pos": [
        7111,
        7151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option joins an enabled user in an account forest with a disabled user in an Exchange resource forest.",
      "pos": [
        7237,
        7344
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is also known as linked mailbox in Exchange.",
      "pos": [
        7345,
        7394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option can also be used if you only use Lync and Exchange is not present in the resource forest.",
      "pos": [
        7395,
        7496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "sAMAccountName and MailNickName",
      "pos": [
        7497,
        7528
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option joins on attributes where it is expected the login ID for the user can be found.",
      "pos": [
        7529,
        7621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "My own attribute",
      "pos": [
        7622,
        7638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option allows you to select your own attribute.",
      "pos": [
        7639,
        7691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Limitation:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Make sure to pick an attribute which will already exist in the metaverse.",
      "pos": [
        7693,
        7782
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you pick a custom attribute the wizard will not be able to complete.",
      "pos": [
        7783,
        7854
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Source Anchor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - The attribute sourceAnchor is an attribute which is immutable during the lifetime of a user object.",
      "pos": [
        7858,
        7977
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is the primary key linking the on-premises user with the user in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        7978,
        8055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since the attribute cannot be changed, you must plan for a good attribute to use.",
      "pos": [
        8056,
        8137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A good candidate is objectGUID.",
      "pos": [
        8138,
        8169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This attribute will not change unless the user account is moved between forests/domains.",
      "pos": [
        8170,
        8258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In a multi-forest environment where you move accounts between forests, another attribute must be used, such as an attribute with the employeeID.",
      "pos": [
        8259,
        8403
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Attributes to avoid are those which would change if a person marries or change assignments.",
      "pos": [
        8404,
        8495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot use attributes with an @-sign, so email and userPrincipalName cannot be used.",
      "pos": [
        8496,
        8584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The attribute is also case sensitive so if you move an object between forests, make sure to preserve the upper/lower case.",
      "pos": [
        8585,
        8707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For binary attributes the value is base64-encoded, but for other attribute types it will remain in its un-encoded state.",
      "pos": [
        8708,
        8828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In federation scenarios and some Azure AD interfaces this attribute is also known as immutableID.",
      "pos": [
        8829,
        8926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "More information about the source anchor can be found in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>design concepts<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-design-concepts.md#sourceAnchor)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8927,
        9067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>UserPrincipalName<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - The attribute userPrincipalName is the attribute users will use when they login to Azure AD and Office 365.",
      "pos": [
        9071,
        9202
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The domains used, also known as the UPN-suffix, should be verified in Azure AD before the users are synchronized.",
      "pos": [
        9203,
        9316
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is strongly recommended to keep the default attribute userPrincipalName.",
      "pos": [
        9317,
        9392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this attribute is non-routable and cannot be verified then it is possible to select another attribute, for example email, as the attribute holding the login ID.",
      "pos": [
        9393,
        9556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is known as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Alternate ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9558,
        9592
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Alternate ID attribute value must follow the RFC822 standard.",
      "pos": [
        9594,
        9659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Alternate ID can be used with both password Single Sign-On (SSO) and federation SSO as the sign-in solution.",
      "pos": [
        9661,
        9772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.WARNING]</ph> Using an Alternate ID is not compatible with all Office 365 workloads.",
      "pos": [
        9775,
        9861
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, please refer to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configuring Alternate Login ID<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn659436.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9863,
        9987
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync filtering  based on groups",
      "pos": [
        9995,
        10026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The filtering on groups feature allows you to run a small pilot where only a small subset of objects should be created in Azure AD and Office 365.",
      "pos": [
        10027,
        10173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use this feature, created a group in your Active Directory and add the users and groups which should be synchronized with Azure AD as direct members.",
      "pos": [
        10174,
        10326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can later add and remove users to this group to maintain the list of objects which should be present in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        10327,
        10444
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use this feature, in the customized path you will see this page:",
      "pos": [
        10445,
        10512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync Filtering",
      "pos": [
        10516,
        10530
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10602,
        10738
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.WARNING]</ph> This feature is only intended to support a pilot deployment and should not be used in a full-blow production deployment."
    },
    {
      "content": "Optional Features",
      "pos": [
        10744,
        10761
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This screen allows you to select the optional features for your specific scenarios.",
      "pos": [
        10763,
        10846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Below are brief explanations of each of the individual features.",
      "pos": [
        10848,
        10912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Optional features",
      "pos": [
        10916,
        10933
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11007,
        11143
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.WARNING]</ph> If you currently have DirSync or Azure AD Sync active, do not activate any of the writeback features in Azure AD Connect"
    },
    {
      "content": "Optional Features",
      "pos": [
        11145,
        11162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        11170,
        11181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exchange Hybrid Deployment",
      "pos": [
        11223,
        11249
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11251,
        11555
      ],
      "content": "The Exchange Hybrid Deployment feature allows for the co-existence of Exchange mailboxes both on-premises and in Azure by synchronizing a specific set of <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>attributes<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-attributes-synchronzied.md#exchange-hybrid-writeback)</ept> from Azure AD back into your on-premises directory."
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD app and attribute filtering",
      "pos": [
        11556,
        11592
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By enabling Azure AD app and attribute filtering, the set of synchronized attributes can be tailored to a specific set on a subsequent page of the wizard.",
      "pos": [
        11593,
        11747
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This opens two additional configuration pages in the wizard.",
      "pos": [
        11749,
        11809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Password synchronization",
      "pos": [
        11812,
        11836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can enable this option if you selected federation as the sign-in solution.",
      "pos": [
        11839,
        11917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Password synchronization can then be used as a backup option.",
      "pos": [
        11918,
        11979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For additional information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Password synchronization<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-implement-password-synchronization.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11980,
        12109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Password writeback",
      "pos": [
        12110,
        12128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By enabling password writeback, password changes that originate with Azure AD will be written back to your on-premises directory.",
      "pos": [
        12129,
        12258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For additional information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting started with password management<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-passwords-getting-started.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        12259,
        12380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Group writeback",
      "pos": [
        12381,
        12396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Groups in Office 365<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> feature then you can have these groups in your on-premises Active Directory as a distribution group.",
      "pos": [
        12398,
        12538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option is only available if you have Exchange present in your on-premises Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        12539,
        12635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For additional information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Group writeback<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-feature-preview.md#group-writeback)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        12636,
        12749
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Device writeback",
      "pos": [
        12750,
        12766
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Allows you to writeback device objects in Azure AD to your on-premises Active Directory for conditional access scenarios.",
      "pos": [
        12769,
        12890
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For additional information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Enabling device writeback in Azure AD Connect<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom-device-writeback.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        12891,
        13037
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Directory extension attribute sync",
      "pos": [
        13038,
        13072
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By enabling directory extensions attribute sync, additional attributes specified will be synced to Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        13073,
        13181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For additional information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Directory extensions<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-feature-preview.md#directory-extensions)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13182,
        13305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD app and attribute filtering",
      "pos": [
        13311,
        13347
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to limit which attributes to synchronize to Azure AD, then start by selecting which services you are using, If you configure this page, any new service has to be selected explicitly by re-running the installation wizard.",
      "pos": [
        13348,
        13580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Optional features",
      "pos": [
        13584,
        13601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Based on the services selected in the previous step, this page will show all attributes which will be synchronized.",
      "pos": [
        13677,
        13792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This list is a combination of all object types being synchronized.",
      "pos": [
        13793,
        13859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If there are some particular attributes you need to not synchronize, you can unselect those.",
      "pos": [
        13860,
        13952
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the picture below the homePhone attribute has been unselected and will not synchronize to Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        13953,
        14055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Optional features",
      "pos": [
        14059,
        14076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Directory Extension attribute sync (preview)",
      "pos": [
        14162,
        14206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With directory extensions you can extend the schema in Azure AD with custom attributes added by your organization or other attributes in Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        14207,
        14361
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use this feature select “Directory Extension attribute sync” on the “Optional Features” page.",
      "pos": [
        14362,
        14458
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will give you this page where you can select your additional attributes.",
      "pos": [
        14459,
        14536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync Filtering",
      "pos": [
        14540,
        14554
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        14628,
        14751
      ],
      "content": "For additional information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Directory extensions<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-feature-preview.md#directory-extensions)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring federation with AD FS",
      "pos": [
        14756,
        14789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring AD FS with Azure AD Connect is simple with just a few clicks.",
      "pos": [
        14790,
        14863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following is required prior to setup.",
      "pos": [
        14864,
        14905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Windows Server 2012 R2 server for the federation server with remote management enabled",
      "pos": [
        14909,
        14997
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Windows Server 2012 R2 server for the Web Application Proxy server with remote management enabled",
      "pos": [
        15000,
        15099
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An SSL certificate for the federation service name you intend to use (e.g. adfs.contoso.com)",
      "pos": [
        15102,
        15194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a new AD FS farm or use an existing AD FS farm",
      "pos": [
        15200,
        15253
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use an existing AD FS farm or you can choose to create a new AD FS farm.",
      "pos": [
        15254,
        15334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you choose to create a new one, you will be required to provide the SSL certificate.",
      "pos": [
        15335,
        15422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the SSL certificate is protected by a password, you will be prompted to provide the password.",
      "pos": [
        15423,
        15519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AD FS Farm",
      "pos": [
        15523,
        15533
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        15602,
        15780
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you choose to use an existing AD FS farm, you will skip a few pages and be taken directly to  a configuring the trust relationship between AD FS and Azure AD screen."
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify the AD FS servers",
      "pos": [
        15786,
        15811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here you will enter the specific servers that you want to install AD FS on.",
      "pos": [
        15813,
        15888
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can add one or more servers based on your capacity planning needs.",
      "pos": [
        15889,
        15959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These servers must all be joined to an Active Directory domain prior to performing this configuration.",
      "pos": [
        15960,
        16062
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend installing a single AD FS server for test and pilot deployments and deploying additional servers by opening up Azure AD Connect and deploying AD FS to additional servers to meet your scaling needs.",
      "pos": [
        16063,
        16273
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16278,
        16388
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Ensure that all of the servers are joined to an AD domain prior to performing this configuration."
    },
    {
      "content": "AD FS Servers",
      "pos": [
        16392,
        16405
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify the Web Application Proxy servers",
      "pos": [
        16480,
        16521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here you will enter the specific servers that you want as your Web Application proxy servers.",
      "pos": [
        16522,
        16615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The web application proxy server is deployed in your DMZ (extranet facing) and supports authentication requests from the extranet.",
      "pos": [
        16616,
        16746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can add one or more servers based on your capacity planning needs.",
      "pos": [
        16747,
        16817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend installing a single Web Application proxy server for test and pilot deployments and deploying additional servers by opening up Azure AD Connect and deploying Web Application Proxy to additional servers.",
      "pos": [
        16818,
        17033
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We typically recommend having an equivalent number of proxy servers to satisfy authentication from the intranet.",
      "pos": [
        17034,
        17146
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the account you are using to install Azure AD Connect is not a local admin on the AD FS server(s) then you will be prompted for credentials for an account that has sufficient permissions.",
      "pos": [
        17166,
        17356
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure that there is HTTP/HTTPS connectivity between the Azure AD Connect server and the Web Application Proxy server prior to configuring this step.",
      "pos": [
        17359,
        17508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, ensure that there is HTTP/HTTPS connectivity between the Web Application Server and the AD FS server to allow authentication requests to flow through.",
      "pos": [
        17511,
        17674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web App",
      "pos": [
        17679,
        17686
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will be prompted to enter credentials so that the web application server can establish a secure connection to the AD FS server.",
      "pos": [
        17756,
        17887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These credentials need to be a local administrator on the AD FS server.",
      "pos": [
        17888,
        17959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Proxy",
      "pos": [
        17963,
        17968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify the service account for the AD FS service",
      "pos": [
        18042,
        18091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The AD FS service requires a domain service account to authenticate users and lookup user information in Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        18092,
        18214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It can support 2 types of service accounts:",
      "pos": [
        18215,
        18258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Group Managed Service Accounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - This is a type of service account introduced in Active Directory Domain Service with Windows Server 2012.",
      "pos": [
        18262,
        18404
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This type of account provides services such as AD FS to use a single account without needing to update the account password on a regular basis.",
      "pos": [
        18405,
        18548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use this option if you already have Windows Server 2012 domain controllers in the domain that AD FS servers will belong to.",
      "pos": [
        18549,
        18672
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Domain User Account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - This type of account will require you to provide a password and regularly update the password when the password changes.",
      "pos": [
        18675,
        18821
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use this only when you do not have Windows Server 2012 domain controllers in the domain that AD FS servers will belong to.",
      "pos": [
        18822,
        18944
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect will auto create the group managed service account if you are logged in as a domain administrator.",
      "pos": [
        18946,
        19061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AD FS Service Account",
      "pos": [
        19065,
        19086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the Azure AD domain that you wish to federate",
      "pos": [
        19160,
        19212
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This configuration is used to setup the federation relationship between AD FS and Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        19213,
        19304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It configures AD FS to issue security tokens to Azure AD and configures Azure AD to trust the tokens from this specific AD FS instance.",
      "pos": [
        19305,
        19440
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This page will only allow you to configure a single domain in the first time experience.",
      "pos": [
        19441,
        19529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can configure additional domains at any time by opening up Azure AD Connect again and performing this task.",
      "pos": [
        19530,
        19641
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Domain",
      "pos": [
        19646,
        19661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perform additional tasks to complete the federation configuration",
      "pos": [
        19735,
        19800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following additional tasks will need to be completed to finish the federation configuration.",
      "pos": [
        19801,
        19897
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up DNS records for the AD FS federation service name (e.g. adfs.contoso.com) for both the intranet (your internal DNS server) and the extranet (public DNS through your domain registrar).",
      "pos": [
        19901,
        20091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the intranet DNS record ensure that you use A records and not CNAME records.",
      "pos": [
        20092,
        20172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is required for windows authentication to work correctly from your domain joined machine.",
      "pos": [
        20173,
        20267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are deploying more than one AD FS server or Web Application Proxy server, ensure that you have configured your load balancer and that the DNS records for the AD FS federation service name (e.g. adfs.contoso.com) point to the load balancer.",
      "pos": [
        20270,
        20516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For windows integrated authentication to work for browser applications using Internet Explorer in your intranet, ensure that the AD FS federation service name (e.g. adfs.contoso.com) is added to the intranet zone in IE.",
      "pos": [
        20519,
        20738
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This can be controlled via group policy and deployed to all your domain joined computers.",
      "pos": [
        20739,
        20828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Optional configuration on your AD FS service",
      "pos": [
        20835,
        20879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can customize the illustration and logo image for your AD FS login pages by logging into the AD FS and using PSH to make this configuration.",
      "pos": [
        20880,
        21024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure and verify pages",
      "pos": [
        21159,
        21185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On this page the configuration will actually happen.",
      "pos": [
        21186,
        21238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Staging mode",
      "pos": [
        21244,
        21256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With staging mode the process to setup a new sync server in parallel with an existing server is possible.",
      "pos": [
        21257,
        21362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is only supported to have one sync server connected to one directory in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        21363,
        21448
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "But if we want to move from another server, for example one running DirSync, then you can enable Azure AD Connect in staging mode.",
      "pos": [
        21449,
        21579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When enabled, the sync engine will import and synchronize data as normal, but it will not export anything to Azure AD and will turn off password sync and password writeback.",
      "pos": [
        21580,
        21753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync Filtering",
      "pos": [
        21757,
        21771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While in staging mode, it is possible to make required changes to the sync engine and review what is about to be exported.",
      "pos": [
        21847,
        21969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When the configuration looks good, run the installation wizard again and disable staging mode.",
      "pos": [
        21970,
        22064
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will enable data to be exported to Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        22065,
        22114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure to disable the other server at the same time so only one server is actively exporting.",
      "pos": [
        22115,
        22211
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        22214,
        22320
      ],
      "content": "For additional information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Staging mode<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-operations.md#staging-mode)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify your federation configuration",
      "pos": [
        22326,
        22362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect will verify the DNS settings for you when you click on the Verify button.",
      "pos": [
        22364,
        22454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Complete",
      "pos": [
        22458,
        22466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, perform the following verification steps:",
      "pos": [
        22536,
        22590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Validate browser login from a domain joined machine from Internet Explorer from the intranet: Connect to https://myapps.microsoft.com and verify the login with your logged in account.",
      "pos": [
        22594,
        22777
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Validate browser login from any device from the extranet: On a home machine or a mobile device, connect to https://myapps.microsoft.com and supply your login ID and your password credential.",
      "pos": [
        22780,
        22970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Validate rich client login: Connect to https://testconnectivity.microsoft.com, choose the ‘Office 365’ tab and choose the ‘Office 365 Single Sign-On Test’.",
      "pos": [
        22973,
        23128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        23134,
        23144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the installation has completed, sign out and sign in again to Windows before you use Synchronization Service Manager or Synchronization Rule Editor.",
      "pos": [
        23145,
        23299
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        23301,
        23443
      ],
      "content": "Now that you have Azure AD Connect installed you can <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>verify the installation and assign licenses<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-whats-next.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        23445,
        23564
      ],
      "content": "Learn more about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Azure AD Connect: Custom installation | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"This document details the custom installation options for Azure AD Connect.\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"billmath\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\"\n    editor=\"curtand\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"  \n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"11/16/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"billmath;andkjell\"/>\n\n# Custom installation of Azure AD Connect\n\n\nThe following documentation provides information on using the custom installation option for Azure AD Connect.  You can use this option if you have additional configuration options or need optional features that are not covered in the express installation.\n\n## Related documentation\nIf you did not read the documentation on [Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory](active-directory-aadconnect.md), the following table provides links to related topics. The first three topics in bold are required before you start the installation.\n\n| Topic |  |\n| --------- | --------- |\n| **Download Azure AD Connect** | [Download Azure AD Connect](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=615771) |\n| **Hardware and prerequisites** | [Azure AD Connect: Hardware and prerequisites](active-directory-aadconnect-prerequisites.md) |\n| **Accounts used for installation** | [Azure AD Connect accounts and permissions](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md) |\n| Install using Express settings | [Express installation of Azure AD Connect](active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-express.md) |\n| Upgrade from DirSync | [Upgrade from Azure AD sync tool (DirSync)](active-directory-aadconnect-dirsync-upgrade-get-started.md) |\n| After installation | [Verify the installation and assign licenses ](active-directory-aadconnect-whats-next.md) |\n\n\n\n\n## Install required components\n\nWhen you install the synchronization services, you can leave the optional configuration section unchecked and Azure AD Connect will set everything up automatically.  This includes setting up a SQL Server 2012 Express instance and creating the appropriate groups and assigning them permissions.  If you wish to change the defaults you can use the table below to understand the optional configuration options that are available.\n\n![Required Components](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/requiredcomponents.png)\n\n\nOptional Configuration  | Description\n------------- | ------------- |\nSQL Server Name | Allows you to specify the SQL Server name and the instance name.  Choose this option if you already have a database server that you would like to use.\nService Account | By default Azure AD Connect will create a local service account for the synchronization services to use. The password is generated automatically and unknown to the person installing Azure AD Connect. If you use a remote SQL server you need a service account in the domain and know the password. In those cases, enter the service account to use. Make sure the user running the installation is an SA in SQL so a login for the service account can be created. See [Azure AD Connect accounts and permissions](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md#custom-settings-installation) |\nPermissions | By default Azure AD Connect will create four groups local to the server when the synchronization services are installed.  These groups are: Administrators group, Operators group, Browse group, and the Password Reset Group.  If you wish to specify your own groups you can do so here. The groups must be local on the server and cannot be located in the domain. |\n\n\n## User sign-in\nAfter installing the required components you will be asked to specify how the single sign-on method that users will use.  The table below provides a brief description of the available options. For a full description of the sign-in methods, see [User sign-in](active-directory-aadconnect-user-signin.md).\n\n![User Signin](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/usersignin.png)\n\n\n\nSingle Sign On option | Description\n------------- | ------------- |\nPassword Sync |Users will be able to sign into Microsoft cloud services, such as Office 365, Dynamics CRM, and Windows InTune, using the same password as they use when logging into their on-premises network.  The user's password is synchronized to Azure via a password hash and authentication occurs in the cloud. See [Password synchronization](active-directory-aadconnectsync-implement-password-synchronization.md) for more information.\nFederation with AD FS|Users will be able to sign into Microsoft cloud services, such as Office 365, Dynamics CRM, and Windows InTune, using the same password as they use when logging into their on-premises network.  The users are redirected to their on-premises ad fs instance for signing in and authentication is done on-premises.\nDo not configure| Neither feature will be installed and configured.  Choose this option if you already have a 3rd party federation server or another existing solution in place.\n\n\n\n## Connect to Azure AD\nOn the Connect to Azure AD screen, enter a global admin account and password. Make sure this account does not have multi-factor authentication enabled.  This will cause it to fail authentication.\nThis account is only used to create a service account in Azure AD and is not used after the wizard has completed.\n\n![User Signin](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/connectaad.png)\n\n\n## Pages under the section Sync\n\n### Connect your directories\nTo connect to your Active Directory Domain Service, Azure AD Connect needs the credentials of an account with sufficient permissions.  This account can be a regular user account because it only needs the default read permissions.  However, depending on your scenario, you may need additional permissions.  For more information see [Azure AD Connect Accounts and permissions](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md#create-the-ad-ds-account)\n\n![User Signin](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/connectdir.png)\n\n\n### Uniquely identifying your users\n\nThe Matching across forests feature allows you to define how users from your AD DS forests are represented in Azure AD.  A user might either be represented only once across all forests or have a combination of enabled and disabled accounts.\n\n![User Signin](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/unique.png)\n\n\nSetting | Description\n------------- | ------------- |\n[My users are only represented once across all forests](active-directory-aadconnect-topologies.md#multiple-forests-separate-topologies) | All users are created as individual objects in Azure AD.<br> The objects are not joined in the metaverse.\n[Mail attribute](active-directory-aadconnect-topologies.md#multiple-forests-full-mesh-with-optional-galsync) | This option joins users and contacts if the mail attribute has the same value in different forests. It is recommended to use this option when your contacts have been created using GALSync.\n[ObjectSID and msExchangeMasterAccountSID](active-directory-aadconnect-topologies.md#multiple-forests-account-resource-forest)|This option joins an enabled user in an account forest with a disabled user in an Exchange resource forest. This is also known as linked mailbox in Exchange. This option can also be used if you only use Lync and Exchange is not present in the resource forest.\nsAMAccountName and MailNickName|This option joins on attributes where it is expected the login ID for the user can be found.\nMy own attribute|This option allows you to select your own attribute.  **Limitation:** Make sure to pick an attribute which will already exist in the metaverse. If you pick a custom attribute the wizard will not be able to complete.\n\n- **Source Anchor** - The attribute sourceAnchor is an attribute which is immutable during the lifetime of a user object. It is the primary key linking the on-premises user with the user in Azure AD. Since the attribute cannot be changed, you must plan for a good attribute to use. A good candidate is objectGUID. This attribute will not change unless the user account is moved between forests/domains. In a multi-forest environment where you move accounts between forests, another attribute must be used, such as an attribute with the employeeID. Attributes to avoid are those which would change if a person marries or change assignments. You cannot use attributes with an @-sign, so email and userPrincipalName cannot be used. The attribute is also case sensitive so if you move an object between forests, make sure to preserve the upper/lower case. For binary attributes the value is base64-encoded, but for other attribute types it will remain in its un-encoded state. In federation scenarios and some Azure AD interfaces this attribute is also known as immutableID. More information about the source anchor can be found in the [design concepts](active-directory-aadconnect-design-concepts.md#sourceAnchor).\n\n- **UserPrincipalName** - The attribute userPrincipalName is the attribute users will use when they login to Azure AD and Office 365. The domains used, also known as the UPN-suffix, should be verified in Azure AD before the users are synchronized. It is strongly recommended to keep the default attribute userPrincipalName. If this attribute is non-routable and cannot be verified then it is possible to select another attribute, for example email, as the attribute holding the login ID.  This is known as **Alternate ID**.  The Alternate ID attribute value must follow the RFC822 standard.  An Alternate ID can be used with both password Single Sign-On (SSO) and federation SSO as the sign-in solution.\n\n>[AZURE.WARNING] Using an Alternate ID is not compatible with all Office 365 workloads.  For more information, please refer to [Configuring Alternate Login ID](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn659436.aspx).\n\n\n\n### Sync filtering  based on groups\nThe filtering on groups feature allows you to run a small pilot where only a small subset of objects should be created in Azure AD and Office 365. To use this feature, created a group in your Active Directory and add the users and groups which should be synchronized with Azure AD as direct members. You can later add and remove users to this group to maintain the list of objects which should be present in Azure AD.\nTo use this feature, in the customized path you will see this page:\n\n![Sync Filtering](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/filter2.png)\n\n>[AZURE.WARNING] This feature is only intended to support a pilot deployment and should not be used in a full-blow production deployment.\n\n### Optional Features\n\nThis screen allows you to select the optional features for your specific scenarios.  Below are brief explanations of each of the individual features.\n\n![Optional features](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/optional.png)\n\n> [AZURE.WARNING] If you currently have DirSync or Azure AD Sync active, do not activate any of the writeback features in Azure AD Connect\n\nOptional Features      | Description\n-------------------    | ------------- |\nExchange Hybrid Deployment |The Exchange Hybrid Deployment feature allows for the co-existence of Exchange mailboxes both on-premises and in Azure by synchronizing a specific set of [attributes](active-directory-aadconnectsync-attributes-synchronzied.md#exchange-hybrid-writeback) from Azure AD back into your on-premises directory.\nAzure AD app and attribute filtering|By enabling Azure AD app and attribute filtering, the set of synchronized attributes can be tailored to a specific set on a subsequent page of the wizard.  This opens two additional configuration pages in the wizard.  \nPassword synchronization | You can enable this option if you selected federation as the sign-in solution. Password synchronization can then be used as a backup option. For additional information see [Password synchronization](active-directory-aadconnectsync-implement-password-synchronization.md).\nPassword writeback|By enabling password writeback, password changes that originate with Azure AD will be written back to your on-premises directory. For additional information see [Getting started with password management](active-directory-passwords-getting-started.md).\nGroup writeback |If you use the **Groups in Office 365** feature then you can have these groups in your on-premises Active Directory as a distribution group. This option is only available if you have Exchange present in your on-premises Active Directory. For additional information see [Group writeback](active-directory-aadconnect-feature-preview.md#group-writeback).\nDevice writeback | Allows you to writeback device objects in Azure AD to your on-premises Active Directory for conditional access scenarios. For additional information see [Enabling device writeback in Azure AD Connect](active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom-device-writeback.md)\nDirectory extension attribute sync|By enabling directory extensions attribute sync, additional attributes specified will be synced to Azure AD. For additional information see [Directory extensions](active-directory-aadconnect-feature-preview.md#directory-extensions).\n\n### Azure AD app and attribute filtering\nIf you want to limit which attributes to synchronize to Azure AD, then start by selecting which services you are using, If you configure this page, any new service has to be selected explicitly by re-running the installation wizard.\n\n![Optional features](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/azureadapps2.png)\n\nBased on the services selected in the previous step, this page will show all attributes which will be synchronized. This list is a combination of all object types being synchronized. If there are some particular attributes you need to not synchronize, you can unselect those. In the picture below the homePhone attribute has been unselected and will not synchronize to Azure AD.\n\n![Optional features](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/azureadattributes2.png)\n\n### Directory Extension attribute sync (preview)\nWith directory extensions you can extend the schema in Azure AD with custom attributes added by your organization or other attributes in Active Directory. To use this feature select “Directory Extension attribute sync” on the “Optional Features” page. This will give you this page where you can select your additional attributes.\n\n![Sync Filtering](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/extension2.png)\n\nFor additional information see [Directory extensions](active-directory-aadconnect-feature-preview.md#directory-extensions).\n\n## Configuring federation with AD FS\nConfiguring AD FS with Azure AD Connect is simple with just a few clicks. The following is required prior to setup.\n\n- A Windows Server 2012 R2 server for the federation server with remote management enabled\n- A Windows Server 2012 R2 server for the Web Application Proxy server with remote management enabled\n- An SSL certificate for the federation service name you intend to use (e.g. adfs.contoso.com)\n\n### Create a new AD FS farm or use an existing AD FS farm\nYou can use an existing AD FS farm or you can choose to create a new AD FS farm. If you choose to create a new one, you will be required to provide the SSL certificate. If the SSL certificate is protected by a password, you will be prompted to provide the password.\n\n![AD FS Farm](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/adfs1.png)\n\n**Note:** If you choose to use an existing AD FS farm, you will skip a few pages and be taken directly to  a configuring the trust relationship between AD FS and Azure AD screen.\n\n### Specify the AD FS servers\n\nHere you will enter the specific servers that you want to install AD FS on. You can add one or more servers based on your capacity planning needs. These servers must all be joined to an Active Directory domain prior to performing this configuration. We recommend installing a single AD FS server for test and pilot deployments and deploying additional servers by opening up Azure AD Connect and deploying AD FS to additional servers to meet your scaling needs.\n\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Ensure that all of the servers are joined to an AD domain prior to performing this configuration.\n\n![AD FS Servers](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/adfs2.png)\n\n\n\n### Specify the Web Application Proxy servers\nHere you will enter the specific servers that you want as your Web Application proxy servers. The web application proxy server is deployed in your DMZ (extranet facing) and supports authentication requests from the extranet. You can add one or more servers based on your capacity planning needs. We recommend installing a single Web Application proxy server for test and pilot deployments and deploying additional servers by opening up Azure AD Connect and deploying Web Application Proxy to additional servers. We typically recommend having an equivalent number of proxy servers to satisfy authentication from the intranet.\n\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE]\n- If the account you are using to install Azure AD Connect is not a local admin on the AD FS server(s) then you will be prompted for credentials for an account that has sufficient permissions.\n- Ensure that there is HTTP/HTTPS connectivity between the Azure AD Connect server and the Web Application Proxy server prior to configuring this step.\n- In addition, ensure that there is HTTP/HTTPS connectivity between the Web Application Server and the AD FS server to allow authentication requests to flow through.\n\n\n![Web App](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/adfs3.png)\n\n\nYou will be prompted to enter credentials so that the web application server can establish a secure connection to the AD FS server. These credentials need to be a local administrator on the AD FS server.\n\n![Proxy](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/adfs4.png)\n\n\n### Specify the service account for the AD FS service\nThe AD FS service requires a domain service account to authenticate users and lookup user information in Active Directory. It can support 2 types of service accounts:\n\n- **Group Managed Service Accounts** - This is a type of service account introduced in Active Directory Domain Service with Windows Server 2012. This type of account provides services such as AD FS to use a single account without needing to update the account password on a regular basis. Use this option if you already have Windows Server 2012 domain controllers in the domain that AD FS servers will belong to.\n- **Domain User Account** - This type of account will require you to provide a password and regularly update the password when the password changes. Use this only when you do not have Windows Server 2012 domain controllers in the domain that AD FS servers will belong to.\n\nAzure AD Connect will auto create the group managed service account if you are logged in as a domain administrator.\n\n![AD FS Service Account](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/adfs5.png)\n\n\n### Select the Azure AD domain that you wish to federate\nThis configuration is used to setup the federation relationship between AD FS and Azure AD. It configures AD FS to issue security tokens to Azure AD and configures Azure AD to trust the tokens from this specific AD FS instance. This page will only allow you to configure a single domain in the first time experience. You can configure additional domains at any time by opening up Azure AD Connect again and performing this task.\n\n\n![Azure AD Domain](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/adfs6.png)\n\n\n### Perform additional tasks to complete the federation configuration\nThe following additional tasks will need to be completed to finish the federation configuration.\n\n- Set up DNS records for the AD FS federation service name (e.g. adfs.contoso.com) for both the intranet (your internal DNS server) and the extranet (public DNS through your domain registrar). For the intranet DNS record ensure that you use A records and not CNAME records. This is required for windows authentication to work correctly from your domain joined machine.\n- If you are deploying more than one AD FS server or Web Application Proxy server, ensure that you have configured your load balancer and that the DNS records for the AD FS federation service name (e.g. adfs.contoso.com) point to the load balancer.\n- For windows integrated authentication to work for browser applications using Internet Explorer in your intranet, ensure that the AD FS federation service name (e.g. adfs.contoso.com) is added to the intranet zone in IE. This can be controlled via group policy and deployed to all your domain joined computers.\n\n\n### Optional configuration on your AD FS service\nYou can customize the illustration and logo image for your AD FS login pages by logging into the AD FS and using PSH to make this configuration.\n\n    Set-AdfsWebTheme -TargetName default -Logo @{path=\"c:\\Contoso\\logo.png\"} –Illustration @{path=”c:\\Contoso\\illustration.png”}\n\n## Configure and verify pages\nOn this page the configuration will actually happen.\n\n### Staging mode\nWith staging mode the process to setup a new sync server in parallel with an existing server is possible. It is only supported to have one sync server connected to one directory in the cloud. But if we want to move from another server, for example one running DirSync, then you can enable Azure AD Connect in staging mode. When enabled, the sync engine will import and synchronize data as normal, but it will not export anything to Azure AD and will turn off password sync and password writeback.\n\n![Sync Filtering](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/stagingmode.png)\n\n\nWhile in staging mode, it is possible to make required changes to the sync engine and review what is about to be exported. When the configuration looks good, run the installation wizard again and disable staging mode. This will enable data to be exported to Azure AD. Make sure to disable the other server at the same time so only one server is actively exporting.\n\n For additional information see [Staging mode](active-directory-aadconnectsync-operations.md#staging-mode).\n\n### Verify your federation configuration\n\nAzure AD Connect will verify the DNS settings for you when you click on the Verify button.\n\n![Complete](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-get-started-custom/adfs7.png)\n\n\nIn addition, perform the following verification steps:\n\n- Validate browser login from a domain joined machine from Internet Explorer from the intranet: Connect to https://myapps.microsoft.com and verify the login with your logged in account.\n- Validate browser login from any device from the extranet: On a home machine or a mobile device, connect to https://myapps.microsoft.com and supply your login ID and your password credential.\n- Validate rich client login: Connect to https://testconnectivity.microsoft.com, choose the ‘Office 365’ tab and choose the ‘Office 365 Single Sign-On Test’.\n\n\n## Next steps\nAfter the installation has completed, sign out and sign in again to Windows before you use Synchronization Service Manager or Synchronization Rule Editor.\n\nNow that you have Azure AD Connect installed you can [verify the installation and assign licenses](active-directory-aadconnect-whats-next.md).\n\nLearn more about [Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory](active-directory-aadconnect.md).\n\n\n"
}