{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        28,
        89
      ],
      "content": "Using Linear Regression in Machine Learning | Microsoft Azure"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        109,
        195
      ],
      "content": "A comparison of linear regression models in Excel and in Azure Machine Learning Studio"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        564,
        613
      ],
      "content": "Using linear regression in Azure Machine Learning"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        617,
        886
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Kate Baroni<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph2\"/> and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Ben Boatman<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph3\"/> are enterprise solution architects in Microsoft’s Data Insights Center of Excellence. In this article, they describe their experience migrating an existing regression analysis suite to a cloud-based solution using Azure Machine Learning.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Kate Baroni<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph2\"/> and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Ben Boatman<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph3\"/> are enterprise solution architects in Microsoft’s Data Insights Center of Excellence.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            221
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "In this article, they describe their experience migrating an existing regression analysis suite to a cloud-based solution using Azure Machine Learning.",
          "pos": [
            222,
            373
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        985,
        989
      ],
      "content": "Goal"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        991,
        1034
      ],
      "content": "Our project started with two goals in mind:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1041,
        1139
      ],
      "content": "Use predictive analytics to improve the accuracy of our organization’s monthly revenue projections"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1145,
        1224
      ],
      "content": "Use Azure ML to confirm, optimize, increase velocity, and scale of our results."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1228,
        1906
      ],
      "content": "Like many businesses, our organization goes through a monthly revenue forecasting process. Our small team of business analysts was tasked with using Machine Learning to support the process and improve forecast accuracy.  The team spent several months collecting data from multiple sources and running the data attributes through statistical analysis identifying key attributes relevant to services sales forecasting.  Next steps was to begin prototyping statistical regression models on the data in Excel.  Within a few weeks we had an Excel regression model that was outperforming the current field and finance forecasting processes. This became the baseline prediction result.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Like many businesses, our organization goes through a monthly revenue forecasting process.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            90
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Our small team of business analysts was tasked with using Machine Learning to support the process and improve forecast accuracy.",
          "pos": [
            91,
            219
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The team spent several months collecting data from multiple sources and running the data attributes through statistical analysis identifying key attributes relevant to services sales forecasting.",
          "pos": [
            221,
            416
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Next steps was to begin prototyping statistical regression models on the data in Excel.",
          "pos": [
            418,
            505
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Within a few weeks we had an Excel regression model that was outperforming the current field and finance forecasting processes.",
          "pos": [
            507,
            634
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This became the baseline prediction result.",
          "pos": [
            635,
            678
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1911,
        2055
      ],
      "content": "We then took the next step to moving our predictive analytics over to Azure ML to find out how Azure ML could improve on predictive performance."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2061,
        2100
      ],
      "content": "Achieving predictive performance parity"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2102,
        2673
      ],
      "content": "Our first priority was to achieve parity between Azure ML and Excel regression models.  Given the exact same data, and the same split for training and testing data we wanted to achieve predictive performance parity between Excel and Azure ML.   Initially we failed. The Excel model outperformed the Azure ML model.   The failure was due to a lack of understanding of the base tool setting in Azure ML. After a sync with the Azure ML product team, we gained a better understanding of the base setting required for our data sets, and achieved parity between the two models.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Our first priority was to achieve parity between Azure ML and Excel regression models.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            86
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Given the exact same data, and the same split for training and testing data we wanted to achieve predictive performance parity between Excel and Azure ML.",
          "pos": [
            88,
            242
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Initially we failed.",
          "pos": [
            245,
            265
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The Excel model outperformed the Azure ML model.",
          "pos": [
            266,
            314
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The failure was due to a lack of understanding of the base tool setting in Azure ML.",
          "pos": [
            317,
            401
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "After a sync with the Azure ML product team, we gained a better understanding of the base setting required for our data sets, and achieved parity between the two models.",
          "pos": [
            402,
            571
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2681,
        2713
      ],
      "content": "Create regression model in Excel"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2714,
        2813
      ],
      "content": "Our Excel Regression used the standard linear regression model found in the Excel Analysis ToolPak."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2816,
        3092
      ],
      "content": "We calculated <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>Mean Absolute % Error<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph5\"/> and used it as the performance measure for the model.  It took 3 months to arrive at a working model using Excel.  We brought much of the learning into the Azure ML experiment which ultimately was beneficial in understanding requirements.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "We calculated <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>Mean Absolute % Error<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph5\"/> and used it as the performance measure for the model.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            143
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "It took 3 months to arrive at a working model using Excel.",
          "pos": [
            145,
            203
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "We brought much of the learning into the Azure ML experiment which ultimately was beneficial in understanding requirements.",
          "pos": [
            205,
            328
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3098,
        3152
      ],
      "content": "Create comparable experiment in Azure Machine Learning"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3155,
        3216
      ],
      "content": "We followed these steps to create our experiment in Azure ML:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3224,
        3288
      ],
      "content": "Uploaded the dataset as a csv file to Azure ML (very small file)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3293,
        3419
      ],
      "content": "Created a new experiment and used the [Project Columns][project-columns] module to select the same data features used in Excel"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3427,
        3563
      ],
      "content": "Used the [Split][split] module (with <bpt id=\"p4\">*</bpt>Relative Expression<ept id=\"p4\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph6\"/> mode) to divide the data into exact same train sets as had been done in Excel"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3570,
        3728
      ],
      "content": "Experimented with the [Linear Regression][linear-regression] module (default options only), documented, and compared the results to our Excel regression model"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3734,
        3756
      ],
      "content": "Review initial results"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3757,
        3823
      ],
      "content": "At first, the Excel model clearly outperformed the Azure ML model:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3832,
        3837
      ],
      "content": "Excel"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3838,
        3846
      ],
      "content": "Azure ML"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3867,
        3878
      ],
      "content": "Performance"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3927,
        3944
      ],
      "content": "Adjusted R Square"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3956,
        3960
      ],
      "content": "0.96"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3962,
        3965
      ],
      "content": "N/A"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4007,
        4021
      ],
      "content": "Coefficient of"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4028,
        4041
      ],
      "content": "Determination"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4052,
        4055
      ],
      "content": "N/A"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4059,
        4063
      ],
      "content": "0.78"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4069,
        4083
      ],
      "content": "(low accuracy)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4086,
        4105
      ],
      "content": "Mean Absolute Error"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4109,
        4114
      ],
      "content": "$9.5M"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4117,
        4124
      ],
      "content": "$ 19.4M"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4127,
        4150
      ],
      "content": "Mean Absolute Error (%)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4154,
        4159
      ],
      "content": "6.03%"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4162,
        4167
      ],
      "content": "12.2%"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4169,
        4304
      ],
      "content": "When we ran our process and results by the developers and data scientists on the Azure ML team, they quickly provided some useful tips."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4310,
        4411
      ],
      "content": "When you use the [Linear Regression][linear-regression] module in Azure ML, two methods are provided:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4419,
        4490
      ],
      "content": "Online Gradient Descent: May be more suitable for larger-scale problems"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4498,
        4668
      ],
      "content": "Ordinary Least Squares: This is the method most people think of when they hear linear regression. For small datasets, Ordinary Least Squares can be a more optimal choice.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Ordinary Least Squares: This is the method most people think of when they hear linear regression.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            97
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For small datasets, Ordinary Least Squares can be a more optimal choice.",
          "pos": [
            98,
            170
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4672,
        4853
      ],
      "content": "Consider tweaking the L2 Regularization Weight parameter to improve performance. It is set to 0.001 by default and for our small data set, we set it to 0.005 to improve performance.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Consider tweaking the L2 Regularization Weight parameter to improve performance.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            80
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "It is set to 0.001 by default and for our small data set, we set it to 0.005 to improve performance.",
          "pos": [
            81,
            181
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4863,
        4878
      ],
      "content": "Mystery solved!"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4879,
        4984
      ],
      "content": "When we applied the recommendations, we achieved the same baseline performance in Azure ML as with Excel:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4992,
        4997
      ],
      "content": "Excel"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4998,
        5016
      ],
      "content": "Azure ML (Initial)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5017,
        5042
      ],
      "content": "Azure ML w/ Least Squares"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5069,
        5082
      ],
      "content": "Labeled value"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5085,
        5102
      ],
      "content": "Actuals (numeric)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5103,
        5107
      ],
      "content": "same"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5108,
        5112
      ],
      "content": "same"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5115,
        5122
      ],
      "content": "Learner"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5125,
        5161
      ],
      "content": "Excel -&gt; Data Analysis -&gt; Regression"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5162,
        5180
      ],
      "content": "Linear Regression."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5181,
        5198
      ],
      "content": "Linear Regression"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5201,
        5216
      ],
      "content": "Learner options"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5217,
        5220
      ],
      "content": "N/A"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5221,
        5229
      ],
      "content": "Defaults"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5230,
        5253
      ],
      "content": "ordinary  least squares"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5259,
        5269
      ],
      "content": "L2 = 0.005"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5272,
        5280
      ],
      "content": "Data Set"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5281,
        5325
      ],
      "content": "26 rows, 3 features, 1 label.   All numeric.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "26 rows, 3 features, 1 label.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            29
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "All numeric.",
          "pos": [
            32,
            44
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5326,
        5330
      ],
      "content": "same"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5331,
        5335
      ],
      "content": "same"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5338,
        5350
      ],
      "content": "Split: Train"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5351,
        5413
      ],
      "content": "Excel trained on the first 18 rows, tested on the last 8 rows."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5414,
        5418
      ],
      "content": "same"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5419,
        5423
      ],
      "content": "same"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5426,
        5437
      ],
      "content": "Split: Test"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5438,
        5489
      ],
      "content": "Excel regression formula applied to the last 8 rows"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5490,
        5494
      ],
      "content": "same"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5495,
        5499
      ],
      "content": "same"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5502,
        5517
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Performance<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5523,
        5540
      ],
      "content": "Adjusted R Square"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5541,
        5545
      ],
      "content": "0.96"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5546,
        5549
      ],
      "content": "N/A"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5553,
        5581
      ],
      "content": "Coefficient of Determination"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5582,
        5585
      ],
      "content": "N/A"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5586,
        5590
      ],
      "content": "0.78"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5591,
        5599
      ],
      "content": "0.952049"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5602,
        5621
      ],
      "content": "Mean Absolute Error"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5623,
        5628
      ],
      "content": "$9.5M"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5629,
        5636
      ],
      "content": "$ 19.4M"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5637,
        5642
      ],
      "content": "$9.5M"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5645,
        5668
      ],
      "content": "Mean Absolute Error (%)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5710,
        5715
      ],
      "content": "6.03%"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5723,
        5728
      ],
      "content": "12.2%"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5770,
        5775
      ],
      "content": "6.03%"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5785,
        5885
      ],
      "content": "In addition, the Excel coefficients compared well to the feature weights in the Azure trained model:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5889,
        5907
      ],
      "content": "Excel Coefficients"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5908,
        5929
      ],
      "content": "Azure Feature Weights"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5950,
        5964
      ],
      "content": "Intercept/Bias"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5965,
        5976
      ],
      "content": "19470209.88"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5977,
        5985
      ],
      "content": "19328500"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5988,
        5997
      ],
      "content": "Feature A"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5998,
        6009
      ],
      "content": "0.832653063"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6010,
        6018
      ],
      "content": "0.834156"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6021,
        6030
      ],
      "content": "Feature B"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6031,
        6042
      ],
      "content": "11071967.08"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6043,
        6051
      ],
      "content": "11007300"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6054,
        6063
      ],
      "content": "Feature C"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6064,
        6075
      ],
      "content": "25383318.09"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6076,
        6084
      ],
      "content": "25140800"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6090,
        6100
      ],
      "content": "Next Steps"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6102,
        6321
      ],
      "content": "We wanted to consume Azure ML web service within Excel.  Our business analysts rely on Excel and we needed a way to call the Azure ML web service with a row of Excel data and have it return the predicted value to Excel.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "We wanted to consume Azure ML web service within Excel.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            55
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Our business analysts rely on Excel and we needed a way to call the Azure ML web service with a row of Excel data and have it return the predicted value to Excel.",
          "pos": [
            57,
            219
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6326,
        6419
      ],
      "content": "We also wanted to optimize our model, using the options and algorithms available in Azure ML."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6425,
        6447
      ],
      "content": "Integration with Excel"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6448,
        6691
      ],
      "content": "Our solution was to operationalize our Azure ML regression model by creating a web service from the trained model.  Within a few minutes, the web service was created and we could call it directly from Excel to return a predicted revenue value.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Our solution was to operationalize our Azure ML regression model by creating a web service from the trained model.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            114
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Within a few minutes, the web service was created and we could call it directly from Excel to return a predicted revenue value.",
          "pos": [
            116,
            243
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6697,
        6965
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p6\">*</bpt>Web Services Dashboard<ept id=\"p6\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph7\"/> section includes a downloadable Excel workbook.  The workbook comes pre-formatted with the web service API and schema information embedded.   When you click on <bpt id=\"p7\">*</bpt>Download Excel Workbook<ept id=\"p7\">*</ept>, it opens and you can save it to your local computer.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The <bpt id=\"p6\">*</bpt>Web Services Dashboard<ept id=\"p6\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph7\"/> section includes a downloadable Excel workbook.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            128
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The workbook comes pre-formatted with the web service API and schema information embedded.",
          "pos": [
            130,
            220
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "When you click on <bpt id=\"p7\">*</bpt>Download Excel Workbook<ept id=\"p7\">*</ept>, it opens and you can save it to your local computer.",
          "pos": [
            223,
            358
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6980,
        7540
      ],
      "content": "With the workbook open, copy your predefined parameters into the blue Parameter section as shown below.  Once the parameters are entered, Excel calls out to the AzureML web service and the predicted scored labels will display in the green Predicted Values section.  The workbook will continue to create predictions for parameters based on your trained model for all row items entered under Parameters.   For more information on how to use this feature, see <bpt id=\"p8\">[</bpt>Consuming an Azure Machine Learning Web Service from Excel<ept id=\"p8\">](machine-learning-consuming-from-excel.md)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "With the workbook open, copy your predefined parameters into the blue Parameter section as shown below.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            103
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Once the parameters are entered, Excel calls out to the AzureML web service and the predicted scored labels will display in the green Predicted Values section.",
          "pos": [
            105,
            264
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The workbook will continue to create predictions for parameters based on your trained model for all row items entered under Parameters.",
          "pos": [
            266,
            401
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information on how to use this feature, see <bpt id=\"p8\">[</bpt>Consuming an Azure Machine Learning Web Service from Excel<ept id=\"p8\">](machine-learning-consuming-from-excel.md)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            404,
            598
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7556,
        7592
      ],
      "content": "Optimization and further experiments"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7593,
        8090
      ],
      "content": "Now that we had a baseline with our Excel model, we moved ahead to optimize our Azure ML Linear Regression Model.  We used the module [Filter-Based Feature Selection][filter-based-feature-selection] to improve on our selection of initial data elements and it helped us achieve a performance improvement of 4.6% Mean Absolute Error.   For future projects we will use this feature which could save us weeks in iterating through data attributes to find the right set of features to use for modelling.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Now that we had a baseline with our Excel model, we moved ahead to optimize our Azure ML Linear Regression Model.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            113
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "We used the module [Filter-Based Feature Selection][filter-based-feature-selection] to improve on our selection of initial data elements and it helped us achieve a performance improvement of 4.6% Mean Absolute Error.",
          "pos": [
            115,
            331
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For future projects we will use this feature which could save us weeks in iterating through data attributes to find the right set of features to use for modelling.",
          "pos": [
            334,
            497
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8094,
        8287
      ],
      "content": "Next we plan to include additional algorithms like [Bayesian][bayesian-linear-regression] or [Boosted Decision Trees][boosted-decision-tree-regression] in our experiment to compare performance."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8293,
        8772
      ],
      "content": "If you want to experiment with regression, a good dataset to try is the Energy Efficiency Regression sample dataset, which has lots of numerical attributes. The dataset is provided as part of the sample datasets in ML Studio.  You can use a variety of learning modules to predict either Heating Load or Cooling Load.  The chart below is a performance comparison of different regression learns against the Energy Efficiency dataset predicting for the target variable Cooling Load:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "If you want to experiment with regression, a good dataset to try is the Energy Efficiency Regression sample dataset, which has lots of numerical attributes.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            156
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The dataset is provided as part of the sample datasets in ML Studio.",
          "pos": [
            157,
            225
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can use a variety of learning modules to predict either Heating Load or Cooling Load.",
          "pos": [
            227,
            316
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The chart below is a performance comparison of different regression learns against the Energy Efficiency dataset predicting for the target variable Cooling Load:",
          "pos": [
            318,
            479
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8776,
        8781
      ],
      "content": "Model"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8782,
        8801
      ],
      "content": "Mean Absolute Error"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8802,
        8825
      ],
      "content": "Root Mean Squared Error"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8826,
        8849
      ],
      "content": "Relative Absolute Error"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8850,
        8872
      ],
      "content": "Relative Squared Error"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8873,
        8901
      ],
      "content": "Coefficient of Determination"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8928,
        8949
      ],
      "content": "Boosted Decision Tree"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8950,
        8958
      ],
      "content": "0.930113"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8959,
        8965
      ],
      "content": "1.4239"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8966,
        8974
      ],
      "content": "0.106647"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8975,
        8983
      ],
      "content": "0.021662"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8984,
        8992
      ],
      "content": "0.978338"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8994,
        9030
      ],
      "content": "Linear Regression (Gradient Descent)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9031,
        9039
      ],
      "content": "2.035693"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9040,
        9047
      ],
      "content": "2.98006"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9048,
        9056
      ],
      "content": "0.233414"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9057,
        9065
      ],
      "content": "0.094881"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9066,
        9074
      ],
      "content": "0.905119"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9076,
        9101
      ],
      "content": "Neural Network Regression"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9102,
        9110
      ],
      "content": "1.548195"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9111,
        9119
      ],
      "content": "2.114617"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9120,
        9128
      ],
      "content": "0.177517"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9129,
        9137
      ],
      "content": "0.047774"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9138,
        9146
      ],
      "content": "0.952226"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9148,
        9190
      ],
      "content": "Linear Regression (Ordinary Least Squares)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9191,
        9199
      ],
      "content": "1.428273"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9200,
        9208
      ],
      "content": "1.984461"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9209,
        9217
      ],
      "content": "0.163767"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9218,
        9226
      ],
      "content": "0.042074"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9227,
        9235
      ],
      "content": "0.957926"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9242,
        9255
      ],
      "content": "Key Takeaways"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9258,
        9585
      ],
      "content": "We learned a lot by from running Excel regression and Azure Machine Learning experiments in parallel. Creating the baseline model in Excel and comparing it to models using  Azure ML [Linear Regression][linear-regression] helped us learn Azure ML, and we discovered opportunities to improve data selection and model performance.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "We learned a lot by from running Excel regression and Azure Machine Learning experiments in parallel.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            101
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Creating the baseline model in Excel and comparing it to models using  Azure ML [Linear Regression][linear-regression] helped us learn Azure ML, and we discovered opportunities to improve data selection and model performance.",
          "pos": [
            102,
            327
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9596,
        9867
      ],
      "content": "We also found that it is advisable to use [Filter-Based Feature Selection][filter-based-feature-selection] to accelerate future prediction projects.  By applying feature selection to your data, you can create an improved model in Azure ML with better overall performance.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "We also found that it is advisable to use [Filter-Based Feature Selection][filter-based-feature-selection] to accelerate future prediction projects.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            148
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "By applying feature selection to your data, you can create an improved model in Azure ML with better overall performance.",
          "pos": [
            150,
            271
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9870,
        10077
      ],
      "content": "The ability to transfer the predictive analytic forecasting from Azure ML to Excel systemically allows a significant increase in the ability to successfully provide results to a broad business user audience."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10088,
        10097
      ],
      "content": "Resources"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10098,
        10161
      ],
      "content": "Some resources are listed for helping you work with regression:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10167,
        10365
      ],
      "content": "Regression in Excel.  If you’ve never tried regression in Excel, this tutorial makes it easy: <bpt id=\"p9\">[</bpt>http://www.excel-easy.com/examples/regression.html<ept id=\"p9\">](http://www.excel-easy.com/examples/regression.html)</ept>",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Regression in Excel.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            20
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "If you’ve never tried regression in Excel, this tutorial makes it easy: <bpt id=\"p9\">[</bpt>http://www.excel-easy.com/examples/regression.html<ept id=\"p9\">](http://www.excel-easy.com/examples/regression.html)</ept>",
          "pos": [
            22,
            236
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10368,
        10744
      ],
      "content": "Regression vs forecasting.  Tyler Chessman wrote a blog article explaining how to do time series forecasting in Excel, which contains a good beginner’s description of linear regression. <bpt id=\"p10\">[</bpt>http://sqlmag.com/sql-server-analysis-services/understanding-time-series-forecasting-concepts<ept id=\"p10\">](http://sqlmag.com/sql-server-analysis-services/understanding-time-series-forecasting-concepts)</ept>",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Regression vs forecasting.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            26
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Tyler Chessman wrote a blog article explaining how to do time series forecasting in Excel, which contains a good beginner’s description of linear regression.",
          "pos": [
            28,
            185
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p10\">[</bpt>http://sqlmag.com/sql-server-analysis-services/understanding-time-series-forecasting-concepts<ept id=\"p10\">](http://sqlmag.com/sql-server-analysis-services/understanding-time-series-forecasting-concepts)</ept>",
          "pos": [
            186,
            416
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10751,
        11101
      ],
      "content": "Ordinary Least Squares Linear Regression: Flaws, Problems and Pitfalls.  For an introduction and discussion of Regression:   <bpt id=\"p11\">[</bpt>http://www.clockbackward.com/2009/06/18/ordinary-least-squares-linear-regression-flaws-problems-and-pitfalls/ \n<ept id=\"p11\">](http://www.clockbackward.com/2009/06/18/ordinary-least-squares-linear-regression-flaws-problems-and-pitfalls/ )</ept>",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Ordinary Least Squares Linear Regression: Flaws, Problems and Pitfalls.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            71
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For an introduction and discussion of Regression:   <bpt id=\"p11\">[</bpt>http://www.clockbackward.com/2009/06/18/ordinary-least-squares-linear-regression-flaws-problems-and-pitfalls/ \n<ept id=\"p11\">](http://www.clockbackward.com/2009/06/18/ordinary-least-squares-linear-regression-flaws-problems-and-pitfalls/ )</ept>",
          "pos": [
            73,
            390
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11346,
        11968
      ],
      "content": "[bayesian-linear-regression]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee12de50-2b34-4145-aec0-23e0485da308/\n[boosted-decision-tree-regression]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/0207d252-6c41-4c77-84c3-73bdf1ac5960/\n[filter-based-feature-selection]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/918b356b-045c-412b-aa12-94a1d2dad90f/\n[linear-regression]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/31960a6f-789b-4cf7-88d6-2e1152c0bd1a/\n[project-columns]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/1ec722fa-b623-4e26-a44e-a50c6d726223/\n[split]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/70530644-c97a-4ab6-85f7-88bf30a8be5f/"
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Using Linear Regression in Machine Learning | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"A comparison of linear regression models in Excel and in Azure Machine Learning Studio\" \n    metaKeywords=\"\" \n    services=\"machine-learning\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"garyericson\" \n    manager=\"paulettm\" \n    editor=\"cgronlun\"  />\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\" \n    ms.workload=\"data-services\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"12/11/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"kbaroni;garye\" />\n\n# Using linear regression in Azure Machine Learning\n\n> *Kate Baroni* and *Ben Boatman* are enterprise solution architects in Microsoft’s Data Insights Center of Excellence. In this article, they describe their experience migrating an existing regression analysis suite to a cloud-based solution using Azure Machine Learning.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [machine-learning-free-trial](../../includes/machine-learning-free-trial.md)]\n\n## Goal\n\nOur project started with two goals in mind:  \n\n1. Use predictive analytics to improve the accuracy of our organization’s monthly revenue projections  \n2. Use Azure ML to confirm, optimize, increase velocity, and scale of our results.  \n\nLike many businesses, our organization goes through a monthly revenue forecasting process. Our small team of business analysts was tasked with using Machine Learning to support the process and improve forecast accuracy.  The team spent several months collecting data from multiple sources and running the data attributes through statistical analysis identifying key attributes relevant to services sales forecasting.  Next steps was to begin prototyping statistical regression models on the data in Excel.  Within a few weeks we had an Excel regression model that was outperforming the current field and finance forecasting processes. This became the baseline prediction result.  \n\n\nWe then took the next step to moving our predictive analytics over to Azure ML to find out how Azure ML could improve on predictive performance.\n\n\n## Achieving predictive performance parity\n\nOur first priority was to achieve parity between Azure ML and Excel regression models.  Given the exact same data, and the same split for training and testing data we wanted to achieve predictive performance parity between Excel and Azure ML.   Initially we failed. The Excel model outperformed the Azure ML model.   The failure was due to a lack of understanding of the base tool setting in Azure ML. After a sync with the Azure ML product team, we gained a better understanding of the base setting required for our data sets, and achieved parity between the two models.  \n\n### Create regression model in Excel\nOur Excel Regression used the standard linear regression model found in the Excel Analysis ToolPak. \n\nWe calculated *Mean Absolute % Error* and used it as the performance measure for the model.  It took 3 months to arrive at a working model using Excel.  We brought much of the learning into the Azure ML experiment which ultimately was beneficial in understanding requirements.\n\n### Create comparable experiment in Azure Machine Learning  \nWe followed these steps to create our experiment in Azure ML:  \n\n1.  Uploaded the dataset as a csv file to Azure ML (very small file)\n2.  Created a new experiment and used the [Project Columns][project-columns] module to select the same data features used in Excel   \n3.  Used the [Split][split] module (with *Relative Expression* mode) to divide the data into exact same train sets as had been done in Excel  \n4.  Experimented with the [Linear Regression][linear-regression] module (default options only), documented, and compared the results to our Excel regression model\n\n### Review initial results\nAt first, the Excel model clearly outperformed the Azure ML model:  \n\n|   |Excel|Azure ML|\n|---|:---:|:---:|\n|Performance|   |  |\n|<ul style=\"list-style-type: none;\"><li>Adjusted R Square</li></ul>| 0.96 |N/A|\n|<ul style=\"list-style-type: none;\"><li>Coefficient of <br />Determination</li></ul>|N/A|   0.78<br />(low accuracy)|\n|Mean Absolute Error |  $9.5M|  $ 19.4M|\n|Mean Absolute Error (%)|   6.03%|  12.2%\n\nWhen we ran our process and results by the developers and data scientists on the Azure ML team, they quickly provided some useful tips.  \n\n* When you use the [Linear Regression][linear-regression] module in Azure ML, two methods are provided:\n    *  Online Gradient Descent: May be more suitable for larger-scale problems\n    *  Ordinary Least Squares: This is the method most people think of when they hear linear regression. For small datasets, Ordinary Least Squares can be a more optimal choice.\n*  Consider tweaking the L2 Regularization Weight parameter to improve performance. It is set to 0.001 by default and for our small data set, we set it to 0.005 to improve performance.    \n\n### Mystery solved!\nWhen we applied the recommendations, we achieved the same baseline performance in Azure ML as with Excel:   \n\n|| Excel|Azure ML (Initial)|Azure ML w/ Least Squares|\n|---|:---:|:---:|:---:|\n|Labeled value  |Actuals (numeric)|same|same|\n|Learner  |Excel -> Data Analysis -> Regression|Linear Regression.|Linear Regression|\n|Learner options|N/A|Defaults|ordinary  least squares<br />L2 = 0.005|\n|Data Set|26 rows, 3 features, 1 label.   All numeric.|same|same|\n|Split: Train|Excel trained on the first 18 rows, tested on the last 8 rows.|same|same|\n|Split: Test|Excel regression formula applied to the last 8 rows|same|same|\n|**Performance**||||\n|Adjusted R Square|0.96|N/A||\n|Coefficient of Determination|N/A|0.78|0.952049|\n|Mean Absolute Error |$9.5M|$ 19.4M|$9.5M|\n|Mean Absolute Error (%)|<span style=\"background-color: 00FF00;\"> 6.03%</span>|12.2%|<span style=\"background-color: 00FF00;\"> 6.03%</span>|\n\nIn addition, the Excel coefficients compared well to the feature weights in the Azure trained model:\n\n||Excel Coefficients|Azure Feature Weights|\n|---|:---:|:---:|\n|Intercept/Bias|19470209.88|19328500|\n|Feature A|0.832653063|0.834156|\n|Feature B|11071967.08|11007300|\n|Feature C|25383318.09|25140800|\n\n## Next Steps\n\nWe wanted to consume Azure ML web service within Excel.  Our business analysts rely on Excel and we needed a way to call the Azure ML web service with a row of Excel data and have it return the predicted value to Excel.   \n\nWe also wanted to optimize our model, using the options and algorithms available in Azure ML.\n\n### Integration with Excel\nOur solution was to operationalize our Azure ML regression model by creating a web service from the trained model.  Within a few minutes, the web service was created and we could call it directly from Excel to return a predicted revenue value.    \n\nThe *Web Services Dashboard* section includes a downloadable Excel workbook.  The workbook comes pre-formatted with the web service API and schema information embedded.   When you click on *Download Excel Workbook*, it opens and you can save it to your local computer.    \n\n![][1]\n \nWith the workbook open, copy your predefined parameters into the blue Parameter section as shown below.  Once the parameters are entered, Excel calls out to the AzureML web service and the predicted scored labels will display in the green Predicted Values section.  The workbook will continue to create predictions for parameters based on your trained model for all row items entered under Parameters.   For more information on how to use this feature, see [Consuming an Azure Machine Learning Web Service from Excel](machine-learning-consuming-from-excel.md). \n\n![][2]\n \n### Optimization and further experiments\nNow that we had a baseline with our Excel model, we moved ahead to optimize our Azure ML Linear Regression Model.  We used the module [Filter-Based Feature Selection][filter-based-feature-selection] to improve on our selection of initial data elements and it helped us achieve a performance improvement of 4.6% Mean Absolute Error.   For future projects we will use this feature which could save us weeks in iterating through data attributes to find the right set of features to use for modelling.  \n\nNext we plan to include additional algorithms like [Bayesian][bayesian-linear-regression] or [Boosted Decision Trees][boosted-decision-tree-regression] in our experiment to compare performance.    \n\nIf you want to experiment with regression, a good dataset to try is the Energy Efficiency Regression sample dataset, which has lots of numerical attributes. The dataset is provided as part of the sample datasets in ML Studio.  You can use a variety of learning modules to predict either Heating Load or Cooling Load.  The chart below is a performance comparison of different regression learns against the Energy Efficiency dataset predicting for the target variable Cooling Load: \n\n|Model|Mean Absolute Error|Root Mean Squared Error|Relative Absolute Error|Relative Squared Error|Coefficient of Determination\n|---|---|---|---|---|---\n|Boosted Decision Tree|0.930113|1.4239|0.106647|0.021662|0.978338\n|Linear Regression (Gradient Descent)|2.035693|2.98006|0.233414|0.094881|0.905119\n|Neural Network Regression|1.548195|2.114617|0.177517|0.047774|0.952226\n|Linear Regression (Ordinary Least Squares)|1.428273|1.984461|0.163767|0.042074|0.957926  \n\n## Key Takeaways \n\nWe learned a lot by from running Excel regression and Azure Machine Learning experiments in parallel. Creating the baseline model in Excel and comparing it to models using  Azure ML [Linear Regression][linear-regression] helped us learn Azure ML, and we discovered opportunities to improve data selection and model performance.         \n\nWe also found that it is advisable to use [Filter-Based Feature Selection][filter-based-feature-selection] to accelerate future prediction projects.  By applying feature selection to your data, you can create an improved model in Azure ML with better overall performance. \n\nThe ability to transfer the predictive analytic forecasting from Azure ML to Excel systemically allows a significant increase in the ability to successfully provide results to a broad business user audience.     \n\n\n## Resources\nSome resources are listed for helping you work with regression:  \n\n* Regression in Excel.  If you’ve never tried regression in Excel, this tutorial makes it easy: [http://www.excel-easy.com/examples/regression.html](http://www.excel-easy.com/examples/regression.html)\n* Regression vs forecasting.  Tyler Chessman wrote a blog article explaining how to do time series forecasting in Excel, which contains a good beginner’s description of linear regression. [http://sqlmag.com/sql-server-analysis-services/understanding-time-series-forecasting-concepts](http://sqlmag.com/sql-server-analysis-services/understanding-time-series-forecasting-concepts)  \n*   Ordinary Least Squares Linear Regression: Flaws, Problems and Pitfalls.  For an introduction and discussion of Regression:   [http://www.clockbackward.com/2009/06/18/ordinary-least-squares-linear-regression-flaws-problems-and-pitfalls/ \n](http://www.clockbackward.com/2009/06/18/ordinary-least-squares-linear-regression-flaws-problems-and-pitfalls/ )\n\n[1]: ./media/machine-learning-linear-regression-in-azure/machine-learning-linear-regression-in-azure-1.png\n[2]: ./media/machine-learning-linear-regression-in-azure/machine-learning-linear-regression-in-azure-2.png\n\n\n<!-- Module References -->\n[bayesian-linear-regression]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee12de50-2b34-4145-aec0-23e0485da308/\n[boosted-decision-tree-regression]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/0207d252-6c41-4c77-84c3-73bdf1ac5960/\n[filter-based-feature-selection]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/918b356b-045c-412b-aa12-94a1d2dad90f/\n[linear-regression]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/31960a6f-789b-4cf7-88d6-2e1152c0bd1a/\n[project-columns]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/1ec722fa-b623-4e26-a44e-a50c6d726223/\n[split]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/70530644-c97a-4ab6-85f7-88bf30a8be5f/\n \n"
}