{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        23,
        65
      ],
      "content": "Use Ambari Tez View with HDInsight | Azure"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        80,
        148
      ],
      "content": "Learn how to use the Ambari Tez view to debug Tez jobs on HDInsight."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        406,
        453
      ],
      "content": "Use Ambari Views to debug Tez Jobs on HDInsight"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        455,
        737
      ],
      "content": "The Ambari Web UI for HDInsight contains a Tez view that can be used to understand and debug jobs that use Tez as the execution engine. The Tez view allows you to visualize the job as a graph of connected items, drill into each item, and retrieve statistics and logging information.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The Ambari Web UI for HDInsight contains a Tez view that can be used to understand and debug jobs that use Tez as the execution engine.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            135
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The Tez view allows you to visualize the job as a graph of connected items, drill into each item, and retrieve statistics and logging information.",
          "pos": [
            136,
            282
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        741,
        996
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph2\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph3\"/> The information in this document is specific to Linux-based HDInsight clusters. For information on debugging Tez jobs using Windows-based HDInsight, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Use the Tez UI to debug Tez jobs on Windows-based HDInsight<ept id=\"p1\">](hdinsight-debug-tez-ui.md)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph2\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph3\"/> The information in this document is specific to Linux-based HDInsight clusters.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            124
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For information on debugging Tez jobs using Windows-based HDInsight, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Use the Tez UI to debug Tez jobs on Windows-based HDInsight<ept id=\"p1\">](hdinsight-debug-tez-ui.md)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            125,
            325
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1000,
        1013
      ],
      "content": "Prerequisites"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1017,
        1181
      ],
      "content": "A Linux-based HDInsight cluster. For steps on creating a new cluster, see <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Get started using Linux-based HDInsight<ept id=\"p2\">](hdinsight-hadoop-linux-tutorial-get-started.md)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "A Linux-based HDInsight cluster.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            32
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For steps on creating a new cluster, see <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Get started using Linux-based HDInsight<ept id=\"p2\">](hdinsight-hadoop-linux-tutorial-get-started.md)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            33,
            202
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1185,
        1226
      ],
      "content": "A modern web browser that supports HTML5."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1230,
        1247
      ],
      "content": "Understanding Tez"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1249,
        1448
      ],
      "content": "Tez is an extensible framework for data processing in Hadoop that provides greater speeds than traditional MapReduce processing. For Linux-based HDInsight clusters, it is the default engine for Hive.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Tez is an extensible framework for data processing in Hadoop that provides greater speeds than traditional MapReduce processing.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            128
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For Linux-based HDInsight clusters, it is the default engine for Hive.",
          "pos": [
            129,
            199
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1450,
        1810
      ],
      "content": "When work is submitted to Tez, it creates a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) that describes the order of execution of the actions required by the job. Individual actions are called vertices, and execute a piece of the overall job. The actual execution of the work described by a vertex is called a task, and may be distributed across multiple nodes in the cluster.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "When work is submitted to Tez, it creates a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) that describes the order of execution of the actions required by the job.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            146
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Individual actions are called vertices, and execute a piece of the overall job.",
          "pos": [
            147,
            226
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The actual execution of the work described by a vertex is called a task, and may be distributed across multiple nodes in the cluster.",
          "pos": [
            227,
            360
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1815,
        1841
      ],
      "content": "Understanding the Tez view"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1843,
        2163
      ],
      "content": "The Tez view provides information on processes that are running, or have previously ran using Tez. It allows you to view the DAG generated by Tez, how it is distributed across clusters, counters such as memory used by tasks and vertices, and error information. It may offer useful information in the following scenarios:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The Tez view provides information on processes that are running, or have previously ran using Tez.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            98
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "It allows you to view the DAG generated by Tez, how it is distributed across clusters, counters such as memory used by tasks and vertices, and error information.",
          "pos": [
            99,
            260
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "It may offer useful information in the following scenarios:",
          "pos": [
            261,
            320
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2167,
        2247
      ],
      "content": "Monitoring long-running processes, viewing the progress of map and reduce tasks."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2251,
        2371
      ],
      "content": "Analyzing historical data for successful or failed processes to learn how processing could be improved or why it failed."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2375,
        2389
      ],
      "content": "Generate a DAG"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2391,
        2680
      ],
      "content": "The Tez view will only contain data if a job that uses the Tez engine is currently running, or has been ran in the past. Simple Hive queries can usually be resolved without using Tez, however more complex queries that do filtering, grouping, ordering, joins, etc. will usually require Tez.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The Tez view will only contain data if a job that uses the Tez engine is currently running, or has been ran in the past.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            120
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Simple Hive queries can usually be resolved without using Tez, however more complex queries that do filtering, grouping, ordering, joins, etc. will usually require Tez.",
          "pos": [
            121,
            289
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2682,
        2754
      ],
      "content": "Use the following steps to run a Hive query that will execute using Tez."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2759,
        2889
      ],
      "content": "In a web browser, navigate to https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net, where <bpt id=\"p3\">__</bpt>CLUSTERNAME<ept id=\"p3\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph4\"/> is the name of your HDInsight cluster."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2894,
        3047
      ],
      "content": "From the menu at the top of the page, select the <bpt id=\"p4\">__</bpt>Views<ept id=\"p4\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph5\"/> icon. This looks like a series of squares. In the dropdown that appears, select <bpt id=\"p5\">__</bpt>Hive view<ept id=\"p5\">__</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "From the menu at the top of the page, select the <bpt id=\"p4\">__</bpt>Views<ept id=\"p4\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph5\"/> icon.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            116
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This looks like a series of squares.",
          "pos": [
            117,
            153
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "In the dropdown that appears, select <bpt id=\"p5\">__</bpt>Hive view<ept id=\"p5\">__</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            154,
            243
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3054,
        3132
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph6\">![</ph>Selecting Hive View<ph id=\"ph7\">](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/selecthive.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3137,
        3233
      ],
      "content": "When the Hive view loads, paste the following into the Query Editor, and then click <bpt id=\"p6\">__</bpt>execute<ept id=\"p6\">__</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3367,
        3519
      ],
      "content": "Once the job has completed, you should see the output displayed in the <bpt id=\"p7\">__</bpt>Query Process Results<ept id=\"p7\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph8\"/> section. The results should be similar to the following",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Once the job has completed, you should see the output displayed in the <bpt id=\"p7\">__</bpt>Query Process Results<ept id=\"p7\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph8\"/> section.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            157
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The results should be similar to the following",
          "pos": [
            158,
            204
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3645,
        3719
      ],
      "content": "Select the <bpt id=\"p8\">__</bpt>Log<ept id=\"p8\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> tab. You will see information similar to the following:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Select the <bpt id=\"p8\">__</bpt>Log<ept id=\"p8\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> tab.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            75
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You will see information similar to the following:",
          "pos": [
            76,
            126
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3887,
        3955
      ],
      "content": "Save the <bpt id=\"p9\">__</bpt>App id<ept id=\"p9\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph10\"/> value, as this will be used in the next section."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3959,
        3975
      ],
      "content": "Use the Tez View"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3980,
        4095
      ],
      "content": "From the menu at the top of the page, select the <bpt id=\"p10\">__</bpt>Views<ept id=\"p10\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph11\"/> icon. In the dropdown that appears, select <bpt id=\"p11\">__</bpt>Tez view<ept id=\"p11\">__</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "From the menu at the top of the page, select the <bpt id=\"p10\">__</bpt>Views<ept id=\"p10\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph11\"/> icon.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            119
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "In the dropdown that appears, select <bpt id=\"p11\">__</bpt>Tez view<ept id=\"p11\">__</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            120,
            210
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4101,
        4177
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph12\">![</ph>Selecting Tez view<ph id=\"ph13\">](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/selecttez.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4182,
        4489
      ],
      "content": "When the Tez view loads, you will see a list of DAGs that are currently running, or have been ran on the cluster. The default view includes the Dag Name, Id, Submitter, Status, Start Time, End Time, Duration, Application ID, and Queue. More columns can be added using the gear icon at the right of the page.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "When the Tez view loads, you will see a list of DAGs that are currently running, or have been ran on the cluster.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            113
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The default view includes the Dag Name, Id, Submitter, Status, Start Time, End Time, Duration, Application ID, and Queue.",
          "pos": [
            114,
            235
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "More columns can be added using the gear icon at the right of the page.",
          "pos": [
            236,
            307
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4495,
        4559
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph14\">![</ph>All DAGS<ph id=\"ph15\">](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/alldags.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4564,
        4785
      ],
      "content": "If you have only one entry, it will be for the query that you ran in the previous section. If you have multiple entries, you can search by entering the application ID in the <bpt id=\"p12\">__</bpt>Application ID<ept id=\"p12\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph16\"/> field, and then press enter.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "If you have only one entry, it will be for the query that you ran in the previous section.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            90
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "If you have multiple entries, you can search by entering the application ID in the <bpt id=\"p12\">__</bpt>Application ID<ept id=\"p12\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph16\"/> field, and then press enter.",
          "pos": [
            91,
            276
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4790,
        4953
      ],
      "content": "Select the <bpt id=\"p13\">__</bpt>Dag Name<ept id=\"p13\">__</ept>. This will display information about the DAG, as well as the option to download a zip of JSON files that contain information about the DAG.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Select the <bpt id=\"p13\">__</bpt>Dag Name<ept id=\"p13\">__</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            64
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This will display information about the DAG, as well as the option to download a zip of JSON files that contain information about the DAG.",
          "pos": [
            65,
            203
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4959,
        5029
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph17\">![</ph>DAG Details<ph id=\"ph18\">](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/dagdetails.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5034,
        5132
      ],
      "content": "Above the <bpt id=\"p14\">__</bpt>DAG Details<ept id=\"p14\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph19\"/> are several links that can be used to display information about the DAG."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5140,
        5200
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p15\">__</bpt>DAG Counters<ept id=\"p15\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph20\"/> displays counters information for this DAG."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5212,
        5279
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p16\">__</bpt>Graphical View<ept id=\"p16\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph21\"/> displays a graphical representation of this DAG."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5291,
        5352
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p17\">__</bpt>All Vertices<ept id=\"p17\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph22\"/> displays a list of the vertices in this DAG."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5364,
        5436
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p18\">__</bpt>All Tasks<ept id=\"p18\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph23\"/> displays a list of the tasks for all vertices in this DAG."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5448,
        5535
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p19\">__</bpt>All TaskAttempts<ept id=\"p19\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph24\"/> displays information about the attempts to run tasks for this DAG."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5547,
        5723
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph25\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph26\"/> If you scroll the column display for Vertices, Tasks and TaskAttempts, notice that there are links to view <bpt id=\"p20\">__</bpt>counters<ept id=\"p20\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph27\"/> and <bpt id=\"p21\">__</bpt>view or download logs<ept id=\"p21\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph28\"/> for each row."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5729,
        5936
      ],
      "content": "If there was a failure with the job, the DAG Details will display a status of FAILED, along with links to information about the failed task. Diagnostics information will be displayed beneath the DAG details.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "If there was a failure with the job, the DAG Details will display a status of FAILED, along with links to information about the failed task.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            140
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Diagnostics information will be displayed beneath the DAG details.",
          "pos": [
            141,
            207
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5946,
        6044
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph29\">![</ph>A DAG Details screen detailing a failure<ph id=\"ph30\">](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/faileddag.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6049,
        6214
      ],
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p22\">__</bpt>Graphical View<ept id=\"p22\">__</ept>. This displays a graphical representation of the DAG. You can place the mouse over each vertex in the view to display information about it.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p22\">__</bpt>Graphical View<ept id=\"p22\">__</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            66
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This displays a graphical representation of the DAG.",
          "pos": [
            67,
            119
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can place the mouse over each vertex in the view to display information about it.",
          "pos": [
            120,
            205
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6220,
        6293
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph31\">![</ph>Graphical view<ph id=\"ph32\">](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/dagdiagram.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6298,
        6430
      ],
      "content": "Clicking on a vertex will load the <bpt id=\"p23\">__</bpt>Vertex Details<ept id=\"p23\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph33\"/> for that item. Click on the <bpt id=\"p24\">__</bpt>Map 1<ept id=\"p24\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph34\"/> vertex to display details for this item.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Clicking on a vertex will load the <bpt id=\"p23\">__</bpt>Vertex Details<ept id=\"p23\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph33\"/> for that item.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            123
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Click on the <bpt id=\"p24\">__</bpt>Map 1<ept id=\"p24\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph34\"/> vertex to display details for this item.",
          "pos": [
            124,
            242
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6436,
        6512
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph35\">![</ph>Vertex details<ph id=\"ph36\">](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/vertexdetails.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6517,
        6608
      ],
      "content": "Note that you now have links at the top of the page that are related to vertices and tasks."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6616,
        6766
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph37\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph38\"/> You can also arrive at this page by going back to <bpt id=\"p25\">__</bpt>DAG Details<ept id=\"p25\">__</ept>, selecting <bpt id=\"p26\">__</bpt>Vertex Details<ept id=\"p26\">__</ept>, and then selecting the <bpt id=\"p27\">__</bpt>Map 1<ept id=\"p27\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph39\"/> vertex."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6774,
        6839
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p28\">__</bpt>Vertex Counters<ept id=\"p28\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph40\"/> displays counter information for this vertex."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6851,
        6892
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p29\">__</bpt>Tasks<ept id=\"p29\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph41\"/> displays tasks for this vertex."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6904,
        6987
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p30\">__</bpt>Task Attempts<ept id=\"p30\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph42\"/> displays information about attempts to run tasks for this vertex."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6999,
        7067
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p31\">__</bpt>Sources &amp; Sinks<ept id=\"p31\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph43\"/> displays data sources and sinks for this vertex."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7075,
        7248
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph44\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph45\"/> As with the previous menu, you can scroll the column display for Tasks, Task Attempts, and Sources &amp; Sinks__ to display links to more information for each item."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7254,
        7439
      ],
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p32\">__</bpt>Tasks<ept id=\"p32\">__</ept>, and then select the item named <bpt id=\"p33\">__</bpt>00_000000<ept id=\"p33\">__</ept>. This will display <bpt id=\"p34\">__</bpt>Task Details<ept id=\"p34\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph46\"/> for this task. From this screen, you can view <bpt id=\"p35\">__</bpt>Task Counters<ept id=\"p35\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph47\"/> and <bpt id=\"p36\">__</bpt>Task Attempts<ept id=\"p36\">__</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p32\">__</bpt>Tasks<ept id=\"p32\">__</ept>, and then select the item named <bpt id=\"p33\">__</bpt>00_000000<ept id=\"p33\">__</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            143
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This will display <bpt id=\"p34\">__</bpt>Task Details<ept id=\"p34\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph46\"/> for this task.",
          "pos": [
            144,
            248
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "From this screen, you can view <bpt id=\"p35\">__</bpt>Task Counters<ept id=\"p35\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph47\"/> and <bpt id=\"p36\">__</bpt>Task Attempts<ept id=\"p36\">__</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            249,
            415
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7445,
        7517
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph48\">![</ph>Task details<ph id=\"ph49\">](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/taskdetails.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7521,
        7531
      ],
      "content": "Next Steps"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7533,
        7650
      ],
      "content": "Now that you have learned how to use the Tez view, learn more about <bpt id=\"p37\">[</bpt>Using Hive on HDInsight<ept id=\"p37\">](hdinsight-use-hive.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7652,
        7770
      ],
      "content": "For more detailed technical information on Tez, see the <bpt id=\"p38\">[</bpt>Tez page at Hortonworks<ept id=\"p38\">](http://hortonworks.com/hadoop/tez/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7772,
        7915
      ],
      "content": "For more information on using Ambari with HDInsight, see <bpt id=\"p39\">[</bpt>Manage HDInsight clusters using the Ambari Web UI<ept id=\"p39\">](hdinsight-hadoop-manage-ambari.md)</ept>"
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\npageTitle=\"Use Ambari Tez View with HDInsight | Azure\"\ndescription=\"Learn how to use the Ambari Tez view to debug Tez jobs on HDInsight.\"\nservices=\"hdinsight\"\ndocumentationCenter=\"\"\nauthors=\"Blackmist\"\nmanager=\"paulettm\"\neditor=\"cgronlun\"/>\n\n<tags\nms.service=\"hdinsight\"\nms.devlang=\"na\"\nms.topic=\"article\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\nms.workload=\"big-data\"\nms.date=\"02/16/2016\"\nms.author=\"larryfr\"/>\n\n# Use Ambari Views to debug Tez Jobs on HDInsight\n\nThe Ambari Web UI for HDInsight contains a Tez view that can be used to understand and debug jobs that use Tez as the execution engine. The Tez view allows you to visualize the job as a graph of connected items, drill into each item, and retrieve statistics and logging information.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] The information in this document is specific to Linux-based HDInsight clusters. For information on debugging Tez jobs using Windows-based HDInsight, see [Use the Tez UI to debug Tez jobs on Windows-based HDInsight](hdinsight-debug-tez-ui.md).\n\n##Prerequisites\n\n* A Linux-based HDInsight cluster. For steps on creating a new cluster, see [Get started using Linux-based HDInsight](hdinsight-hadoop-linux-tutorial-get-started.md).\n\n* A modern web browser that supports HTML5.\n\n##Understanding Tez\n\nTez is an extensible framework for data processing in Hadoop that provides greater speeds than traditional MapReduce processing. For Linux-based HDInsight clusters, it is the default engine for Hive.\n\nWhen work is submitted to Tez, it creates a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) that describes the order of execution of the actions required by the job. Individual actions are called vertices, and execute a piece of the overall job. The actual execution of the work described by a vertex is called a task, and may be distributed across multiple nodes in the cluster.\n\n###Understanding the Tez view\n\nThe Tez view provides information on processes that are running, or have previously ran using Tez. It allows you to view the DAG generated by Tez, how it is distributed across clusters, counters such as memory used by tasks and vertices, and error information. It may offer useful information in the following scenarios:\n\n* Monitoring long-running processes, viewing the progress of map and reduce tasks.\n\n* Analyzing historical data for successful or failed processes to learn how processing could be improved or why it failed.\n\n##Generate a DAG\n\nThe Tez view will only contain data if a job that uses the Tez engine is currently running, or has been ran in the past. Simple Hive queries can usually be resolved without using Tez, however more complex queries that do filtering, grouping, ordering, joins, etc. will usually require Tez.\n\nUse the following steps to run a Hive query that will execute using Tez.\n\n1. In a web browser, navigate to https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net, where __CLUSTERNAME__ is the name of your HDInsight cluster.\n\n2. From the menu at the top of the page, select the __Views__ icon. This looks like a series of squares. In the dropdown that appears, select __Hive view__. \n\n    ![Selecting Hive View](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/selecthive.png)\n\n3. When the Hive view loads, paste the following into the Query Editor, and then click __execute__.\n\n        select market, state, country from hivesampletable where deviceplatform='Android' group by market, country, state;\n    \n    Once the job has completed, you should see the output displayed in the __Query Process Results__ section. The results should be similar to the following\n    \n        market  state       country\n        en-GB   Hessen      Germany\n        en-GB   Kingston    Jamaica\n        \n4. Select the __Log__ tab. You will see information similar to the following:\n    \n        INFO : Session is already open\n        INFO :\n\n        INFO : Status: Running (Executing on YARN cluster with App id application_1454546500517_0063)\n\n    Save the __App id__ value, as this will be used in the next section.\n\n##Use the Tez View\n\n1. From the menu at the top of the page, select the __Views__ icon. In the dropdown that appears, select __Tez view__.\n\n    ![Selecting Tez view](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/selecttez.png)\n\n2. When the Tez view loads, you will see a list of DAGs that are currently running, or have been ran on the cluster. The default view includes the Dag Name, Id, Submitter, Status, Start Time, End Time, Duration, Application ID, and Queue. More columns can be added using the gear icon at the right of the page.\n\n    ![All DAGS](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/alldags.png)\n\n3. If you have only one entry, it will be for the query that you ran in the previous section. If you have multiple entries, you can search by entering the application ID in the __Application ID__ field, and then press enter.\n\n4. Select the __Dag Name__. This will display information about the DAG, as well as the option to download a zip of JSON files that contain information about the DAG.\n\n    ![DAG Details](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/dagdetails.png)\n\n5. Above the __DAG Details__ are several links that can be used to display information about the DAG.\n\n    * __DAG Counters__ displays counters information for this DAG.\n    \n    * __Graphical View__ displays a graphical representation of this DAG.\n    \n    * __All Vertices__ displays a list of the vertices in this DAG.\n    \n    * __All Tasks__ displays a list of the tasks for all vertices in this DAG.\n    \n    * __All TaskAttempts__ displays information about the attempts to run tasks for this DAG.\n    \n    > [AZURE.NOTE] If you scroll the column display for Vertices, Tasks and TaskAttempts, notice that there are links to view __counters__ and __view or download logs__ for each row.\n\n    If there was a failure with the job, the DAG Details will display a status of FAILED, along with links to information about the failed task. Diagnostics information will be displayed beneath the DAG details.\n    \n    ![A DAG Details screen detailing a failure](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/faileddag.png)\n\n7. Select __Graphical View__. This displays a graphical representation of the DAG. You can place the mouse over each vertex in the view to display information about it.\n\n    ![Graphical view](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/dagdiagram.png)\n\n8. Clicking on a vertex will load the __Vertex Details__ for that item. Click on the __Map 1__ vertex to display details for this item.\n\n    ![Vertex details](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/vertexdetails.png)\n\n9. Note that you now have links at the top of the page that are related to vertices and tasks.\n\n    > [AZURE.NOTE] You can also arrive at this page by going back to __DAG Details__, selecting __Vertex Details__, and then selecting the __Map 1__ vertex.\n\n    * __Vertex Counters__ displays counter information for this vertex.\n    \n    * __Tasks__ displays tasks for this vertex.\n    \n    * __Task Attempts__ displays information about attempts to run tasks for this vertex.\n    \n    * __Sources & Sinks__ displays data sources and sinks for this vertex.\n\n    > [AZURE.NOTE] As with the previous menu, you can scroll the column display for Tasks, Task Attempts, and Sources & Sinks__ to display links to more information for each item.\n\n10. Select __Tasks__, and then select the item named __00_000000__. This will display __Task Details__ for this task. From this screen, you can view __Task Counters__ and __Task Attempts__.\n\n    ![Task details](./media/hdinsight-debug-ambari-tez-view/taskdetails.png)\n\n##Next Steps\n\nNow that you have learned how to use the Tez view, learn more about [Using Hive on HDInsight](hdinsight-use-hive.md).\n\nFor more detailed technical information on Tez, see the [Tez page at Hortonworks](http://hortonworks.com/hadoop/tez/).\n\nFor more information on using Ambari with HDInsight, see [Manage HDInsight clusters using the Ambari Web UI](hdinsight-hadoop-manage-ambari.md)"
}