{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Managing Applications with Azure Active Directory | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        93
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article the benefits of integrating Azure Active Directory with your on-premises, cloud and SaaS applications.",
      "pos": [
        111,
        226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managing Applications with Azure Active Directory (AD)",
      "pos": [
        547,
        601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        606,
        614
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Beyond the actual workflow or content, businesses have two basic requirements for all applications:",
      "pos": [
        616,
        715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To increase productivity, applications should be easy to discover and access",
      "pos": [
        720,
        796
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To enable security and governance, the organization needs control and oversight on who can and actually is accessing each application",
      "pos": [
        801,
        934
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        936,
        1052
      ],
      "content": "In the word of cloud applications this can best be achieved using identity to control “<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>WHO is allowed to do WHAT<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>”."
    },
    {
      "content": "In computing terminology:",
      "pos": [
        1054,
        1079
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1083,
        1160
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Who<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is known as <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>identity<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> - a data store that consists of users and groups"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1164,
        1248
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>What<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is known as <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>access management<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> – management of access to protected resources"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1250,
        1575
      ],
      "content": "Both components together is known as <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Identity and Access Management (IAM)<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, which is defined by the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Gartner<ept id=\"p2\">](http://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/identity-and-access-management-iam)</ept> group as “<bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>the security discipline that enables the right individuals to access the right resources at the right times for the right reasons<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept>”."
    },
    {
      "content": "Okay, so what’s the problem?",
      "pos": [
        1577,
        1605
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If IAM is <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>not managed<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> in one place with an integrated solution:",
      "pos": [
        1606,
        1671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Identity administrators have to individually create and update user accounts in all applications separately, a redundant and time consuming activity.",
      "pos": [
        1675,
        1824
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users have to memorize multiple credentials to access the applications they need to work with, especially since they are encouraged not to use the same password for every application for security reasons.",
      "pos": [
        1828,
        2032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, users tend to write down their passwords or use other password management solutions which introduces other data security risks.",
      "pos": [
        2033,
        2173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Redundant, time consuming activities reduce the amount of time users and administrators are working on business activities that increase your business’s bottom line.",
      "pos": [
        2177,
        2342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "So, what generally prevents organizations from adopting integrated IAM solutions?",
      "pos": [
        2344,
        2425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Most technical solutions are based on software platforms that need to be deployed and adapted by each organization for their own applications.",
      "pos": [
        2429,
        2571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cloud applications are often adopted at a higher rate than IT organization can integrate with existing IAM solutions.",
      "pos": [
        2575,
        2692
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Security and monitoring tooling require additional customization and integration to achieve comprehensive E2E scenarios.",
      "pos": [
        2696,
        2816
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory (AD) integrated with applications",
      "pos": [
        2821,
        2877
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory (AD) is Microsoft’s comprehensive Identity as a Service (IDaaS) solution enabling IAM as a cloud service and providing built in access management, single-sign on (SSO), and reporting <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>pre-integrated with thousands of applications<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/active-directory/)</ept>, including Salesforce, Google Apps, Box, Concur, and lots more.",
      "pos": [
        2879,
        3255
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With Azure AD applications you publish for your partners and customers (business or consumer) will have the same identity and access management capabilities freeing you to focus on you main business.",
      "pos": [
        3256,
        3455
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The value of Azure AD goes beyond “just” cloud applications.",
      "pos": [
        3457,
        3517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use it with on-premises applications by providing secure remote access, avoiding the need for VPNs or other traditional remote access management system.",
      "pos": [
        3518,
        3683
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What if you need to implement an application that is not yet listed in the application gallery?",
      "pos": [
        3685,
        3780
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While this is a bit more time-consuming than configuring SSO for applications from the application gallery, Azure AD provides you with a wizard that helps you with the configuration.",
      "pos": [
        3781,
        3963
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By providing central access management and single sign on (SSO) for all your applications, Azure AD provides the solution to data security and productivity problems.",
      "pos": [
        3965,
        4130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users can access multiple applications with one sign on giving more time to income generating or business operations activities done.",
      "pos": [
        4134,
        4267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Identity administrators can manage access to applications in one place.",
      "pos": [
        4271,
        4342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The benefit for the user and for your company is obvious.",
      "pos": [
        4344,
        4401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let’s take a closer look at the benefits for an identity administrator and the organization.",
      "pos": [
        4402,
        4494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Integrated application benefits",
      "pos": [
        4499,
        4530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The SSO process has two steps:",
      "pos": [
        4532,
        4562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authentication, the process of validating the user’s identity.",
      "pos": [
        4566,
        4628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authorization, the decision to enable or block access to a resource with an access policy.",
      "pos": [
        4632,
        4722
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using Azure AD to manage applications and enable SSO:",
      "pos": [
        4724,
        4782
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authentication is done on the user’s on-premises (e.g. AD) or Azure AD account.",
      "pos": [
        4786,
        4865
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authorization executes on the Azure AD assignment and protection policy ensuring consistent end user experience and enabling you to add assignment, locations, and MFA conditions on any application, regardless of its internal capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        4869,
        5107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It important to understand that the way the authorization is enacted on the target application varies depending on how the application was integrated with Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        5109,
        5273
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Applications pre-integrated by service provider<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Like Office 365 and Azure, these are applications built directly on Azure AD and relying on it for their comprehensive identity and access management capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        5277,
        5492
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access to these applications is enabled through directory information and token issuance.",
      "pos": [
        5493,
        5582
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Applications pre-integrated by Microsoft and custom applications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> These are independent cloud applications that rely on an internal application directory and can operate independently of Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        5586,
        5785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access to these applications is enabled by issuing an application specific credential mapped to an application account.",
      "pos": [
        5786,
        5905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Depending on the application capabilities, the credential may be a federation token or user-name and password for an account that was previously provisioned in the application.",
      "pos": [
        5906,
        6082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>On-premises applications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Applications published through the Azure AD application proxy primarily enabling access to on-premises applications.",
      "pos": [
        6086,
        6231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These applications rely on a central on premise directory like Windows Server Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        6232,
        6327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access to these applications is enabled by triggering the proxy to deliver the application content to the end user while honoring the on-premises sign-on requirement.",
      "pos": [
        6328,
        6494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if a user joins your organization, you need to create an account for the user in Azure AD for the primary sign-on operations.",
      "pos": [
        6496,
        6634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this user requires access to a managed application such as Salesforce, you also need to create an account for this user in Salesforce and link it to the Azure account to make SSO work.",
      "pos": [
        6635,
        6822
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When the user leaves your organization, it is advisable to delete the Azure AD account and all counterpart accounts in the IAM stores of the applications the user had access to.",
      "pos": [
        6823,
        7000
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access detection",
      "pos": [
        7005,
        7021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In modern enterprises, IT departments are often not aware of all the cloud applications that are being used.",
      "pos": [
        7023,
        7131
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In conjunction with Cloud App Discovery, Azure AD provides you with a solution to detect these applications.",
      "pos": [
        7132,
        7240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Account management",
      "pos": [
        7245,
        7263
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traditionally, managing accounts in the various applications is a manual process performed by IT or support personal in the organization.",
      "pos": [
        7265,
        7402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD fully automated account management across all service provider integrated applications and those applications pre-integrated by Microsoft supporting automated user provisioning or SAML JIT.",
      "pos": [
        7403,
        7601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automated user provisioning",
      "pos": [
        7606,
        7633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some applications provide automation interfaces for creation and removal (or deactivation) of accounts.",
      "pos": [
        7635,
        7738
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a provider offers such an interface, it is leveraged by Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        7739,
        7807
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This reduces your operational costs because administrative tasks happen automatically, and improves the security of your environment because it decreases the chance of unauthorized access.",
      "pos": [
        7808,
        7996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access management",
      "pos": [
        8001,
        8018
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Azure AD you can manage access to applications using individual or rule driven assignments.",
      "pos": [
        8020,
        8117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also delegate access management to the right people in the organization ensuring the best oversight and reducing the burden on helpdesk.",
      "pos": [
        8118,
        8262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On-premises applications",
      "pos": [
        8267,
        8291
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The built in application proxy enables you to publish your on-premises applications to your users resulting in both consistent access experience with modern cloud application and the benefits from Azure AD monitoring, reporting, and security capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        8293,
        8548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reporting and monitoring",
      "pos": [
        8553,
        8577
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD provides you with pre-integrated reporting and monitoring capabilities that enable you to know who has access to applications and when they actually used them.",
      "pos": [
        8579,
        8747
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Related capabilities",
      "pos": [
        8752,
        8772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With Azure AD you can secure your applications with granular access policies and pre-integrated MFA.",
      "pos": [
        8774,
        8874
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To learn more about Azure MFA see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure MFA<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/services/multi-factor-authentication/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8875,
        8988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting started",
      "pos": [
        8993,
        9008
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9010,
        9223
      ],
      "content": "To get started integrating applications with Azure AD, take a look at the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Integrating Azure Active Directory with applications getting started guide<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-integrating-applications-getting-started.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Managing Applications with Azure Active Directory | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"This article the benefits of integrating Azure Active Directory with your on-premises, cloud and SaaS applications.\"\n   services=\"active-directory\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"ihenkel\"\n   manager=\"stevenpo\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n   <tags\n      ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n      ms.devlang=\"na\"\n      ms.topic=\"article\"\n      ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n      ms.workload=\"identity\"\n      ms.date=\"10/16/2015\"\n      ms.author=\"inhenk\"/>\n\n# Managing Applications with Azure Active Directory (AD)\n\n## Overview\n\nBeyond the actual workflow or content, businesses have two basic requirements for all applications:\n\n1. To increase productivity, applications should be easy to discover and access\n\n2. To enable security and governance, the organization needs control and oversight on who can and actually is accessing each application\n\nIn the word of cloud applications this can best be achieved using identity to control “*WHO is allowed to do WHAT*”.\n\nIn computing terminology:\n\n- *Who* is known as *identity* - a data store that consists of users and groups\n\n- *What* is known as *access management* – management of access to protected resources\n\nBoth components together is known as *Identity and Access Management (IAM)*, which is defined by the [Gartner](http://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/identity-and-access-management-iam) group as “*the security discipline that enables the right individuals to access the right resources at the right times for the right reasons*”.\n\nOkay, so what’s the problem? If IAM is *not managed* in one place with an integrated solution:\n\n- Identity administrators have to individually create and update user accounts in all applications separately, a redundant and time consuming activity.\n\n- Users have to memorize multiple credentials to access the applications they need to work with, especially since they are encouraged not to use the same password for every application for security reasons. As a result, users tend to write down their passwords or use other password management solutions which introduces other data security risks.\n\n- Redundant, time consuming activities reduce the amount of time users and administrators are working on business activities that increase your business’s bottom line.\n\nSo, what generally prevents organizations from adopting integrated IAM solutions?\n\n- Most technical solutions are based on software platforms that need to be deployed and adapted by each organization for their own applications.\n\n- Cloud applications are often adopted at a higher rate than IT organization can integrate with existing IAM solutions.\n\n- Security and monitoring tooling require additional customization and integration to achieve comprehensive E2E scenarios.\n\n## Azure Active Directory (AD) integrated with applications\n\nAzure Active Directory (AD) is Microsoft’s comprehensive Identity as a Service (IDaaS) solution enabling IAM as a cloud service and providing built in access management, single-sign on (SSO), and reporting [pre-integrated with thousands of applications](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/active-directory/), including Salesforce, Google Apps, Box, Concur, and lots more. With Azure AD applications you publish for your partners and customers (business or consumer) will have the same identity and access management capabilities freeing you to focus on you main business.\n\nThe value of Azure AD goes beyond “just” cloud applications. You can also use it with on-premises applications by providing secure remote access, avoiding the need for VPNs or other traditional remote access management system.\n\nWhat if you need to implement an application that is not yet listed in the application gallery? While this is a bit more time-consuming than configuring SSO for applications from the application gallery, Azure AD provides you with a wizard that helps you with the configuration.\n\nBy providing central access management and single sign on (SSO) for all your applications, Azure AD provides the solution to data security and productivity problems.\n\n- Users can access multiple applications with one sign on giving more time to income generating or business operations activities done.\n\n- Identity administrators can manage access to applications in one place.\n\nThe benefit for the user and for your company is obvious. Let’s take a closer look at the benefits for an identity administrator and the organization.\n\n## Integrated application benefits\n\nThe SSO process has two steps:\n\n- Authentication, the process of validating the user’s identity.\n\n- Authorization, the decision to enable or block access to a resource with an access policy.\n\nWhen using Azure AD to manage applications and enable SSO:\n\n- Authentication is done on the user’s on-premises (e.g. AD) or Azure AD account.\n\n- Authorization executes on the Azure AD assignment and protection policy ensuring consistent end user experience and enabling you to add assignment, locations, and MFA conditions on any application, regardless of its internal capabilities.\n\nIt important to understand that the way the authorization is enacted on the target application varies depending on how the application was integrated with Azure AD.\n\n- **Applications pre-integrated by service provider** Like Office 365 and Azure, these are applications built directly on Azure AD and relying on it for their comprehensive identity and access management capabilities. Access to these applications is enabled through directory information and token issuance.\n\n- **Applications pre-integrated by Microsoft and custom applications** These are independent cloud applications that rely on an internal application directory and can operate independently of Azure AD. Access to these applications is enabled by issuing an application specific credential mapped to an application account. Depending on the application capabilities, the credential may be a federation token or user-name and password for an account that was previously provisioned in the application.\n\n- **On-premises applications** Applications published through the Azure AD application proxy primarily enabling access to on-premises applications. These applications rely on a central on premise directory like Windows Server Active Directory. Access to these applications is enabled by triggering the proxy to deliver the application content to the end user while honoring the on-premises sign-on requirement.\n\nFor example, if a user joins your organization, you need to create an account for the user in Azure AD for the primary sign-on operations. If this user requires access to a managed application such as Salesforce, you also need to create an account for this user in Salesforce and link it to the Azure account to make SSO work. When the user leaves your organization, it is advisable to delete the Azure AD account and all counterpart accounts in the IAM stores of the applications the user had access to.\n\n## Access detection\n\nIn modern enterprises, IT departments are often not aware of all the cloud applications that are being used. In conjunction with Cloud App Discovery, Azure AD provides you with a solution to detect these applications.\n\n## Account management\n\nTraditionally, managing accounts in the various applications is a manual process performed by IT or support personal in the organization. Azure AD fully automated account management across all service provider integrated applications and those applications pre-integrated by Microsoft supporting automated user provisioning or SAML JIT.\n\n## Automated user provisioning\n\nSome applications provide automation interfaces for creation and removal (or deactivation) of accounts. If a provider offers such an interface, it is leveraged by Azure AD. This reduces your operational costs because administrative tasks happen automatically, and improves the security of your environment because it decreases the chance of unauthorized access.\n\n## Access management\n\nUsing Azure AD you can manage access to applications using individual or rule driven assignments. You can also delegate access management to the right people in the organization ensuring the best oversight and reducing the burden on helpdesk.\n\n## On-premises applications\n\nThe built in application proxy enables you to publish your on-premises applications to your users resulting in both consistent access experience with modern cloud application and the benefits from Azure AD monitoring, reporting, and security capabilities.\n\n## Reporting and monitoring\n\nAzure AD provides you with pre-integrated reporting and monitoring capabilities that enable you to know who has access to applications and when they actually used them.\n\n## Related capabilities\n\nWith Azure AD you can secure your applications with granular access policies and pre-integrated MFA. To learn more about Azure MFA see [Azure MFA](https://azure.microsoft.com/services/multi-factor-authentication/).\n\n## Getting started\n\nTo get started integrating applications with Azure AD, take a look at the [Integrating Azure Active Directory with applications getting started guide](active-directory-integrating-applications-getting-started.md).\n\n\n"
}