{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Configuring single sign-on to applications that are not in the Azure Active Directory application gallery | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to self-service connect apps to Azure Active Directory using SAML and password-based SSO",
      "pos": [
        171,
        269
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring single sign-on to applications that are not in the Azure Active Directory application gallery",
      "pos": [
        580,
        685
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Active Directory application gallery provides a listing of applications that are known to support a form of single sign-on with Azure Active Directory, as described in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>this article<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        687,
        970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you (as an IT specialist or system integrator in your organization) have found the application you want to connect, you can get started by follow the step-by-step instructions presented in the Azure management portal to enable single sign-on.",
      "pos": [
        971,
        1218
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1220,
        1454
      ],
      "content": "Customers with <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Active Directory Premium<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn532272.aspx)</ept> licenses get these additional capabilities, which can be invoked from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Custom<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> category of the Azure AD application gallery:"
    },
    {
      "content": "Self-service connection of any application that supports SAML 2.0 identity providers",
      "pos": [
        1458,
        1542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Self-service connection of any web application that has an HTML-based sign-in page using password-based SSO",
      "pos": [
        1545,
        1652
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1655,
        1977
      ],
      "content": "Ability to add links to any application in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Office 365 app launcher<ept id=\"p1\">](https://blogs.office.com/2014/10/16/organize-office-365-new-app-launcher-2/)</ept> or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure AD access panel<ept id=\"p2\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis/#deploying-azure-ad-integrated-applications-to-users)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1980,
        2123
      ],
      "content": "Self-service connection of applications that use the SCIM protocol for user provisioning (<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>described here<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-scim-provisioning)</ept>)"
    },
    {
      "content": "This can include not only SaaS applications that you use but have not yet been on-boarded to the Azure AD application gallery, but third-party web applications that your organization has deployed to servers you control, either in the cloud or on-premises.",
      "pos": [
        2125,
        2380
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2382,
        2772
      ],
      "content": "Note: Application developers who are looking to test compatibility between their application and this feature can do so by using a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>free trial of Azure Active Directory Premium<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/trial/get-started-active-directory/)</ept>, but are encouraged to acquire an <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Internal Use Rights license<ept id=\"p2\">](https://mspartner.microsoft.com/en/us/pages/membership/internal-use-software.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Adding an unlisted or custom application",
      "pos": [
        2776,
        2816
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2819,
        3085
      ],
      "content": "To configure an application, sign into the Azure management portal using your Azure Active Directory administrator account, and browse to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active Directory &gt; [Directory] &gt; Applications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Add an application from the gallery<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "In the app gallery, you can add a custom app using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Custom<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> category on the left, or by selecting the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add an unlisted application<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> link that is shown in the search results if your desired app wasn't found.",
      "pos": [
        3096,
        3310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After entering a Name for your application, you can configure the single sign-on options and behavior.",
      "pos": [
        3311,
        3413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quick tip<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:  As a best practice, use the search function to check to see if the application already exists in the application gallery.",
      "pos": [
        3416,
        3553
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the app is found and its description mentions \"single sign on\", then the application is already supported for federated single sign-on.",
      "pos": [
        3554,
        3692
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adding a custom application provides a very similar experience to the one available for pre-integrated applications.",
      "pos": [
        3703,
        3819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To start, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure Single Sign-On<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3820,
        3866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The next screen presents the following three options for configuring single sign on, which are described in the following sections.",
      "pos": [
        3867,
        3998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Single Sign-On",
      "pos": [
        4011,
        4034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select this option to configure SAML-based authentication for the application.",
      "pos": [
        4036,
        4114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This requires that the application support SAML 2.0, and you should collect information on how to use the SAML capabilities of the application before continuing.",
      "pos": [
        4115,
        4276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After selecting <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you will be prompted to enter three different URLs corresponding to the SAML endpoints for the application.",
      "pos": [
        4277,
        4410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The tooltip icons in the dialog provide details about what each URL is and how it is used.",
      "pos": [
        4421,
        4511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After these have been entered, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to proceed to the next screen.",
      "pos": [
        4512,
        4588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This screen provides information about what needs to be configured on the application side to enable it to accept a SAML token from Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        4589,
        4730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Which values are required will vary depending on the application, so check the application's SAML documentation for details.",
      "pos": [
        4741,
        4865
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sign-On<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Sign-Out<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> service URL both resolve to the same endpoint, which is the SAML request-handling endpoint for your instance of Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        4866,
        5020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Issuer URL is the value that appears as the \"Issuer\" inside the SAML token issued to the application.",
      "pos": [
        5021,
        5126
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5129,
        5241
      ],
      "content": "After your application has been configured, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button and then the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Complete<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to close the dialog."
    },
    {
      "content": "Assigning users and groups to your SAML application",
      "pos": [
        5246,
        5297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once your application has been configured to use Azure AD as a SAML-based identity provider, then it is almost ready to test.",
      "pos": [
        5300,
        5425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a security control, Azure AD will not issue a token allowing them to sign into the application unless they have been granted access using Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        5426,
        5576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users may be granted access directly, or through a group that they are a member of.",
      "pos": [
        5577,
        5660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To assign a user or group to your application, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Assign Users<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button.",
      "pos": [
        5663,
        5744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the user or group you wish to assign, and then select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Assign<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button.",
      "pos": [
        5745,
        5828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Assigning a user will allow Azure AD to issue a token for the user, as well as causing a tile for this application to appear in the user's Access Panel.",
      "pos": [
        5839,
        5991
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An application tile will also appear in the Office 365 application launcher if the user is using Office 365.",
      "pos": [
        5992,
        6100
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6103,
        6228
      ],
      "content": "You can upload a tile logo for the application using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Upload Logo<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab for the application."
    },
    {
      "content": "Customizing the claims issued in the SAML token",
      "pos": [
        6234,
        6281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a user authenticates to the application, Azure AD will issue a SAML token to the app that contains information (or claims) about the user that uniquely identifies them.",
      "pos": [
        6284,
        6457
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default this includes the user's username, email address, first name, and last name.",
      "pos": [
        6458,
        6545
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6548,
        6651
      ],
      "content": "You can view or edit the claims sent in the SAML token to the application under the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Attributes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab."
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two possible reasons why you might need to edit the claims issued in the SAML token:",
      "pos": [
        6662,
        6756
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "•The application has been written to require a different set of claim URIs or claim values",
      "pos": [
        6758,
        6848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "•Your application has been deployed in a way that requires the NameIdentifier claim to be something other than the username (AKA user principal name) stored in Azure Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        6850,
        7033
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7036,
        7199
      ],
      "content": "For information on how to add and edit claims for these scenarios, check out this <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>article on claims customization<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-saml-claims-customization.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Testing the SAML application",
      "pos": [
        7205,
        7233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the SAML URLs and certificate have been configured in Azure AD and in the application, users or groups have been assigned to the application in Azure, and the claims have been reviewed and edited if necessary, then the user is ready to sign into the application.",
      "pos": [
        7236,
        7503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To test, simply sign-into the Azure AD access panel at https://myapps.microsoft.com using a user account you assigned to the application, and then click on the tile for the application to kick off the single sign-on process.",
      "pos": [
        7506,
        7730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Alternately, you can browse directly to the Sign-On URL for the application and sign-in from there.",
      "pos": [
        7731,
        7830
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7833,
        7965
      ],
      "content": "For debugging tips, see this <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>article on how to debug SAML-based single sign-on to applications<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-saml-debugging.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Password Single Sign-On",
      "pos": [
        7970,
        7993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select this option to configure <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>password-based single sign-on<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis.md)</ept> for a web application that has an HTML sign-in page.",
      "pos": [
        7995,
        8152
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Password-based SSO, also referred to as password vaulting, enables you to manage user access and passwords to web applications that don't support identity federation.",
      "pos": [
        8153,
        8319
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is also useful for scenarios where several users need to share a single account, such as to your organization's social media app accounts.",
      "pos": [
        8320,
        8461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After selecting <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you will be prompted to enter the URL of the application's web-based sign-in page.",
      "pos": [
        8464,
        8572
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that this must be the page that includes the username and password input fields.",
      "pos": [
        8573,
        8658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once entered, Azure AD starts a process to parse the sign-in page for a username input and a password input.",
      "pos": [
        8659,
        8767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the process is not successful, then it guides you through an alternate process of installing a browser extension (requires Internet Explorer, Chrome, or Firefox) that will allow you to manually capture the fields.",
      "pos": [
        8768,
        8984
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8986,
        9168
      ],
      "content": "Once the sign-in page is captured, users and groups may be assigned and credential policies can be set just like regular <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>password SSO apps<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9170,
        9301
      ],
      "content": "Note: You can upload a tile logo for the application using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Upload Logo<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab for the application."
    },
    {
      "content": "Existing Single Sign-On",
      "pos": [
        9306,
        9329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select this option to add a link to an application to your organization's Azure AD Access Panel or Office 365 portal.",
      "pos": [
        9331,
        9448
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use this to add links to custom web apps that currently use Azure Active Directory Federation Services (or other federation service) instead of Azure AD for authentication.",
      "pos": [
        9449,
        9629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Or, you can add deep links to specific SharePoint pages or other web pages that you just want to appear on your user's Access Panels.",
      "pos": [
        9630,
        9763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After selecting <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you will be prompted to enter the URL of the application to link to.",
      "pos": [
        9766,
        9860
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once completed, users and groups may be assigned to the application, which causes the application to appear in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Office 365 app launcher<ept id=\"p1\">](https://blogs.office.com/2014/10/16/organize-office-365-new-app-launcher-2/)</ept> or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure AD access panel<ept id=\"p2\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis/#deploying-azure-ad-integrated-applications-to-users)</ept> for those users.",
      "pos": [
        9861,
        10268
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10270,
        10401
      ],
      "content": "Note: You can upload a tile logo for the application using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Upload Logo<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab for the application."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Configuring single sign-on to applications that are not in the Azure Active Directory application gallery | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"Learn how to self-service connect apps to Azure Active Directory using SAML and password-based SSO\" \n    services=\"active-directory\" \n    authors=\"asmalser-msft\"  \n    documentationCenter=\"na\" manager=\"stevenpo\"/>\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"active-directory\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.workload=\"identity\" \n    ms.date=\"11/18/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"asmalser\" />\n\n#Configuring single sign-on to applications that are not in the Azure Active Directory application gallery\n\nThe Azure Active Directory application gallery provides a listing of applications that are known to support a form of single sign-on with Azure Active Directory, as described in [this article](https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis/). Once you (as an IT specialist or system integrator in your organization) have found the application you want to connect, you can get started by follow the step-by-step instructions presented in the Azure management portal to enable single sign-on.\n\nCustomers with [Azure Active Directory Premium](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn532272.aspx) licenses get these additional capabilities, which can be invoked from the **Custom** category of the Azure AD application gallery:\n\n* Self-service connection of any application that supports SAML 2.0 identity providers\n* Self-service connection of any web application that has an HTML-based sign-in page using password-based SSO\n* Ability to add links to any application in the [Office 365 app launcher](https://blogs.office.com/2014/10/16/organize-office-365-new-app-launcher-2/) or the [Azure AD access panel](https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis/#deploying-azure-ad-integrated-applications-to-users)\n* Self-service connection of applications that use the SCIM protocol for user provisioning ([described here](active-directory-scim-provisioning))\n\nThis can include not only SaaS applications that you use but have not yet been on-boarded to the Azure AD application gallery, but third-party web applications that your organization has deployed to servers you control, either in the cloud or on-premises.\n\nNote: Application developers who are looking to test compatibility between their application and this feature can do so by using a [free trial of Azure Active Directory Premium](https://azure.microsoft.com/trial/get-started-active-directory/), but are encouraged to acquire an [Internal Use Rights license](https://mspartner.microsoft.com/en/us/pages/membership/internal-use-software.aspx).\n\n##Adding an unlisted or custom application \n\nTo configure an application, sign into the Azure management portal using your Azure Active Directory administrator account, and browse to the **Active Directory > [Directory] > Applications** section, select **Add**, and then **Add an application from the gallery**. \n\n![][1]\n\nIn the app gallery, you can add a custom app using the **Custom** category on the left, or by selecting the **Add an unlisted application** link that is shown in the search results if your desired app wasn't found. After entering a Name for your application, you can configure the single sign-on options and behavior. \n\n**Quick tip**:  As a best practice, use the search function to check to see if the application already exists in the application gallery. If the app is found and its description mentions \"single sign on\", then the application is already supported for federated single sign-on. \n\n![][2]\n\nAdding a custom application provides a very similar experience to the one available for pre-integrated applications. To start, select **Configure Single Sign-On**. The next screen presents the following three options for configuring single sign on, which are described in the following sections.\n\n![][3]\n\n\n##Azure AD Single Sign-On\n\nSelect this option to configure SAML-based authentication for the application. This requires that the application support SAML 2.0, and you should collect information on how to use the SAML capabilities of the application before continuing. After selecting **Next**, you will be prompted to enter three different URLs corresponding to the SAML endpoints for the application. \n\n![][4]\n\nThe tooltip icons in the dialog provide details about what each URL is and how it is used. After these have been entered, click **Next** to proceed to the next screen. This screen provides information about what needs to be configured on the application side to enable it to accept a SAML token from Azure AD. \n\n![][5]\n\nWhich values are required will vary depending on the application, so check the application's SAML documentation for details. The **Sign-On** and **Sign-Out** service URL both resolve to the same endpoint, which is the SAML request-handling endpoint for your instance of Azure AD. The Issuer URL is the value that appears as the \"Issuer\" inside the SAML token issued to the application. \n\nAfter your application has been configured, click **Next** button and then the **Complete** to close the dialog. \n\n##Assigning users and groups to your SAML application \n\nOnce your application has been configured to use Azure AD as a SAML-based identity provider, then it is almost ready to test. As a security control, Azure AD will not issue a token allowing them to sign into the application unless they have been granted access using Azure AD. Users may be granted access directly, or through a group that they are a member of. \n\nTo assign a user or group to your application, click the **Assign Users** button. Select the user or group you wish to assign, and then select the **Assign** button. \n\n![][6]\n\nAssigning a user will allow Azure AD to issue a token for the user, as well as causing a tile for this application to appear in the user's Access Panel. An application tile will also appear in the Office 365 application launcher if the user is using Office 365. \n\nYou can upload a tile logo for the application using the **Upload Logo** button on the **Configure** tab for the application. \n\n###Customizing the claims issued in the SAML token \n\nWhen a user authenticates to the application, Azure AD will issue a SAML token to the app that contains information (or claims) about the user that uniquely identifies them. By default this includes the user's username, email address, first name, and last name. \n\nYou can view or edit the claims sent in the SAML token to the application under the **Attributes** tab. \n\n![][7]\n\nThere are two possible reasons why you might need to edit the claims issued in the SAML token: \n•The application has been written to require a different set of claim URIs or claim values \n•Your application has been deployed in a way that requires the NameIdentifier claim to be something other than the username (AKA user principal name) stored in Azure Active Directory. \n\nFor information on how to add and edit claims for these scenarios, check out this [article on claims customization](active-directory-saml-claims-customization.md). \n\n###Testing the SAML application \n\nOnce the SAML URLs and certificate have been configured in Azure AD and in the application, users or groups have been assigned to the application in Azure, and the claims have been reviewed and edited if necessary, then the user is ready to sign into the application. \n\nTo test, simply sign-into the Azure AD access panel at https://myapps.microsoft.com using a user account you assigned to the application, and then click on the tile for the application to kick off the single sign-on process. Alternately, you can browse directly to the Sign-On URL for the application and sign-in from there. \n\nFor debugging tips, see this [article on how to debug SAML-based single sign-on to applications](active-directory-saml-debugging.md) \n\n##Password Single Sign-On\n\nSelect this option to configure [password-based single sign-on](active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis.md) for a web application that has an HTML sign-in page. Password-based SSO, also referred to as password vaulting, enables you to manage user access and passwords to web applications that don't support identity federation. It is also useful for scenarios where several users need to share a single account, such as to your organization's social media app accounts. \n\nAfter selecting **Next**, you will be prompted to enter the URL of the application's web-based sign-in page. Note that this must be the page that includes the username and password input fields. Once entered, Azure AD starts a process to parse the sign-in page for a username input and a password input. If the process is not successful, then it guides you through an alternate process of installing a browser extension (requires Internet Explorer, Chrome, or Firefox) that will allow you to manually capture the fields.\n\nOnce the sign-in page is captured, users and groups may be assigned and credential policies can be set just like regular [password SSO apps](active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis.md).\n\nNote: You can upload a tile logo for the application using the **Upload Logo** button on the **Configure** tab for the application. \n\n##Existing Single Sign-On\n\nSelect this option to add a link to an application to your organization's Azure AD Access Panel or Office 365 portal. You can use this to add links to custom web apps that currently use Azure Active Directory Federation Services (or other federation service) instead of Azure AD for authentication. Or, you can add deep links to specific SharePoint pages or other web pages that you just want to appear on your user's Access Panels. \n\nAfter selecting **Next**, you will be prompted to enter the URL of the application to link to. Once completed, users and groups may be assigned to the application, which causes the application to appear in the [Office 365 app launcher](https://blogs.office.com/2014/10/16/organize-office-365-new-app-launcher-2/) or the [Azure AD access panel](https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/active-directory-appssoaccess-whatis/#deploying-azure-ad-integrated-applications-to-users) for those users.\n\nNote: You can upload a tile logo for the application using the **Upload Logo** button on the **Configure** tab for the application. \n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/active-directory-saas-custom-apps/customapp1.png\n[2]: ./media/active-directory-saas-custom-apps/customapp2.png\n[3]: ./media/active-directory-saas-custom-apps/customapp3.png\n[4]: ./media/active-directory-saas-custom-apps/customapp4.png\n[5]: ./media/active-directory-saas-custom-apps/customapp5.png\n[6]: ./media/active-directory-saas-custom-apps/customapp6.png\n[7]: ./media/active-directory-saas-custom-apps/customapp7.png\n\n\n"
}