{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "What are reverse DNS records?",
      "pos": [
        3,
        32
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reverse DNS records are used in a variety of situations.",
      "pos": [
        34,
        90
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server validation and authenticating server requests among them.",
      "pos": [
        91,
        155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, reverse DNS records are widely used in combating e-mail spam by verifying the sender of an e-mail message by verifying its reverse DNS record, and also, if that host was recognized as authorized to send e-mail from the originating domain.",
      "pos": [
        156,
        407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reverse DNS records, or PTR records, are DNS record types that enable the translation of a publically routable IP address back to a name.",
      "pos": [
        412,
        549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In DNS, names such as app1.contoso.com, are resolved to IP addresses in a process that is called forward resolution.",
      "pos": [
        550,
        666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With reverse DNS, this process is reversed to enable the resolution of the name given its IP address.",
      "pos": [
        667,
        768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on Reverse DNS records, please see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p1\">](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_DNS_lookup)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        773,
        885
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How does Azure support reverse DNS records for your Azure services?",
      "pos": [
        894,
        961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft works with a number of registries to secure an adequate supply of publically routable IP blocks.",
      "pos": [
        963,
        1069
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each of these blocks is then delegated to Microsoft-owned and operated authoritative DNS servers.",
      "pos": [
        1070,
        1167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft hosts the reverse DNS zones for all publically routable IP blocks assigned to it.",
      "pos": [
        1168,
        1259
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure enables you to specify a custom fully-qualified domain name (FQDN) for public routable IPs assigned to your deployments.",
      "pos": [
        1265,
        1391
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These custom FQDNs will then be returned for reverse DNS lookups for those IPs.",
      "pos": [
        1392,
        1471
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure provides reverse DNS support for all publically routable IPs at no additional cost, and for services deployed using the classic and ARM deployment models.",
      "pos": [
        1477,
        1637
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "## What are reverse DNS records?\n\nReverse DNS records are used in a variety of situations. Server validation and authenticating server requests among them. For example, reverse DNS records are widely used in combating e-mail spam by verifying the sender of an e-mail message by verifying its reverse DNS record, and also, if that host was recognized as authorized to send e-mail from the originating domain.<BR>\nReverse DNS records, or PTR records, are DNS record types that enable the translation of a publically routable IP address back to a name. In DNS, names such as app1.contoso.com, are resolved to IP addresses in a process that is called forward resolution. With reverse DNS, this process is reversed to enable the resolution of the name given its IP address.<BR>\nFor more information on Reverse DNS records, please see [here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_DNS_lookup).<BR>\n\n## How does Azure support reverse DNS records for your Azure services?\n\nMicrosoft works with a number of registries to secure an adequate supply of publically routable IP blocks. Each of these blocks is then delegated to Microsoft-owned and operated authoritative DNS servers. Microsoft hosts the reverse DNS zones for all publically routable IP blocks assigned to it. <BR>\nAzure enables you to specify a custom fully-qualified domain name (FQDN) for public routable IPs assigned to your deployments. These custom FQDNs will then be returned for reverse DNS lookups for those IPs.<BR> \nAzure provides reverse DNS support for all publically routable IPs at no additional cost, and for services deployed using the classic and ARM deployment models.\n"
}