{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "What is Azure App Service",
      "pos": [
        28,
        53
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn why Azure App Service is the best platform for developing web and mobile apps.",
      "pos": [
        73,
        157
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Azure App Service?",
      "pos": [
        585,
        611
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure App Service is the only cloud service that integrates everything you need to quickly and easily build web and mobile apps for any platform and any device.",
      "pos": [
        612,
        772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Built for developers, App Service is a fully managed platform with powerful capabilities such as built-in DevOps, continuous integration with Visual Studio Team Services and GitHub, staging and production support, and automatic patching.",
      "pos": [
        773,
        1010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure App Service is a single service that includes all of the existing capabilities from Azure Websites, Azure Mobile Services, and Azure Biztalk Services, while adding new capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        1012,
        1199
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Learn more<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/services/app-service/)</ept> about how App Service relates to these existing services.",
      "pos": [
        1201,
        1335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Why App Service?",
      "pos": [
        1340,
        1356
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Focused on rapid development of web and mobile apps, as well as automating business processes, Azure App Service provides an integrated set of enterprise capabilities through a single development and management experience offering you the following benefits:",
      "pos": [
        1357,
        1615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Build Web and Mobile Apps Fast<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Rapidly build, deploy and manage web and mobile apps for employees or customers using a single back-end.",
      "pos": [
        1619,
        1760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use your existing languages skills -- .NET, Java, NodeJS, PHP, or Python.",
      "pos": [
        1761,
        1834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Accelerate development with access to a rich gallery of APIs, connectors, and logic available in the Azure Marketplace.",
      "pos": [
        1835,
        1954
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Connect to any service and unlock your data<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Connect your web or mobile app to enterprise systems or SaaS in minutes with built-in connectors.",
      "pos": [
        1958,
        2105
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose from more than 50 connectors for enterprise systems such as SAP, Siebel, and Oracle to popular enterprise SaaS services like Salesforce and Office 365 to popular internet services such as Facebook, Twitter and Dropbox.",
      "pos": [
        2106,
        2331
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Integration made simple<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Integrate data across clouds and automate business processes in minutes with a simple visual design experience.",
      "pos": [
        2335,
        2476
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Easily integrate your logic it with any mobile or web app via standard REST APIs.",
      "pos": [
        2477,
        2558
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Build sophisticated enterprise application integration, B2B solutions using EDI, business policies (rules engine), and more based on the industry leading BizTalk platform.",
      "pos": [
        2560,
        2731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Unparalleled developer productivity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Optimized for DevOps, with continuous integration support for Visual Studio Team Services and Github, so you can focus on rapidly improving your apps without worrying about infrastructure.",
      "pos": [
        2735,
        2965
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy app updates with built-in staging, roll-back and in-production testing capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        2966,
        3057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enterprise Ready<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Enjoy peace of mind with enterprise grade security and management.",
      "pos": [
        3061,
        3150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provide delegated and role-based administration; easily secure and manage data flowing to your mobile apps; and protect your assets with built-in backup and restore capability.",
      "pos": [
        3151,
        3327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rest confidently knowing App Service is PCI compliant.",
      "pos": [
        3328,
        3382
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stay in control with dedicated environments, and the ability to deploy across public and private clouds.",
      "pos": [
        3383,
        3487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Benefit from over 25 years of Microsoft experience and our enterprise Service Level Agreement.",
      "pos": [
        3489,
        3583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service Concepts",
      "pos": [
        3588,
        3608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following high-level concepts describe what you can do with App Service.",
      "pos": [
        3609,
        3685
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Types",
      "pos": [
        3691,
        3700
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service allows you to create the following app types from a single development experience:",
      "pos": [
        3701,
        3795
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3799,
        3927
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Web Apps<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-web-overview)</ept> - Quickly create and deploy mission critical Web apps that scale with your business."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3930,
        4059
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Mobile Apps<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-mobile-value-prop-preview)</ept> - Engage employees, partners and customers on any device at any time."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4062,
        4158
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>API Apps<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-api-apps-why-best-platform)</ept> - Easily build and consume Cloud APIs."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4161,
        4293
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Logic Apps<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps)</ept> - Automate the access and use of data across clouds without writing code."
    },
    {
      "content": "As a single integrated service, App Service makes its easy to compose the above app types into a single solution, allowing you to easily build apps that target both web and mobile clients using the same back-end and integrate with on-premise systems as well as popular services such as Office 365 and salesforce.com.",
      "pos": [
        4295,
        4611
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service Plans",
      "pos": [
        4617,
        4634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service Plans represent a set of features and capacity that you can share across your apps.",
      "pos": [
        4635,
        4730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service Plans support a few pricing tiers (e.g. Free, Shared, Basic, Standard, and Premium) where each tier has its own capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        4731,
        4868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can quickly change which App Service Plan an app is hosted on with no downtime.",
      "pos": [
        4869,
        4952
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Learn more about App Service Plans<ept id=\"p1\">](../web-sites-web-hosting-plan-overview.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4953,
        5033
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get Started with App Service",
      "pos": [
        5037,
        5065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Want a taste?",
      "pos": [
        5066,
        5079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get going in seconds.",
      "pos": [
        5080,
        5101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With Azure App Service, this is as easy as selecting a language!",
      "pos": [
        5103,
        5167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a new app<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=523751)</ept> right away for free.",
      "pos": [
        5170,
        5256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No credit card required, no commitments, no hassles.",
      "pos": [
        5257,
        5309
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"What is Azure App Service\" \n    description=\"Learn why Azure App Service is the best platform for developing web and mobile apps.\" \n    keywords=\"app service, azure app service, app service cost, scale, scalable, app deployment, azure app deployment\"\n    services=\"app-service\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"omarkmsft\" \n    manager=\"dwrede\" \n    editor=\"jimbe\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"app-service\" \n    ms.workload=\"na\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"10/02/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"omark\"/>\n\n# What is Azure App Service?\nAzure App Service is the only cloud service that integrates everything you need to quickly and easily build web and mobile apps for any platform and any device. Built for developers, App Service is a fully managed platform with powerful capabilities such as built-in DevOps, continuous integration with Visual Studio Team Services and GitHub, staging and production support, and automatic patching.\n\nAzure App Service is a single service that includes all of the existing capabilities from Azure Websites, Azure Mobile Services, and Azure Biztalk Services, while adding new capabilities.  [Learn more](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/services/app-service/) about how App Service relates to these existing services.\n\n## Why App Service?\nFocused on rapid development of web and mobile apps, as well as automating business processes, Azure App Service provides an integrated set of enterprise capabilities through a single development and management experience offering you the following benefits:\n\n- **Build Web and Mobile Apps Fast** - Rapidly build, deploy and manage web and mobile apps for employees or customers using a single back-end. Use your existing languages skills -- .NET, Java, NodeJS, PHP, or Python. Accelerate development with access to a rich gallery of APIs, connectors, and logic available in the Azure Marketplace.\n\n- **Connect to any service and unlock your data** - Connect your web or mobile app to enterprise systems or SaaS in minutes with built-in connectors. Choose from more than 50 connectors for enterprise systems such as SAP, Siebel, and Oracle to popular enterprise SaaS services like Salesforce and Office 365 to popular internet services such as Facebook, Twitter and Dropbox.\n\n- **Integration made simple** - Integrate data across clouds and automate business processes in minutes with a simple visual design experience. Easily integrate your logic it with any mobile or web app via standard REST APIs.  Build sophisticated enterprise application integration, B2B solutions using EDI, business policies (rules engine), and more based on the industry leading BizTalk platform.\n\n- **Unparalleled developer productivity** - Optimized for DevOps, with continuous integration support for Visual Studio Team Services and Github, so you can focus on rapidly improving your apps without worrying about infrastructure. Deploy app updates with built-in staging, roll-back and in-production testing capabilities.\n\n- **Enterprise Ready** - Enjoy peace of mind with enterprise grade security and management. Provide delegated and role-based administration; easily secure and manage data flowing to your mobile apps; and protect your assets with built-in backup and restore capability. Rest confidently knowing App Service is PCI compliant. Stay in control with dedicated environments, and the ability to deploy across public and private clouds.  Benefit from over 25 years of Microsoft experience and our enterprise Service Level Agreement.\n\n\n##App Service Concepts\nThe following high-level concepts describe what you can do with App Service.\n\n### App Types\nApp Service allows you to create the following app types from a single development experience:\n\n- [**Web Apps**](../app-service-web-overview) - Quickly create and deploy mission critical Web apps that scale with your business.\n- [**Mobile Apps**](../app-service-mobile-value-prop-preview) - Engage employees, partners and customers on any device at any time.\n- [**API Apps**](../app-service-api-apps-why-best-platform) - Easily build and consume Cloud APIs.\n- [**Logic Apps**](../app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps) - Automate the access and use of data across clouds without writing code.\n\nAs a single integrated service, App Service makes its easy to compose the above app types into a single solution, allowing you to easily build apps that target both web and mobile clients using the same back-end and integrate with on-premise systems as well as popular services such as Office 365 and salesforce.com.\n\n### App Service Plans\nApp Service Plans represent a set of features and capacity that you can share across your apps. App Service Plans support a few pricing tiers (e.g. Free, Shared, Basic, Standard, and Premium) where each tier has its own capabilities. You can quickly change which App Service Plan an app is hosted on with no downtime. [Learn more about App Service Plans](../web-sites-web-hosting-plan-overview.md).\n\n##Get Started with App Service\nWant a taste? Get going in seconds.\n\nWith Azure App Service, this is as easy as selecting a language! \n\n[Create a new app](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=523751) right away for free. No credit card required, no commitments, no hassles.\n \n\n\n"
}