{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect: Upgrade from a previous version | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        93
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Explains the different methods to upgrade to the latest release of Azure Active Direcotry Connect, including in-place upgrade and swing migration.",
      "pos": [
        111,
        257
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect: Upgrade from a previous version to the latest",
      "pos": [
        557,
        620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic describes the different methods you can use to upgrade your Azure AD Connect installation to the latest release.",
      "pos": [
        621,
        744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommendation that you keep current with the releases of Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        745,
        823
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        825,
        978
      ],
      "content": "If you want to upgrade from DirSync, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Upgrade from Azure AD sync tool (DirSync)<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-dirsync-upgrade-get-started.md)</ept> instead."
    },
    {
      "content": "There are a few different strategies to upgrade Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        980,
        1045
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Method",
      "pos": [
        1049,
        1055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        1058,
        1069
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automatic upgrade",
      "pos": [
        1089,
        1106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For customers with an express installation, this is the easiest method.",
      "pos": [
        1168,
        1239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In-place upgrade",
      "pos": [
        1245,
        1261
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have a single server, upgrade the installation in-place on the same server.",
      "pos": [
        1284,
        1366
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Swing migration",
      "pos": [
        1372,
        1387
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With two servers, you can prepare one of the servers with the new release and change active server when you are ready.",
      "pos": [
        1409,
        1527
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1529,
        1655
      ],
      "content": "For required permissions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>permissions required for upgrade<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md#upgrade)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "In-place upgrade",
      "pos": [
        1660,
        1676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An in-place upgrade will work for moving from Azure AD Sync or Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        1677,
        1757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It will not work for DirSync or for a solution with FIM + Azure AD Connector.",
      "pos": [
        1758,
        1835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This method is preferred if you have a single server and less than about 100,000 objects.",
      "pos": [
        1837,
        1926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the upgrade, a full import and full synchronization will occur.",
      "pos": [
        1927,
        1996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will ensure that the new configuration will be applied to all existing objects in the system.",
      "pos": [
        1997,
        2095
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This might take a few hours depending on the number of objects in scope of the sync engine.",
      "pos": [
        2096,
        2187
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The normal delta synchronization scheduled, by default every 30 minutes, is suspended but password synchronization will continue.",
      "pos": [
        2188,
        2317
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You might consider to do the in-place upgrade during a weekend.",
      "pos": [
        2318,
        2381
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In-Place Upgrade",
      "pos": [
        2385,
        2401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have made changes to out-of-box synchronization rules, these will be set back to default configuration on upgrade.",
      "pos": [
        2485,
        2606
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To make sure your configuration is kept between upgrades, make sure the changes are made as described in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Best practices for changing the default configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2607,
        2850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Swing migration",
      "pos": [
        2855,
        2870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have a complex deployment or very many objects, it might be impractical to do an in-place upgrade on the live system.",
      "pos": [
        2871,
        2995
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This could for some customers take multiple days and during this time no delta changes will be processed.",
      "pos": [
        2996,
        3101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instead the recommended method to use is a swing migration.",
      "pos": [
        3103,
        3162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For this method you will need (at least) two servers, one active and one staging server.",
      "pos": [
        3163,
        3251
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The active server (solid blue lines in the picture below) will be responsible for the active load.",
      "pos": [
        3252,
        3350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The staging server (dashed purple lines in the picture below) will be prepared with the new release and when fully ready, this server will be made active.",
      "pos": [
        3351,
        3505
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The previous active server, now with the old version installed, will be made the staging server and upgraded.",
      "pos": [
        3506,
        3615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Staging server",
      "pos": [
        3619,
        3633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note: It has been noted that some customers prefer to have three or four servers for this.",
      "pos": [
        3717,
        3807
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since the staging server is being upgrades, you will during this time not have a backup server in case of a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>disaster recovery<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-operations.md#disaster-recovery)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3808,
        4001
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With a maximum of four servers, a new set of primary/standby servers with the new version can be prepared, ensuring there are always a staging server ready to take over.",
      "pos": [
        4002,
        4171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These steps will also work to move from Azure AD Sync or a solution with FIM + Azure AD Connector.",
      "pos": [
        4173,
        4271
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These steps will not work for DirSync, but the same swing migration (also called parallel deployment) method with steps for DirSync can be found in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Upgrade Azure Active Directory sync (DirSync)<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-dirsync-upgrade-get-started.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4272,
        4528
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Swing migration steps",
      "pos": [
        4534,
        4555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure your active server and staging server are both using the same version.",
      "pos": [
        4560,
        4640
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4644,
        4868
      ],
      "content": "If you have made some custom configuration and your staging server does not have it, follow the steps under <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Move custom configuration from active to staging server<ept id=\"p1\">](#move-custom-configuration-from-active-to-staging-server)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Upgrade the staging server to the latest version.",
      "pos": [
        4872,
        4921
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let the sync engine run full import and full synchronization.",
      "pos": [
        4925,
        4986
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify that the new configuration did not cause any unexpected changes using the steps under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Verify<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Verify the configuration of a server<ept id=\"p2\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-operations.md#verify-the-configuration-of-a-server)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4990,
        5220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If something is not as expected, correct, run import and sync, and verify until the data looks good.",
      "pos": [
        5221,
        5321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These steps can be found in the linked topic.",
      "pos": [
        5322,
        5367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Switch the staging server to be the active server.",
      "pos": [
        5371,
        5421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is the final step <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>switch active server<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Verify the configuration of a server<ept id=\"p2\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-operations.md#verify-the-configuration-of-a-server)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5422,
        5596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upgrade the server now in staging mode to the latest release.",
      "pos": [
        5600,
        5661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Follow the same steps as before to get the data and configuration upgraded.",
      "pos": [
        5662,
        5737
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Move custom configuration from active to staging server",
      "pos": [
        5743,
        5798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have made configuration changes to the active server, you need to make sure the same changes are applied to the staging server.",
      "pos": [
        5799,
        5933
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The custom sync rules you have created can be moved with PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        5935,
        6003
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Other changes must be applied the same way on both systems.",
      "pos": [
        6004,
        6063
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Thing you must make sure is configured the same way on both servers:",
      "pos": [
        6065,
        6133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connection to the same forests.",
      "pos": [
        6137,
        6168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any Domain and OU filtering.",
      "pos": [
        6171,
        6199
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The same optional features, such as password sync and password writeback.",
      "pos": [
        6202,
        6275
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Move synchronization rules",
      "pos": [
        6279,
        6305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To move a custom synchronization rule, do the following:",
      "pos": [
        6310,
        6366
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6371,
        6431
      ],
      "content": "Open <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Synchronization Rules Editor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on your active server."
    },
    {
      "content": "Select your custom rule.",
      "pos": [
        6435,
        6459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click on <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Export<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6460,
        6480
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will bring up a notepad window.",
      "pos": [
        6481,
        6517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save the temporary file with a PS1 extension; this will make it a PowerShell script.",
      "pos": [
        6518,
        6602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the ps1 file to the staging server.",
      "pos": [
        6603,
        6643
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Sync Rule Export<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-upgrade-previous-version/exportrule.png)</ph>",
      "pos": [
        6644,
        6740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Connector GUID will be different on the staging server.",
      "pos": [
        6744,
        6803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get the GUID, start the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Synchronization Rules Editor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select one of the out-of-box rules representing the same connected system, and click on <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Export<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6804,
        6964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replace the GUID in your PS1 file with the GUID from the staging server.",
      "pos": [
        6965,
        7037
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In a PowerShell prompt, run the PS1 file.",
      "pos": [
        7041,
        7082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will create the custom synchronization rule on the staging server.",
      "pos": [
        7083,
        7154
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have multiple custom rules, repeat for all custom rules.",
      "pos": [
        7158,
        7221
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        7226,
        7236
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7237,
        7356
      ],
      "content": "Learn more about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Azure AD Connect: Upgrade from a previous version | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Explains the different methods to upgrade to the latest release of Azure Active Direcotry Connect, including in-place upgrade and swing migration.\"\n   services=\"active-directory\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"AndKjell\"\n   manager=\"stevenpo\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"Identity\"\n   ms.date=\"02/29/2016\"\n   ms.author=\"andkjell\"/>\n\n# Azure AD Connect: Upgrade from a previous version to the latest\nThis topic describes the different methods you can use to upgrade your Azure AD Connect installation to the latest release. We recommendation that you keep current with the releases of Azure AD Connect.\n\nIf you want to upgrade from DirSync, see [Upgrade from Azure AD sync tool (DirSync)](active-directory-aadconnect-dirsync-upgrade-get-started.md) instead.\n\nThere are a few different strategies to upgrade Azure AD Connect.\n\n| Method | Description |\n| --- | --- |\n| [Automatic upgrade](active-directory-aadconnect-feature-automatic-upgrade.md) | For customers with an express installation, this is the easiest method. |\n| [In-place upgrade](#in-place-upgrade) | If you have a single server, upgrade the installation in-place on the same server. |\n| [Swing migration](#swing-migration) | With two servers, you can prepare one of the servers with the new release and change active server when you are ready.\n\nFor required permissions, see [permissions required for upgrade](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md#upgrade).\n\n## In-place upgrade\nAn in-place upgrade will work for moving from Azure AD Sync or Azure AD Connect. It will not work for DirSync or for a solution with FIM + Azure AD Connector.\n\nThis method is preferred if you have a single server and less than about 100,000 objects. After the upgrade, a full import and full synchronization will occur. This will ensure that the new configuration will be applied to all existing objects in the system. This might take a few hours depending on the number of objects in scope of the sync engine. The normal delta synchronization scheduled, by default every 30 minutes, is suspended but password synchronization will continue. You might consider to do the in-place upgrade during a weekend.\n\n![In-Place Upgrade](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-upgrade-previous-version/inplaceupgrade.png)\n\nIf you have made changes to out-of-box synchronization rules, these will be set back to default configuration on upgrade. To make sure your configuration is kept between upgrades, make sure the changes are made as described in [Best practices for changing the default configuration](active-directory-aadconnectsync-best-practices-changing-default-configuration.md).\n\n## Swing migration\nIf you have a complex deployment or very many objects, it might be impractical to do an in-place upgrade on the live system. This could for some customers take multiple days and during this time no delta changes will be processed.\n\nInstead the recommended method to use is a swing migration. For this method you will need (at least) two servers, one active and one staging server. The active server (solid blue lines in the picture below) will be responsible for the active load. The staging server (dashed purple lines in the picture below) will be prepared with the new release and when fully ready, this server will be made active. The previous active server, now with the old version installed, will be made the staging server and upgraded.\n\n![Staging server](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-upgrade-previous-version/stagingserver1.png)\n\nNote: It has been noted that some customers prefer to have three or four servers for this. Since the staging server is being upgrades, you will during this time not have a backup server in case of a [disaster recovery](active-directory-aadconnectsync-operations.md#disaster-recovery). With a maximum of four servers, a new set of primary/standby servers with the new version can be prepared, ensuring there are always a staging server ready to take over.\n\nThese steps will also work to move from Azure AD Sync or a solution with FIM + Azure AD Connector. These steps will not work for DirSync, but the same swing migration (also called parallel deployment) method with steps for DirSync can be found in [Upgrade Azure Active Directory sync (DirSync)](active-directory-aadconnect-dirsync-upgrade-get-started.md).\n\n### Swing migration steps\n\n1. Make sure your active server and staging server are both using the same version.\n2. If you have made some custom configuration and your staging server does not have it, follow the steps under [Move custom configuration from active to staging server](#move-custom-configuration-from-active-to-staging-server).\n3. Upgrade the staging server to the latest version.\n4. Let the sync engine run full import and full synchronization.\n5. Verify that the new configuration did not cause any unexpected changes using the steps under **Verify** in [Verify the configuration of a server](active-directory-aadconnectsync-operations.md#verify-the-configuration-of-a-server). If something is not as expected, correct, run import and sync, and verify until the data looks good. These steps can be found in the linked topic.\n6. Switch the staging server to be the active server. This is the final step **switch active server** in [Verify the configuration of a server](active-directory-aadconnectsync-operations.md#verify-the-configuration-of-a-server).\n7. Upgrade the server now in staging mode to the latest release. Follow the same steps as before to get the data and configuration upgraded.\n\n### Move custom configuration from active to staging server\nIf you have made configuration changes to the active server, you need to make sure the same changes are applied to the staging server.\n\nThe custom sync rules you have created can be moved with PowerShell. Other changes must be applied the same way on both systems.\n\nThing you must make sure is configured the same way on both servers:\n\n- Connection to the same forests.\n- Any Domain and OU filtering.\n- The same optional features, such as password sync and password writeback.\n\n**Move synchronization rules**  \nTo move a custom synchronization rule, do the following:\n\n1. Open **Synchronization Rules Editor** on your active server.\n2. Select your custom rule. Click on **Export**. This will bring up a notepad window. Save the temporary file with a PS1 extension; this will make it a PowerShell script. Copy the ps1 file to the staging server.\n![Sync Rule Export](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-upgrade-previous-version/exportrule.png)\n3. The Connector GUID will be different on the staging server. To get the GUID, start the **Synchronization Rules Editor**, select one of the out-of-box rules representing the same connected system, and click on **Export**. Replace the GUID in your PS1 file with the GUID from the staging server.\n4. In a PowerShell prompt, run the PS1 file. This will create the custom synchronization rule on the staging server.\n5. If you have multiple custom rules, repeat for all custom rules.\n\n## Next steps\nLearn more about [Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory](active-directory-aadconnect.md).\n"
}