{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Identity Protection | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        87
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how Azure AD Identity Protection enables you to limit the ability of an attacker to exploit a compromised identity or device and to secure an identity or a device that was previously suspected or known to be compromised.",
      "pos": [
        106,
        332
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Identity Protection",
      "pos": [
        803,
        845
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Identity Protection is a security service that provides a consolidated view into risk events and potential vulnerabilities affecting your organization’s identities.",
      "pos": [
        848,
        1035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft has been securing cloud-based identities for over a decade, and with Azure AD Identity Protection, Microsoft is making these same protection systems available to enterprise customers.",
      "pos": [
        1036,
        1229
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Identity Protection leverages existing Azure AD’s anomaly detection capabilities (available through Azure AD’s Anomalous Activity Reports), and introduces new risk event types that can detect anomalies in real-time.",
      "pos": [
        1230,
        1445
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Limitations of the current preview",
      "pos": [
        1450,
        1484
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This section lists limitations that apply to the current preview of Azure Active Directory Identity Protection.",
      "pos": [
        1485,
        1596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Country or Region limitation",
      "pos": [
        1602,
        1630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The preview of Azure Active Directory Identity Protection is currently available only for directories with a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Country or Region<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value of <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>United States<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1632,
        1790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Remediation<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/222.png \"Remediation\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        1800,
        1881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Identity Protection and federated domains",
      "pos": [
        1888,
        1929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The preview of Azure Active Directory Identity Protection has the following limitations in conjunction with federated domains:",
      "pos": [
        1931,
        2057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Security policies do not work for federated domains",
      "pos": [
        2061,
        2112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk events are are only detected for apps federating with Azure Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        2116,
        2197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting Started",
      "pos": [
        2201,
        2216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The vast majority of security breaches take place when attackers gain access to an environment by stealing a user’s identity.",
      "pos": [
        2218,
        2343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Attackers have become increasingly effective at leveraging third party breaches, and using sophisticated phishing attacks.",
      "pos": [
        2344,
        2466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once an attacker gains access to even a low privileged user account, it is relatively straightforward for them to gain access to important company resources through lateral movement.",
      "pos": [
        2467,
        2649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is therefore essential to protect all identities and, when an identity is compromised, proactively prevent the compromised identity from being abused.",
      "pos": [
        2650,
        2803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Discovering compromised identities is no easy task.",
      "pos": [
        2806,
        2857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Fortunately, Identity Protection can help: Identity Protection uses adaptive machine learning algorithms and heuristics to detect anomalies and risk events that may indicate that an identity has been compromised.",
      "pos": [
        2858,
        3070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using this data, Identity Protection generates reports and alerts that enables you to investigate these risk events and take appropriate remediation or mitigation action.",
      "pos": [
        3073,
        3243
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "But Azure Active Directory Identity Protection more than a monitoring and reporting tool.",
      "pos": [
        3246,
        3335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Based on risk events, Identity Protection calculates a user risk level for each user, enabling you to configure risk-based policies to automatically protect the identities of your organization.",
      "pos": [
        3336,
        3529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These risk-based policies, in addition to other conditional access controls provided by Azure Active Directory and EMS, can automatically block or offer adaptive remediation actions that include password resets and multi-factor authentication enforcement.",
      "pos": [
        3531,
        3786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Explore Identity Protection's capabilities",
      "pos": [
        3794,
        3836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Detecting risk events and risky accounts:",
      "pos": [
        3841,
        3882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Detecting 6 risk event types using machine learning and heuristic rules",
      "pos": [
        3890,
        3961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Calculating user risk levels",
      "pos": [
        3966,
        3994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Providing custom recommendations to improve overall security posture by highlighting vulnerabilities",
      "pos": [
        3998,
        4098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Investigating risk events:",
      "pos": [
        4108,
        4134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sending notifications for risk events",
      "pos": [
        4140,
        4177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Investigating risk events using relevant and contextual information",
      "pos": [
        4181,
        4248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Providing basic workflows to track investigations",
      "pos": [
        4252,
        4301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Providing easy access to remediation actions such as password reset",
      "pos": [
        4305,
        4372
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk-based conditional access policies:",
      "pos": [
        4382,
        4421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policy to mitigate risky sign-ins by blocking sign-ins or requiring multi-factor authentication challenges.",
      "pos": [
        4427,
        4534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policy to block or secure risky user accounts",
      "pos": [
        4538,
        4583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policy to require users to register for multi-factor authentication",
      "pos": [
        4587,
        4654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Detection and Risk",
      "pos": [
        4660,
        4678
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk events",
      "pos": [
        4684,
        4695
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk events are events that were flagged as suspicious by Identity Protection, and indicate that an identity may have been compromised.",
      "pos": [
        4697,
        4832
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a complete list of risk events, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Types of risk events detected by Azure Active Directory Identity Protection<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-identityprotection-risk-events-types.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4833,
        5009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some of these risk events have been available through the Azure AD Anomalous Activity reports in the Azure Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        5012,
        5137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The table below lists the various risk event types and the corresponding <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure AD Anomalous Activity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report.",
      "pos": [
        5139,
        5251
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft is continuing to invest in this space, and plans to continuously improve the detection accuracy of existing risk events and add new risk event types on an ongoing basis.",
      "pos": [
        5252,
        5431
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Identity Protection Risk Event Type",
      "pos": [
        5438,
        5473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Corresponding Azure AD Anomalous Activity Report",
      "pos": [
        5476,
        5524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Leaked credentials",
      "pos": [
        5543,
        5561
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users with leaked credentials",
      "pos": [
        5567,
        5596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Impossible travel to atypical locations",
      "pos": [
        5601,
        5640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Irregular sign-in activity",
      "pos": [
        5643,
        5669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-ins from infected devices",
      "pos": [
        5674,
        5704
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-ins from possibly infected devices",
      "pos": [
        5710,
        5749
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-ins from anonymous IP addresses",
      "pos": [
        5754,
        5790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-ins from unknown sources",
      "pos": [
        5794,
        5823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-ins from IP addresses with suspicious activity",
      "pos": [
        5828,
        5879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-ins from IP addresses with suspicious activity",
      "pos": [
        5882,
        5933
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Signs in from unfamiliar locations",
      "pos": [
        5938,
        5972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "-",
      "pos": [
        5978,
        5979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Lockout events (not in public preview)",
      "pos": [
        5984,
        6022
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "-",
      "pos": [
        6028,
        6029
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following Azure AD Anomalous Activity reports are not included as risk events in Azure AD Identity Protection, and will therefore not be available through Identity Protection.",
      "pos": [
        6033,
        6212
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These reports are still available in the Azure Management Portal however they will be deprecated at some time in the future as they are being superseded by risk events in Identity Protection.",
      "pos": [
        6213,
        6404
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-ins after multiple failures",
      "pos": [
        6408,
        6440
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-ins from multiple geographies",
      "pos": [
        6443,
        6477
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk level",
      "pos": [
        6483,
        6493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Risk level for a risk event is an indication (High, Medium, or Low) of the severity of the risk event.",
      "pos": [
        6495,
        6601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The risk level helps Identity Protection users prioritize the actions they must take to reduce the risk to their organization.",
      "pos": [
        6602,
        6728
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The severity of the risk event represents the strength of the signal as a predictor of identity compromise, combined with the amount of noise that it typically introduces.",
      "pos": [
        6729,
        6900
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>High<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: High confidence and high severity risk event.",
      "pos": [
        6905,
        6960
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These events are strong indicators that the user’s identity has been compromised, and any user accounts impacted should be remediated immediately.",
      "pos": [
        6961,
        7107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Medium<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: High severity, but lower confidence risk event, or vice versa.",
      "pos": [
        7111,
        7185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These events are potentially risky, and any user accounts impacted should be remediated.",
      "pos": [
        7186,
        7274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Low<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Low confidence and low severity risk event.",
      "pos": [
        7278,
        7330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This event may not require an immediate action, but when combined with other risk events, may provide a strong indication that the identity is compromised.",
      "pos": [
        7331,
        7486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk Level",
      "pos": [
        7492,
        7502
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk events are either identified in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>real-time<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, or in post-processing after the risk event has already taken place (offline).",
      "pos": [
        7573,
        7702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Currently most risk events in Identity Protection are computed offline, and show up in Identity Protection within 2-4 hours.",
      "pos": [
        7703,
        7827
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While evaluated in real-time, the real-time risk events will show up in the Identity Protection Console within 5-10 minutes.",
      "pos": [
        7829,
        7953
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Several legacy clients do not currently support real-time risk event detection and prevention.",
      "pos": [
        7955,
        8049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, sign-ins from these clients cannot be detected or prevented in real-time.",
      "pos": [
        8050,
        8136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Investigation",
      "pos": [
        8142,
        8155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your journey through Identity Protection typically starts with the Identity Protection dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        8156,
        8253
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remediation",
      "pos": [
        8267,
        8278
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The dashboard gives you access to:",
      "pos": [
        8353,
        8387
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8392,
        8475
      ],
      "content": "Reports such as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Users flagged for risk<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Risk events<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Vulnerabilities<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8478,
        8610
      ],
      "content": "Settings such as the configuration of your <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Security Policies<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Notifications<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>multi-factor authentication registration<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "It is typically your starting point for investigation, which is the process of reviewing the activities, logs, and other relevant information related to a risk event to decide whether remediation or mitigation steps are necessary,  and how the identity was compromised, and understand how the compromised identity was used.",
      "pos": [
        8614,
        8937
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8939,
        9108
      ],
      "content": "You can tie your investigation activities to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>notifications<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-identityprotection-notifications.md)</ept> Azure Active Directory Protection sends per email."
    },
    {
      "content": "The following sections provide you with more details and the steps that are related to an investigation.",
      "pos": [
        9110,
        9214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is a user risk level?",
      "pos": [
        9223,
        9249
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A user risk level is an indication (High, Medium, or Low) of the likelihood that the user’s identity has been compromised.",
      "pos": [
        9251,
        9373
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is calculated based on the user risk events that are associated with the user's identity.",
      "pos": [
        9374,
        9466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The status of a risk event is either <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Closed<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9469,
        9531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only risk events that are <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> contribute to the user risk calculation.",
      "pos": [
        9532,
        9609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The user risk level is calculated using the following inputs:",
      "pos": [
        9612,
        9673
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Active risk events impacting the user",
      "pos": [
        9677,
        9714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk level of these events",
      "pos": [
        9717,
        9743
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Whether any remediation actions have been taken",
      "pos": [
        9747,
        9794
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User risks",
      "pos": [
        9804,
        9814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the user risk levels to create conditional access policies to block risky users from signing in, or force them to securely change their password.",
      "pos": [
        9889,
        10046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Closing risk events manually",
      "pos": [
        10053,
        10081
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In most cases, you will take remediation actions such as a secure password reset to automatically close risk events.",
      "pos": [
        10083,
        10199
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, this might not always be possible.",
      "pos": [
        10200,
        10243
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is, for example, the case, when:",
      "pos": [
        10250,
        10287
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A user with Active risk events has been deleted",
      "pos": [
        10291,
        10338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An investigation reveals that a reported risk event has been perform by the legitimate user",
      "pos": [
        10341,
        10432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because risk events that are <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> contribute to the user risk calculation, you may have to manually lower a risk level by closing risk events manually.",
      "pos": [
        10434,
        10591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During the course of investigation, you can choose to take any of these actions to change the status of a risk event:",
      "pos": [
        10597,
        10714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actions",
      "pos": [
        10723,
        10730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Resolve<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - If after investigating a risk event, you took an appropriate remediation action outside Identity Protection, and you believe that the risk event should be considered closed, mark the event as Resolved.",
      "pos": [
        10802,
        11017
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resolved events will set the risk event’s status to Closed and the risk event will no longer contribute to user risk.",
      "pos": [
        11018,
        11135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Mark as false-positive<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - In some cases, you may investigate a risk event and discover that it was incorrectly flagged as a risky.",
      "pos": [
        11139,
        11272
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can help reduce the number of such occurrences by marking the risk event as False-positive.",
      "pos": [
        11273,
        11368
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will help the machine learning algorithms to improve the classification of similar events in the future.",
      "pos": [
        11369,
        11478
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The status of false-positive events is to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Closed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and they will no longer contribute to user risk.",
      "pos": [
        11479,
        11580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Ignore<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - If you have not taken any remediation action, but want the risk event to be removed from the active list, you can mark a risk event Ignore and the event status will be Closed.",
      "pos": [
        11584,
        11772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ignored events do not contribute to user risk.",
      "pos": [
        11773,
        11819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option should only be used under unusual circumstances.",
      "pos": [
        11820,
        11880
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reactivate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Risk events that were manually closed (by choosing <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Resolve<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>False positive<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Ignore<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>) can be reactivated, setting the event status back to <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11885,
        12065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reactivated risk events contribute to the user risk level calculation.",
      "pos": [
        12066,
        12136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risk events closed through remediation (such as a secure password reset) cannot be reactivated.",
      "pos": [
        12137,
        12232
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12235,
        12280
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>To open the related configuration dialog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure AD Identity Protection<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> blade, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Users flagged for risk<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        12285,
        12365
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Manual password reset<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/408.png \"Manual password reset\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        12375,
        12476
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Right-click the affected user.",
      "pos": [
        12486,
        12516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manual password reset",
      "pos": [
        12528,
        12549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remediating user risk events",
      "pos": [
        12637,
        12665
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A remediation is an action to secure an identity or a device that was previously suspected or known to be compromised.",
      "pos": [
        12667,
        12785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A remediation action restores the identity or device to a safe state, and resolves previous risk events associated with the identity or device.",
      "pos": [
        12786,
        12929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remediate user risk events, you can:",
      "pos": [
        12931,
        12970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perform a secure password reset to remediate user risk events manually",
      "pos": [
        12974,
        13044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure a user risk security policy to mitigate or remediate user risk events automatically",
      "pos": [
        13049,
        13142
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Re-image the infected device",
      "pos": [
        13146,
        13174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manual secure password reset",
      "pos": [
        13183,
        13211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A secure password reset is an effective remediation for many risk events, and when performed, automatically closes these risk events and recalculates the user risk level.",
      "pos": [
        13213,
        13383
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the Identity Protection dashboard to initiate a password reset for a risky user.",
      "pos": [
        13384,
        13476
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The related dialog provides two different methods to reset a password:",
      "pos": [
        13479,
        13549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reset password<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Require user to reset password<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to allow the user to self-recover if the user has registered for multi-factor authentication.",
      "pos": [
        13551,
        13707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During the user's next sign-in, the user will be required to solve a multi-factor authentication challenge successfully and then, forced to change the password.",
      "pos": [
        13708,
        13868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option isn't available if the user account is not already registered multi-factor authentication.",
      "pos": [
        13869,
        13971
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Temporary password<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Generate a temporary password<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to immediately invalidate the existing password, and create a new temporary password for the user.",
      "pos": [
        13973,
        14137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Send the new temporary password to an alternate email address for the user or to the user's manager.",
      "pos": [
        14138,
        14238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because the password is temporary, the user will be prompted to change the password upon sign-in.",
      "pos": [
        14239,
        14336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policy",
      "pos": [
        14345,
        14351
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        14420,
        14465
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>To open the related configuration dialog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure AD Identity Protection<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> blade, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Users flagged for risk<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        14470,
        14550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Manual password reset<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/408.png \"Manual password reset\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        14560,
        14661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the affected user",
      "pos": [
        14671,
        14694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manual password reset",
      "pos": [
        14706,
        14727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click Reset password",
      "pos": [
        14815,
        14835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manual password reset",
      "pos": [
        14847,
        14868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User risk security policy",
      "pos": [
        14960,
        14985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A user risk security policy is a conditional access policy that evaluates the risk level to a specific user and applies remediation and mitigation actions based on predefined conditions and rules.",
      "pos": [
        14987,
        15183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User ridk policy",
      "pos": [
        15195,
        15211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Identity Protection helps you manage the mitigation and remediation of users flagged for risk by enabling you to:",
      "pos": [
        15291,
        15413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set the users and groups the policy applies to:",
      "pos": [
        15417,
        15464
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User ridk policy",
      "pos": [
        15477,
        15493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set the user risk level threshold (low, medium, or high) that triggers a password change:",
      "pos": [
        15575,
        15664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User ridk policy",
      "pos": [
        15677,
        15693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set the user risk level threshold (low, medium, or high) that triggers blocking a user:",
      "pos": [
        15775,
        15862
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User ridk policy",
      "pos": [
        15874,
        15890
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Switch the state of your policy:",
      "pos": [
        15972,
        16004
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MFA Registration",
      "pos": [
        16016,
        16032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Review and evaluate the impact of a change before activating it:",
      "pos": [
        16114,
        16178
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User ridk policy",
      "pos": [
        16190,
        16206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choosing a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>High<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold reduces the number of times a policy is triggered and minimizes the impact to users.",
      "pos": [
        16287,
        16401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, it excludes <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Low<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Medium<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> users flagged for risk from the policy, which may not secure identities or devices that were previously suspected or known to be compromised.",
      "pos": [
        16402,
        16587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When setting the policy,",
      "pos": [
        16589,
        16613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exclude users who are likely to generate a lot of false-positives (developers, security analysts)",
      "pos": [
        16617,
        16714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exclude users in locales where enabling the policy is not practical (for example no access to helpdesk)",
      "pos": [
        16718,
        16821
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16825,
        16935
      ],
      "content": "Use a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>High<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold during initial policy roll out, or if you must minimize challenges seen by end users."
    },
    {
      "content": "Use a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Low<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold if your organization requires greater security.",
      "pos": [
        16939,
        17010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Selecting a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Low<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold introduces additional user sign-in challenges, but increased security.",
      "pos": [
        17011,
        17111
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        17113,
        17261
      ],
      "content": "The recommended default for most organizations is to configure a rule for a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Medium<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold to strike a balance between usability and security."
    },
    {
      "content": "For an overview of the related user experience, see:",
      "pos": [
        17263,
        17315
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        17319,
        17430
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Compromised account recovery flow<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#compromised-account-recovery)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        17436,
        17545
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Compromised account blocked flow<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#compromised-account-blocked)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        17550,
        17595
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>To open the related configuration dialog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure AD Identity Protection<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> blade, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        17600,
        17666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>User risk policy<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/401.png \"User risk policy\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        17676,
        17767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Security Policies<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>User risk<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        17777,
        17835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>User risk policy<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/500.png \"User risk policy\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        17845,
        17936
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Mitigating user risk events",
      "pos": [
        17951,
        17978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Administrators can set a user risk security policy to block users upon sign-in depending on the risk level.",
      "pos": [
        17979,
        18086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Blocking a sign-in:",
      "pos": [
        18089,
        18108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Prevents the generation of new user risk events for the affected user",
      "pos": [
        18113,
        18182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enables administrators to manually remediate the risk events affecting the user's identity and restore it to a secure state",
      "pos": [
        18186,
        18309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is a sign-in risk level?",
      "pos": [
        18316,
        18345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A sign-in risk level is an indication (High, Medium, or Low) of the likelihood that for a specific sign-in, someone else is attempting to authenticate with the user’s identity.",
      "pos": [
        18347,
        18523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The sign-in risk level is evaluated at the time of a sign-in and considers risk events and indicators detected in real-time for that specific sign-in.",
      "pos": [
        18524,
        18674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Mitigating sign-in risk events",
      "pos": [
        18680,
        18710
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A mitigation is an action to limit the ability of an attacker to exploit a compromised identity or device without restoring the identity or device to a safe state.",
      "pos": [
        18712,
        18875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A mitigation does not resolve previous sign-in risk events associated with the identity or device.",
      "pos": [
        18876,
        18974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use conditional access in Azure AD Identity Protection to automatically mitigate sign-in risk events.",
      "pos": [
        18976,
        19085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using these policies, you consider the risk level of the user or the sign-in to block risky sign-ins or require the user to perform multi-factor authentication.",
      "pos": [
        19086,
        19246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These actions may prevent an attacker from exploiting a stolen identity to cause damage, and may give you some time to secure the identity.",
      "pos": [
        19247,
        19386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-in risk security policy",
      "pos": [
        19393,
        19421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A sign-in risk policy is a conditional access policy that evaluates the risk to a specific sign-in and applies mitigations based on predefined conditions and rules.",
      "pos": [
        19423,
        19587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-in risk policy",
      "pos": [
        19599,
        19618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Identity Protection helps you manage the mitigation of risky sign-ins by enabling you to:",
      "pos": [
        19701,
        19799
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set the users and groups the policy applies to:",
      "pos": [
        19803,
        19850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-in risk policy",
      "pos": [
        19863,
        19882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set the sign-in risk level threshold (low, medium, or high) that triggers a multi-factor authentication challenge for the affected sign-ins:",
      "pos": [
        19967,
        20107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-in risk policy",
      "pos": [
        20120,
        20139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set the sign-in risk level threshold (low, medium, or high) that blocks the affected sign-ins:",
      "pos": [
        20224,
        20318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-in risk policy",
      "pos": [
        20332,
        20351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Switch the state of your policy:",
      "pos": [
        20436,
        20468
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MFA Registration",
      "pos": [
        20480,
        20496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Review and evaluate the impact of a change before activating it:",
      "pos": [
        20578,
        20642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign-in risk policy",
      "pos": [
        20655,
        20674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choosing a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>High<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold reduces the number of times a policy is triggered and minimizes the impact to users.",
      "pos": [
        20759,
        20873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, it excludes <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Low<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Medium<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> sign-ins flagged for risk from the policy, which may not block an attacker from exploiting a compromised identity.",
      "pos": [
        20879,
        21037
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When setting the policy,",
      "pos": [
        21040,
        21064
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exclude users who do not/cannot have multi-factor authentication",
      "pos": [
        21069,
        21133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exclude users in locales where enabling the policy is not practical (for example no access to helpdesk)",
      "pos": [
        21137,
        21240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exclude users who are likely to generate a lot of false-positives (developers, security analysts)",
      "pos": [
        21244,
        21341
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21345,
        21455
      ],
      "content": "Use a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>High<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold during initial policy roll out, or if you must minimize challenges seen by end users."
    },
    {
      "content": "Use a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Low<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  threshold if your organization requires greater security.",
      "pos": [
        21459,
        21531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Selecting a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Low<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold introduces additional user sign-in challenges, but increased security.",
      "pos": [
        21532,
        21632
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21634,
        21782
      ],
      "content": "The recommended default for most organizations is to configure a rule for a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Medium<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> threshold to strike a balance between usability and security."
    },
    {
      "content": "The sign-in risk policy is:",
      "pos": [
        21786,
        21813
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Applied to all browser traffic and sign-ins using modern authentication.",
      "pos": [
        21817,
        21889
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not applied to applications using older security protocols by disabling the WS-Trust endpoint at the federated IDP, such as ADFS.",
      "pos": [
        21892,
        22021
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        22023,
        22100
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Risk Events<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in the Identity Protection console lists all events:"
    },
    {
      "content": "This policy was applied to",
      "pos": [
        22104,
        22130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can review the activity and determine whether the action was appropriate or not",
      "pos": [
        22133,
        22216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For an overview of the related user experience, see:",
      "pos": [
        22219,
        22271
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risky sign-in recovery",
      "pos": [
        22276,
        22298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Risky sign-in blocked",
      "pos": [
        22374,
        22395
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Multi-factor authentication registration during a risky sign-in",
      "pos": [
        22471,
        22534
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        22653,
        22698
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>To open the related configuration dialog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure AD Identity Protection<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> blade, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        22703,
        22769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>MFA Registration<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/401.png \"MFA Registration\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        22779,
        22870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Security Policies<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Sign-in risk<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        22880,
        22941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>MFA Registration<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/700.png \"MFA Registration\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        22951,
        23042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Multi-factor authentication registration policy",
      "pos": [
        23055,
        23102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Multi-factor authentication is a method of verifying who you are that requires the use of more than just a username and password.",
      "pos": [
        23104,
        23239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It provides a second layer of security to user sign-ins and transactions.",
      "pos": [
        23240,
        23313
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend that you require Azure Multi-Factor Authentication for user sign-ins because it:",
      "pos": [
        23319,
        23412
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delivers strong authentication with a range of easy verification options",
      "pos": [
        23416,
        23488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Plays a key role in preparing your organization to protect and recover from account compromises",
      "pos": [
        23492,
        23587
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        23589,
        23718
      ],
      "content": "For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>What is Azure Multi-Factor Authentication?<ept id=\"p1\">](../multi-factor-authentication/multi-factor-authentication.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Identity Protection helps you manage the roll-out of multi-factor authentication registration by configuring a policy that enables you to:",
      "pos": [
        23721,
        23868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "View the current registration status:",
      "pos": [
        23873,
        23910
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MFA Registration",
      "pos": [
        23923,
        23939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set the users and groups the policy applies to:",
      "pos": [
        24021,
        24068
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MFA Registration",
      "pos": [
        24080,
        24096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Define how long they are allowed to skip registration:",
      "pos": [
        24178,
        24232
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MFA Registration",
      "pos": [
        24244,
        24260
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Switch the state of your policy:",
      "pos": [
        24342,
        24374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MFA Registration",
      "pos": [
        24386,
        24402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For an overview of the related user experience, see:",
      "pos": [
        24482,
        24534
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        24538,
        24673
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Multi-factor authentication registration flow<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#multi-factor-authentication-registration)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        24679,
        24855
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Multi-factor authentication registration during a risky sign-in<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#multi-factor-authentication-registration-during-a-risky-sign-in)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        24863,
        24908
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>To open the related configuration dialog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure AD Identity Protection<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> blade, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        24913,
        24979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>MFA Registration<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/401.png \"MFA Registration\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        24989,
        25080
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Multi-Factor Authentication<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Registration<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        25090,
        25161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>MFA Registration<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/402.png \"MFA Registration\")</ph>",
      "pos": [
        25171,
        25262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See also",
      "pos": [
        25275,
        25283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Channel 9: Azure AD and Identity Show: Identity Protection Preview",
      "pos": [
        25289,
        25355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Types of risk events detected by Azure Active Directory Identity Protection",
      "pos": [
        25468,
        25543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Vulnerabilities detected by Azure Active Directory Identity Protection",
      "pos": [
        25607,
        25677
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Identity Protection notifications",
      "pos": [
        25739,
        25795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Identity Protection flows",
      "pos": [
        25855,
        25903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Identity Protection playbook",
      "pos": [
        25955,
        26006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Identity Protection glossary",
      "pos": [
        26061,
        26112
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Azure Active Directory Identity Protection | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Learn how Azure AD Identity Protection enables you to limit the ability of an attacker to exploit a compromised identity or device and to secure an identity or a device that was previously suspected or known to be compromised.\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    keywords=\"azure active directory identity protection, cloud app discovery, managing applications, security, risk, risk level, vulnerability, security policy\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"markusvi\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"03/18/2016\"\n    ms.author=\"markvi\"/>\n\n#Azure Active Directory Identity Protection \n\nAzure Active Directory Identity Protection is a security service that provides a consolidated view into risk events and potential vulnerabilities affecting your organization’s identities. Microsoft has been securing cloud-based identities for over a decade, and with Azure AD Identity Protection, Microsoft is making these same protection systems available to enterprise customers. Identity Protection leverages existing Azure AD’s anomaly detection capabilities (available through Azure AD’s Anomalous Activity Reports), and introduces new risk event types that can detect anomalies in real-time.\n\n## Limitations of the current preview\nThis section lists limitations that apply to the current preview of Azure Active Directory Identity Protection.\n\n### Country or Region limitation\n\nThe preview of Azure Active Directory Identity Protection is currently available only for directories with a **Country or Region** value of **United States**. <br><br>\n![Remediation](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/222.png \"Remediation\")\n\n\n### Identity Protection and federated domains\n\nThe preview of Azure Active Directory Identity Protection has the following limitations in conjunction with federated domains:\n\n- Security policies do not work for federated domains\n\n- Risk events are are only detected for apps federating with Azure Active Directory\n\n##Getting Started\n\nThe vast majority of security breaches take place when attackers gain access to an environment by stealing a user’s identity. Attackers have become increasingly effective at leveraging third party breaches, and using sophisticated phishing attacks. Once an attacker gains access to even a low privileged user account, it is relatively straightforward for them to gain access to important company resources through lateral movement. It is therefore essential to protect all identities and, when an identity is compromised, proactively prevent the compromised identity from being abused. \n\nDiscovering compromised identities is no easy task. Fortunately, Identity Protection can help: Identity Protection uses adaptive machine learning algorithms and heuristics to detect anomalies and risk events that may indicate that an identity has been compromised.\n \nUsing this data, Identity Protection generates reports and alerts that enables you to investigate these risk events and take appropriate remediation or mitigation action.\n \nBut Azure Active Directory Identity Protection more than a monitoring and reporting tool. Based on risk events, Identity Protection calculates a user risk level for each user, enabling you to configure risk-based policies to automatically protect the identities of your organization.  These risk-based policies, in addition to other conditional access controls provided by Azure Active Directory and EMS, can automatically block or offer adaptive remediation actions that include password resets and multi-factor authentication enforcement.  \n\n####Explore Identity Protection's capabilities \n\n**Detecting risk events and risky accounts:**  \n\n- Detecting 6 risk event types using machine learning and heuristic rules \n\n- Calculating user risk levels\n\n- Providing custom recommendations to improve overall security posture by highlighting vulnerabilities\n\n<br>\n\n**Investigating risk events:**\n\n- Sending notifications for risk events\n\n- Investigating risk events using relevant and contextual information\n\n- Providing basic workflows to track investigations\n\n- Providing easy access to remediation actions such as password reset\n\n<br>\n\n**Risk-based conditional access policies:**\n\n- Policy to mitigate risky sign-ins by blocking sign-ins or requiring multi-factor authentication challenges.\n\n- Policy to block or secure risky user accounts\n\n- Policy to require users to register for multi-factor authentication\n\n\n## Detection and Risk\n\n### Risk events\n\nRisk events are events that were flagged as suspicious by Identity Protection, and indicate that an identity may have been compromised. For a complete list of risk events, see [Types of risk events detected by Azure Active Directory Identity Protection](active-directory-identityprotection-risk-events-types.md). \n\nSome of these risk events have been available through the Azure AD Anomalous Activity reports in the Azure Management Portal. \nThe table below lists the various risk event types and the corresponding **Azure AD Anomalous Activity** report. Microsoft is continuing to invest in this space, and plans to continuously improve the detection accuracy of existing risk events and add new risk event types on an ongoing basis. \n\n\n\n| Identity Protection Risk Event Type | Corresponding Azure AD Anomalous Activity Report |\n| :-- | :-- |\n| Leaked credentials    | Users with leaked credentials |\n| Impossible travel to atypical locations | Irregular sign-in activity |\n| Sign-ins from infected devices    | Sign-ins from possibly infected devices |\n| Sign-ins from anonymous IP addresses  | Sign-ins from unknown sources |\n| Sign-ins from IP addresses with suspicious activity | Sign-ins from IP addresses with suspicious activity |\n| Signs in from unfamiliar locations    | - |\n| Lockout events (not in public preview)    | - |\n\nThe following Azure AD Anomalous Activity reports are not included as risk events in Azure AD Identity Protection, and will therefore not be available through Identity Protection. These reports are still available in the Azure Management Portal however they will be deprecated at some time in the future as they are being superseded by risk events in Identity Protection.\n\n- Sign-ins after multiple failures\n- Sign-ins from multiple geographies\n\n### Risk level\n\nThe Risk level for a risk event is an indication (High, Medium, or Low) of the severity of the risk event. The risk level helps Identity Protection users prioritize the actions they must take to reduce the risk to their organization. The severity of the risk event represents the strength of the signal as a predictor of identity compromise, combined with the amount of noise that it typically introduces. \n\n- **High**: High confidence and high severity risk event. These events are strong indicators that the user’s identity has been compromised, and any user accounts impacted should be remediated immediately.\n\n- **Medium**: High severity, but lower confidence risk event, or vice versa. These events are potentially risky, and any user accounts impacted should be remediated.\n\n- **Low**: Low confidence and low severity risk event. This event may not require an immediate action, but when combined with other risk events, may provide a strong indication that the identity is compromised. \n\n\n![Risk Level](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/01.png \"Risk Level\")\n\n \n\nRisk events are either identified in **real-time**, or in post-processing after the risk event has already taken place (offline). Currently most risk events in Identity Protection are computed offline, and show up in Identity Protection within 2-4 hours. \nWhile evaluated in real-time, the real-time risk events will show up in the Identity Protection Console within 5-10 minutes.\n\nSeveral legacy clients do not currently support real-time risk event detection and prevention. As a result, sign-ins from these clients cannot be detected or prevented in real-time.\n\n\n## Investigation\nYour journey through Identity Protection typically starts with the Identity Protection dashboard. \n\n<br><br>\n![Remediation](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/29.png \"Remediation\")\n<br> \n\nThe dashboard gives you access to:\n \n- Reports such as **Users flagged for risk**, **Risk events** and **Vulnerabilities**\n- Settings such as the configuration of your **Security Policies**, **Notifications** and **multi-factor authentication registration**\n \n\nIt is typically your starting point for investigation, which is the process of reviewing the activities, logs, and other relevant information related to a risk event to decide whether remediation or mitigation steps are necessary,  and how the identity was compromised, and understand how the compromised identity was used.\n\nYou can tie your investigation activities to the [notifications](active-directory-identityprotection-notifications.md) Azure Active Directory Protection sends per email.\n\nThe following sections provide you with more details and the steps that are related to an investigation.  \n\n\n\n## What is a user risk level?\n\nA user risk level is an indication (High, Medium, or Low) of the likelihood that the user’s identity has been compromised. It is calculated based on the user risk events that are associated with the user's identity. \n\nThe status of a risk event is either **Active** or **Closed**. Only risk events that are **Active** contribute to the user risk calculation. \n\nThe user risk level is calculated using the following inputs:\n\n- Active risk events impacting the user\n- Risk level of these events \n- Whether any remediation actions have been taken \n\n<br>\n![User risks](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/86.png \"User risks\")\n<br>\n\n\n\nYou can use the user risk levels to create conditional access policies to block risky users from signing in, or force them to securely change their password. \n\n\n## Closing risk events manually\n\nIn most cases, you will take remediation actions such as a secure password reset to automatically close risk events. However, this might not always be possible. <br> \nThis is, for example, the case, when:\n\n- A user with Active risk events has been deleted\n- An investigation reveals that a reported risk event has been perform by the legitimate user\n\nBecause risk events that are **Active** contribute to the user risk calculation, you may have to manually lower a risk level by closing risk events manually. <br>\nDuring the course of investigation, you can choose to take any of these actions to change the status of a risk event:\n\n<br>\n![Actions](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/34.png \"Actions\")\n<br>\n\n- **Resolve** - If after investigating a risk event, you took an appropriate remediation action outside Identity Protection, and you believe that the risk event should be considered closed, mark the event as Resolved. Resolved events will set the risk event’s status to Closed and the risk event will no longer contribute to user risk.\n\n- **Mark as false-positive** - In some cases, you may investigate a risk event and discover that it was incorrectly flagged as a risky. You can help reduce the number of such occurrences by marking the risk event as False-positive. This will help the machine learning algorithms to improve the classification of similar events in the future. The status of false-positive events is to **Closed** and they will no longer contribute to user risk.\n\n- **Ignore** - If you have not taken any remediation action, but want the risk event to be removed from the active list, you can mark a risk event Ignore and the event status will be Closed. Ignored events do not contribute to user risk. This option should only be used under unusual circumstances. \n\n- **Reactivate** - Risk events that were manually closed (by choosing **Resolve**, **False positive**, or **Ignore**) can be reactivated, setting the event status back to **Active**. Reactivated risk events contribute to the user risk level calculation. Risk events closed through remediation (such as a secure password reset) cannot be reactivated. \n\n**To open the related configuration dialog**:\n\n1. On the **Azure AD Identity Protection** blade, click **Users flagged for risk**.\n<br><br>\n![Manual password reset](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/408.png \"Manual password reset\")\n<br>\n\n2. Right-click the affected user.\n<br><br>\n![Manual password reset](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/437.png \"Manual password reset\")\n<br>\n\n## Remediating user risk events\n\nA remediation is an action to secure an identity or a device that was previously suspected or known to be compromised. A remediation action restores the identity or device to a safe state, and resolves previous risk events associated with the identity or device.\n\nTo remediate user risk events, you can:\n\n- Perform a secure password reset to remediate user risk events manually \n\n- Configure a user risk security policy to mitigate or remediate user risk events automatically\n\n- Re-image the infected device  \n\n\n### Manual secure password reset\n\nA secure password reset is an effective remediation for many risk events, and when performed, automatically closes these risk events and recalculates the user risk level. You can use the Identity Protection dashboard to initiate a password reset for a risky user. \n\nThe related dialog provides two different methods to reset a password:\n\n**Reset password** - Select **Require user to reset password** to allow the user to self-recover if the user has registered for multi-factor authentication. During the user's next sign-in, the user will be required to solve a multi-factor authentication challenge successfully and then, forced to change the password. This option isn't available if the user account is not already registered multi-factor authentication.\n\n**Temporary password** - Select **Generate a temporary password** to immediately invalidate the existing password, and create a new temporary password for the user. Send the new temporary password to an alternate email address for the user or to the user's manager. Because the password is temporary, the user will be prompted to change the password upon sign-in.\n\n<br>\n![Policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/71.png \"Policy\")\n<br>\n\n**To open the related configuration dialog**:\n\n1. On the **Azure AD Identity Protection** blade, click **Users flagged for risk**.\n<br><br>\n![Manual password reset](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/408.png \"Manual password reset\")\n<br>\n\n2. Click the affected user\n<br><br>\n![Manual password reset](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/404.png \"Manual password reset\")\n<br>\n\n2. Click Reset password\n<br><br>\n![Manual password reset](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/420.png \"Manual password reset\")\n<br>\n\n\n\n\n\n## User risk security policy\n\nA user risk security policy is a conditional access policy that evaluates the risk level to a specific user and applies remediation and mitigation actions based on predefined conditions and rules.\n<br><br>\n![User ridk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/500.png \"User ridk policy\")\n<br>\n\nAzure AD Identity Protection helps you manage the mitigation and remediation of users flagged for risk by enabling you to:\n\n- Set the users and groups the policy applies to: \n<br><br>\n![User ridk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/501.png \"User ridk policy\")\n<br>\n\n- Set the user risk level threshold (low, medium, or high) that triggers a password change: \n<br><br>\n![User ridk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/502.png \"User ridk policy\")\n<br>\n\n- Set the user risk level threshold (low, medium, or high) that triggers blocking a user:\n<br><br>\n![User ridk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/503.png \"User ridk policy\")\n<br>\n\n- Switch the state of your policy:\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/403.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n- Review and evaluate the impact of a change before activating it:\n<br><br>\n![User ridk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/504.png \"User ridk policy\")\n<br>\n\n\nChoosing a **High** threshold reduces the number of times a policy is triggered and minimizes the impact to users.\nHowever, it excludes **Low** and **Medium** users flagged for risk from the policy, which may not secure identities or devices that were previously suspected or known to be compromised.\n\nWhen setting the policy,\n\n- Exclude users who are likely to generate a lot of false-positives (developers, security analysts)\n\n- Exclude users in locales where enabling the policy is not practical (for example no access to helpdesk)\n\n- Use a **High** threshold during initial policy roll out, or if you must minimize challenges seen by end users.\n\n- Use a **Low** threshold if your organization requires greater security. Selecting a **Low** threshold introduces additional user sign-in challenges, but increased security.\n\nThe recommended default for most organizations is to configure a rule for a **Medium** threshold to strike a balance between usability and security.\n\nFor an overview of the related user experience, see:\n\n- [Compromised account recovery flow](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#compromised-account-recovery).  \n\n- [Compromised account blocked flow](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#compromised-account-blocked).  \n\n\n**To open the related configuration dialog**:\n\n1. On the **Azure AD Identity Protection** blade, click **Settings**.\n<br><br>\n![User risk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/401.png \"User risk policy\")\n<br>\n\n2. In the **Security Policies** section, click **User risk**.\n<br><br>\n![User risk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/500.png \"User risk policy\")\n<br>\n\n\n\n\n\n\n## Mitigating user risk events\nAdministrators can set a user risk security policy to block users upon sign-in depending on the risk level. \n\nBlocking a sign-in:\n \n- Prevents the generation of new user risk events for the affected user\n\n- Enables administrators to manually remediate the risk events affecting the user's identity and restore it to a secure state\n\n\n\n## What is a sign-in risk level?\n\nA sign-in risk level is an indication (High, Medium, or Low) of the likelihood that for a specific sign-in, someone else is attempting to authenticate with the user’s identity. The sign-in risk level is evaluated at the time of a sign-in and considers risk events and indicators detected in real-time for that specific sign-in. \n\n## Mitigating sign-in risk events \nA mitigation is an action to limit the ability of an attacker to exploit a compromised identity or device without restoring the identity or device to a safe state. A mitigation does not resolve previous sign-in risk events associated with the identity or device.\n\nYou can use conditional access in Azure AD Identity Protection to automatically mitigate sign-in risk events. Using these policies, you consider the risk level of the user or the sign-in to block risky sign-ins or require the user to perform multi-factor authentication. These actions may prevent an attacker from exploiting a stolen identity to cause damage, and may give you some time to secure the identity. \n\n\n## Sign-in risk security policy\n\nA sign-in risk policy is a conditional access policy that evaluates the risk to a specific sign-in and applies mitigations based on predefined conditions and rules.\n<br><br>\n![Sign-in risk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/700.png \"Sign-in risk policy\")\n<br>\n\nAzure AD Identity Protection helps you manage the mitigation of risky sign-ins by enabling you to:\n\n- Set the users and groups the policy applies to: \n<br><br>\n![Sign-in risk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/701.png \"Sign-in risk policy\")\n<br>\n\n- Set the sign-in risk level threshold (low, medium, or high) that triggers a multi-factor authentication challenge for the affected sign-ins: \n<br><br>\n![Sign-in risk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/702.png \"Sign-in risk policy\")\n<br>\n\n- Set the sign-in risk level threshold (low, medium, or high) that blocks the affected sign-ins:  \n<br><br>\n![Sign-in risk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/703.png \"Sign-in risk policy\")\n<br>\n\n- Switch the state of your policy:\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/403.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n- Review and evaluate the impact of a change before activating it: \n<br><br>\n![Sign-in risk policy](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/704.png \"Sign-in risk policy\")\n<br>\n\n \nChoosing a **High** threshold reduces the number of times a policy is triggered and minimizes the impact to users.<br> \nHowever, it excludes **Low** and **Medium** sign-ins flagged for risk from the policy, which may not block an attacker from exploiting a compromised identity. \n\nWhen setting the policy, \n\n- Exclude users who do not/cannot have multi-factor authentication\n\n- Exclude users in locales where enabling the policy is not practical (for example no access to helpdesk)\n\n- Exclude users who are likely to generate a lot of false-positives (developers, security analysts)\n\n- Use a **High** threshold during initial policy roll out, or if you must minimize challenges seen by end users.\n\n- Use a **Low**  threshold if your organization requires greater security. Selecting a **Low** threshold introduces additional user sign-in challenges, but increased security.\n\nThe recommended default for most organizations is to configure a rule for a **Medium** threshold to strike a balance between usability and security.\n\n \nThe sign-in risk policy is:\n\n- Applied to all browser traffic and sign-ins using modern authentication.\n- Not applied to applications using older security protocols by disabling the WS-Trust endpoint at the federated IDP, such as ADFS.\n\nThe **Risk Events** page in the Identity Protection console lists all events:\n\n- This policy was applied to\n- You can review the activity and determine whether the action was appropriate or not \n\nFor an overview of the related user experience, see:\n\n- [Risky sign-in recovery](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#risky-sign-in-recovery) \n\n- [Risky sign-in blocked](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#risky-sign-in-blocked)  \n\n- [Multi-factor authentication registration during a risky sign-in](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#multi-factor-authentication-registration-during-a-risky-sign-in)  \n\n\n\n\n\n**To open the related configuration dialog**:\n\n1. On the **Azure AD Identity Protection** blade, click **Settings**.\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/401.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n1. In the **Security Policies** section, click **Sign-in risk**.\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/700.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n\n\n\n## Multi-factor authentication registration policy\n\nAzure Multi-factor authentication is a method of verifying who you are that requires the use of more than just a username and password. It provides a second layer of security to user sign-ins and transactions. <br>\nWe recommend that you require Azure Multi-Factor Authentication for user sign-ins because it:\n\n- Delivers strong authentication with a range of easy verification options\n\n- Plays a key role in preparing your organization to protect and recover from account compromises\n\nFor more details, see [What is Azure Multi-Factor Authentication?](../multi-factor-authentication/multi-factor-authentication.md)\n\n\nAzure AD Identity Protection helps you manage the roll-out of multi-factor authentication registration by configuring a policy that enables you to: \n\n- View the current registration status: \n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/603.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n- Set the users and groups the policy applies to:\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/601.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n- Define how long they are allowed to skip registration:\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/602.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n- Switch the state of your policy:\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/403.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\nFor an overview of the related user experience, see:\n\n- [Multi-factor authentication registration flow](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#multi-factor-authentication-registration).  \n\n- [Multi-factor authentication registration during a risky sign-in](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md#multi-factor-authentication-registration-during-a-risky-sign-in).  \n\n\n\n\n\n**To open the related configuration dialog**:\n\n1. On the **Azure AD Identity Protection** blade, click **Settings**.\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/401.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n2. In the **Multi-Factor Authentication** section, click **Registration**.\n<br><br>\n![MFA Registration](./media/active-directory-identityprotection/402.png \"MFA Registration\")\n<br>\n\n\n\n\n## See also\n\n - [Channel 9: Azure AD and Identity Show: Identity Protection Preview](https://channel9.msdn.com/Series/Azure-AD-Identity/Azure-AD-and-Identity-Show-Identity-Protection-Preview)\n - [Types of risk events detected by Azure Active Directory Identity Protection](active-directory-identityprotection-risk-events-types.md)\n - [Vulnerabilities detected by Azure Active Directory Identity Protection](active-directory-identityprotection-vulnerabilities.md)\n - [Azure Active Directory Identity Protection notifications](active-directory-identityprotection-notifications.md)\n - [Azure Active Directory Identity Protection flows](active-directory-identityprotection-flows.md)\n - [Azure Active Directory Identity Protection playbook](active-directory-identityprotection-playbook.md)\n - [Azure Active Directory Identity Protection glossary](active-directory-identityprotection-glossary.md)\n\n\n"
}