{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Troubleshooting update failures",
      "pos": [
        49,
        80
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What if you see a notification that the pre-upgrade checks have failed?",
      "pos": [
        84,
        155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a pre-check fails, make sure that you have looked at the detailed notification bar at the bottom of the page.",
      "pos": [
        159,
        271
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This provides guidance as to which pre-check has failed.",
      "pos": [
        272,
        328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following illustration shows an instance in which such a notification appears.",
      "pos": [
        329,
        411
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, the controller health check and hardware component health check have failed.",
      "pos": [
        412,
        502
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Hardware Status<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, you can see that both <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Controller 0<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Controller 1<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> components need attention.",
      "pos": [
        503,
        628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pre-check failure",
      "pos": [
        634,
        651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will need to make sure that both controllers are healthy and online.",
      "pos": [
        735,
        807
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will also need to make sure that all the hardware components in the StorSimple device are shown to be healthy on the Maintenance page.",
      "pos": [
        808,
        946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can then try to install updates.",
      "pos": [
        947,
        983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are not able to fix the hardware component issues, then you will need to contact Microsoft Support for next steps.",
      "pos": [
        984,
        1105
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What if you receive a \"Could not install updates\" error message, and the recommendation is to refer to the update troubleshooting guide to determine the cause of the failure?",
      "pos": [
        1109,
        1283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One likely cause for this could be that you do not have connectivity to the Microsoft Update servers.",
      "pos": [
        1287,
        1388
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is a manual check that needs to be performed.",
      "pos": [
        1389,
        1439
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you lose connectivity to the update server, your update job would fail.",
      "pos": [
        1440,
        1514
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can check the connectivity by running the following cmdlet from the Windows PowerShell interface of your StorSimple device:",
      "pos": [
        1515,
        1642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run the cmdlet on both controllers.",
      "pos": [
        1770,
        1805
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have verified the connectivity exists, and you continue to see this issue, please contact Microsoft Support for next steps.",
      "pos": [
        1807,
        1937
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<!--author=alkohli last changed: 03/17/16-->\n\n## Troubleshooting update failures\n\n**What if you see a notification that the pre-upgrade checks have failed?**\n\nIf a pre-check fails, make sure that you have looked at the detailed notification bar at the bottom of the page. This provides guidance as to which pre-check has failed. The following illustration shows an instance in which such a notification appears. In this case, the controller health check and hardware component health check have failed. Under the **Hardware Status** section, you can see that both **Controller 0** and **Controller 1** components need attention.\n\n  ![Pre-check failure](./media/storsimple-install-troubleshooting/HCS_PreUpdateCheckFailed-include.png)\n\nYou will need to make sure that both controllers are healthy and online. You will also need to make sure that all the hardware components in the StorSimple device are shown to be healthy on the Maintenance page. You can then try to install updates. If you are not able to fix the hardware component issues, then you will need to contact Microsoft Support for next steps.\n\n**What if you receive a \"Could not install updates\" error message, and the recommendation is to refer to the update troubleshooting guide to determine the cause of the failure?**\n\nOne likely cause for this could be that you do not have connectivity to the Microsoft Update servers. This is a manual check that needs to be performed. If you lose connectivity to the update server, your update job would fail. You can check the connectivity by running the following cmdlet from the Windows PowerShell interface of your StorSimple device:\n\n `Test-Connection -Source <Fixed IP of your device controller> -Destination <Any IP or computer name outside of datacenter>`\n\nRun the cmdlet on both controllers.\n\nIf you have verified the connectivity exists, and you continue to see this issue, please contact Microsoft Support for next steps.\n"
}