{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Customizing claims issued in the SAML token for pre-integrated apps in Azure Active Directory | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        138
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to custom the claims issued in the SAML token for pre-integrated apps in Azure Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        157,
        262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Customizing claims issued in the SAML token for pre-integrated apps in Azure Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        578,
        671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Today Azure Active Directory supports thousands of pre-integrated applications in the Azure AD Application Gallery, including over 150 that support single sign-on using the SAML 2.0 protocol.",
      "pos": [
        673,
        864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a user authenticates to an application through Azure AD using SAML, Azure AD sends a token to the application (via an HTTP 302 redirect) which the application then validates and uses to log the user in instead of prompting for a username and password.",
      "pos": [
        865,
        1121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These SAML tokens contains pieces of information about the user known as \"claims\".",
      "pos": [
        1122,
        1204
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In identity-speak, a “claim” is information that an identity provider states about a user inside the token they issue for that user.",
      "pos": [
        1206,
        1338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SAML token<ept id=\"p1\">](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SAML_2.0)</ept>, this data is typically contained in the SAML Attribute Statement, and the user’s unique ID is typically represented in the SAML Subject.",
      "pos": [
        1339,
        1533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default, Azure AD will issue a SAML token to your application that contains a NameIdentifier claim, with a value of the user’s username in Azure AD (this value uniquely identifies the user).",
      "pos": [
        1535,
        1728
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The SAML token also contains additional claims containing the user’s email address, first name, and last name.",
      "pos": [
        1729,
        1839
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1841,
        2033
      ],
      "content": "To view or edit the claims issued in the SAML token to the application, open the application record in the Azure management portal and select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Attributes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab underneath the application."
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two possible reasons why you might need to edit the claims issued in the SAML token:",
      "pos": [
        2043,
        2137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "•The application has been written to require a different set of claim URIs or claim values",
      "pos": [
        2138,
        2228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "•Your application has been deployed in a way that requires the NameIdentifier claim to be something other than the username (AKA user principal name) stored in Azure Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        2230,
        2413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can edit any of the default claim values by selecting the pencil-shaped icon that appears on the right whenever you mouse over one of the rows in the SAML token attributes table.",
      "pos": [
        2416,
        2598
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also remove claims (other than NameIdentifier) using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>X<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> icon, and add new claims using the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add user attribute<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> button.",
      "pos": [
        2599,
        2735
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Editing the NameIdentifier claim",
      "pos": [
        2739,
        2771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To solve the problem where the application has been deployed using a different username, click the pencil icon next to the NameIdentifier claim.",
      "pos": [
        2773,
        2917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This provides a dialog with several different options:",
      "pos": [
        2918,
        2972
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2982,
        3245
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Attribute Value<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>user.mail<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to set the NameIdentifier claim to be the user’s email address in the directory, or select <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>user.onpremisessamaccountname<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> to set to the user’s SAM Account Name that has been synced from on-premise Azure AD."
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use the special ExtractMailPrefix() function to remove the domain suffix from either the email address or the user principal name resulting in only the first part of the user name being passed through (e.g. “joesmith” instead of joesmith@contoso.com).",
      "pos": [
        3248,
        3512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adding claims",
      "pos": [
        3524,
        3537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When adding a new claim, you can specify the attribute name (which doesn’t strictly need to follow a URI pattern as per the SAML spec), as well as set the value to any user attribute that is stored in the directory.",
      "pos": [
        3539,
        3754
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3764,
        4005
      ],
      "content": "For example, if you need to send the department that the user belongs to in their organization as a claim (e.g. Sales), then you can enter whatever claim value is expected by the application, and then select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>user.department<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the value."
    },
    {
      "content": "If for a given user there is no value stored for a selected attribute, then that claim with not be issued in the token.",
      "pos": [
        4007,
        4126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>user.onpremisesecurityidentifier<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>user.onpremisesamaccountname<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> are only supported when synchronizing user data from on-premise Active Directory using the latest preview of the AAD Connect tool.",
      "pos": [
        4128,
        4346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download the preview of the connect tool at the link below:",
      "pos": [
        4347,
        4414
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "http://connect.microsoft.com/site1164/Downloads/DownloadDetails.aspx?DownloadID=53949",
      "pos": [
        4418,
        4503
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Customizing claims issued in the SAML token for pre-integrated apps in Azure Active Directory | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Learn how to custom the claims issued in the SAML token for pre-integrated apps in Azure Active Directory\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"asmalser-msft\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"11/18/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"asmalser\"/>\n\n#Customizing claims issued in the SAML token for pre-integrated apps in Azure Active Directory\n\nToday Azure Active Directory supports thousands of pre-integrated applications in the Azure AD Application Gallery, including over 150 that support single sign-on using the SAML 2.0 protocol. When a user authenticates to an application through Azure AD using SAML, Azure AD sends a token to the application (via an HTTP 302 redirect) which the application then validates and uses to log the user in instead of prompting for a username and password. These SAML tokens contains pieces of information about the user known as \"claims\".\n\nIn identity-speak, a “claim” is information that an identity provider states about a user inside the token they issue for that user. In a [SAML token](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SAML_2.0), this data is typically contained in the SAML Attribute Statement, and the user’s unique ID is typically represented in the SAML Subject.\n\nBy default, Azure AD will issue a SAML token to your application that contains a NameIdentifier claim, with a value of the user’s username in Azure AD (this value uniquely identifies the user). The SAML token also contains additional claims containing the user’s email address, first name, and last name.\n\nTo view or edit the claims issued in the SAML token to the application, open the application record in the Azure management portal and select the **Attributes** tab underneath the application.\n\n![][1]\n\nThere are two possible reasons why you might need to edit the claims issued in the SAML token:\n•The application has been written to require a different set of claim URIs or claim values \n•Your application has been deployed in a way that requires the NameIdentifier claim to be something other than the username (AKA user principal name) stored in Azure Active Directory. \n\nYou can edit any of the default claim values by selecting the pencil-shaped icon that appears on the right whenever you mouse over one of the rows in the SAML token attributes table. You can also remove claims (other than NameIdentifier) using the **X** icon, and add new claims using the **Add user attribute** button.\n\n##Editing the NameIdentifier claim\n\nTo solve the problem where the application has been deployed using a different username, click the pencil icon next to the NameIdentifier claim. This provides a dialog with several different options:\n\n![][2]\n\nIn the **Attribute Value** menu, select **user.mail** to set the NameIdentifier claim to be the user’s email address in the directory, or select **user.onpremisessamaccountname** to set to the user’s SAM Account Name that has been synced from on-premise Azure AD. \n\nYou can also use the special ExtractMailPrefix() function to remove the domain suffix from either the email address or the user principal name resulting in only the first part of the user name being passed through (e.g. “joesmith” instead of joesmith@contoso.com).\n\n![][3]\n\n##Adding claims\n\nWhen adding a new claim, you can specify the attribute name (which doesn’t strictly need to follow a URI pattern as per the SAML spec), as well as set the value to any user attribute that is stored in the directory.\n\n![][4]\n\nFor example, if you need to send the department that the user belongs to in their organization as a claim (e.g. Sales), then you can enter whatever claim value is expected by the application, and then select **user.department** as the value.\n\nIf for a given user there is no value stored for a selected attribute, then that claim with not be issued in the token.\n\n**Note:** The **user.onpremisesecurityidentifier** and **user.onpremisesamaccountname** are only supported when synchronizing user data from on-premise Active Directory using the latest preview of the AAD Connect tool. You can download the preview of the connect tool at the link below:  \n\nhttp://connect.microsoft.com/site1164/Downloads/DownloadDetails.aspx?DownloadID=53949\n    \n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/active-directory-saml-claims-customization/claimscustomization1.png\n[2]: ./media/active-directory-saml-claims-customization/claimscustomization2.png\n[3]: ./media/active-directory-saml-claims-customization/claimscustomization3.png\n[4]: ./media/active-directory-saml-claims-customization/claimscustomization4.png\n\n\n"
}