{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "To install Update 1.2 from the Azure classic portal",
      "pos": [
        51,
        102
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        107,
        186
      ],
      "content": "In the Azure classic portal, go to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Devices<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page and select your device."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        191,
        231
      ],
      "content": "Navigate to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Devices<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Network Interfaces<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, first verify that you have at least one network interface that is iSCSI-enabled.",
      "pos": [
        236,
        346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then locate the network interface (other than DATA 0) that has a gateway assigned.",
      "pos": [
        347,
        429
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Disable the network interface that has an assigned gateway and save the modified configuration.",
      "pos": [
        434,
        529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note the network interface settings are retained and so when you re-enable this network interface later, the portal will revert to the original settings.",
      "pos": [
        530,
        683
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can now <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>use the Azure classic portal to install Update 1.2<ept id=\"p1\">](#install-update-12-via-the-azure-classic-portal)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        688,
        802
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Follow the instructions starting from step 3 of this procedure.",
      "pos": [
        803,
        866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you have installed all the updates, you can re-enable the network interface that you disabled.",
      "pos": [
        867,
        967
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<!--author=SharS last changed: 03/17/2016-->\n\n#### To install Update 1.2 from the Azure classic portal\n\n1. In the Azure classic portal, go to the **Devices** page and select your device.\n\n2. Navigate to **Devices** > **Configure**.\n\n3. Under **Network Interfaces**, first verify that you have at least one network interface that is iSCSI-enabled. Then locate the network interface (other than DATA 0) that has a gateway assigned.\n\n4. Disable the network interface that has an assigned gateway and save the modified configuration. Note the network interface settings are retained and so when you re-enable this network interface later, the portal will revert to the original settings.\n\n7. You can now [use the Azure classic portal to install Update 1.2](#install-update-12-via-the-azure-classic-portal). Follow the instructions starting from step 3 of this procedure. After you have installed all the updates, you can re-enable the network interface that you disabled.\n"
}