{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory B2B collaboration preview: Simple, secure cloud partner integration | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory B2B collaboration supports your cross-company relationships by enabling business partners to selectively access your corporate applications",
      "pos": [
        152,
        314
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) B2B collaboration preview: Simple, secure cloud partner integration",
      "pos": [
        596,
        697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As companies focus more on their core business, the need to partner with other businesses increases.",
      "pos": [
        699,
        799
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Companies need to easily and securely share resources (such as access to corporate applications) with their partners to engage in effective collaboration.",
      "pos": [
        800,
        954
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory B2B collaboration supports your cross-company relationships by enabling partners to selectively access your corporate applications and data using their self-managed identities.",
      "pos": [
        955,
        1154
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD B2B collaboration is:",
      "pos": [
        1155,
        1185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Simple<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Each partner user uses an existing Azure AD account or one that is easily created during invitation acceptance.",
      "pos": [
        1189,
        1312
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can provide this user with direct access to your chosen corporate app or a set of applications through the App Access Panel.",
      "pos": [
        1313,
        1441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Secure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Your admin controls all access to your corporate apps through your Azure AD directory.",
      "pos": [
        1445,
        1543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When collaboration is terminated, partner users can be removed from your Azure AD and their access to your apps is immediately revoked.",
      "pos": [
        1544,
        1679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additionally, when the partner user leaves the partner organization, access is lost automatically.",
      "pos": [
        1680,
        1778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Free<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Azure AD B2B collaboration is a free feature that comes with Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        1782,
        1862
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The partner companies who need access to your corporate apps <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>do not need to have Azure AD.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        1863,
        1957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD B2B collaboration provides a simple user sign-up experience to provide these partners with immediate access to your apps.",
      "pos": [
        1958,
        2088
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2090,
        2438
      ],
      "content": "Check out <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>the blog post announcing public preview<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.technet.com/b/ad/archive/2015/09/15/learn-all-about-the-azure-ad-b2b-collaboration-preview.aspx)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>this deep dive video<ept id=\"p2\">](https://channel9.msdn.com/Series/Azure-Active-Directory-Videos-Demos/Azure-Active-Directory-B2B-collaboration-demo)</ept> walking through Azure AD B2B collaboration."
    },
    {
      "content": "Related articles",
      "pos": [
        2443,
        2459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Browse our other articles on Azure B2B collaboration:",
      "pos": [
        2460,
        2513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How it works",
      "pos": [
        2518,
        2530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Detailed walkthrough",
      "pos": [
        2573,
        2593
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CSV file format reference",
      "pos": [
        2644,
        2669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "External user token format",
      "pos": [
        2726,
        2752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "External user object attribute changes",
      "pos": [
        2820,
        2858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Current preview limitations",
      "pos": [
        2938,
        2965
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Azure Active Directory B2B collaboration preview: Simple, secure cloud partner integration | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Azure Active Directory B2B collaboration supports your cross-company relationships by enabling business partners to selectively access your corporate applications\"\n   services=\"active-directory\"\n   authors=\"viv-liu\"\n   manager=\"cliffdi\"\n   editor=\"\"\n   tags=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"identity\"\n   ms.date=\"10/27/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"viviali\"/>\n\n# Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) B2B collaboration preview: Simple, secure cloud partner integration\n\nAs companies focus more on their core business, the need to partner with other businesses increases. Companies need to easily and securely share resources (such as access to corporate applications) with their partners to engage in effective collaboration. Azure Active Directory B2B collaboration supports your cross-company relationships by enabling partners to selectively access your corporate applications and data using their self-managed identities. Azure AD B2B collaboration is:\n\n- **Simple**: Each partner user uses an existing Azure AD account or one that is easily created during invitation acceptance. You can provide this user with direct access to your chosen corporate app or a set of applications through the App Access Panel.\n\n- **Secure**: Your admin controls all access to your corporate apps through your Azure AD directory. When collaboration is terminated, partner users can be removed from your Azure AD and their access to your apps is immediately revoked. Additionally, when the partner user leaves the partner organization, access is lost automatically.\n\n- **Free**: Azure AD B2B collaboration is a free feature that comes with Azure AD. The partner companies who need access to your corporate apps **do not need to have Azure AD.** Azure AD B2B collaboration provides a simple user sign-up experience to provide these partners with immediate access to your apps.\n\nCheck out [the blog post announcing public preview](http://blogs.technet.com/b/ad/archive/2015/09/15/learn-all-about-the-azure-ad-b2b-collaboration-preview.aspx) and [this deep dive video](https://channel9.msdn.com/Series/Azure-Active-Directory-Videos-Demos/Azure-Active-Directory-B2B-collaboration-demo) walking through Azure AD B2B collaboration.\n\n## Related articles\nBrowse our other articles on Azure B2B collaboration:\n\n- [How it works](active-directory-b2b-how-it-works.md)\n- [Detailed walkthrough](active-directory-b2b-detailed-walkthrough.md)\n- [CSV file format reference](active-directory-b2b-references-csv-file-format.md)\n- [External user token format](active-directory-b2b-references-external-user-token-format.md)\n- [External user object attribute changes](active-directory-b2b-references-external-user-object-attribute-changes.md)\n- [Current preview limitations](active-directory-b2b-current-preview-limitations.md)\n\n\n"
}