{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Track B2B messages in your logic apps in Azure App Service | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic covers tracking of B2B processing",
      "pos": [
        122,
        166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Track B2B messages",
      "pos": [
        494,
        512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "B2B Tracking Information",
      "pos": [
        517,
        541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "B2B communication involves message processing between trading partners.",
      "pos": [
        542,
        613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The relationships are defined as agreements between two trading partners.",
      "pos": [
        614,
        687
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the communication is established, there needs to be a way to monitor if the communication is happening as expected.",
      "pos": [
        688,
        808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We've implemented message tracking for the following B2B scenarios: AS2, EDIFACT, and X12.",
      "pos": [
        811,
        901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AS2",
      "pos": [
        906,
        909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have created an instance of an AS2 API App, browse to that instance, and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tracking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        910,
        1012
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Herein you can view and filter all the AS2 tracking information:",
      "pos": [
        1013,
        1077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EDIFACT",
      "pos": [
        1094,
        1101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have created an instance of an EDIFACT API App, browse to that instance, and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tracking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1102,
        1208
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Herein you can view and filter all the EDIFACT tracking information.",
      "pos": [
        1209,
        1277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additionally, you can view the interchange level, group level, and transaction set level data, all in a single view.",
      "pos": [
        1278,
        1394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If batches are created as part of EDIFACT agreements in the associated Trading Partner Management API app, then the Batching section lists all these batches.",
      "pos": [
        1397,
        1554
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can select a batch to see the active message (if any) and also the information for the completed:",
      "pos": [
        1555,
        1656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X12",
      "pos": [
        1677,
        1680
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have created an instance of an X12 API App, browse to that instance, and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tracking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1681,
        1783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Herein you can view and filter all the X12 tracking information.",
      "pos": [
        1784,
        1848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additionally, you can view the interchange level, group level, and transaction set level data, all in a single view.",
      "pos": [
        1849,
        1965
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If batches are created as part of X12 agreements in the associated Trading Partner Management API app, then the Batching section lists all these batches.",
      "pos": [
        1967,
        2120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can select a batch to see the active message (if any) and also the information for the completed batches.",
      "pos": [
        2121,
        2230
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Track B2B messages in your logic apps in Azure App Service | Microsoft Azure\" \n   description=\"This topic covers tracking of B2B processing\" \n   services=\"app-service\\logic\" \n   documentationCenter=\".net,nodejs,java\" \n   authors=\"rajram\" \n   manager=\"dwrede\" \n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"app-service-logic\"\n   ms.devlang=\"multiple\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"integration\" \n   ms.date=\"12/07/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"rajram\"/>\n\n\n# Track B2B messages\n\n## B2B Tracking Information\nB2B communication involves message processing between trading partners. The relationships are defined as agreements between two trading partners. Once the communication is established, there needs to be a way to monitor if the communication is happening as expected. \n\nWe've implemented message tracking for the following B2B scenarios: AS2, EDIFACT, and X12.\n\n## AS2\nOnce you have created an instance of an AS2 API App, browse to that instance, and select **Tracking**. Herein you can view and filter all the AS2 tracking information:  \n\n![][1]  \n\n## EDIFACT\nOnce you have created an instance of an EDIFACT API App, browse to that instance, and select **Tracking**. Herein you can view and filter all the EDIFACT tracking information. Additionally, you can view the interchange level, group level, and transaction set level data, all in a single view. \n\nIf batches are created as part of EDIFACT agreements in the associated Trading Partner Management API app, then the Batching section lists all these batches. You can select a batch to see the active message (if any) and also the information for the completed:  \n\n![][2]      \n\n## X12\nOnce you have created an instance of an X12 API App, browse to that instance, and select **Tracking**. Herein you can view and filter all the X12 tracking information. Additionally, you can view the interchange level, group level, and transaction set level data, all in a single view.\n\nIf batches are created as part of X12 agreements in the associated Trading Partner Management API app, then the Batching section lists all these batches. You can select a batch to see the active message (if any) and also the information for the completed batches.\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/app-service-logic-track-b2b-messages/AS2Tracking.png\n[2]: ./media/app-service-logic-track-b2b-messages/EDIFACTTracking.png\n\n\n"
}