{"nodes":[{"pos":[17,19],"content":"na","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"na","pos":[0,2]}]},{"pos":[30,32],"content":"na","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"na","pos":[0,2]}]},{"pos":[40,107],"content":"FastTrack Center Benefit Process for Azure Active Directory Premium","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"FastTrack Center Benefit Process for Azure Active Directory Premium","pos":[0,67]}]},{"content":"FastTrack Center Benefit Process for Azure Active Directory Premium","pos":[231,298]},{"content":"If your organization is eligible for the FastTrack Center Benefit for Microsoft Azure AD Premium, you can work remotely with Microsoft specialists to get your Microsoft Azure AD Premium environment ready for use.","pos":[300,512]},{"content":"To learn whether your organization is eligible, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>FastTrack Center Benefit for Azure Active Directory Premium<ept id=\"p1\">](../Topic/FastTrack_Center_Benefit_for_Azure_Active_Directory_Premium.md)</ept>.","pos":[513,700],"source":" To learn whether your organization is eligible, see [FastTrack Center Benefit for Azure Active Directory Premium](../Topic/FastTrack_Center_Benefit_for_Azure_Active_Directory_Premium.md)."},{"content":"This article provides the following:","pos":[702,738]},{"content":"Overview of the onboarding process","pos":[745,779]},{"content":"Expectations for your source environment","pos":[798,838]},{"content":"Phases of the onboarding process","pos":[873,905]},{"pos":[940,1012],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft responsibilities<ept id=\"p1\">](#microsoft_responsibilities)</ept> for each phase","source":"[Microsoft responsibilities](#microsoft_responsibilities) for each phase"},{"pos":[1018,1080],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Your responsibilities<ept id=\"p1\">](#your_responsibilities)</ept> for each phase","source":"[Your responsibilities](#your_responsibilities) for each phase"},{"content":"Here’s what you can expect when onboarding is complete:","pos":[1082,1137]},{"content":"Your Microsoft Azure AD Premium  tenant is created.","pos":[1143,1194]},{"content":"Licensed users can access Microsoft Azure AD Premium services by using one of the following identity options:","pos":[1200,1309]},{"content":"Cloud Identities (unique Microsoft Azure AD Premium accounts).","pos":[1319,1381]},{"content":"Synchronized Identities: Microsoft Azure AD Premium accounts synchronized from your on-premises Active Directory with the Azure Active Directory Connect (Azure AD Connect)  tool for customers with a single forest or multiple Active Directory forests.","pos":[1391,1641]},{"content":"Federated Identities--with Microsoft Azure AD Premium accounts that are:","pos":[1651,1723]},{"content":"Synchronized from Active Directory with the Microsoft Azure AD Connect tool for customers with a single Active Directory forest configuration.","pos":[1737,1879]},{"content":"Federated with Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS) 2.0 or later from your on-premises Active Directory.","pos":[1893,2005]},{"pos":[2033,2067],"content":"Overview of the onboarding process"},{"content":"Onboarding has two major components:","pos":[2068,2104]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Core capabilities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - tasks required for tenant configuration and integration with Azure AD, if needed.","pos":[2110,2215],"source":"**Core capabilities** - tasks required for tenant configuration and integration with Azure AD, if needed."},{"content":"Core capabilities also provide the baseline for onboarding other Microsoft Online eligible services.","pos":[2216,2316]},{"pos":[2322,2473],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Service onboarding<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - tasks required to configure Microsoft Azure AD Premium standalone or with Azure AD Connect directory synchronization or AD FS.","source":"**Service onboarding** - tasks required to configure Microsoft Azure AD Premium standalone or with Azure AD Connect directory synchronization or AD FS."},{"content":"The following diagram describes the timeline for using the FastTrack Center benefit.","pos":[2475,2559]},{"content":"The basic process is as follows:","pos":[2605,2637]},{"content":"Microsoft will attempt to contact you within 30 days from the date you purchase an eligible plan.","pos":[2643,2740]},{"content":"You can also request assistance from the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>FastTrack Center<ept id=\"p1\">](http://fasttrack.microsoft.com/)</ept> if you are ready to deploy these services for your organization.","pos":[2741,2898],"source":" You can also request assistance from the [FastTrack Center](http://fasttrack.microsoft.com/) if you are ready to deploy these services for your organization."},{"content":"To request assistance, sign in to the FastTrack Center (http://fasttrack.microsoft.com), go to the dashboard, select your company name, click the Offers tab, and click the request assistance button for the eligible service.","pos":[2899,3122]},{"content":"Once onboarding support starts, we’ll set up a schedule of online meetings.","pos":[3123,3198]},{"content":"The Microsoft team will help you with core capabilities, and then will help you onboard once for each eligible service.","pos":[3204,3323]},{"content":"All onboarding support will be provided remotely by assigned Microsoft personnel:","pos":[3325,3406]},{"content":"Microsoft will remotely assist you with various onboarding activities by using a combination of tools, documentation, and guidance.","pos":[3412,3543]},{"content":"If you want Microsoft to do certain configuration tasks for you, you may choose to provide appropriate access and permissions to Microsoft for carrying out these tasks.","pos":[3544,3712]},{"content":"Onboarding support is provided by the FastTrack Center, and is available during normal business hours for a given region.","pos":[3718,3839]},{"content":"Onboarding support is available in Traditional Chinese, English, French, German, Italian, Japanese, Portuguese (Brazil), or Spanish.","pos":[3845,3977]},{"content":"The Microsoft team can work directly with you or your representative.","pos":[3983,4052]},{"pos":[4096,4136],"content":"Expectations for your source environment"},{"content":"You may already have Microsoft Active Directory on-premise in your source environment that you want to integrate with Microsoft Azure AD Premium for leveraging rich identity management from a single console.","pos":[4137,4344]},{"content":"The FastTrack Center benefit includes helping you integrate Microsoft Azure AD Premium with your existing on-prem implementation.","pos":[4345,4474]},{"content":"If integration is required, your source environment must be at a minimum level for that application.","pos":[4475,4575]},{"content":"The following table shows what is expected in your existing source environment for onboarding.","pos":[4577,4671]},{"content":"Activity","pos":[4674,4682]},{"content":"Source environment expectation","pos":[4683,4713]},{"content":"Core capabilities","pos":[4766,4783]},{"content":"Active Directory forests with the functional forest level set to Windows Server 2008 or above, with the following forest configuration:","pos":[4784,4919]},{"content":"-   Single Active Directory forest","pos":[4931,4965]},{"content":"-   Multiple Active Directory forests <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> For all multiple forests configurations, AD FS deployment is out of scope for the FastTrack Center Benefit.","pos":[4971,5126],"source":"-   Multiple Active Directory forests **Note:** For all multiple forests configurations, AD FS deployment is out of scope for the FastTrack Center Benefit."},{"content":"Service onboarding","pos":[5129,5147]},{"content":"-   Microsoft Azure AD Premium","pos":[5159,5189]},{"content":"On-premises Active Directory and environment have been prepared for Azure AD Premium, which includes remediation of identified issues that would prevent integration with Azure AD and Azure AD Premium features.","pos":[5190,5399]},{"pos":[5445,5477],"content":"Phases of the onboarding process"},{"content":"Microsoft Azure AD Premium onboarding has five primary phases, as shown in the following figure:","pos":[5478,5574]},{"content":"Initiate","pos":[5580,5588]},{"content":"Assess","pos":[5594,5600]},{"content":"Remediate","pos":[5606,5615]},{"content":"Enable","pos":[5621,5627]},{"pos":[5681,5844],"content":"For detailed tasks for each phase, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft responsibilities<ept id=\"p1\">](#microsoft_responsibilities)</ept> and  <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Your responsibilities<ept id=\"p2\">](#your_responsibilities)</ept> sections.","source":"For detailed tasks for each phase, see the [Microsoft responsibilities](#microsoft_responsibilities) and  [Your responsibilities](#your_responsibilities) sections."},{"content":"Initiate phase","pos":[5850,5864]},{"content":"After you have purchased the appropriate number of licenses, follow the guidance from the purchase confirmation email to associate the licenses to your existing tenant or new tenant.","pos":[5865,6047]},{"content":"Microsoft will verify your eligibility for the FastTrack Center Benefit.","pos":[6048,6120]},{"content":"Microsoft will attempt to contact you within 30 days from the date you purchase an eligible plan.","pos":[6121,6218]},{"content":"You can also request assistance from the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>FastTrack Center<ept id=\"p1\">](http://fasttrack.microsoft.com/)</ept> if you are ready to deploy these services for your organization.","pos":[6219,6376],"source":" You can also request assistance from the [FastTrack Center](http://fasttrack.microsoft.com/) if you are ready to deploy these services for your organization."},{"content":"To request assistance, sign in to the FastTrack Center (http://fasttrack.microsoft.com), go to the dashboard, select your company name, click the Offers tab, and click the request assistance button for the eligible service.","pos":[6377,6600]},{"content":"Once onboarding support starts, we’ll set up a schedule of online meetings.","pos":[6601,6676]},{"content":"During this phase, we’ll discuss the onboarding process, verify data, and set up a kick-off meeting.","pos":[6678,6778]},{"content":"Assess phase","pos":[6847,6859]},{"content":"Once the onboarding process begins, Microsoft will work with you to assess your source environment and the requirements.","pos":[6860,6980]},{"content":"Tools will be run to assess your environment, and Microsoft will guide you through assessing your on-premises Active Directory, Internet browsers, client devices' operating systems, DNS, network, infrastructure, and identity system to determine if any changes are required for onboarding.","pos":[6981,7269]},{"content":"Based on your current setup, we’ll provide a remediation plan that will bring your source environment up to the minimum requirements for successful onboarding to Microsoft Azure AD Premium.","pos":[7270,7459]},{"content":"We’ll also set up appropriate checkpoint calls for the remediation phase.","pos":[7460,7533]},{"content":"Remediate phase","pos":[7601,7616]},{"content":"If needed, you’ll do the tasks in the remediation plan on your source environment so that you meet the requirements for onboarding each service.","pos":[7617,7761]},{"content":"Before beginning the Enable phase, we’ll jointly verify the outcomes of the remediation activities to make sure you’re ready to proceed.","pos":[7827,7963]},{"content":"Enable phase","pos":[7969,7981]},{"content":"When all remediation activities are complete, the project shifts to configuring the core infrastructure for service consumption and to provisioning Microsoft Azure AD Premium.","pos":[7982,8157]},{"content":"Enable phase - Core capabilities","pos":[8161,8193]},{"content":"Enabling core capabilities involves service provisioning and tenant and identity integration.","pos":[8197,8290]},{"content":"It also includes steps for providing a foundation for onboarding Microsoft Azure AD Premium.","pos":[8291,8383]},{"content":"Onboarding for Microsoft Azure AD Premium can begin when core onboarding is finished.","pos":[8385,8470]},{"content":"Enable phase – Microsoft Azure AD Premium","pos":[8474,8515]},{"content":"The Microsoft Azure AD Premium environment can be set up with Azure AD Connect directory synchronization and Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS), as needed.","pos":[8519,8684]},{"content":"For Microsoft Azure AD Premium scenarios that include synchronizing on-premises identities to the cloud, we’ll help you by adding IT administrators and users to your subscription, configuring management prerequisites, setting up Microsoft Azure AD Premium, setting up directory synchronization using Azure AD Connect, and Active Directory Federation Services using Azure AD Connect, configuring test users and validating your core use cases for the service.","pos":[8686,9143]},{"content":"Microsoft Azure AD Premium setup includes enabling the following features:","pos":[9145,9219]},{"content":"Self Service Password Reset (SSPR)","pos":[9225,9259]},{"content":"Azure Multi-factor Authentication (MFA)","pos":[9265,9304]},{"content":"Software as a Service (SaaS) application--set up one SaaS application","pos":[9310,9379]},{"content":"Self-Service Group Management (SSGM)","pos":[9385,9421]},{"content":"Administrative reports","pos":[9427,9449]},{"pos":[9556,9582],"content":"Microsoft responsibilities"},{"content":"General","pos":[9588,9595]},{"content":"Provide remote support assistance to you for the required configuration activities, as described in the detailed phase descriptions.","pos":[9601,9733]},{"content":"Provide available documentation and software tools, admin consoles, and scripts to help you reduce or eliminate configuration tasks.","pos":[9739,9871]},{"content":"Providing access and permissions to Microsoft isn’t required to use the FastTrack Center benefit.","pos":[9873,9970]},{"content":"In some cases, you can choose to give Microsoft the appropriate access and permissions to perform specific activities on your behalf.","pos":[9971,10104]},{"content":"Initiate phase","pos":[10110,10124]},{"content":"Contact you within 30 days of the purchase of eligible licenses for a new tenant.","pos":[10130,10211]},{"content":"Work with you to begin onboarding within 90 days from purchase of eligible licenses.","pos":[10217,10301]},{"content":"Define which eligible services you want to onboard.","pos":[10307,10358]},{"content":"Assess phase","pos":[10364,10376]},{"content":"Provide an administrative overview.","pos":[10382,10417]},{"content":"Provide guidance with:","pos":[10423,10445]},{"content":"DNS, network, and infrastructure needs.","pos":[10455,10494]},{"content":"Client needs (Internet browser, client operating system, and services' needs).","pos":[10504,10582]},{"content":"User identity and provisioning.","pos":[10592,10623]},{"content":"Identification of Directory Synchronization requirements.","pos":[10633,10690]},{"content":"Determining if password hash sync meets customer goals, or if AD FS is required.","pos":[10700,10780]},{"content":"Enabling eligible services that have been purchased and defined to be part of the onboarding.","pos":[10790,10883]},{"content":"Identifying required piloting and test environment requirements, e.g., test accounts, test instance of SaaS application (e.g., SalesForce).","pos":[10893,11032]},{"content":"Establish the timeline for remediation activities.","pos":[11038,11088]},{"content":"Provide a remediation checklist.","pos":[11094,11126]},{"content":"Remediate phase","pos":[11132,11147]},{"content":"Hold conference calls with you according to the agreed-upon schedule to review the progress of the remediation activities.","pos":[11153,11275]},{"content":"Assist with running tools to identify and remediate issues, and with interpreting the results.","pos":[11281,11375]},{"content":"Enable phase","pos":[11381,11393]},{"content":"Provide guidance about:","pos":[11394,11417]},{"content":"Activating your Microsoft Azure AD Premium tenant.","pos":[11423,11473]},{"content":"Configuring firewall ports.","pos":[11479,11506]},{"content":"Configuring DNS for eligible services.","pos":[11512,11550]},{"content":"Validating connectivity to Microsoft Azure AD Premium services.","pos":[11556,11619]},{"content":"For a single-forest environment:","pos":[11625,11657]},{"content":"Installing a directory synchronization between your Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and Azure AD Connect, if required.","pos":[11667,11794]},{"content":"Configuring password synchronization with the Azure AD Connect tool.","pos":[11804,11872]},{"content":"For a multiple forest environment:","pos":[11878,11912]},{"content":"Install Azure AD Connect synchronization, set up for multiple forest scenarios.","pos":[11922,12001]},{"content":"Note that password hash sync and password writeback support multiple forest.","pos":[12002,12078]},{"content":"However, other writeback scenarios are not supported.","pos":[12080,12133]},{"content":"Configure synchronization between on-premises Active Directory forests and Microsoft Azure AD Premium directory (Azure Active Directory).","pos":[12143,12280]},{"pos":[12292,12386],"content":"[!NOTE]\nDevelopment and implementation for custom rules extensions are out of scope.","leadings":["","        > "],"nodes":[{"content":"Development and implementation for custom rules extensions are out of scope.","pos":[8,84]}]},{"content":"For a single forest when the target is federated identities: Installing and configuring Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS) for local domain authentication with Microsoft Azure AD Premium in a single-site, fault-tolerant configuration, if required.","pos":[12392,12649]},{"pos":[12657,12746],"content":"[!NOTE]\nFor all multiple forest configurations, AD FS deployments are out of scope.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"For all multiple forest configurations, AD FS deployments are out of scope.","pos":[8,83]}]},{"content":"Testing single sign-on (SSO) functionality, if deployed.","pos":[12752,12808]},{"content":"Enable phase - Azure AD Premium--with Azure AD Connect and AD FS","pos":[12815,12879]},{"content":"Provide guidance about setting up:","pos":[12880,12914]},{"content":"User provisioning, including licensing.","pos":[12920,12959]},{"content":"Azure AD Connect directory synchronization (with password writeback and password hash sync).","pos":[12965,13057]},{"content":"Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS).","pos":[13063,13108]},{"content":"Self-Service Password Reset (SSPR).","pos":[13114,13149]},{"content":"Azure Multi-factor Authentication (MFA).","pos":[13155,13195]},{"content":"One integrated application, which can include Single Sign-On for SaaS applications.","pos":[13201,13284]},{"content":"Usage and security reports to administrators.","pos":[13290,13335]},{"content":"Self Service Group Management (SSGM).","pos":[13341,13378]},{"content":"Application proxy.","pos":[13384,13402]},{"content":"Administrator notifications.","pos":[13408,13436]},{"content":"Customized logon screen, including logo, text and images.","pos":[13442,13499]},{"pos":[13540,13561],"content":"Your responsibilities"},{"content":"This section describes some of your responsibilities during the onboarding process.","pos":[13562,13645]},{"content":"General","pos":[13651,13658]},{"content":"Any enhancements and integrations to your Microsoft Azure AD Premium tenant beyond the configurable options listed in this article.","pos":[13664,13795]},{"content":"Overall program and project management of your resources.","pos":[13801,13858]},{"content":"End-user communications, documentation, training, and change management.","pos":[13864,13936]},{"content":"Helpdesk documentation and training.","pos":[13942,13978]},{"content":"Producing any reports, presentations, or meeting minutes that are specific to your organization.","pos":[13984,14080]},{"content":"Creating architectural and technical documentation specific to your organization.","pos":[14086,14167]},{"content":"Designing, procuring, installing, and configuring hardware and networking.","pos":[14173,14247]},{"content":"Procuring, installing, and configuring software.","pos":[14253,14301]},{"content":"Managing, configuring, and applying security policies beyond those created for testing your Microsoft Azure AD Premium services baseline configuration and functionality.","pos":[14307,14476]},{"content":"Enrolling user accounts beyond those used to test the Microsoft Azure AD Premium services baseline configuration and functionality.","pos":[14482,14613]},{"content":"Network configuration, analysis, bandwidth validation, testing, and monitoring.","pos":[14619,14698]},{"content":"Managing a technical change management approval process and creating supporting documentation.","pos":[14704,14798]},{"content":"Modifying your operational model and operation guides.","pos":[14804,14858]},{"content":"Setting up on-premise multifactor authentication.","pos":[14864,14913]},{"content":"Decommissioning and removing source environments and services previously used by the customer.","pos":[14919,15013]},{"content":"Constructing and maintaining your test environment.","pos":[15019,15070]},{"content":"Installing service packs and other required updates on infrastructure servers.","pos":[15076,15154]},{"content":"Providing and configuring any public SSL certificates.","pos":[15160,15214]},{"content":"Writing the organization’s Terms of Use (TOU) statement to be configured and displayed on devices owned by end users.","pos":[15220,15337]},{"content":"Initiate phase","pos":[15343,15357]},{"content":"Work with the Microsoft team to begin onboarding of eligible services.","pos":[15363,15433]},{"content":"Participate in the engagement kick-off meeting, manage and lead participants from your organization, and confirm remediation timelines.","pos":[15439,15574]},{"content":"Assess phase","pos":[15580,15592]},{"content":"Identify appropriate stakeholders (including a project manager) to complete the necessary assessment activities.","pos":[15598,15710]},{"content":"If you choose to, share your screen with Microsoft if guidance is needed when running evaluation tools against your environment or your Microsoft Azure AD Premium subscription.","pos":[15716,15892]},{"content":"Participate in the meetings to create the remediation checklist and to contribute to the overall plan, including infrastructure, network, administration, directory synchronization preparation, network security, and federated identity topics.","pos":[15898,16139]},{"content":"Participate in the meetings to outline the user-provisioning approach.","pos":[16145,16215]},{"content":"Participate in the meetings to plan online service configuration.","pos":[16221,16286]},{"content":"Create a support plan for migration readiness.","pos":[16292,16338]},{"content":"Remediate phase","pos":[16344,16359]},{"content":"Perform required steps to complete remediation activities identified in the Assess phase.","pos":[16365,16454]},{"content":"Participate in checkpoint meetings.","pos":[16460,16495]},{"content":"Enable phase","pos":[16501,16513]},{"content":"If you choose to, share your screen with Microsoft if guidance is needed when making changes to your environment or to your Microsoft Azure AD Premium subscription.","pos":[16519,16683]},{"content":"Manage resources as appropriate.","pos":[16689,16721]},{"content":"Configure network-related items per guidance from Microsoft.","pos":[16727,16787]},{"content":"Perform directory readiness and configure directory synchronization per guidance from Microsoft.","pos":[16793,16889]},{"content":"Configure security-related infrastructure (such as firewall ports) per guidance from Microsoft.","pos":[16895,16990]},{"content":"Implement the appropriate client infrastructure.","pos":[16996,17044]},{"content":"Implement a user-provisioning approach per guidance from Microsoft.","pos":[17050,17117]},{"content":"Enable various services per guidance from Microsoft.","pos":[17123,17175]},{"content":"Want to learn more?","pos":[17180,17199]},{"pos":[17200,17439],"content":"See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Azure Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/services/active-directory/)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Enterprise Mobility Suite<ept id=\"p2\">](http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/enterprise-mobility-suite/default.aspx)</ept>.","source":"See [Microsoft Azure Active Directory](http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/services/active-directory/) and [Enterprise Mobility Suite](http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/enterprise-mobility-suite/default.aspx)."}],"content":"---\ndescription: na\nkeywords: na\ntitle: FastTrack Center Benefit Process for Azure Active Directory Premium \nsearch: na\nms.date: 2015-11-25\nms.tgt_pltfrm: na\nms.topic: article\nms.assetid: f1e8d94d-ce42-4d4c-a25b-0f28b93a9e10\n---\n# FastTrack Center Benefit Process for Azure Active Directory Premium \nIf your organization is eligible for the FastTrack Center Benefit for Microsoft Azure AD Premium, you can work remotely with Microsoft specialists to get your Microsoft Azure AD Premium environment ready for use. To learn whether your organization is eligible, see [FastTrack Center Benefit for Azure Active Directory Premium](../Topic/FastTrack_Center_Benefit_for_Azure_Active_Directory_Premium.md).\n\nThis article provides the following:\n\n-   [Overview of the onboarding process](#overview)\n\n-   [Expectations for your source environment](#expectations_src_environ)\n\n-   [Phases of the onboarding process](#phases_onboarding_process)\n\n-   [Microsoft responsibilities](#microsoft_responsibilities) for each phase\n\n-   [Your responsibilities](#your_responsibilities) for each phase\n\nHere’s what you can expect when onboarding is complete:\n\n-   Your Microsoft Azure AD Premium  tenant is created.\n\n-   Licensed users can access Microsoft Azure AD Premium services by using one of the following identity options:\n\n    -   Cloud Identities (unique Microsoft Azure AD Premium accounts).\n\n    -   Synchronized Identities: Microsoft Azure AD Premium accounts synchronized from your on-premises Active Directory with the Azure Active Directory Connect (Azure AD Connect)  tool for customers with a single forest or multiple Active Directory forests.\n\n    -   Federated Identities--with Microsoft Azure AD Premium accounts that are:\n\n        -   Synchronized from Active Directory with the Microsoft Azure AD Connect tool for customers with a single Active Directory forest configuration.\n\n        -   Federated with Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS) 2.0 or later from your on-premises Active Directory.\n\n## <a name=\"overview\"></a>Overview of the onboarding process\nOnboarding has two major components:\n\n-   **Core capabilities** - tasks required for tenant configuration and integration with Azure AD, if needed. Core capabilities also provide the baseline for onboarding other Microsoft Online eligible services.\n\n-   **Service onboarding** - tasks required to configure Microsoft Azure AD Premium standalone or with Azure AD Connect directory synchronization or AD FS.\n\nThe following diagram describes the timeline for using the FastTrack Center benefit.\n\n![](../Image/1-rms_onboarding_process.png)\n\nThe basic process is as follows:\n\n-   Microsoft will attempt to contact you within 30 days from the date you purchase an eligible plan. You can also request assistance from the [FastTrack Center](http://fasttrack.microsoft.com/) if you are ready to deploy these services for your organization. To request assistance, sign in to the FastTrack Center (http://fasttrack.microsoft.com), go to the dashboard, select your company name, click the Offers tab, and click the request assistance button for the eligible service. Once onboarding support starts, we’ll set up a schedule of online meetings.\n\n-   The Microsoft team will help you with core capabilities, and then will help you onboard once for each eligible service.\n\nAll onboarding support will be provided remotely by assigned Microsoft personnel:\n\n-   Microsoft will remotely assist you with various onboarding activities by using a combination of tools, documentation, and guidance. If you want Microsoft to do certain configuration tasks for you, you may choose to provide appropriate access and permissions to Microsoft for carrying out these tasks.\n\n-   Onboarding support is provided by the FastTrack Center, and is available during normal business hours for a given region.\n\n-   Onboarding support is available in Traditional Chinese, English, French, German, Italian, Japanese, Portuguese (Brazil), or Spanish.\n\n-   The Microsoft team can work directly with you or your representative.\n\n## <a name=\"expectations_src_environ\"></a>Expectations for your source environment\nYou may already have Microsoft Active Directory on-premise in your source environment that you want to integrate with Microsoft Azure AD Premium for leveraging rich identity management from a single console. The FastTrack Center benefit includes helping you integrate Microsoft Azure AD Premium with your existing on-prem implementation. If integration is required, your source environment must be at a minimum level for that application.\n\nThe following table shows what is expected in your existing source environment for onboarding.\n\n|Activity|Source environment expectation|\n|------------|----------------------------------|\n|Core capabilities|Active Directory forests with the functional forest level set to Windows Server 2008 or above, with the following forest configuration:<br /><br />-   Single Active Directory forest<br />-   Multiple Active Directory forests **Note:** For all multiple forests configurations, AD FS deployment is out of scope for the FastTrack Center Benefit.|\n|Service onboarding<br /><br />-   Microsoft Azure AD Premium|On-premises Active Directory and environment have been prepared for Azure AD Premium, which includes remediation of identified issues that would prevent integration with Azure AD and Azure AD Premium features.|\n\n## <a name=\"phases_onboarding_process\"></a>Phases of the onboarding process\nMicrosoft Azure AD Premium onboarding has five primary phases, as shown in the following figure:\n\n-   Initiate\n\n-   Assess\n\n-   Remediate\n\n-   Enable\n\n![](../Image/Intune_onboarding_phases_9-15-15.png)\n\nFor detailed tasks for each phase, see the [Microsoft responsibilities](#microsoft_responsibilities) and  [Your responsibilities](#your_responsibilities) sections.\n\n### Initiate phase\nAfter you have purchased the appropriate number of licenses, follow the guidance from the purchase confirmation email to associate the licenses to your existing tenant or new tenant. Microsoft will verify your eligibility for the FastTrack Center Benefit. Microsoft will attempt to contact you within 30 days from the date you purchase an eligible plan. You can also request assistance from the [FastTrack Center](http://fasttrack.microsoft.com/) if you are ready to deploy these services for your organization. To request assistance, sign in to the FastTrack Center (http://fasttrack.microsoft.com), go to the dashboard, select your company name, click the Offers tab, and click the request assistance button for the eligible service. Once onboarding support starts, we’ll set up a schedule of online meetings.\n\nDuring this phase, we’ll discuss the onboarding process, verify data, and set up a kick-off meeting.\n\n![](../Image/Microsoft_Azure_AD_Premium_initiate_phase_1.png)\n\n### Assess phase\nOnce the onboarding process begins, Microsoft will work with you to assess your source environment and the requirements. Tools will be run to assess your environment, and Microsoft will guide you through assessing your on-premises Active Directory, Internet browsers, client devices' operating systems, DNS, network, infrastructure, and identity system to determine if any changes are required for onboarding. Based on your current setup, we’ll provide a remediation plan that will bring your source environment up to the minimum requirements for successful onboarding to Microsoft Azure AD Premium. We’ll also set up appropriate checkpoint calls for the remediation phase.\n\n![](../Image/Microsoft_Azure_AD_Premium_assess_phase_v6.png)\n\n### Remediate phase\nIf needed, you’ll do the tasks in the remediation plan on your source environment so that you meet the requirements for onboarding each service.\n\n![](../Image/Microsoft_Azure_AD_Premium_remediate_phase_1.png)\n\nBefore beginning the Enable phase, we’ll jointly verify the outcomes of the remediation activities to make sure you’re ready to proceed.\n\n### Enable phase\nWhen all remediation activities are complete, the project shifts to configuring the core infrastructure for service consumption and to provisioning Microsoft Azure AD Premium.\n\n**Enable phase - Core capabilities**\n\nEnabling core capabilities involves service provisioning and tenant and identity integration. It also includes steps for providing a foundation for onboarding Microsoft Azure AD Premium.\n\nOnboarding for Microsoft Azure AD Premium can begin when core onboarding is finished.\n\n**Enable phase – Microsoft Azure AD Premium**\n\nThe Microsoft Azure AD Premium environment can be set up with Azure AD Connect directory synchronization and Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS), as needed.\n\nFor Microsoft Azure AD Premium scenarios that include synchronizing on-premises identities to the cloud, we’ll help you by adding IT administrators and users to your subscription, configuring management prerequisites, setting up Microsoft Azure AD Premium, setting up directory synchronization using Azure AD Connect, and Active Directory Federation Services using Azure AD Connect, configuring test users and validating your core use cases for the service.\n\nMicrosoft Azure AD Premium setup includes enabling the following features:\n\n-   Self Service Password Reset (SSPR)\n\n-   Azure Multi-factor Authentication (MFA)\n\n-   Software as a Service (SaaS) application--set up one SaaS application\n\n-   Self-Service Group Management (SSGM)\n\n-   Administrative reports\n\n![](../Image/Microsoft_Azure_AD_Premium_enable_phase_2.png)\n\n## <a name=\"microsoft_responsibilities\"></a>Microsoft responsibilities\n\n### General\n\n-   Provide remote support assistance to you for the required configuration activities, as described in the detailed phase descriptions.\n\n-   Provide available documentation and software tools, admin consoles, and scripts to help you reduce or eliminate configuration tasks.\n\nProviding access and permissions to Microsoft isn’t required to use the FastTrack Center benefit. In some cases, you can choose to give Microsoft the appropriate access and permissions to perform specific activities on your behalf.\n\n### Initiate phase\n\n-   Contact you within 30 days of the purchase of eligible licenses for a new tenant.\n\n-   Work with you to begin onboarding within 90 days from purchase of eligible licenses.\n\n-   Define which eligible services you want to onboard.\n\n### Assess phase\n\n-   Provide an administrative overview.\n\n-   Provide guidance with:\n\n    -   DNS, network, and infrastructure needs.\n\n    -   Client needs (Internet browser, client operating system, and services' needs).\n\n    -   User identity and provisioning.\n\n    -   Identification of Directory Synchronization requirements.\n\n    -   Determining if password hash sync meets customer goals, or if AD FS is required.\n\n    -   Enabling eligible services that have been purchased and defined to be part of the onboarding.\n\n    -   Identifying required piloting and test environment requirements, e.g., test accounts, test instance of SaaS application (e.g., SalesForce).\n\n-   Establish the timeline for remediation activities.\n\n-   Provide a remediation checklist.\n\n### Remediate phase\n\n-   Hold conference calls with you according to the agreed-upon schedule to review the progress of the remediation activities.\n\n-   Assist with running tools to identify and remediate issues, and with interpreting the results.\n\n### Enable phase\nProvide guidance about:\n\n-   Activating your Microsoft Azure AD Premium tenant.\n\n-   Configuring firewall ports.\n\n-   Configuring DNS for eligible services.\n\n-   Validating connectivity to Microsoft Azure AD Premium services.\n\n-   For a single-forest environment:\n\n    -   Installing a directory synchronization between your Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and Azure AD Connect, if required.\n\n    -   Configuring password synchronization with the Azure AD Connect tool.\n\n-   For a multiple forest environment:\n\n    -   Install Azure AD Connect synchronization, set up for multiple forest scenarios. Note that password hash sync and password writeback support multiple forest.  However, other writeback scenarios are not supported.\n\n    -   Configure synchronization between on-premises Active Directory forests and Microsoft Azure AD Premium directory (Azure Active Directory).\n\n        > [!NOTE]\n        > Development and implementation for custom rules extensions are out of scope.\n\n-   For a single forest when the target is federated identities: Installing and configuring Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS) for local domain authentication with Microsoft Azure AD Premium in a single-site, fault-tolerant configuration, if required.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > For all multiple forest configurations, AD FS deployments are out of scope.\n\n-   Testing single sign-on (SSO) functionality, if deployed.\n\n#### Enable phase - Azure AD Premium--with Azure AD Connect and AD FS\nProvide guidance about setting up:\n\n-   User provisioning, including licensing.\n\n-   Azure AD Connect directory synchronization (with password writeback and password hash sync).\n\n-   Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS).\n\n-   Self-Service Password Reset (SSPR).\n\n-   Azure Multi-factor Authentication (MFA).\n\n-   One integrated application, which can include Single Sign-On for SaaS applications.\n\n-   Usage and security reports to administrators.\n\n-   Self Service Group Management (SSGM).\n\n-   Application proxy.\n\n-   Administrator notifications.\n\n-   Customized logon screen, including logo, text and images.\n\n## <a name=\"your_responsibilities\"></a>Your responsibilities\nThis section describes some of your responsibilities during the onboarding process.\n\n### General\n\n-   Any enhancements and integrations to your Microsoft Azure AD Premium tenant beyond the configurable options listed in this article.\n\n-   Overall program and project management of your resources.\n\n-   End-user communications, documentation, training, and change management.\n\n-   Helpdesk documentation and training.\n\n-   Producing any reports, presentations, or meeting minutes that are specific to your organization.\n\n-   Creating architectural and technical documentation specific to your organization.\n\n-   Designing, procuring, installing, and configuring hardware and networking.\n\n-   Procuring, installing, and configuring software.\n\n-   Managing, configuring, and applying security policies beyond those created for testing your Microsoft Azure AD Premium services baseline configuration and functionality.\n\n-   Enrolling user accounts beyond those used to test the Microsoft Azure AD Premium services baseline configuration and functionality.\n\n-   Network configuration, analysis, bandwidth validation, testing, and monitoring.\n\n-   Managing a technical change management approval process and creating supporting documentation.\n\n-   Modifying your operational model and operation guides.\n\n-   Setting up on-premise multifactor authentication.\n\n-   Decommissioning and removing source environments and services previously used by the customer.\n\n-   Constructing and maintaining your test environment.\n\n-   Installing service packs and other required updates on infrastructure servers.\n\n-   Providing and configuring any public SSL certificates.\n\n-   Writing the organization’s Terms of Use (TOU) statement to be configured and displayed on devices owned by end users.\n\n### Initiate phase\n\n-   Work with the Microsoft team to begin onboarding of eligible services.\n\n-   Participate in the engagement kick-off meeting, manage and lead participants from your organization, and confirm remediation timelines.\n\n### Assess phase\n\n-   Identify appropriate stakeholders (including a project manager) to complete the necessary assessment activities.\n\n-   If you choose to, share your screen with Microsoft if guidance is needed when running evaluation tools against your environment or your Microsoft Azure AD Premium subscription.\n\n-   Participate in the meetings to create the remediation checklist and to contribute to the overall plan, including infrastructure, network, administration, directory synchronization preparation, network security, and federated identity topics.\n\n-   Participate in the meetings to outline the user-provisioning approach.\n\n-   Participate in the meetings to plan online service configuration.\n\n-   Create a support plan for migration readiness.\n\n### Remediate phase\n\n-   Perform required steps to complete remediation activities identified in the Assess phase.\n\n-   Participate in checkpoint meetings.\n\n### Enable phase\n\n-   If you choose to, share your screen with Microsoft if guidance is needed when making changes to your environment or to your Microsoft Azure AD Premium subscription.\n\n-   Manage resources as appropriate.\n\n-   Configure network-related items per guidance from Microsoft.\n\n-   Perform directory readiness and configure directory synchronization per guidance from Microsoft.\n\n-   Configure security-related infrastructure (such as firewall ports) per guidance from Microsoft.\n\n-   Implement the appropriate client infrastructure.\n\n-   Implement a user-provisioning approach per guidance from Microsoft.\n\n-   Enable various services per guidance from Microsoft.\n\n## Want to learn more?\nSee [Microsoft Azure Active Directory](http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/services/active-directory/) and [Enterprise Mobility Suite](http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/enterprise-mobility-suite/default.aspx).\n\n"}