{"nodes":[{"content":"Back up a Windows server or client to Azure | Microsoft Azure","pos":[27,88]},{"content":"Backup Windows servers or clients to Azure by creating a backup vault, downloading credentials, installing the backup agent, and completing an initial backup of your files and folders.","pos":[107,291]},{"content":"Back up a Windows server or client to Azure","pos":[687,730]},{"content":"This article covers the procedures that you need to follow to prepare your environment and back up a Windows server (or client) to Azure.","pos":[731,868]},{"content":"It also covers considerations for deploying your backup solution.","pos":[869,934]},{"content":"If you're interested in trying Azure Backup for the first time, this article quickly walks you through the process.","pos":[935,1050]},{"content":"Create vault","pos":[1054,1066]},{"content":"Before you start","pos":[1131,1147]},{"content":"To back up a server or client to Azure, you need an Azure account.","pos":[1148,1214]},{"content":"If you don't have one, you can create a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>free account<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/free/)</ept> in just a couple of minutes.","pos":[1215,1333]},{"content":"Step 1: Create a backup vault","pos":[1338,1367]},{"content":"To back up files and folders from a server or client, you need to create a backup vault in the geographic region where you want to store the data.","pos":[1368,1514]},{"content":"To create a backup vault","pos":[1520,1544]},{"pos":[1549,1612],"content":"Sign in to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>the Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://manage.windowsazure.com/)</ept>"},{"pos":[1618,1728],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> &gt; </ph><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Data Services<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph2\"> &gt; </ph><bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph3\"> &gt; </ph><bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Backup Vault<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, and then choose <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Quick Create<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>"},{"content":"For the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter, enter a friendly name for the backup vault.","pos":[1734,1805]},{"content":"Type a name that contains between 2 and 50 characters.","pos":[1806,1860]},{"content":"It must start with a letter, and can contain only letters, numbers, and hyphens.","pos":[1861,1941]},{"content":"This name needs to be unique for each subscription.","pos":[1942,1993]},{"content":"For the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Region<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter, select the geographic region for the backup vault.","pos":[1998,2078]},{"content":"This choice determines the geographic region where your backup data is sent.","pos":[2079,2155]},{"content":"By choosing a geographic region that's close to your location, you can reduce network latency when backing up to Azure.","pos":[2156,2275]},{"pos":[2280,2302],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create Vault<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"content":"Create a backup vault","pos":[2311,2332]},{"content":"It can take a while for the backup vault to be created.","pos":[2391,2446]},{"content":"To check the status, monitor the notifications at the bottom of the portal.","pos":[2447,2522]},{"content":"After the backup vault has been created, you'll see a message saying that the vault has been successfully created.","pos":[2528,2642]},{"content":"It also appears as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> resource list.","pos":[2643,2716]},{"content":"Creating vault status","pos":[2724,2745]},{"content":"Select the storage redundancy option by following the steps described here.","pos":[2818,2893]},{"content":"The best time to identify your storage redundancy option is right after vault creation and before any machines are registered to the vault.","pos":[2918,3057]},{"content":"After an item has been registered to the vault, the storage redundancy option is locked and cannot be modified.","pos":[3058,3169]},{"pos":[3175,3419],"content":"If you are using Azure as a primary backup storage endpoint (for example, you are backing up to Azure from a Windows server), consider picking (the default) <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>geo-redundant storage<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-redundancy.md#geo-redundant-storage)</ept> option."},{"content":"If you are using Azure as a tertiary backup storage endpoint (for example, you are using System Center Data Protection Manager to store a local backup copy on-premises and using Azure for long-term retention needs), consider choosing <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>locally redundant storage<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-redundancy.md#locally-redundant-storage)</ept>.","pos":[3425,3747]},{"content":"This brings down the cost of storing data in Azure, while providing a lower level of durability for your data that might be acceptable for tertiary copies.","pos":[3748,3903]},{"content":"To select the storage redundancy option:","pos":[3911,3951]},{"content":"a.","pos":[3959,3961]},{"content":"Click the vault you just created.","pos":[3962,3995]},{"content":"b.","pos":[4001,4003]},{"content":"On the Quick Start page, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[4004,4049]},{"content":"Configure vault status","pos":[4058,4080]},{"content":"c.","pos":[4139,4141]},{"content":"Choose the appropriate storage redundancy option.","pos":[4142,4191]},{"pos":[4197,4311],"content":"If you select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Locally Redundant<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you need to click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> (because <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Geo-Redundant<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> is the default option)."},{"content":"d.","pos":[4317,4319]},{"content":"In the left navigation pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to return to the list of resources for Recovery Services.","pos":[4320,4434]},{"content":"Step 2: Download the vault credential file","pos":[4439,4481]},{"content":"The on-premises machine needs to be authenticated with a backup vault before it can back up data to Azure.","pos":[4482,4588]},{"content":"The authentication is achieved through <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>vault credentials<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[4589,4648]},{"content":"The vault credential file is downloaded through a secure channel from the Azure portal.","pos":[4649,4736]},{"content":"The certificate private key does not persist in the portal or the service.","pos":[4737,4811]},{"pos":[4813,4969],"content":"Learn more about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>using vault credentials to authenticate with the Backup service<ept id=\"p1\">](backup-introduction-to-azure-backup.md#what-is-the-vault-credential-file)</ept>"},{"content":"To download the vault credential file to a local machine","pos":[4976,5032]},{"pos":[5037,5145],"content":"In the left navigation pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then select the backup vault that you created."},{"content":"IR complete","pos":[5153,5164]},{"pos":[5219,5280],"content":"On the Quick Start page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download vault credentials<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"content":"The portal generates a vault credential by using a combination of the vault name and the current date.","pos":[5287,5389]},{"content":"The vault credentials file is used only during the registration workflow and expires after 48 hours.","pos":[5390,5490]},{"content":"The vault credential file can be downloaded from the portal.","pos":[5496,5556]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to download the vault credential file to the Downloads folder of the local account.","pos":[5561,5659]},{"content":"You can also select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save As<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> menu to specify a location for the vault credential file.","pos":[5660,5767]},{"content":"Make sure the vault credential file is saved in a location that can be accessed from your machine.","pos":[5787,5885]},{"content":"If it is stored in a file share or server message block, verify that you have the permissions to access it.","pos":[5886,5993]},{"content":"Step 3: Download, install, and register the Backup agent","pos":[5998,6054]},{"content":"After you create the backup vault and download the vault credential file, an agent must be installed on each of your Windows machines.","pos":[6055,6189]},{"content":"To download, install, and register the agent","pos":[6195,6239]},{"pos":[6244,6346],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then select the backup vault that you want to register with a server."},{"content":"On the Quick Start page, click the agent <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Agent for Windows Server or System Center Data Protection Manager or Windows client<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[6351,6480]},{"content":"Then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[6481,6500]},{"content":"Save agent","pos":[6509,6519]},{"pos":[6567,6704],"content":"After the MARSagentinstaller.exe file has downloaded, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Run<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (or double-click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>MARSAgentInstaller.exe<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> from the saved location)."},{"content":"Choose the installation folder and cache folder that are required for the agent, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[6709,6814]},{"content":"The cache location you specify must have free space equal to at least 5 percent of the backup data.","pos":[6815,6914]},{"content":"You can continue to connect to the Internet through the default proxy settings.","pos":[6919,6998]},{"content":"If you use a proxy server to connect to the Internet, on the Proxy Configuration page, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use custom proxy settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check box, and then enter the proxy server details.","pos":[7008,7187]},{"content":"If you use an authenticated proxy, enter the user name and password details, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[7188,7288]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Install<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to begin the agent installation.","pos":[7294,7344]},{"content":"The Backup agent installs .NET Framework 4.5 and Windows PowerShell (if it’s not already installed) to complete the installation.","pos":[7345,7474]},{"pos":[7479,7573],"content":"After the agent is installed, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Proceed to Registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to continue with the workflow."},{"content":"On the Vault Identification page, browse to and select the vault credential file that you previously downloaded.","pos":[7578,7690]},{"content":"The vault credential file is valid for only 48 hours after it’s downloaded from the portal.","pos":[7696,7787]},{"content":"If you encounter an error on this page (such as “Vault credentials file provided has expired”), sign in to the portal and download the vault credential file again.","pos":[7788,7951]},{"content":"Ensure that the vault credential file is available in a location that can be accessed by the setup application.","pos":[7957,8068]},{"content":"If you encounter access-related errors, copy the vault credential file to a temporary location on the same machine and retry the operation.","pos":[8069,8208]},{"content":"If you encounter a vault credential error such as “Invalid vault credentials provided,\" the file is damaged or does not have the latest credentials associated with the recovery service.","pos":[8214,8399]},{"content":"Retry the operation after downloading a new vault credential file from the portal.","pos":[8400,8482]},{"content":"This error can also occur if a user clicks the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download vault credential<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option several times in quick succession.","pos":[8483,8601]},{"content":"In this case, only the last vault credential file is valid.","pos":[8602,8661]},{"content":"On the Encryption Setting page, you can either generate a passphrase or provide a passphrase (with a minimum of 16 characters).","pos":[8666,8793]},{"content":"Remember to save the passphrase in a secure location.","pos":[8794,8847]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Finish<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[8853,8870]},{"content":"The Register Server Wizard registers the server with Backup.","pos":[8871,8931]},{"content":"If you lose or forget the passphrase, Microsoft cannot help you recover the backup data.","pos":[8956,9044]},{"content":"You own the encryption passphrase, and Microsoft does not have visibility into the passphrase that you use.","pos":[9045,9152]},{"content":"Save the file in a secure location because it will be required during a recovery operation.","pos":[9153,9244]},{"pos":[9250,9388],"content":"After the encryption key is set, leave the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Launch Microsoft Azure Recovery Services Agent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check box selected, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Close<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>"},{"content":"Step 4: Complete the initial backup","pos":[9394,9429]},{"content":"The initial backup includes two key tasks:","pos":[9431,9473]},{"content":"Creating the backup schedule","pos":[9477,9505]},{"content":"Backing up files and folders for the first time","pos":[9508,9555]},{"content":"After the backup policy completes the initial backup, it creates backup points that you can use if you need to recover the data.","pos":[9557,9685]},{"content":"The backup policy does this based on the schedule that you define.","pos":[9686,9752]},{"content":"To schedule the backup","pos":[9758,9780]},{"content":"Open the Microsoft Azure Backup agent.","pos":[9785,9823]},{"content":"(It will open automatically if you left the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Launch Microsoft Azure Recovery Services Agent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check box selected when you closed the Register Server Wizard.) You can find it by searching your machine for <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Microsoft Azure Backup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>","pos":[9824,10055]},{"content":"Launch the Azure Backup agent","pos":[10064,10093]},{"pos":[10150,10196],"content":"In the Backup agent, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Schedule Backup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"content":"Schedule a Windows Server backup","pos":[10205,10237]},{"pos":[10301,10374],"content":"On the Getting started page of the Schedule Backup Wizard, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"pos":[10380,10435],"content":"On the Select Items to Backup page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add Items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"pos":[10441,10519],"content":"Select the files and folders that you want to back up, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Okay<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"pos":[10525,10539],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"pos":[10545,10636],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify Backup Schedule<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, specify the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>backup schedule<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>"},{"content":"You can schedule daily (at a maximum rate of three times per day) or weekly backups.","pos":[10643,10727]},{"content":"Items for Windows Server Backup","pos":[10735,10766]},{"pos":[10853,11024],"content":"For more information about how to specify the backup schedule, see the article <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Use Azure Backup to replace your tape infrastructure<ept id=\"p1\">](backup-azure-backup-cloud-as-tape.md)</ept>"},{"pos":[11030,11123],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select Retention Policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Retention Policy<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> for the backup copy."},{"content":"The retention policy specifies the duration for which the backup will be stored.","pos":[11129,11209]},{"content":"Rather than just specifying a “flat policy” for all backup points, you can specify different retention policies based on when the backup occurs.","pos":[11210,11354]},{"content":"You can modify the daily, weekly, monthly, and yearly retention policies to meet your needs.","pos":[11355,11447]},{"content":"On the Choose Initial Backup Type page, choose the initial backup type.","pos":[11452,11523]},{"content":"Leave the option <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Automatically over the network<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> selected, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>","pos":[11524,11609]},{"content":"You can back up automatically over the network, or you can back up offline.","pos":[11616,11691]},{"content":"The remainder of this article describes the process for backing up automatically.","pos":[11692,11773]},{"content":"If you prefer to do an offline backup, review the article <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Offline backup workflow in Azure Backup<ept id=\"p1\">](backup-azure-backup-import-export.md)</ept> for additional information.","pos":[11774,11939]},{"pos":[11945,12020],"content":"On the Confirmation page, review the information, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Finish<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"pos":[12027,12098],"content":"After the wizard finishes creating the backup schedule, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Close<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"content":"Enable network throttling (optional)","pos":[12105,12141]},{"content":"The Backup agent provides network throttling.","pos":[12143,12188]},{"content":"Throttling controls how network bandwidth is used during data transfer.","pos":[12189,12260]},{"content":"This control can be helpful if you need to back up data during work hours but do not want the backup process to interfere with other Internet traffic.","pos":[12261,12411]},{"content":"Throttling applies to back up and restore activities.","pos":[12412,12465]},{"content":"To enable network throttling","pos":[12469,12497]},{"pos":[12504,12552],"content":"In the Backup agent, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change Properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"content":"Change properties","pos":[12561,12578]},{"pos":[12638,12755],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Throttling<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, select the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Enable internet bandwidth usage throttling for backup operations<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> check box."},{"content":"Network throttling","pos":[12763,12781]},{"pos":[12841,12975],"content":"After you have enabled throttling, specify the allowed bandwidth for backup data transfer during <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Work hours<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Non-work hours<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>"},{"content":"The bandwidth values begin at 512 kilobytes per second (KBps) and can go up to 1,023 megabytes per second (MBps).","pos":[12982,13095]},{"content":"You can also designate the start and finish for <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Work hours<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and which days of the week are considered work days.","pos":[13096,13212]},{"content":"Hours outside of designated work hours are considered non-work hours.","pos":[13213,13282]},{"pos":[13287,13299],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"},{"content":"To back up now","pos":[13306,13320]},{"pos":[13325,13417],"content":"In the Backup agent, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Back Up Now<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to complete the initial seeding over the network."},{"content":"Windows Server backup now","pos":[13425,13450]},{"content":"On the Confirmation page, review the settings that the Back Up Now Wizard will use to back up the machine.","pos":[13503,13609]},{"content":"Then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Back Up<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[13610,13632]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Close<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to close the wizard.","pos":[13638,13674]},{"content":"If you do this before the backup process finishes, the wizard continues to run in the background.","pos":[13675,13772]},{"pos":[13774,13872],"content":"After the initial backup is completed, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job completed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status appears in the Backup console."},{"content":"IR complete","pos":[13876,13887]},{"content":"Next steps","pos":[13940,13950]},{"pos":[13953,14022],"content":"Sign up for a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>free Azure account<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/free/)</ept>"},{"content":"For additional information about backing up VMs or other workloads, see:","pos":[14025,14097]},{"content":"Back up IaaS VMs","pos":[14102,14118]},{"content":"Back up workloads to Azure with Microsoft Azure Backup Server","pos":[14152,14213]},{"content":"Back up workloads to Azure with DPM","pos":[14258,14293]}],"content":"<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Back up a Windows server or client to Azure | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Backup Windows servers or clients to Azure by creating a backup vault, downloading credentials, installing the backup agent, and completing an initial backup of your files and folders.\"\n    services=\"backup\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"Jim-Parker\"\n    manager=\"jwhit\"\n    editor=\"\"\n    keywords=\"backup vault; back up a Windows server; backup windows;\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"backup\"\n    ms.workload=\"storage-backup-recovery\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"03/19/2016\"\n    ms.author=\"jimpark; trinadhk; markgal\"/>\n\n\n# Back up a Windows server or client to Azure\nThis article covers the procedures that you need to follow to prepare your environment and back up a Windows server (or client) to Azure. It also covers considerations for deploying your backup solution. If you're interested in trying Azure Backup for the first time, this article quickly walks you through the process.\n\n![Create vault](./media/backup-configure-vault/initial-backup-process.png)\n\n## Before you start\nTo back up a server or client to Azure, you need an Azure account. If you don't have one, you can create a [free account](https://azure.microsoft.com/free/) in just a couple of minutes.\n\n## Step 1: Create a backup vault\nTo back up files and folders from a server or client, you need to create a backup vault in the geographic region where you want to store the data.\n\n### To create a backup vault\n\n1. Sign in to [the Azure portal](https://manage.windowsazure.com/).\n\n2. Click **New** > **Data Services** > **Recovery Services** > **Backup Vault**, and then choose **Quick Create**.\n\n3. For the **Name** parameter, enter a friendly name for the backup vault. Type a name that contains between 2 and 50 characters. It must start with a letter, and can contain only letters, numbers, and hyphens. This name needs to be unique for each subscription.\n\n4. For the **Region** parameter, select the geographic region for the backup vault. This choice determines the geographic region where your backup data is sent. By choosing a geographic region that's close to your location, you can reduce network latency when backing up to Azure.\n\n5. Click **Create Vault**.\n\n    ![Create a backup vault](./media/backup-configure-vault/demo-vault-name.png)\n\n    It can take a while for the backup vault to be created. To check the status, monitor the notifications at the bottom of the portal.\n\n    After the backup vault has been created, you'll see a message saying that the vault has been successfully created. It also appears as **Active** in the **Recovery Services** resource list.\n\n    ![Creating vault status](./media/backup-configure-vault/recovery-services-select-vault.png)\n\n4. Select the storage redundancy option by following the steps described here.\n\n    >[AZURE.IMPORTANT] The best time to identify your storage redundancy option is right after vault creation and before any machines are registered to the vault. After an item has been registered to the vault, the storage redundancy option is locked and cannot be modified.\n\n    If you are using Azure as a primary backup storage endpoint (for example, you are backing up to Azure from a Windows server), consider picking (the default) [geo-redundant storage](../storage/storage-redundancy.md#geo-redundant-storage) option.\n\n    If you are using Azure as a tertiary backup storage endpoint (for example, you are using System Center Data Protection Manager to store a local backup copy on-premises and using Azure for long-term retention needs), consider choosing [locally redundant storage](../storage/storage-redundancy.md#locally-redundant-storage). This brings down the cost of storing data in Azure, while providing a lower level of durability for your data that might be acceptable for tertiary copies.\n\n    **To select the storage redundancy option:**\n\n    a. Click the vault you just created.\n\n    b. On the Quick Start page, select **Configure**.\n\n    ![Configure vault status](./media/backup-configure-vault/configure-vault.png)\n\n    c. Choose the appropriate storage redundancy option.\n\n    If you select **Locally Redundant**, you need to click **Save** (because **Geo-Redundant** is the default option).\n\n    d. In the left navigation pane, click **Recovery Services** to return to the list of resources for Recovery Services.\n\n## Step 2: Download the vault credential file\nThe on-premises machine needs to be authenticated with a backup vault before it can back up data to Azure. The authentication is achieved through *vault credentials*. The vault credential file is downloaded through a secure channel from the Azure portal. The certificate private key does not persist in the portal or the service.\n\nLearn more about [using vault credentials to authenticate with the Backup service](backup-introduction-to-azure-backup.md#what-is-the-vault-credential-file).\n\n### To download the vault credential file to a local machine\n\n1. In the left navigation pane, click **Recovery Services**, and then select the backup vault that you created.\n\n    ![IR complete](./media/backup-configure-vault/rs-left-nav.png)\n\n2.  On the Quick Start page, click **Download vault credentials**.\n\n    The portal generates a vault credential by using a combination of the vault name and the current date. The vault credentials file is used only during the registration workflow and expires after 48 hours.\n\n    The vault credential file can be downloaded from the portal.\n\n3. Click **Save** to download the vault credential file to the Downloads folder of the local account. You can also select **Save As** from the **Save** menu to specify a location for the vault credential file.\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] Make sure the vault credential file is saved in a location that can be accessed from your machine. If it is stored in a file share or server message block, verify that you have the permissions to access it.\n\n## Step 3: Download, install, and register the Backup agent\nAfter you create the backup vault and download the vault credential file, an agent must be installed on each of your Windows machines.\n\n### To download, install, and register the agent\n\n1. Click **Recovery Services**, and then select the backup vault that you want to register with a server.\n\n2. On the Quick Start page, click the agent **Agent for Windows Server or System Center Data Protection Manager or Windows client**. Then click **Save**.\n\n    ![Save agent](./media/backup-configure-vault/agent.png)\n\n3. After the MARSagentinstaller.exe file has downloaded, click **Run** (or double-click **MARSAgentInstaller.exe** from the saved location).\n\n4. Choose the installation folder and cache folder that are required for the agent, and then click **Next**. The cache location you specify must have free space equal to at least 5 percent of the backup data.\n\n5. You can continue to connect to the Internet through the default proxy settings.          If you use a proxy server to connect to the Internet, on the Proxy Configuration page, select the **Use custom proxy settings** check box, and then enter the proxy server details. If you use an authenticated proxy, enter the user name and password details, and then click **Next**.\n\n7. Click **Install** to begin the agent installation. The Backup agent installs .NET Framework 4.5 and Windows PowerShell (if it’s not already installed) to complete the installation.\n\n8. After the agent is installed, click **Proceed to Registration** to continue with the workflow.\n\n9. On the Vault Identification page, browse to and select the vault credential file that you previously downloaded.\n\n    The vault credential file is valid for only 48 hours after it’s downloaded from the portal. If you encounter an error on this page (such as “Vault credentials file provided has expired”), sign in to the portal and download the vault credential file again.\n\n    Ensure that the vault credential file is available in a location that can be accessed by the setup application. If you encounter access-related errors, copy the vault credential file to a temporary location on the same machine and retry the operation.\n\n    If you encounter a vault credential error such as “Invalid vault credentials provided,\" the file is damaged or does not have the latest credentials associated with the recovery service. Retry the operation after downloading a new vault credential file from the portal. This error can also occur if a user clicks the **Download vault credential** option several times in quick succession. In this case, only the last vault credential file is valid.\n\n9. On the Encryption Setting page, you can either generate a passphrase or provide a passphrase (with a minimum of 16 characters). Remember to save the passphrase in a secure location.\n\n10. Click **Finish**. The Register Server Wizard registers the server with Backup.\n\n\n    > [AZURE.WARNING] If you lose or forget the passphrase, Microsoft cannot help you recover the backup data. You own the encryption passphrase, and Microsoft does not have visibility into the passphrase that you use. Save the file in a secure location because it will be required during a recovery operation.\n\n11. After the encryption key is set, leave the **Launch Microsoft Azure Recovery Services Agent** check box selected, and then click **Close**.\n\n## Step 4: Complete the initial backup\n\nThe initial backup includes two key tasks:\n\n- Creating the backup schedule\n- Backing up files and folders for the first time\n\nAfter the backup policy completes the initial backup, it creates backup points that you can use if you need to recover the data. The backup policy does this based on the schedule that you define.\n\n### To schedule the backup\n\n1. Open the Microsoft Azure Backup agent. (It will open automatically if you left the **Launch Microsoft Azure Recovery Services Agent** check box selected when you closed the Register Server Wizard.) You can find it by searching your machine for **Microsoft Azure Backup**.\n\n    ![Launch the Azure Backup agent](./media/backup-configure-vault/snap-in-search.png)\n\n2. In the Backup agent, click **Schedule Backup**.\n\n    ![Schedule a Windows Server backup](./media/backup-configure-vault/schedule-backup-close.png)\n\n3. On the Getting started page of the Schedule Backup Wizard, click **Next**.\n\n4. On the Select Items to Backup page, click **Add Items**.\n\n5. Select the files and folders that you want to back up, and then click **Okay**.\n\n6. Click **Next**.\n\n7. On the **Specify Backup Schedule** page, specify the **backup schedule** and click **Next**.\n\n    You can schedule daily (at a maximum rate of three times per day) or weekly backups.\n\n    ![Items for Windows Server Backup](./media/backup-configure-vault/specify-backup-schedule-close.png)\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] For more information about how to specify the backup schedule, see the article [Use Azure Backup to replace your tape infrastructure](backup-azure-backup-cloud-as-tape.md).\n\n8. On the **Select Retention Policy** page, select the **Retention Policy** for the backup copy.\n\n    The retention policy specifies the duration for which the backup will be stored. Rather than just specifying a “flat policy” for all backup points, you can specify different retention policies based on when the backup occurs. You can modify the daily, weekly, monthly, and yearly retention policies to meet your needs.\n\n9. On the Choose Initial Backup Type page, choose the initial backup type. Leave the option **Automatically over the network** selected, and then click **Next**.\n\n    You can back up automatically over the network, or you can back up offline. The remainder of this article describes the process for backing up automatically. If you prefer to do an offline backup, review the article [Offline backup workflow in Azure Backup](backup-azure-backup-import-export.md) for additional information.\n\n10. On the Confirmation page, review the information, and then click **Finish**.\n\n11. After the wizard finishes creating the backup schedule, click **Close**.\n\n### Enable network throttling (optional)\n\nThe Backup agent provides network throttling. Throttling controls how network bandwidth is used during data transfer. This control can be helpful if you need to back up data during work hours but do not want the backup process to interfere with other Internet traffic. Throttling applies to back up and restore activities.\n\n**To enable network throttling**\n\n1. In the Backup agent, click **Change Properties**.\n\n    ![Change properties](./media/backup-configure-vault/change-properties.png)\n\n2. On the **Throttling** tab, select the **Enable internet bandwidth usage throttling for backup operations** check box.\n\n    ![Network throttling](./media/backup-configure-vault/throttling-dialog.png)\n\n3. After you have enabled throttling, specify the allowed bandwidth for backup data transfer during **Work hours** and **Non-work hours**.\n\n    The bandwidth values begin at 512 kilobytes per second (KBps) and can go up to 1,023 megabytes per second (MBps). You can also designate the start and finish for **Work hours**, and which days of the week are considered work days. Hours outside of designated work hours are considered non-work hours.\n\n4. Click **OK**.\n\n### To back up now\n\n1. In the Backup agent, click **Back Up Now** to complete the initial seeding over the network.\n\n    ![Windows Server backup now](./media/backup-configure-vault/backup-now.png)\n\n2. On the Confirmation page, review the settings that the Back Up Now Wizard will use to back up the machine. Then click **Back Up**.\n\n3. Click **Close** to close the wizard. If you do this before the backup process finishes, the wizard continues to run in the background.\n\nAfter the initial backup is completed, the **Job completed** status appears in the Backup console.\n\n![IR complete](./media/backup-configure-vault/ircomplete.png)\n\n## Next steps\n- Sign up for a [free Azure account](https://azure.microsoft.com/free/).\n\nFor additional information about backing up VMs or other workloads, see:\n\n- [Back up IaaS VMs](backup-azure-vms-prepare.md)\n- [Back up workloads to Azure with Microsoft Azure Backup Server](backup-azure-microsoft-azure-backup.md)\n- [Back up workloads to Azure with DPM](backup-azure-dpm-introduction.md)\n"}