{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        27,
        107
      ],
      "content": "Consume a Machine Learning web service with a web app template | Microsoft Azure"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        126,
        232
      ],
      "content": "Use a web app template in Azure Marketplace to consume a predictive web service in Azure Machine Learning."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        638,
        707
      ],
      "content": "Consume an Azure Machine Learning web service with a web app template"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        709,
        859
      ],
      "content": "Once you've developed your predictive model and deployed it as an Azure web service using Machine Learning Studio, or using tools such as R or Python,"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        860,
        918
      ],
      "content": "you can access the operationalized model using a REST API."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        920,
        1348
      ],
      "content": "There are a number of ways to consume the REST API and access the web service. For example, you can write an application in C#, R, or Python using the sample code generated for you when you deployed the web service (available on the API Help Page in the web service dashboard in Machine Learning Studio). Or you can use the sample Microsoft Excel workbook created for you (also available in the web service dashboard in Studio).",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "There are a number of ways to consume the REST API and access the web service.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            78
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For example, you can write an application in C#, R, or Python using the sample code generated for you when you deployed the web service (available on the API Help Page in the web service dashboard in Machine Learning Studio).",
          "pos": [
            79,
            304
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Or you can use the sample Microsoft Excel workbook created for you (also available in the web service dashboard in Studio).",
          "pos": [
            305,
            428
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1350,
        1551
      ],
      "content": "But the quickest and easiest way to access your web service is through the Web App Templates available in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Web App Marketplace<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/web-applications/all/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1650,
        1694
      ],
      "content": "The Azure Machine Learning Web App Templates"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1696,
        1950
      ],
      "content": "The web app templates available in the Azure Marketplace can build a custom web app that knows your web service's input data and expected results. All you need to do is give the web app access to your web service and data, and the template does the rest.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The web app templates available in the Azure Marketplace can build a custom web app that knows your web service's input data and expected results.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            146
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "All you need to do is give the web app access to your web service and data, and the template does the rest.",
          "pos": [
            147,
            254
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1952,
        1980
      ],
      "content": "Two templates are available:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1984,
        2125
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure ML Request-Response Service Web App Template<ept id=\"p2\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/partners/microsoft/azuremlaspnettemplateforrrs/)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2128,
        2265
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Azure ML Batch Execution Service Web App Template<ept id=\"p3\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/partners/microsoft/azuremlbeswebapptemplate/)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2267,
        2683
      ],
      "content": "Each template creates a sample ASP.NET application, using the API URI and Key for your web service, and deploys it as a web site to Azure. The Request-Response Service (RRS) template creates a web app that allows you to send a single row of data to the web service to get a single result. The Batch Execution Service (BES) template creates a web app that allows you to send many rows of data to get multiple results.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Each template creates a sample ASP.NET application, using the API URI and Key for your web service, and deploys it as a web site to Azure.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            138
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The Request-Response Service (RRS) template creates a web app that allows you to send a single row of data to the web service to get a single result.",
          "pos": [
            139,
            288
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The Batch Execution Service (BES) template creates a web app that allows you to send many rows of data to get multiple results.",
          "pos": [
            289,
            416
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2685,
        2815
      ],
      "content": "No coding is required to use these templates. You just supply the API URI and Key and the template builds the application for you.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "No coding is required to use these templates.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            45
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You just supply the API URI and Key and the template builds the application for you.",
          "pos": [
            46,
            130
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2820,
        2874
      ],
      "content": "How to use the Request-Response Service (RRS) template"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2876,
        3013
      ],
      "content": "Once you've deployed your web service, you can follow the steps below to use the RRS web app template, as shown in the following diagram."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3015,
        3057
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph3\">![</ph>Process to use RRS web template<ph id=\"ph4\">][image1]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3062,
        3220
      ],
      "content": "In Machine Learning Studio, open the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Web Services<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph5\"/> tab and then open the web service you want to access. Copy the key listed under <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>API key<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph6\"/> and save it.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "In Machine Learning Studio, open the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Web Services<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph5\"/> tab and then open the web service you want to access.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            159
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Copy the key listed under <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>API key<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph6\"/> and save it.",
          "pos": [
            160,
            262
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3226,
        3244
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph7\">![</ph>API Key<ph id=\"ph8\">][image3]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3249,
        3417
      ],
      "content": "Open the <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>REQUEST/RESPONSE<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> API Help Page. At the top of the help page, under <bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>Request<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept>, copy the <bpt id=\"p8\">**</bpt>Request URI<ept id=\"p8\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph10\"/> value and save it. This value will look like this:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Open the <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>REQUEST/RESPONSE<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> API Help Page.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            96
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "At the top of the help page, under <bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>Request<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept>, copy the <bpt id=\"p8\">**</bpt>Request URI<ept id=\"p8\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph10\"/> value and save it.",
          "pos": [
            97,
            279
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This value will look like this:",
          "pos": [
            280,
            311
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3561,
        3583
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph11\">![</ph>Request URI<ph id=\"ph12\">][image4]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3588,
        3757
      ],
      "content": "Go to the <bpt id=\"p9\">[</bpt>Azure portal<ept id=\"p9\">](https://portal.azure.com)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p10\">**</bpt>Login<ept id=\"p10\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p11\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p11\">**</ept>, Search for and select <bpt id=\"p12\">**</bpt>Azure ML Request-Response Service Web App<ept id=\"p12\">**</ept>, then click <bpt id=\"p13\">**</bpt>Create<ept id=\"p13\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3766,
        3928
      ],
      "content": "Give your web app a unique name. The URL of the web app will be this name followed by <ph id=\"ph13\">`.azurewebsites.net.`</ph><ph id=\"ph14\"/> For example, <ph id=\"ph15\">`http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net.`</ph>",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Give your web app a unique name.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            32
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The URL of the web app will be this name followed by <ph id=\"ph13\">`.azurewebsites.net.`</ph><ph id=\"ph14\"/> For example, <ph id=\"ph15\">`http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net.`</ph>",
          "pos": [
            33,
            215
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3936,
        4019
      ],
      "content": "Select the Azure subscription and services under which your web service is running."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4027,
        4044
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p14\">**</bpt>Create<ept id=\"p14\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4050,
        4075
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph16\">![</ph>Create web app<ph id=\"ph17\">][image5]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4080,
        4273
      ],
      "content": "When Azure has finished deploying the web app, click the <bpt id=\"p15\">**</bpt>URL<ept id=\"p15\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph18\"/> on the web app settings page in Azure, or enter the URL in a web browser. For example, <ph id=\"ph19\">`http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net.`</ph>",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "When Azure has finished deploying the web app, click the <bpt id=\"p15\">**</bpt>URL<ept id=\"p15\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph18\"/> on the web app settings page in Azure, or enter the URL in a web browser.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            193
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For example, <ph id=\"ph19\">`http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net.`</ph>",
          "pos": [
            194,
            267
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4278,
        4399
      ],
      "content": "When the web app first runs it will ask you for the <bpt id=\"p16\">**</bpt>API Post URL<ept id=\"p16\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph20\"/> and <bpt id=\"p17\">**</bpt>API Key<ept id=\"p17\">**</ept>.\nEnter the values you saved earlier:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "When the web app first runs it will ask you for the <bpt id=\"p16\">**</bpt>API Post URL<ept id=\"p16\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph20\"/> and <bpt id=\"p17\">**</bpt>API Key<ept id=\"p17\">**</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            180
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Enter the values you saved earlier:",
          "pos": [
            181,
            216
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4406,
        4465
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p18\">**</bpt>Request URI<ept id=\"p18\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph21\"/> from the API Help Page for <bpt id=\"p19\">**</bpt>API Post URL<ept id=\"p19\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4472,
        4535
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p20\">**</bpt>API Key<ept id=\"p20\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph22\"/> from the web service dashboard for the <bpt id=\"p21\">**</bpt>API Key<ept id=\"p21\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4541,
        4558
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p22\">**</bpt>Submit<ept id=\"p22\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4564,
        4601
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph23\">![</ph>Enter Post URI and API Key<ph id=\"ph24\">][image6]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4606,
        4763
      ],
      "content": "The web app displays its <bpt id=\"p23\">**</bpt>Web App Configuration<ept id=\"p23\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph25\"/> page with the current web service settings. Here you can make changes to the settings used by the web app.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The web app displays its <bpt id=\"p23\">**</bpt>Web App Configuration<ept id=\"p23\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph25\"/> page with the current web service settings.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            149
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Here you can make changes to the settings used by the web app.",
          "pos": [
            150,
            212
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4771,
        5055
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph26\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph27\"/> Changing the settings here only changes them for this web app. It doesn't change the default settings of your web service. For example, if you change the <bpt id=\"p24\">**</bpt>Description<ept id=\"p24\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph28\"/> here it doesn't change the description shown on the web service dashboard in Machine Learning Studio.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph26\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph27\"/> Changing the settings here only changes them for this web app.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            109
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "It doesn't change the default settings of your web service.",
          "pos": [
            110,
            169
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For example, if you change the <bpt id=\"p24\">**</bpt>Description<ept id=\"p24\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph28\"/> here it doesn't change the description shown on the web service dashboard in Machine Learning Studio.",
          "pos": [
            170,
            373
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5061,
        5138
      ],
      "content": "When you're done, click <bpt id=\"p25\">**</bpt>Save changes<ept id=\"p25\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p26\">**</bpt>Go to Home Page<ept id=\"p26\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5143,
        5262
      ],
      "content": "From the home page you can enter values to send to your web service, click <bpt id=\"p27\">**</bpt>Submit<ept id=\"p27\">**</ept>, and the result will be returned."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5264,
        5538
      ],
      "content": "If you want to return to the <bpt id=\"p28\">**</bpt>Configuration<ept id=\"p28\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph29\"/> page, go to the <ph id=\"ph30\">`setting.aspx`</ph><ph id=\"ph31\"/> page of the web app. For example: <ph id=\"ph32\">`http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net/setting.aspx.`</ph><ph id=\"ph33\"/> You will be prompted to enter the API key again - you need that to access the page and update the settings.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "If you want to return to the <bpt id=\"p28\">**</bpt>Configuration<ept id=\"p28\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph29\"/> page, go to the <ph id=\"ph30\">`setting.aspx`</ph><ph id=\"ph31\"/> page of the web app.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            187
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For example: <ph id=\"ph32\">`http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net/setting.aspx.`</ph><ph id=\"ph33\"/> You will be prompted to enter the API key again - you need that to access the page and update the settings.",
          "pos": [
            188,
            397
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5540,
        5714
      ],
      "content": "You can stop, restart, or delete the web app in the Azure portal like any other web app. As long as it is running you can browse to the home web address and enter new values.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "You can stop, restart, or delete the web app in the Azure portal like any other web app.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            88
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "As long as it is running you can browse to the home web address and enter new values.",
          "pos": [
            89,
            174
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5719,
        5772
      ],
      "content": "How to use the Batch Execution Service (BES) template"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5774,
        5963
      ],
      "content": "You can use the BES web app template in the same way as the RRS template, except that the web app that's created will allow you to submit multiple rows of data and receive multiple results."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5965,
        6116
      ],
      "content": "The results from a batch execution web service are stored in an Azure storage container; the input values can come from Azure storage or a local file.\n",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The results from a batch execution web service are stored in an Azure storage container; the input values can come from Azure storage or a local file.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            150
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "\n",
          "pos": [
            150,
            151
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6116,
        6249
      ],
      "content": "So, you'll need an Azure storage container to hold the results returned by the web app, and you'll need to get your input data ready."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6251,
        6293
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph34\">![</ph>Process to use BES web template<ph id=\"ph35\">][image2]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6298,
        6382
      ],
      "content": "Follow the same procedure to create the BES web app as for the RRS template, except:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6389,
        6476
      ],
      "content": "Get the <bpt id=\"p29\">**</bpt>Request URI<ept id=\"p29\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph36\"/> from the <bpt id=\"p30\">**</bpt>BATCH EXECUTION<ept id=\"p30\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph37\"/> API Help Page for the web service."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6483,
        6702
      ],
      "content": "Go to <bpt id=\"p31\">[</bpt>Azure ML Batch Execution Service Web App Template<ept id=\"p31\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/partners/microsoft/azuremlbeswebapptemplate/)</ept><ph id=\"ph38\"/> to open the BES template on Azure Marketplace and click <bpt id=\"p32\">**</bpt>Create Web App<ept id=\"p32\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6707,
        6951
      ],
      "content": "To specify where you want the results stored, enter the destination container information on the web app home page. Also specify where the web app can get the input values, either in a local file or an Azure storage container.\nClick <bpt id=\"p33\">**</bpt>Submit<ept id=\"p33\">**</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "To specify where you want the results stored, enter the destination container information on the web app home page.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            115
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Also specify where the web app can get the input values, either in a local file or an Azure storage container.",
          "pos": [
            116,
            226
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p33\">**</bpt>Submit<ept id=\"p33\">**</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            227,
            284
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6957,
        6987
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph39\">![</ph>Storage information<ph id=\"ph40\">][image7]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6989,
        7038
      ],
      "content": "The web app will display a page with job status.\n",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The web app will display a page with job status.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            48
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "\n",
          "pos": [
            48,
            49
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7038,
        7200
      ],
      "content": "When the job has completed you'll be given the location of the results in Azure blob storage. You also have the option of downloading the results to a local file.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "When the job has completed you'll be given the location of the results in Azure blob storage.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            93
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You also have the option of downloading the results to a local file.",
          "pos": [
            94,
            162
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7205,
        7225
      ],
      "content": "For more information"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7227,
        7249
      ],
      "content": "To learn more about..."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7253,
        7428
      ],
      "content": "creating a machine learning experiment with Machine Learning Studio, see <bpt id=\"p34\">[</bpt>Create your first experiment in Azure Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p34\">](machine-learning-create-experiment.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7432,
        7607
      ],
      "content": "how to deploy your machine learning experiment as a web service, see <bpt id=\"p35\">[</bpt>Deploy an Azure Machine Learning web service<ept id=\"p35\">](machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7611,
        7750
      ],
      "content": "other ways to access your web service, see <bpt id=\"p36\">[</bpt>How to consume an Azure Machine Learning web service<ept id=\"p36\">](machine-learning-consume-web-services.md)</ept>"
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Consume a Machine Learning web service with a web app template | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Use a web app template in Azure Marketplace to consume a predictive web service in Azure Machine Learning.\"\n    keywords=\"web service,operationalization,REST API,machine learning\"\n    services=\"machine-learning\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"garyericson\"\n    manager=\"paulettm\"\n    editor=\"cgronlun\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\"\n    ms.workload=\"data-services\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"02/03/2016\"\n    ms.author=\"garye;raymondl\"/>\n\n# Consume an Azure Machine Learning web service with a web app template\n\nOnce you've developed your predictive model and deployed it as an Azure web service using Machine Learning Studio, or using tools such as R or Python,\nyou can access the operationalized model using a REST API.\n\nThere are a number of ways to consume the REST API and access the web service. For example, you can write an application in C#, R, or Python using the sample code generated for you when you deployed the web service (available on the API Help Page in the web service dashboard in Machine Learning Studio). Or you can use the sample Microsoft Excel workbook created for you (also available in the web service dashboard in Studio).\n\nBut the quickest and easiest way to access your web service is through the Web App Templates available in the [Azure Web App Marketplace](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/web-applications/all/).\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [machine-learning-free-trial](../../includes/machine-learning-free-trial.md)]\n\n## The Azure Machine Learning Web App Templates\n\nThe web app templates available in the Azure Marketplace can build a custom web app that knows your web service's input data and expected results. All you need to do is give the web app access to your web service and data, and the template does the rest.\n\nTwo templates are available:\n\n- [Azure ML Request-Response Service Web App Template](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/partners/microsoft/azuremlaspnettemplateforrrs/)\n- [Azure ML Batch Execution Service Web App Template](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/partners/microsoft/azuremlbeswebapptemplate/)\n\nEach template creates a sample ASP.NET application, using the API URI and Key for your web service, and deploys it as a web site to Azure. The Request-Response Service (RRS) template creates a web app that allows you to send a single row of data to the web service to get a single result. The Batch Execution Service (BES) template creates a web app that allows you to send many rows of data to get multiple results.\n\nNo coding is required to use these templates. You just supply the API URI and Key and the template builds the application for you.\n\n## How to use the Request-Response Service (RRS) template\n\nOnce you've deployed your web service, you can follow the steps below to use the RRS web app template, as shown in the following diagram.\n\n![Process to use RRS web template][image1]\n\n1. In Machine Learning Studio, open the **Web Services** tab and then open the web service you want to access. Copy the key listed under **API key** and save it.\n\n    ![API Key][image3]\n\n2. Open the **REQUEST/RESPONSE** API Help Page. At the top of the help page, under **Request**, copy the **Request URI** value and save it. This value will look like this:\n\n        https://ussouthcentral.services.azureml.net/workspaces/<workspace-id>/services/<service-id>/execute?api-version=2.0&details=true\n\n    ![Request URI][image4]\n\n3. Go to the [Azure portal](https://portal.azure.com), **Login**, click **New**, Search for and select **Azure ML Request-Response Service Web App**, then click **Create**. \n\n    - Give your web app a unique name. The URL of the web app will be this name followed by `.azurewebsites.net.` For example, `http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net.`\n\n    - Select the Azure subscription and services under which your web service is running.\n\n    - Click **Create**.\n\n    ![Create web app][image5]\n\n4. When Azure has finished deploying the web app, click the **URL** on the web app settings page in Azure, or enter the URL in a web browser. For example, `http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net.`\n\n5. When the web app first runs it will ask you for the **API Post URL** and **API Key**.\nEnter the values you saved earlier:\n    - **Request URI** from the API Help Page for **API Post URL**\n    - **API Key** from the web service dashboard for the **API Key**.\n\n    Click **Submit**.\n\n    ![Enter Post URI and API Key][image6]\n\n6. The web app displays its **Web App Configuration** page with the current web service settings. Here you can make changes to the settings used by the web app.\n\n    > [AZURE.NOTE] Changing the settings here only changes them for this web app. It doesn't change the default settings of your web service. For example, if you change the **Description** here it doesn't change the description shown on the web service dashboard in Machine Learning Studio.\n\n    When you're done, click **Save changes**, and then click **Go to Home Page**.\n\n7. From the home page you can enter values to send to your web service, click **Submit**, and the result will be returned.\n\nIf you want to return to the **Configuration** page, go to the `setting.aspx` page of the web app. For example: `http://carprediction.azurewebsites.net/setting.aspx.` You will be prompted to enter the API key again - you need that to access the page and update the settings.\n\nYou can stop, restart, or delete the web app in the Azure portal like any other web app. As long as it is running you can browse to the home web address and enter new values.\n\n## How to use the Batch Execution Service (BES) template\n\nYou can use the BES web app template in the same way as the RRS template, except that the web app that's created will allow you to submit multiple rows of data and receive multiple results.\n\nThe results from a batch execution web service are stored in an Azure storage container; the input values can come from Azure storage or a local file.\nSo, you'll need an Azure storage container to hold the results returned by the web app, and you'll need to get your input data ready.\n\n![Process to use BES web template][image2]\n\n1. Follow the same procedure to create the BES web app as for the RRS template, except:\n    - Get the **Request URI** from the **BATCH EXECUTION** API Help Page for the web service.\n    - Go to [Azure ML Batch Execution Service Web App Template](https://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/partners/microsoft/azuremlbeswebapptemplate/) to open the BES template on Azure Marketplace and click **Create Web App**.\n\n2. To specify where you want the results stored, enter the destination container information on the web app home page. Also specify where the web app can get the input values, either in a local file or an Azure storage container.\nClick **Submit**.\n\n    ![Storage information][image7]\n\nThe web app will display a page with job status.\nWhen the job has completed you'll be given the location of the results in Azure blob storage. You also have the option of downloading the results to a local file.\n\n## For more information\n\nTo learn more about...\n\n- creating a machine learning experiment with Machine Learning Studio, see [Create your first experiment in Azure Machine Learning Studio](machine-learning-create-experiment.md)\n\n- how to deploy your machine learning experiment as a web service, see [Deploy an Azure Machine Learning web service](machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service.md)\n\n- other ways to access your web service, see [How to consume an Azure Machine Learning web service](machine-learning-consume-web-services.md)\n\n\n[image1]: media\\machine-learning-consume-web-service-with-web-app-template\\rrs-web-template-flow.png\n[image2]: media\\machine-learning-consume-web-service-with-web-app-template\\bes-web-template-flow.png\n[image3]: media\\machine-learning-consume-web-service-with-web-app-template\\api-key.png\n[image4]: media\\machine-learning-consume-web-service-with-web-app-template\\post-uri.png\n[image5]: media\\machine-learning-consume-web-service-with-web-app-template\\create-web-app.png\n[image6]: media\\machine-learning-consume-web-service-with-web-app-template\\web-service-info.png\n[image7]: media\\machine-learning-consume-web-service-with-web-app-template\\storage.png\n"
}