{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        0,
        577
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;properties\n    pageTitle=\"</ph>How to use multiple clients with a single mobile service backend | Azure Mobile Services<ph id=\"ph2\">\"\n    description=\"</ph>Learn how to use a single mobile service back-end from multiple client apps that target different mobile platforms.<ph id=\"ph3\">\"\n    services=\"mobile-services\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"ggailey777\"\n    manager=\"dwrede\"\n    editor=\"mollybos\"/&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph4\">\n&lt;tags\n    ms.service=\"mobile-services\"\n    ms.workload=\"mobile\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"mobile-multiple\"\n    ms.devlang=\"multiple\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"12/07/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"glenga\"/&gt;</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        581,
        646
      ],
      "content": "Supporting multiple device platforms from a single mobile service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        751,
        757
      ],
      "content": "&amp;nbsp;"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        760,
        1281
      ],
      "content": "One of the major benefits of using Azure Mobile Services in your mobile app development is the ability to use a single backend service that supports your app on multiple client platforms. Mobile Services provides native client libraries for all major device platforms, which makes it easier to develop apps using a single backend service and by using cross-platform developer tools. This topic discusses considerations for getting your app running on multiple client platforms while using a single mobile service backend.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "One of the major benefits of using Azure Mobile Services in your mobile app development is the ability to use a single backend service that supports your app on multiple client platforms.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            187
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Mobile Services provides native client libraries for all major device platforms, which makes it easier to develop apps using a single backend service and by using cross-platform developer tools.",
          "pos": [
            188,
            382
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This topic discusses considerations for getting your app running on multiple client platforms while using a single mobile service backend.",
          "pos": [
            383,
            521
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1283,
        1285
      ],
      "content": "##"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1302,
        1335
      ],
      "content": "Cross-platform push notifications"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1337,
        1745
      ],
      "content": "Mobile Services uses Azure Notification Hubs for sending push notifications to your client apps on all major device platforms. Notification Hubs provide a consistent and unified infrastructure for creating and managing device registrations and for sending cross-platform push notifications. Notification Hubs supports sending push notifications by using the following platform-specific notification services:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Mobile Services uses Azure Notification Hubs for sending push notifications to your client apps on all major device platforms.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            126
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Notification Hubs provide a consistent and unified infrastructure for creating and managing device registrations and for sending cross-platform push notifications.",
          "pos": [
            127,
            290
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Notification Hubs supports sending push notifications by using the following platform-specific notification services:",
          "pos": [
            291,
            408
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1749,
        1800
      ],
      "content": "Apple Push Notification Service (APNS) for iOS apps"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1803,
        1856
      ],
      "content": "Google Cloud Messaging (GCM) service for Android apps"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1859,
        1964
      ],
      "content": "Windows Notification Service (WNS) for Windows Store, Windows Phone 8.1 Store, and universal Windows apps"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1967,
        2044
      ],
      "content": "Microsoft Push Notification Service (MPNS) for Windows Phone Silverlight apps"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2046,
        2098
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see [Azure Notification Hubs]."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2100,
        2324
      ],
      "content": "Client registrations are created by using the register function in the platform-specific Mobile Services client library or by using the Mobile Services REST APIs. Notification Hubs supports two kinds of device registrations:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Client registrations are created by using the register function in the platform-specific Mobile Services client library or by using the Mobile Services REST APIs.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            162
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Notification Hubs supports two kinds of device registrations:",
          "pos": [
            163,
            224
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2328,
        2678
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Native registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph6\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Native registrations are tailored to the platform-specific push notification service. When sending notifications to devices registered using native registrations, you must call platform-specific APIs in your mobile service. To send a notification to devices on multiple platforms requires multiple platform-specific calls.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Native registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph6\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Native registrations are tailored to the platform-specific push notification service.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            175
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "When sending notifications to devices registered using native registrations, you must call platform-specific APIs in your mobile service.",
          "pos": [
            176,
            313
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "To send a notification to devices on multiple platforms requires multiple platform-specific calls.",
          "pos": [
            314,
            412
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2682,
        2991
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Template registration<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph7\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Notification Hubs also supports platform-specific template registrations. By using template registrations, you can use a single API call to send a notification to your app running on any registered platform. For more information, see [Send cross-platform notifications to users].",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Template registration<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph7\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Notification Hubs also supports platform-specific template registrations.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            165
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "By using template registrations, you can use a single API call to send a notification to your app running on any registered platform.",
          "pos": [
            166,
            299
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information, see [Send cross-platform notifications to users].",
          "pos": [
            300,
            371
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2993,
        3168
      ],
      "content": "Tables in the following sections link to the client-specific tutorials that show you how to implement push notifications from both .NET and JavaScript backend mobile services."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3173,
        3185
      ],
      "content": ".NET backend"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3187,
        3849
      ],
      "content": "In a .NET backend mobile service, you send notifications by calling the [SendAsync] method on the <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>PushClient<ept id=\"p3\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.notifications.pushclient.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph8\"/> object obtained from the <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>ApiServices.Push<ept id=\"p4\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.apiservices.push.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> property. The push notification sent (native or template) depends on the specific <bpt id=\"p5\">[</bpt>IPushMessage<ept id=\"p5\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.notifications.ipushmessage.aspx)</ept>-derived object that is passed to the [SendAsync] method, as shown in the following table:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "In a .NET backend mobile service, you send notifications by calling the [SendAsync] method on the <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>PushClient<ept id=\"p3\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.notifications.pushclient.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph8\"/> object obtained from the <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>ApiServices.Push<ept id=\"p4\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.apiservices.push.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> property.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            478
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The push notification sent (native or template) depends on the specific <bpt id=\"p5\">[</bpt>IPushMessage<ept id=\"p5\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.notifications.ipushmessage.aspx)</ept>-derived object that is passed to the [SendAsync] method, as shown in the following table:",
          "pos": [
            479,
            804
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3852,
        3860
      ],
      "content": "Platform"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3862,
        3924
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p6\">[</bpt>APNS<ept id=\"p6\">](mobile-services-dotnet-backend-ios-get-started-push.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3925,
        3990
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p7\">[</bpt>GCM<ept id=\"p7\">](mobile-services-dotnet-backend-android-get-started-push.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3992,
        4070
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p8\">[</bpt>WNS<ept id=\"p8\">](mobile-services-dotnet-backend-windows-store-dotnet-get-started-push.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4073,
        4077
      ],
      "content": "MPNS"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4109,
        4115
      ],
      "content": "Native"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4116,
        4235
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p9\">[</bpt>ApplePushMessage<ept id=\"p9\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.applepushmessage.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4239,
        4360
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p10\">[</bpt>GooglePushMessage<ept id=\"p10\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.googlepushmessage.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4366,
        4489
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p11\">[</bpt>WindowsPushMessage<ept id=\"p11\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.windowspushmessage.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4492,
        4609
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p12\">[</bpt>MpnsPushMessage<ept id=\"p12\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.mpnspushmessage.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4613,
        4736
      ],
      "content": "The following code sends a push notification from a .NET backend service to all iOS and Windows Store device registrations:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5440,
        5583
      ],
      "content": "For examples of how to send push notifications to the other native client platforms, click the platform links in the header of the above table."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5585,
        5797
      ],
      "content": "When you use template client registrations rather than native client registrations, you can send the same notification with only a single call to [SendAsync], supplying a [TemplatePushMessage] object, as follows:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6089,
        6107
      ],
      "content": "JavaScript backend"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6109,
        6307
      ],
      "content": "In a JavaScript backend mobile service, you send notifications by calling the <bpt id=\"p13\">**</bpt>send<ept id=\"p13\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph10\"/> method on the platform-specific object obtained from the global [push object], as shown in the following table:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6310,
        6318
      ],
      "content": "Platform"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6320,
        6386
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p14\">[</bpt>APNS<ept id=\"p14\">](mobile-services-javascript-backend-ios-get-started-push.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6387,
        6456
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p15\">[</bpt>GCM<ept id=\"p15\">](mobile-services-javascript-backend-android-get-started-push.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6458,
        6540
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p16\">[</bpt>WNS<ept id=\"p16\">](mobile-services-javascript-backend-windows-store-dotnet-get-started-push.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6542,
        6618
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p17\">[</bpt>MPNS<ept id=\"p17\">](mobile-services-javascript-backend-windows-phone-get-started-push.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6651,
        6657
      ],
      "content": "Native"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6658,
        6726
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p18\">[</bpt>apns object<ept id=\"p18\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj839711.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6730,
        6797
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p19\">[</bpt>gcm object<ept id=\"p19\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn126137.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6803,
        6870
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p20\">[</bpt>wns object<ept id=\"p20\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj860484.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6873,
        6941
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p21\">[</bpt>mpns object<ept id=\"p21\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj871025.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6945,
        7035
      ],
      "content": "The following code sends push notification to all Android and Windows Phone registrations:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8075,
        8218
      ],
      "content": "For examples of how to send push notifications to the other native client platforms, click the platform links in the header of the above table."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8220,
        8463
      ],
      "content": "When you use template client registrations rather than native client registrations, you can send the same notification with only a single call the <bpt id=\"p22\">**</bpt>send<ept id=\"p22\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph11\"/> function on the global [push object], supplying a template message payload, as follows:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8913,
        8915
      ],
      "content": "##"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8941,
        8971
      ],
      "content": "Cross-platform app development"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8972,
        9497
      ],
      "content": "Developing native mobile device apps for all of the major mobile device platforms requires you (or your organization) to have expertise in at least Objective-C, Java, and C# or JavaScript programming languages. Because of the expense of developing across these disparate platforms, some developers choose a fully web browser-based experience for their apps. However, such web-based experiences cannot access most of the native resources that provide the rich experience that users have come to expect on their mobile devices.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Developing native mobile device apps for all of the major mobile device platforms requires you (or your organization) to have expertise in at least Objective-C, Java, and C# or JavaScript programming languages.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            210
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Because of the expense of developing across these disparate platforms, some developers choose a fully web browser-based experience for their apps.",
          "pos": [
            211,
            357
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "However, such web-based experiences cannot access most of the native resources that provide the rich experience that users have come to expect on their mobile devices.",
          "pos": [
            358,
            525
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9499,
        9842
      ],
      "content": "Cross-platform tools are available that provide a richer native experience on a mobile device, while still sharing a single code base, usually JavaScript. Mobile Services makes it easy to create and manage a backend service for cross-platform app development platforms by providing quickstart tutorials for the following development platforms:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Cross-platform tools are available that provide a richer native experience on a mobile device, while still sharing a single code base, usually JavaScript.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            154
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Mobile Services makes it easy to create and manage a backend service for cross-platform app development platforms by providing quickstart tutorials for the following development platforms:",
          "pos": [
            155,
            343
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9846,
        10225
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p23\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p24\">**</bpt>Appcelerator<ept id=\"p24\">**</ept><ept id=\"p23\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=509987)</ept><ph id=\"ph12\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Appcelerator lets you use JavaScript to develop a single app that is compiled to run  as native on all mobile device platforms. This provides a rich user experience in UI, access to all native device resources, and native app performance. For more information, see the [Appcelerator tutorial][Appcelerator].",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p23\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p24\">**</bpt>Appcelerator<ept id=\"p24\">**</ept><ept id=\"p23\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=509987)</ept><ph id=\"ph12\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Appcelerator lets you use JavaScript to develop a single app that is compiled to run  as native on all mobile device platforms.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            304
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This provides a rich user experience in UI, access to all native device resources, and native app performance.",
          "pos": [
            305,
            415
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information, see the [Appcelerator tutorial][Appcelerator].",
          "pos": [
            416,
            484
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10229,
        10868
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p25\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p26\">**</bpt>PhoneGap<ept id=\"p26\">**</ept><ept id=\"p25\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=390707)</ept><bpt id=\"p27\">**</bpt>/<ept id=\"p27\">**</ept><bpt id=\"p28\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p29\">**</bpt>Cordova<ept id=\"p29\">**</ept><ept id=\"p28\">](http://cordova.apache.org/)</ept><ph id=\"ph13\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>PhoneGap (a distribution of the Apache Cordova project) is a free and open source framework that lets you use standardized web APIs, HTML and JavaScript to develop a single app that runs on Android, iOS and Windows devices. PhoneGap provides a web view based UI, but with a user experience enhanced by accessing native resources on the device, such as such as push notifications, the accelerometer, camera, storage, geolocation, and the in-app browser. For more information, see the [PhoneGap quickstart tutorial][PhoneGap].",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p25\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p26\">**</bpt>PhoneGap<ept id=\"p26\">**</ept><ept id=\"p25\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=390707)</ept><bpt id=\"p27\">**</bpt>/<ept id=\"p27\">**</ept><bpt id=\"p28\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p29\">**</bpt>Cordova<ept id=\"p29\">**</ept><ept id=\"p28\">](http://cordova.apache.org/)</ept><ph id=\"ph13\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>PhoneGap (a distribution of the Apache Cordova project) is a free and open source framework that lets you use standardized web APIs, HTML and JavaScript to develop a single app that runs on Android, iOS and Windows devices.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            563
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "PhoneGap provides a web view based UI, but with a user experience enhanced by accessing native resources on the device, such as such as push notifications, the accelerometer, camera, storage, geolocation, and the in-app browser.",
          "pos": [
            564,
            792
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information, see the [PhoneGap quickstart tutorial][PhoneGap].",
          "pos": [
            793,
            864
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10874,
        11193
      ],
      "content": "Visual Studio now also enables you to build cross-platform Cordova apps by using the Multi-Device Hybrid Apps extension for Visual Studio, which is pre-release software. For more information, see <bpt id=\"p30\">[</bpt>Getting Started with Multi-Device Hybrid Apps Using HTML and JavaScript<ept id=\"p30\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn771545.aspx)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Visual Studio now also enables you to build cross-platform Cordova apps by using the Multi-Device Hybrid Apps extension for Visual Studio, which is pre-release software.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            169
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p30\">[</bpt>Getting Started with Multi-Device Hybrid Apps Using HTML and JavaScript<ept id=\"p30\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn771545.aspx)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            170,
            359
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11197,
        11649
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p31\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p32\">**</bpt>Sencha Touch<ept id=\"p32\">**</ept><ept id=\"p31\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=509988)</ept><ph id=\"ph14\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Sencha Touch provides a set of controls, optimized for touch screens, that provide a like-native experience on a wide variety of mobile devices from a single HTML and JavaScript code base. Sencha Touch can be used along with PhoneGap or Cordova libraries to provide users access to native device resources. For more information, see the [Sencha Touch quickstart tutorial][Sencha].",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p31\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p32\">**</bpt>Sencha Touch<ept id=\"p32\">**</ept><ept id=\"p31\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=509988)</ept><ph id=\"ph14\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Sencha Touch provides a set of controls, optimized for touch screens, that provide a like-native experience on a wide variety of mobile devices from a single HTML and JavaScript code base.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            365
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Sencha Touch can be used along with PhoneGap or Cordova libraries to provide users access to native device resources.",
          "pos": [
            366,
            483
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information, see the [Sencha Touch quickstart tutorial][Sencha].",
          "pos": [
            484,
            557
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11653,
        12282
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p33\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p34\">**</bpt>Xamarin<ept id=\"p34\">**</ept><ept id=\"p33\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=330242)</ept><ph id=\"ph15\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Xamarin lets you create fully native apps for both iOS and Android devices, with fully native UI and access to all device resources. Xamarin apps are coded in C# instead of Objective-C and Java. This enables .NET developers to publish apps to iOS and Android and share code from Windows projects. Xamarin provides a fully native user experience on both iOS and Android devices from C# code. This enables you to reuse some of your Mobile Services code from Windows apps on iOS and Android devices. For more information, see <bpt id=\"p35\">[</bpt>Xamarin development<ept id=\"p35\">](#xamarin)</ept><ph id=\"ph16\"/> below.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p33\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p34\">**</bpt>Xamarin<ept id=\"p34\">**</ept><ept id=\"p33\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=330242)</ept><ph id=\"ph15\">&lt;br/&gt;</ph>Xamarin lets you create fully native apps for both iOS and Android devices, with fully native UI and access to all device resources.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            305
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Xamarin apps are coded in C# instead of Objective-C and Java.",
          "pos": [
            306,
            367
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This enables .NET developers to publish apps to iOS and Android and share code from Windows projects.",
          "pos": [
            368,
            469
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Xamarin provides a fully native user experience on both iOS and Android devices from C# code.",
          "pos": [
            470,
            563
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This enables you to reuse some of your Mobile Services code from Windows apps on iOS and Android devices.",
          "pos": [
            564,
            669
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p35\">[</bpt>Xamarin development<ept id=\"p35\">](#xamarin)</ept><ph id=\"ph16\"/> below.",
          "pos": [
            670,
            789
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12299,
        14393
      ],
      "content": "[Azure Notification Hubs]: /develop/net/how-to-guides/service-bus-notification-hubs/\n[SSO Windows Store]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/single-sign-on-windows-8-dotnet/\n[SSO Windows Phone]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/single-sign-on-wp8/\n[Tutorials and resources]: /develop/mobile/resources/\n[Get started with Notification Hubs]: /manage/services/notification-hubs/getting-started-windows-dotnet/\n[Send cross-platform notifications to users]: /manage/services/notification-hubs/notify-users-xplat-mobile-services/\n[Get started with push Windows dotnet]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-dotnet-vs2012/\n[Get started with push Windows js]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-js-vs2012/\n[Get started with push Windows Phone]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-wp8/\n[Get started with push iOS]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-ios/\n[Get started with push Android]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-android/\n[Dynamic schema]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windowsazure/jj193175.aspx\n[How to use a .NET client with Mobile Services]: documentation/articles/mobile-services-windows-dotnet-how-to-use-client-library/\n[push object]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windowsazure/jj554217.aspx\n[TemplatePushMessage]:http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.templatepushmessage.aspx\n[PhoneGap]: mobile-services-javascript-backend-phonegap-get-started.md\n[Sencha]: partner-sencha-mobile-services-get-started.md\n[Appcelerator]: ../partner-appcelerator-mobile-services-javascript-backend-appcelerator-get-started.md\n[SendAsync]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.notifications.pushclient.sendasync.aspx\n[What's next for Windows Phone 8 developers]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/dn655121(v=vs.105).aspx\n[Building universal Windows apps for all Windows devices]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=509905\n[Universal Windows app project for Azure Mobile Services using MVVM]: http://code.msdn.microsoft.com/Universal-Windows-app-for-db3564de"
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"How to use multiple clients with a single mobile service backend | Azure Mobile Services\"\n    description=\"Learn how to use a single mobile service back-end from multiple client apps that target different mobile platforms.\"\n    services=\"mobile-services\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"ggailey777\"\n    manager=\"dwrede\"\n    editor=\"mollybos\"/>\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"mobile-services\"\n    ms.workload=\"mobile\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"mobile-multiple\"\n    ms.devlang=\"multiple\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"12/07/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"glenga\"/>\n\n# Supporting multiple device platforms from a single mobile service\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [mobile-service-note-mobile-apps](../../includes/mobile-services-note-mobile-apps.md)]\n\n&nbsp;\n\n\nOne of the major benefits of using Azure Mobile Services in your mobile app development is the ability to use a single backend service that supports your app on multiple client platforms. Mobile Services provides native client libraries for all major device platforms, which makes it easier to develop apps using a single backend service and by using cross-platform developer tools. This topic discusses considerations for getting your app running on multiple client platforms while using a single mobile service backend.\n\n##<a id=\"push\"></a>Cross-platform push notifications\n\nMobile Services uses Azure Notification Hubs for sending push notifications to your client apps on all major device platforms. Notification Hubs provide a consistent and unified infrastructure for creating and managing device registrations and for sending cross-platform push notifications. Notification Hubs supports sending push notifications by using the following platform-specific notification services:\n\n+ Apple Push Notification Service (APNS) for iOS apps\n+ Google Cloud Messaging (GCM) service for Android apps\n+ Windows Notification Service (WNS) for Windows Store, Windows Phone 8.1 Store, and universal Windows apps\n+ Microsoft Push Notification Service (MPNS) for Windows Phone Silverlight apps\n\nFor more information, see [Azure Notification Hubs].\n\nClient registrations are created by using the register function in the platform-specific Mobile Services client library or by using the Mobile Services REST APIs. Notification Hubs supports two kinds of device registrations:\n\n+ **Native registration**<br/>Native registrations are tailored to the platform-specific push notification service. When sending notifications to devices registered using native registrations, you must call platform-specific APIs in your mobile service. To send a notification to devices on multiple platforms requires multiple platform-specific calls.\n\n+ **Template registration**<br/>Notification Hubs also supports platform-specific template registrations. By using template registrations, you can use a single API call to send a notification to your app running on any registered platform. For more information, see [Send cross-platform notifications to users].\n\nTables in the following sections link to the client-specific tutorials that show you how to implement push notifications from both .NET and JavaScript backend mobile services.\n\n###.NET backend\n\nIn a .NET backend mobile service, you send notifications by calling the [SendAsync] method on the [PushClient](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.notifications.pushclient.aspx) object obtained from the [ApiServices.Push](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.apiservices.push.aspx) property. The push notification sent (native or template) depends on the specific [IPushMessage](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.notifications.ipushmessage.aspx)-derived object that is passed to the [SendAsync] method, as shown in the following table:\n\n|Platform |[APNS](mobile-services-dotnet-backend-ios-get-started-push.md)|[GCM](mobile-services-dotnet-backend-android-get-started-push.md) |[WNS](mobile-services-dotnet-backend-windows-store-dotnet-get-started-push.md) | MPNS\n|-----|-----|----|----|-----|\n|Native|[ApplePushMessage](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.applepushmessage.aspx)   |[GooglePushMessage](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.googlepushmessage.aspx)     |[WindowsPushMessage](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.windowspushmessage.aspx) | [MpnsPushMessage](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.mpnspushmessage.aspx) |\n\nThe following code sends a push notification from a .NET backend service to all iOS and Windows Store device registrations:\n\n    // Define a push notification for APNS.\n    ApplePushMessage apnsMessage = new ApplePushMessage(item.Text, TimeSpan.FromHours(1));\n\n    // Define a push notification for WNS.\n    WindowsPushMessage wnsMessage = new WindowsPushMessage();\n    wnsMessage.XmlPayload = @\"<?xml version=\"\"1.0\"\" encoding=\"\"utf-8\"\"?>\" +\n                         @\"<toast><visual><binding template=\"\"ToastText01\"\">\" +\n                         @\"<text id=\"\"1\"\">\" + item.Text + @\"</text>\" +\n                         @\"</binding></visual></toast>\";\n\n    // Send push notifications to all registered iOS and Windows Store devices.\n    await Services.Push.SendAsync(apnsMessage);\n    await Services.Push.SendAsync(wnsMessage);\n\nFor examples of how to send push notifications to the other native client platforms, click the platform links in the header of the above table.\n\nWhen you use template client registrations rather than native client registrations, you can send the same notification with only a single call to [SendAsync], supplying a [TemplatePushMessage] object, as follows:\n\n    // Create a new template message and add the 'message' parameter.\n    var templatePayload = new TemplatePushMessage();\n    templatePayload.Add(\"message\", item.Text);\n\n    // Send a push notification to all template registrations.\n    await Services.Push.SendAsync(templatePayload);\n\n###JavaScript backend\n\nIn a JavaScript backend mobile service, you send notifications by calling the **send** method on the platform-specific object obtained from the global [push object], as shown in the following table:\n\n|Platform |[APNS](mobile-services-javascript-backend-ios-get-started-push.md)|[GCM](mobile-services-javascript-backend-android-get-started-push.md) |[WNS](mobile-services-javascript-backend-windows-store-dotnet-get-started-push.md) |[MPNS](mobile-services-javascript-backend-windows-phone-get-started-push.md)|\n|-----|-----|----|----|-----|\n|Native|[apns object](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj839711.aspx)   |[gcm object](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn126137.aspx)     |[wns object](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj860484.aspx) | [mpns object](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj871025.aspx) |\n\nThe following code sends push notification to all Android and Windows Phone registrations:\n\n    // Define a push notification for GCM.\n    var gcmPayload =\n    '{\"data\":{\"message\" : item.text }}';\n\n    // Define the payload for a Windows Phone toast notification.\n    var mpnsPayload = '<?xml version=\"1.0\" encoding=\"utf-8\"?>' +\n    '<wp:Notification xmlns:wp=\"WPNotification\"><wp:Toast>' +\n    '<wp:Text1>New Item</wp:Text1><wp:Text2>' + item.text +\n    '</wp:Text2></wp:Toast></wp:Notification>';\n\n    // Send push notifications to all registered Android and Windows Phone 8.0 devices.\n    push.mpns.send(null, mpnsPayload, 'toast', 22, {\n            success: function(pushResponse) {\n                // Push succeeds.\n                },\n                error: function (pushResponse) {\n                    // Push fails.\n                    }\n                });\n    push.gcm.send(null, gcmPayload, {\n            success: function(pushResponse) {\n                // Push succeeds.\n                },\n                error: function (pushResponse) {\n                    // Push fails.\n                    }\n                });\n\nFor examples of how to send push notifications to the other native client platforms, click the platform links in the header of the above table.\n\nWhen you use template client registrations rather than native client registrations, you can send the same notification with only a single call the **send** function on the global [push object], supplying a template message payload, as follows:\n\n    // Create a new template message with the 'message' parameter.\n    var templatePayload = { \"message\": item.text };\n\n    // Send a push notification to all template registrations.\n    push.send(null, templatePayload, {\n            success: function(pushResponse) {\n                // Push succeeds.\n                },\n                error: function (pushResponse) {\n                    // Push fails.\n                    }\n                });\n\n##<a id=\"xplat-app-dev\"></a>Cross-platform app development\nDeveloping native mobile device apps for all of the major mobile device platforms requires you (or your organization) to have expertise in at least Objective-C, Java, and C# or JavaScript programming languages. Because of the expense of developing across these disparate platforms, some developers choose a fully web browser-based experience for their apps. However, such web-based experiences cannot access most of the native resources that provide the rich experience that users have come to expect on their mobile devices.\n\nCross-platform tools are available that provide a richer native experience on a mobile device, while still sharing a single code base, usually JavaScript. Mobile Services makes it easy to create and manage a backend service for cross-platform app development platforms by providing quickstart tutorials for the following development platforms:\n\n+ [**Appcelerator**](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=509987)<br/>Appcelerator lets you use JavaScript to develop a single app that is compiled to run  as native on all mobile device platforms. This provides a rich user experience in UI, access to all native device resources, and native app performance. For more information, see the [Appcelerator tutorial][Appcelerator].\n\n+ [**PhoneGap**](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=390707)**/**[**Cordova**](http://cordova.apache.org/)<br/>PhoneGap (a distribution of the Apache Cordova project) is a free and open source framework that lets you use standardized web APIs, HTML and JavaScript to develop a single app that runs on Android, iOS and Windows devices. PhoneGap provides a web view based UI, but with a user experience enhanced by accessing native resources on the device, such as such as push notifications, the accelerometer, camera, storage, geolocation, and the in-app browser. For more information, see the [PhoneGap quickstart tutorial][PhoneGap].\n\n    Visual Studio now also enables you to build cross-platform Cordova apps by using the Multi-Device Hybrid Apps extension for Visual Studio, which is pre-release software. For more information, see [Getting Started with Multi-Device Hybrid Apps Using HTML and JavaScript](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn771545.aspx).\n\n+ [**Sencha Touch**](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=509988)<br/>Sencha Touch provides a set of controls, optimized for touch screens, that provide a like-native experience on a wide variety of mobile devices from a single HTML and JavaScript code base. Sencha Touch can be used along with PhoneGap or Cordova libraries to provide users access to native device resources. For more information, see the [Sencha Touch quickstart tutorial][Sencha].\n\n+ [**Xamarin**](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=330242)<br/>Xamarin lets you create fully native apps for both iOS and Android devices, with fully native UI and access to all device resources. Xamarin apps are coded in C# instead of Objective-C and Java. This enables .NET developers to publish apps to iOS and Android and share code from Windows projects. Xamarin provides a fully native user experience on both iOS and Android devices from C# code. This enables you to reuse some of your Mobile Services code from Windows apps on iOS and Android devices. For more information, see [Xamarin development](#xamarin) below.\n\n\n<!-- URLs -->\n[Azure Notification Hubs]: /develop/net/how-to-guides/service-bus-notification-hubs/\n[SSO Windows Store]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/single-sign-on-windows-8-dotnet/\n[SSO Windows Phone]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/single-sign-on-wp8/\n[Tutorials and resources]: /develop/mobile/resources/\n[Get started with Notification Hubs]: /manage/services/notification-hubs/getting-started-windows-dotnet/\n[Send cross-platform notifications to users]: /manage/services/notification-hubs/notify-users-xplat-mobile-services/\n[Get started with push Windows dotnet]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-dotnet-vs2012/\n[Get started with push Windows js]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-js-vs2012/\n[Get started with push Windows Phone]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-wp8/\n[Get started with push iOS]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-ios/\n[Get started with push Android]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started-with-push-android/\n[Dynamic schema]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windowsazure/jj193175.aspx\n[How to use a .NET client with Mobile Services]: documentation/articles/mobile-services-windows-dotnet-how-to-use-client-library/\n[push object]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windowsazure/jj554217.aspx\n[TemplatePushMessage]:http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.templatepushmessage.aspx\n[PhoneGap]: mobile-services-javascript-backend-phonegap-get-started.md\n[Sencha]: partner-sencha-mobile-services-get-started.md\n[Appcelerator]: ../partner-appcelerator-mobile-services-javascript-backend-appcelerator-get-started.md\n[SendAsync]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/microsoft.windowsazure.mobile.service.notifications.pushclient.sendasync.aspx\n[What's next for Windows Phone 8 developers]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/dn655121(v=vs.105).aspx\n[Building universal Windows apps for all Windows devices]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=509905\n[Universal Windows app project for Azure Mobile Services using MVVM]: http://code.msdn.microsoft.com/Universal-Windows-app-for-db3564de\n"
}