{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        28,
        78
      ],
      "content": "Lexicon Based Sentiment Analysis | Microsoft Azure"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        98,
        130
      ],
      "content": "Lexicon Based Sentiment Analysis"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        467,
        499
      ],
      "content": "Lexicon Based Sentiment Analysis"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        502,
        716
      ],
      "content": "How can you measure users’ opinions and attitudes toward brands or topics in online social networks, such as Facebook posts, tweets, reviews, etc.? Sentiment analysis provides a method for analyzing such questions.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "How can you measure users’ opinions and attitudes toward brands or topics in online social networks, such as Facebook posts, tweets, reviews, etc.?",
          "pos": [
            0,
            147
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Sentiment analysis provides a method for analyzing such questions.",
          "pos": [
            148,
            214
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        813,
        1488
      ],
      "content": "There are generally two methods for sentiment analysis. One is using a supervised learning algorithm, and the other can be treated as unsupervised learning. A supervised learning algorithm generally builds a classification model on a large annotated corpus. Its accuracy is mainly based on the quality of the annotation, and usually the training process will take a long time. Besides that, when we apply the algorithm to another domain, the result is usually not good. Compared to supervised learning, lexicon-based unsupervised learning uses a sentiment dictionary, which doesn’t require storing a large data corpus and training - which makes the whole process much faster.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "There are generally two methods for sentiment analysis.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            55
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "One is using a supervised learning algorithm, and the other can be treated as unsupervised learning.",
          "pos": [
            56,
            156
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "A supervised learning algorithm generally builds a classification model on a large annotated corpus.",
          "pos": [
            157,
            257
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Its accuracy is mainly based on the quality of the annotation, and usually the training process will take a long time.",
          "pos": [
            258,
            376
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Besides that, when we apply the algorithm to another domain, the result is usually not good.",
          "pos": [
            377,
            469
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Compared to supervised learning, lexicon-based unsupervised learning uses a sentiment dictionary, which doesn’t require storing a large data corpus and training - which makes the whole process much faster.",
          "pos": [
            470,
            675
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1491,
        2004
      ],
      "content": "Our <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>service<ept id=\"p1\">](https://datamarket.azure.com/dataset/aml_labs/lexicon_based_sentiment_analysis)</ept><ph id=\"ph3\"/> is built on the MPQA Subjectivity Lexicon (http://mpqa.cs.pitt.edu/lexicons/subj_lexicon/), which is one of the most commonly used subjectivity lexicons. There are 5097 negative and 2533 positive words in MPQA. And all of these words are annotated as strong or weak polarity. The whole corpus is under GNU General Public License. The web service can be applied to any short sentences, such as tweets and Facebook posts.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Our <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>service<ept id=\"p1\">](https://datamarket.azure.com/dataset/aml_labs/lexicon_based_sentiment_analysis)</ept><ph id=\"ph3\"/> is built on the MPQA Subjectivity Lexicon (http://mpqa.cs.pitt.edu/lexicons/subj_lexicon/), which is one of the most commonly used subjectivity lexicons.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            299
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "There are 5097 negative and 2533 positive words in MPQA.",
          "pos": [
            300,
            356
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "And all of these words are annotated as strong or weak polarity.",
          "pos": [
            357,
            421
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The whole corpus is under GNU General Public License.",
          "pos": [
            422,
            475
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The web service can be applied to any short sentences, such as tweets and Facebook posts.",
          "pos": [
            476,
            565
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2008,
        2639
      ],
      "content": "This web service could be consumed by users – potentially through a mobile app, through a website, or even on a local computer for example. But the purpose of the web service is also to serve as an example of how Azure Machine Learning can be used to create web services on top of R code. With just a few lines of R code and clicks of a button within Azure Machine Learning Studio, an experiment can be created with R code and published as a web service. The web service can then be published to the Azure Marketplace and consumed by users and devices across the world with no infrastructure setup by the author of the web service.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "This web service could be consumed by users – potentially through a mobile app, through a website, or even on a local computer for example.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            139
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "But the purpose of the web service is also to serve as an example of how Azure Machine Learning can be used to create web services on top of R code.",
          "pos": [
            140,
            288
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "With just a few lines of R code and clicks of a button within Azure Machine Learning Studio, an experiment can be created with R code and published as a web service.",
          "pos": [
            289,
            454
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The web service can then be published to the Azure Marketplace and consumed by users and devices across the world with no infrastructure setup by the author of the web service.",
          "pos": [
            455,
            631
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2643,
        2669
      ],
      "content": "Consumption of web service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2671,
        2979
      ],
      "content": "The input data can be any text, but the web service works better with short sentences. The output is a numeric value between -1 and 1. Any value below 0 denotes that the sentiment of the text is negative; positive if above 0. The absolute value of the result denotes the strength of the associated sentiment.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The input data can be any text, but the web service works better with short sentences.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            86
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The output is a numeric value between -1 and 1.",
          "pos": [
            87,
            134
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Any value below 0 denotes that the sentiment of the text is negative; positive if above 0.",
          "pos": [
            135,
            225
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The absolute value of the result denotes the strength of the associated sentiment.",
          "pos": [
            226,
            308
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2983,
        3102
      ],
      "content": "This service, as hosted on the Azure Marketplace, is an OData service; these may be called through POST or GET methods."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3105,
        3262
      ],
      "content": "There are multiple ways of consuming the service in an automated fashion (an example app is <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p2\">](http://microsoftazuremachinelearning.azurewebsites.net/)</ept>)."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3267,
        3312
      ],
      "content": "Starting C# code for web service consumption:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4262,
        4389
      ],
      "content": "The input is “Today is a good day.” The output is “1”, which indicates a positive sentiment associated with the input sentence.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The input is “Today is a good day.”",
          "pos": [
            0,
            35
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The output is “1”, which indicates a positive sentiment associated with the input sentence.",
          "pos": [
            36,
            127
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4394,
        4417
      ],
      "content": "Creation of web service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4419,
        4822
      ],
      "content": "This web service was created using Azure Machine Learning. For a free trial, as well as introductory videos on creating experiments and <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>publishing web services<ept id=\"p3\">](machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service.md)</ept>, please see <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>azure.com/ml<ept id=\"p4\">](http://azure.com/ml)</ept>. Below is a screenshot of the experiment that created the web service and example code for each of the modules within the experiment.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "This web service was created using Azure Machine Learning.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            58
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For a free trial, as well as introductory videos on creating experiments and <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>publishing web services<ept id=\"p3\">](machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service.md)</ept>, please see <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>azure.com/ml<ept id=\"p4\">](http://azure.com/ml)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            59,
            346
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Below is a screenshot of the experiment that created the web service and example code for each of the modules within the experiment.",
          "pos": [
            347,
            479
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4825,
        5576
      ],
      "content": "From within Azure Machine Learning, a new blank experiment was created. The figure below shows the experiment flow of lexicon-based sentiment analysis. The “sent_dict.csv” file is the MPQA subjectivity lexicon, and is set as one of the inputs of [Execute R Script][execute-r-script]. Another input is a sampled review from the Amazon review dataset for test, where we performed selection, column name modification, and split operations. We use a hash package to store the subjectivity lexicon in the memory and accelerate the score computation process. The whole text will be tokenized by “tm” package and compared with the word in the sentiment dictionary. Finally, a score will be calculated by adding the weight of each subjective word in the text.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "From within Azure Machine Learning, a new blank experiment was created.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            71
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The figure below shows the experiment flow of lexicon-based sentiment analysis.",
          "pos": [
            72,
            151
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The “sent_dict.csv” file is the MPQA subjectivity lexicon, and is set as one of the inputs of [Execute R Script][execute-r-script].",
          "pos": [
            152,
            283
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Another input is a sampled review from the Amazon review dataset for test, where we performed selection, column name modification, and split operations.",
          "pos": [
            284,
            436
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "We use a hash package to store the subjectivity lexicon in the memory and accelerate the score computation process.",
          "pos": [
            437,
            552
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The whole text will be tokenized by “tm” package and compared with the word in the sentiment dictionary.",
          "pos": [
            553,
            657
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Finally, a score will be calculated by adding the weight of each subjective word in the text.",
          "pos": [
            658,
            751
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5582,
        5598
      ],
      "content": "Experiment flow:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5600,
        5621
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph4\">![</ph>experiment flow<ph id=\"ph5\">][2]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5628,
        5637
      ],
      "content": "Module 1:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5821,
        5841
      ],
      "content": "Install hash package"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7370,
        7381
      ],
      "content": "Limitations"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7383,
        7888
      ],
      "content": "From an algorithm perspective, lexicon-based sentiment analysis is a general sentiment analysis tool, which may not perform better than the classification method for specific fields. The negation problem is not well dealt with. We hardcode several negation words in our program, but a better way is using a negation dictionary and build some rules. The web service performs better on short and simple sentences, such as tweets and Facebook posts, than on long and complex sentences such as Amazon reviews.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "From an algorithm perspective, lexicon-based sentiment analysis is a general sentiment analysis tool, which may not perform better than the classification method for specific fields.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            182
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The negation problem is not well dealt with.",
          "pos": [
            183,
            227
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "We hardcode several negation words in our program, but a better way is using a negation dictionary and build some rules.",
          "pos": [
            228,
            348
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The web service performs better on short and simple sentences, such as tweets and Facebook posts, than on long and complex sentences such as Amazon reviews.",
          "pos": [
            349,
            505
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7893,
        8050
      ],
      "content": "FAQ\nFor frequently asked questions on consumption of the web service or publishing to the Azure Marketplace, see <bpt id=\"p5\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p5\">](machine-learning-marketplace-faq.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8275,
        8373
      ],
      "content": "[execute-r-script]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/30806023-392b-42e0-94d6-6b775a6e0fd5/"
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Lexicon Based Sentiment Analysis | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"Lexicon Based Sentiment Analysis\" \n    services=\"machine-learning\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"pengxia\" \n    manager=\"paulettm\" \n    editor=\"cgronlun\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\" \n    ms.workload=\"data-services\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"12/01/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"pengxia\"/> \n\n\n\n#Lexicon Based Sentiment Analysis \n\nHow can you measure users’ opinions and attitudes toward brands or topics in online social networks, such as Facebook posts, tweets, reviews, etc.? Sentiment analysis provides a method for analyzing such questions.\n\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [machine-learning-free-trial](../../includes/machine-learning-free-trial.md)]\n\nThere are generally two methods for sentiment analysis. One is using a supervised learning algorithm, and the other can be treated as unsupervised learning. A supervised learning algorithm generally builds a classification model on a large annotated corpus. Its accuracy is mainly based on the quality of the annotation, and usually the training process will take a long time. Besides that, when we apply the algorithm to another domain, the result is usually not good. Compared to supervised learning, lexicon-based unsupervised learning uses a sentiment dictionary, which doesn’t require storing a large data corpus and training - which makes the whole process much faster. \n\nOur [service](https://datamarket.azure.com/dataset/aml_labs/lexicon_based_sentiment_analysis) is built on the MPQA Subjectivity Lexicon (http://mpqa.cs.pitt.edu/lexicons/subj_lexicon/), which is one of the most commonly used subjectivity lexicons. There are 5097 negative and 2533 positive words in MPQA. And all of these words are annotated as strong or weak polarity. The whole corpus is under GNU General Public License. The web service can be applied to any short sentences, such as tweets and Facebook posts. \n\n>This web service could be consumed by users – potentially through a mobile app, through a website, or even on a local computer for example. But the purpose of the web service is also to serve as an example of how Azure Machine Learning can be used to create web services on top of R code. With just a few lines of R code and clicks of a button within Azure Machine Learning Studio, an experiment can be created with R code and published as a web service. The web service can then be published to the Azure Marketplace and consumed by users and devices across the world with no infrastructure setup by the author of the web service.\n\n##Consumption of web service\n\nThe input data can be any text, but the web service works better with short sentences. The output is a numeric value between -1 and 1. Any value below 0 denotes that the sentiment of the text is negative; positive if above 0. The absolute value of the result denotes the strength of the associated sentiment. \n\n>This service, as hosted on the Azure Marketplace, is an OData service; these may be called through POST or GET methods. \n\nThere are multiple ways of consuming the service in an automated fashion (an example app is [here](http://microsoftazuremachinelearning.azurewebsites.net/)).\n\n###Starting C# code for web service consumption:\n\n    public class ScoreResult\n    {\n            [DataMember]\n            public double result\n            {\n                get;\n                set;\n            }\n    }\n\n    void main()\n    {\n            using (var wb = new WebClient())\n            {\n                var acitionUri = new Uri(\"PutAPIURLHere,e.g.https://api.datamarket.azure.com/..../v1/Score\");\n                DataServiceContext ctx = new DataServiceContext(acitionUri);\n                var cred = new NetworkCredential(\"PutEmailAddressHere\", \"ChangeToAPIKey\");\n                var cache = new CredentialCache();\n    \n                cache.Add(acitionUri, \"Basic\", cred);\n                ctx.Credentials = cache;\n                var query = ctx.Execute<ScoreResult>(acitionUri, \"POST\", true, new BodyOperationParameter(\"Text\", TextBox1.Text));\n                ScoreResult scoreResult = query.ElementAt(0);\n                double result = scoreResult.result;\n            }\n    }\n\n\n\nThe input is “Today is a good day.” The output is “1”, which indicates a positive sentiment associated with the input sentence. \n\n##Creation of web service\n>This web service was created using Azure Machine Learning. For a free trial, as well as introductory videos on creating experiments and [publishing web services](machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service.md), please see [azure.com/ml](http://azure.com/ml). Below is a screenshot of the experiment that created the web service and example code for each of the modules within the experiment.\n\n\nFrom within Azure Machine Learning, a new blank experiment was created. The figure below shows the experiment flow of lexicon-based sentiment analysis. The “sent_dict.csv” file is the MPQA subjectivity lexicon, and is set as one of the inputs of [Execute R Script][execute-r-script]. Another input is a sampled review from the Amazon review dataset for test, where we performed selection, column name modification, and split operations. We use a hash package to store the subjectivity lexicon in the memory and accelerate the score computation process. The whole text will be tokenized by “tm” package and compared with the word in the sentiment dictionary. Finally, a score will be calculated by adding the weight of each subjective word in the text. \n\n###Experiment flow:\n\n![experiment flow][2]\n\n\n####Module 1:\n    \n    # Map 1-based optional input ports to variables\n    sent_dict_data<- maml.mapInputPort(1) # class: data.frame\n    dataset2 <- maml.mapInputPort(2) # class: data.frame\n \n   # Install hash package\n    install.packages(\"src/hash_2.2.6.zip\", lib = \".\", repos = NULL, verbose = TRUE)\n    success <- library(\"hash\", lib.loc = \".\", logical.return = TRUE, verbose = TRUE)\n    library(tm)\n    library(stringr)\n\n    #create sentiment dictionary\n    negation_word <- c(\"not\",\"nor\", \"no\")\n    result <- c()\n    sent_dict <- hash()\n    sent_dict <- hash(sent_dict_data$word, sent_dict_data$polarity)\n\n    #  Compute sentiment score for each document\n    for (m in 1:nrow(dataset2)){\n    polarity_ratio <- 0\n    polarity_total <- 0\n    not <- 0\n    sentence <- tolower(dataset2[m,1])\n    if (nchar(sentence) > 0){\n        token_array <- scan_tokenizer(sentence)\n        for (j in 1:length(token_array)){\n            word = str_replace_all(token_array[j], \"[^[:alnum:]]\", \"\")\n            for (k in 1:length(negation_word)){\n              if (word == negation_word[k]){\n                not <- (not+1) %% 2\n\n              }\n            }\n            if (word != \"\"){\n                if (!is.null(sent_dict[[word]])){\n                  polarity_ratio <- polarity_ratio + (-2*not+1)*sent_dict[[word]]\n                  polarity_total <- polarity_total + abs(sent_dict[[word]])\n                }\n            }\n          \n        }\n    }\n    if (polarity_total > 0){\n        result <- c(result, polarity_ratio/polarity_total)\n    }else{\n        result<- c(result,0)\n    }\n    }\n\n    # Sample operation\n    data.set <- data.frame(result)\n\n    # Select data.frame to be sent to the output Dataset port\n    maml.mapOutputPort(\"data.set\")\n    \n\n\n##Limitations\n\nFrom an algorithm perspective, lexicon-based sentiment analysis is a general sentiment analysis tool, which may not perform better than the classification method for specific fields. The negation problem is not well dealt with. We hardcode several negation words in our program, but a better way is using a negation dictionary and build some rules. The web service performs better on short and simple sentences, such as tweets and Facebook posts, than on long and complex sentences such as Amazon reviews. \n\n##FAQ\nFor frequently asked questions on consumption of the web service or publishing to the Azure Marketplace, see [here](machine-learning-marketplace-faq.md).\n\n[1]: ./media/machine-learning-r-csharp-lexicon-based-sentiment-analysis/sentiment_analysis_1.png\n[2]: ./media/machine-learning-r-csharp-lexicon-based-sentiment-analysis/sentiment_analysis_2.png\n\n\n<!-- Module References -->\n[execute-r-script]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/30806023-392b-42e0-94d6-6b775a6e0fd5/\n\n \n"
}