{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        28,
        84
      ],
      "content": "What is Azure Machine Learning Studio? | Microsoft Azure",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "What is Azure Machine Learning Studio?",
          "pos": [
            0,
            38
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "| Microsoft Azure",
          "pos": [
            39,
            56
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        103,
        235
      ],
      "content": "Overview of Azure ML Studio, a drag-and-drop tool for quickly building models from a ready-to-use library of algorithms and modules."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        618,
        656
      ],
      "content": "What is Azure Machine Learning Studio?"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        658,
        947
      ],
      "content": "Microsoft Azure Machine Learning Studio is a collaborative, drag-and-drop tool you can use to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions on your data. Machine Learning Studio publishes models as web services that can easily be consumed by custom apps or BI tools such as Excel.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Microsoft Azure Machine Learning Studio is a collaborative, drag-and-drop tool you can use to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions on your data.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            162
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Machine Learning Studio publishes models as web services that can easily be consumed by custom apps or BI tools such as Excel.",
          "pos": [
            163,
            289
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        949,
        1054
      ],
      "content": "Machine Learning Studio is where data science, predictive analytics, cloud resources, and your data meet."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1153,
        1202
      ],
      "content": "The Machine Learning Studio interactive workspace"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1204,
        1616
      ],
      "content": "To develop a predictive analysis model, you typically use data from one or more sources, transform and analyze that data through various data manipulation and statistical functions, and generate a set of results. Developing a model like this is an iterative process. As you modify the various functions and their parameters, your results converge until you are satisfied that you have a trained, effective model.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "To develop a predictive analysis model, you typically use data from one or more sources, transform and analyze that data through various data manipulation and statistical functions, and generate a set of results.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            212
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Developing a model like this is an iterative process.",
          "pos": [
            213,
            266
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "As you modify the various functions and their parameters, your results converge until you are satisfied that you have a trained, effective model.",
          "pos": [
            267,
            412
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1618,
        2264
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph3\"/> gives you an interactive, visual workspace to easily build, test, and iterate on a predictive analysis model. You drag-and-drop <bpt id=\"p2\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p3\"/>datasets<ept id=\"p3\">***</ept><ept id=\"p2\"/><ph id=\"ph4\"/> and analysis <bpt id=\"p4\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p5\"/>modules<ept id=\"p5\">***</ept><ept id=\"p4\"/><ph id=\"ph5\"/> onto an interactive <bpt id=\"p6\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p7\"/>canvas<ept id=\"p7\">***</ept><ept id=\"p6\"/>, connecting them together to form an <bpt id=\"p8\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p9\"/>experiment<ept id=\"p9\">***</ept><ept id=\"p8\"/>, which you <bpt id=\"p10\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p11\"/>run<ept id=\"p11\">***</ept><ept id=\"p10\"/><ph id=\"ph6\"/> in Machine Learning Studio. To iterate on your model design, you <bpt id=\"p12\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p13\"/>edit<ept id=\"p13\">***</ept><ept id=\"p12\"/><ph id=\"ph7\"/> the experiment, <bpt id=\"p14\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p15\"/>save<ept id=\"p15\">***</ept><ept id=\"p14\"/><ph id=\"ph8\"/> a copy if desired, and run it again. When you're ready, you can convert your <bpt id=\"p16\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p17\"/>training experiment<ept id=\"p17\">***</ept><ept id=\"p16\"/><ph id=\"ph9\"/> to a <bpt id=\"p18\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p19\"/>predictive experiment<ept id=\"p19\">***</ept><ept id=\"p18\"/>, and then <bpt id=\"p20\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p21\"/>publish<ept id=\"p21\">***</ept><ept id=\"p20\"/><ph id=\"ph10\"/> it as a <bpt id=\"p22\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p23\"/>web service<ept id=\"p23\">***</ept><ept id=\"p22\"/><ph id=\"ph11\"/> so that your model can be accessed by others.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph3\"/> gives you an interactive, visual workspace to easily build, test, and iterate on a predictive analysis model.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            195
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You drag-and-drop <bpt id=\"p2\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p3\"/>datasets<ept id=\"p3\">***</ept><ept id=\"p2\"/><ph id=\"ph4\"/> and analysis <bpt id=\"p4\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p5\"/>modules<ept id=\"p5\">***</ept><ept id=\"p4\"/><ph id=\"ph5\"/> onto an interactive <bpt id=\"p6\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p7\"/>canvas<ept id=\"p7\">***</ept><ept id=\"p6\"/>, connecting them together to form an <bpt id=\"p8\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p9\"/>experiment<ept id=\"p9\">***</ept><ept id=\"p8\"/>, which you <bpt id=\"p10\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p11\"/>run<ept id=\"p11\">***</ept><ept id=\"p10\"/><ph id=\"ph6\"/> in Machine Learning Studio.",
          "pos": [
            196,
            767
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "To iterate on your model design, you <bpt id=\"p12\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p13\"/>edit<ept id=\"p13\">***</ept><ept id=\"p12\"/><ph id=\"ph7\"/> the experiment, <bpt id=\"p14\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p15\"/>save<ept id=\"p15\">***</ept><ept id=\"p14\"/><ph id=\"ph8\"/> a copy if desired, and run it again.",
          "pos": [
            768,
            1047
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "When you're ready, you can convert your <bpt id=\"p16\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p17\"/>training experiment<ept id=\"p17\">***</ept><ept id=\"p16\"/><ph id=\"ph9\"/> to a <bpt id=\"p18\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p19\"/>predictive experiment<ept id=\"p19\">***</ept><ept id=\"p18\"/>, and then <bpt id=\"p20\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p21\"/>publish<ept id=\"p21\">***</ept><ept id=\"p20\"/><ph id=\"ph10\"/> it as a <bpt id=\"p22\">***</bpt><bpt id=\"p23\"/>web service<ept id=\"p23\">***</ept><ept id=\"p22\"/><ph id=\"ph11\"/> so that your model can be accessed by others.",
          "pos": [
            1048,
            1566
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2267,
        2496
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph12\">[AZURE.TIP]</ph><ph id=\"ph13\"/> To download and print a diagram that gives an overview of the capabilities of Machine Learning Studio, see <bpt id=\"p24\">[</bpt>Overview diagram of Azure Machine Learning Studio capabilities<ept id=\"p24\">](machine-learning-studio-overview-diagram.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2498,
        2622
      ],
      "content": "There is no programming required, just visually connecting datasets and modules to construct your predictive analysis model."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2624,
        2752
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph14\">![</ph>Azure ML Studio diagram: Create experiments, read data for many sources, write scored data, write models.<ph id=\"ph15\">][ml-studio-overview]</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2757,
        2797
      ],
      "content": "Get started with Machine Learning Studio"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2799,
        2991
      ],
      "content": "When you first enter <bpt id=\"p25\">[</bpt>Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p25\">](https://studio.azureml.net)</ept><ph id=\"ph16\"/> you see the <bpt id=\"p26\">**</bpt>Home<ept id=\"p26\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph17\"/> page. From here you can view documentation, videos, webinars, and find other valuable resources.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "When you first enter <bpt id=\"p25\">[</bpt>Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p25\">](https://studio.azureml.net)</ept><ph id=\"ph16\"/> you see the <bpt id=\"p26\">**</bpt>Home<ept id=\"p26\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph17\"/> page.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            211
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "From here you can view documentation, videos, webinars, and find other valuable resources.",
          "pos": [
            212,
            302
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2993,
        3086
      ],
      "content": "There are three tabs across the top: <bpt id=\"p27\">**</bpt>Home<ept id=\"p27\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph18\"/> (where you start), <bpt id=\"p28\">**</bpt>Studio<ept id=\"p28\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p29\">**</bpt>Gallery<ept id=\"p29\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3092,
        3098
      ],
      "content": "Studio"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3100,
        3276
      ],
      "content": "Click the <bpt id=\"p30\">**</bpt>Studio<ept id=\"p30\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph19\"/> tab and you'll be asked to sign in using your Microsoft account, or your work or school account. Once signed in, you'll see the following tabs on the left:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Click the <bpt id=\"p30\">**</bpt>Studio<ept id=\"p30\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph19\"/> tab and you'll be asked to sign in using your Microsoft account, or your work or school account.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            172
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Once signed in, you'll see the following tabs on the left:",
          "pos": [
            173,
            231
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3280,
        3358
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p31\">**</bpt>EXPERIMENTS<ept id=\"p31\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph20\"/> - Experiments that have been created, run, and saved as drafts"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3361,
        3437
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p32\">**</bpt>WEB SERVICES<ept id=\"p32\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph21\"/> - Web services that you have deployed from your experiments"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3440,
        3495
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p33\">**</bpt>NOTEBOOKS<ept id=\"p33\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph22\"/> - Jupyter notebooks that you have created"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3498,
        3556
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p34\">**</bpt>DATASETS<ept id=\"p34\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph23\"/> - Datasets that you have uploaded into Studio"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3559,
        3643
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p35\">**</bpt>TRAINED MODELS<ept id=\"p35\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph24\"/> - Models that you have trained in experiments and saved in Studio"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3646,
        3743
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p36\">**</bpt>SETTINGS<ept id=\"p36\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph25\"/> - A collection of settings that you can use to configure your account and resources."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3749,
        3756
      ],
      "content": "Gallery"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3758,
        3989
      ],
      "content": "Click the <bpt id=\"p37\">**</bpt>Gallery<ept id=\"p37\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph26\"/> tab and you'll be taken to the Cortana Analytics Gallery. The Gallery is a place where a community of data scientists and developers can share solutions created using components of the Cortana Analytics Suite.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Click the <bpt id=\"p37\">**</bpt>Gallery<ept id=\"p37\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph26\"/> tab and you'll be taken to the Cortana Analytics Gallery.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            134
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The Gallery is a place where a community of data scientists and developers can share solutions created using components of the Cortana Analytics Suite.",
          "pos": [
            135,
            286
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3991,
        4158
      ],
      "content": "For more information about the Gallery, see <bpt id=\"p38\">[</bpt>Share and discover solutions in the Cortana Analytics Gallery<ept id=\"p38\">](machine-learning-gallery-how-to-use-contribute-publish.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4163,
        4190
      ],
      "content": "Components of an experiment"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4192,
        4396
      ],
      "content": "An experiment consists of datasets that provide data to analytical modules, which you connect together to construct a predictive analysis model. Specifically, a valid experiment has these characteristics:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "An experiment consists of datasets that provide data to analytical modules, which you connect together to construct a predictive analysis model.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            144
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Specifically, a valid experiment has these characteristics:",
          "pos": [
            145,
            204
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4400,
        4454
      ],
      "content": "The experiment has at least one dataset and one module"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4457,
        4498
      ],
      "content": "Datasets may be connected only to modules"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4501,
        4561
      ],
      "content": "Modules may be connected to either datasets or other modules"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4564,
        4634
      ],
      "content": "All input ports for modules must have some connection to the data flow"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4637,
        4688
      ],
      "content": "All required parameters for each module must be set"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4690,
        4910
      ],
      "content": "You can create an experiment from scratch, or you can use an existing sample experiment as a template. For more information, see <bpt id=\"p39\">[</bpt>Use sample experiments to create new experiments<ept id=\"p39\">](machine-learning-sample-experiments.md)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "You can create an experiment from scratch, or you can use an existing sample experiment as a template.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            102
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p39\">[</bpt>Use sample experiments to create new experiments<ept id=\"p39\">](machine-learning-sample-experiments.md)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            103,
            260
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4912,
        5065
      ],
      "content": "For an example of creating a simple experiment, see <bpt id=\"p40\">[</bpt>Create a simple experiment in Azure Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p40\">](machine-learning-create-experiment.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5067,
        5269
      ],
      "content": "For a more complete walkthrough of creating a predictive analytics solution, see <bpt id=\"p41\">[</bpt>Develop a predictive solution with Azure Machine Learning<ept id=\"p41\">](machine-learning-walkthrough-develop-predictive-solution.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5275,
        5283
      ],
      "content": "Datasets"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5285,
        5594
      ],
      "content": "A dataset is data that has been uploaded to Machine Learning Studio so that it can be used in the modeling process. A number of sample datasets are included with Machine Learning Studio for you to experiment with, and you can upload more datasets as you need them. Here are some examples of included datasets:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "A dataset is data that has been uploaded to Machine Learning Studio so that it can be used in the modeling process.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            115
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "A number of sample datasets are included with Machine Learning Studio for you to experiment with, and you can upload more datasets as you need them.",
          "pos": [
            116,
            264
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Here are some examples of included datasets:",
          "pos": [
            265,
            309
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5598,
        5734
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p42\">**</bpt>MPG data for various automobiles<ept id=\"p42\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph27\"/> - Miles per gallon (MPG) values for automobiles identified by number of cylinders, horsepower, etc."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5737,
        5791
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p43\">**</bpt>Breast cancer data<ept id=\"p43\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph28\"/> - Breast cancer diagnosis data."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5794,
        5858
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p44\">**</bpt>Forest fires data<ept id=\"p44\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph29\"/> - Forest fire sizes in northeast Portugal."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5860,
        5964
      ],
      "content": "As you build an experiment you can choose from the list of datasets available to the left of the canvas."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5966,
        6138
      ],
      "content": "For a list of sample datasets included in Machine Learning Studio, see <bpt id=\"p45\">[</bpt>Use the sample data sets in Azure Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p45\">](machine-learning-use-sample-datasets.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6144,
        6151
      ],
      "content": "Modules"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6153,
        6388
      ],
      "content": "A module is an algorithm that you can perform on your data. Machine Learning Studio has a number of modules ranging from data ingress functions to training, scoring, and validation processes. Here are some examples of included modules:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "A module is an algorithm that you can perform on your data.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            59
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Machine Learning Studio has a number of modules ranging from data ingress functions to training, scoring, and validation processes.",
          "pos": [
            60,
            191
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Here are some examples of included modules:",
          "pos": [
            192,
            235
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6392,
        6505
      ],
      "content": "[Convert to ARFF][convert-to-arff] - Converts a .NET serialized dataset to Attribute-Relation File Format (ARFF)."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6508,
        6636
      ],
      "content": "[Compute Elementary Statistics][elementary-statistics] - Calculates elementary statistics such as mean, standard deviation, etc."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6639,
        6745
      ],
      "content": "[Linear Regression][linear-regression] - Creates an online gradient descent-based linear regression model."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6748,
        6829
      ],
      "content": "[Score Model][score-model] - Scores a trained classification or regression model."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6831,
        6934
      ],
      "content": "As you build an experiment you can choose from the list of modules available to the left of the canvas."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6938,
        7235
      ],
      "content": "A module may have a set of parameters that you can use to configure the module's internal algorithms. When you select a module on the canvas, the module's parameters are displayed in the <bpt id=\"p46\">**</bpt>Properties<ept id=\"p46\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph30\"/> pane to the right of the canvas. You can modify the parameters in that pane to tune your model.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "A module may have a set of parameters that you can use to configure the module's internal algorithms.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            101
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "When you select a module on the canvas, the module's parameters are displayed in the <bpt id=\"p46\">**</bpt>Properties<ept id=\"p46\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph30\"/> pane to the right of the canvas.",
          "pos": [
            102,
            289
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can modify the parameters in that pane to tune your model.",
          "pos": [
            290,
            352
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7237,
        7436
      ],
      "content": "For some help navigating through the large library of machine learning algorithms available, see <bpt id=\"p47\">[</bpt>How to choose algorithms for Microsoft Azure Machine Learning<ept id=\"p47\">](machine-learning-algorithm-choice.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7441,
        7485
      ],
      "content": "Deploying a predictive analytics web service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7487,
        7750
      ],
      "content": "Once your predictive analytics model is ready, you can deploy it as a web service right from Machine Learning Studio. For more details on this process, see <bpt id=\"p48\">[</bpt>Deploy an Azure Machine Learning web service<ept id=\"p48\">](machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service.md)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Once your predictive analytics model is ready, you can deploy it as a web service right from Machine Learning Studio.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            117
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more details on this process, see <bpt id=\"p48\">[</bpt>Deploy an Azure Machine Learning web service<ept id=\"p48\">](machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service.md)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            118,
            303
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7872,
        8267
      ],
      "content": "[convert-to-arff]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/62d2cece-d832-4a7a-a0bd-f01f03af0960/\n[elementary-statistics]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/3086b8d4-c895-45ba-8aa9-34f0c944d4d3/\n[linear-regression]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/31960a6f-789b-4cf7-88d6-2e1152c0bd1a/\n[score-model]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/401b4f92-e724-4d5a-be81-d5b0ff9bdb33/"
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"What is Azure Machine Learning Studio? | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Overview of Azure ML Studio, a drag-and-drop tool for quickly building models from a ready-to-use library of algorithms and modules.\"\n    keywords=\"azure machine learning,azure ml, ml studio\"\n    services=\"machine-learning\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"garyericson\"\n    manager=\"paulettm\"\n    editor=\"cgronlun\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\"\n    ms.workload=\"data-services\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"02/03/2016\"\n    ms.author=\"garye\"/>\n\n# What is Azure Machine Learning Studio?\n\nMicrosoft Azure Machine Learning Studio is a collaborative, drag-and-drop tool you can use to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions on your data. Machine Learning Studio publishes models as web services that can easily be consumed by custom apps or BI tools such as Excel.\n\nMachine Learning Studio is where data science, predictive analytics, cloud resources, and your data meet.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [machine-learning-free-trial](../../includes/machine-learning-free-trial.md)]\n\n## The Machine Learning Studio interactive workspace\n\nTo develop a predictive analysis model, you typically use data from one or more sources, transform and analyze that data through various data manipulation and statistical functions, and generate a set of results. Developing a model like this is an iterative process. As you modify the various functions and their parameters, your results converge until you are satisfied that you have a trained, effective model.\n\n**Azure Machine Learning Studio** gives you an interactive, visual workspace to easily build, test, and iterate on a predictive analysis model. You drag-and-drop ***datasets*** and analysis ***modules*** onto an interactive ***canvas***, connecting them together to form an ***experiment***, which you ***run*** in Machine Learning Studio. To iterate on your model design, you ***edit*** the experiment, ***save*** a copy if desired, and run it again. When you're ready, you can convert your ***training experiment*** to a ***predictive experiment***, and then ***publish*** it as a ***web service*** so that your model can be accessed by others.\n\n>[AZURE.TIP] To download and print a diagram that gives an overview of the capabilities of Machine Learning Studio, see [Overview diagram of Azure Machine Learning Studio capabilities](machine-learning-studio-overview-diagram.md).\n\nThere is no programming required, just visually connecting datasets and modules to construct your predictive analysis model.\n\n![Azure ML Studio diagram: Create experiments, read data for many sources, write scored data, write models.][ml-studio-overview]\n\n## Get started with Machine Learning Studio\n\nWhen you first enter [Machine Learning Studio](https://studio.azureml.net) you see the **Home** page. From here you can view documentation, videos, webinars, and find other valuable resources.\n\nThere are three tabs across the top: **Home** (where you start), **Studio**, and **Gallery**.\n\n### Studio\n\nClick the **Studio** tab and you'll be asked to sign in using your Microsoft account, or your work or school account. Once signed in, you'll see the following tabs on the left:\n\n- **EXPERIMENTS** - Experiments that have been created, run, and saved as drafts\n- **WEB SERVICES** - Web services that you have deployed from your experiments\n- **NOTEBOOKS** - Jupyter notebooks that you have created\n- **DATASETS** - Datasets that you have uploaded into Studio\n- **TRAINED MODELS** - Models that you have trained in experiments and saved in Studio\n- **SETTINGS** - A collection of settings that you can use to configure your account and resources.\n\n### Gallery\n\nClick the **Gallery** tab and you'll be taken to the Cortana Analytics Gallery. The Gallery is a place where a community of data scientists and developers can share solutions created using components of the Cortana Analytics Suite.\n\nFor more information about the Gallery, see [Share and discover solutions in the Cortana Analytics Gallery](machine-learning-gallery-how-to-use-contribute-publish.md).\n\n## Components of an experiment\n\nAn experiment consists of datasets that provide data to analytical modules, which you connect together to construct a predictive analysis model. Specifically, a valid experiment has these characteristics:\n\n- The experiment has at least one dataset and one module\n- Datasets may be connected only to modules\n- Modules may be connected to either datasets or other modules\n- All input ports for modules must have some connection to the data flow\n- All required parameters for each module must be set\n\nYou can create an experiment from scratch, or you can use an existing sample experiment as a template. For more information, see [Use sample experiments to create new experiments](machine-learning-sample-experiments.md).\n\nFor an example of creating a simple experiment, see [Create a simple experiment in Azure Machine Learning Studio](machine-learning-create-experiment.md).\n\nFor a more complete walkthrough of creating a predictive analytics solution, see [Develop a predictive solution with Azure Machine Learning](machine-learning-walkthrough-develop-predictive-solution.md).\n\n### Datasets\n\nA dataset is data that has been uploaded to Machine Learning Studio so that it can be used in the modeling process. A number of sample datasets are included with Machine Learning Studio for you to experiment with, and you can upload more datasets as you need them. Here are some examples of included datasets:\n\n- **MPG data for various automobiles** - Miles per gallon (MPG) values for automobiles identified by number of cylinders, horsepower, etc.\n- **Breast cancer data** - Breast cancer diagnosis data.\n- **Forest fires data** - Forest fire sizes in northeast Portugal.\n\nAs you build an experiment you can choose from the list of datasets available to the left of the canvas.\n\nFor a list of sample datasets included in Machine Learning Studio, see [Use the sample data sets in Azure Machine Learning Studio](machine-learning-use-sample-datasets.md).\n\n### Modules\n\nA module is an algorithm that you can perform on your data. Machine Learning Studio has a number of modules ranging from data ingress functions to training, scoring, and validation processes. Here are some examples of included modules:\n\n- [Convert to ARFF][convert-to-arff] - Converts a .NET serialized dataset to Attribute-Relation File Format (ARFF).\n- [Compute Elementary Statistics][elementary-statistics] - Calculates elementary statistics such as mean, standard deviation, etc.\n- [Linear Regression][linear-regression] - Creates an online gradient descent-based linear regression model.\n- [Score Model][score-model] - Scores a trained classification or regression model.\n\nAs you build an experiment you can choose from the list of modules available to the left of the canvas.  \n\nA module may have a set of parameters that you can use to configure the module's internal algorithms. When you select a module on the canvas, the module's parameters are displayed in the **Properties** pane to the right of the canvas. You can modify the parameters in that pane to tune your model.\n\nFor some help navigating through the large library of machine learning algorithms available, see [How to choose algorithms for Microsoft Azure Machine Learning](machine-learning-algorithm-choice.md).\n\n## Deploying a predictive analytics web service\n\nOnce your predictive analytics model is ready, you can deploy it as a web service right from Machine Learning Studio. For more details on this process, see [Deploy an Azure Machine Learning web service](machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service.md).\n\n[ml-studio-overview]:./media/machine-learning-what-is-ml-studio/azure-ml-studio-diagram.jpg\n\n<!-- Module References -->\n[convert-to-arff]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/62d2cece-d832-4a7a-a0bd-f01f03af0960/\n[elementary-statistics]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/3086b8d4-c895-45ba-8aa9-34f0c944d4d3/\n[linear-regression]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/31960a6f-789b-4cf7-88d6-2e1152c0bd1a/\n[score-model]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/401b4f92-e724-4d5a-be81-d5b0ff9bdb33/\n"
}