{"nodes":[{"content":"Design external help pages for detailed instructions and advice about your app.","pos":[37,116]},{"content":"Guidelines for designing external help pages","pos":[124,168]},{"content":"External help pages","pos":[218,237]},{"content":"Updated for Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps in Windows 10.","pos":[242,306]},{"content":"For Windows 8.x articles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>archive<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132)</ept>","pos":[307,399]},{"content":"If your app requires detailed help for complex content, consider hosting these instructions on a web page.","pos":[404,510]},{"pos":[615,646],"content":"When to use external help pages"},{"content":"External help pages are less convenient for general use or quick reference, but they are suitable for help content that is too extensive to be incorporated into the app itself, as well as for tutorials and instructions for advanced functions of an app that won't be used by its general audience.","pos":[648,943]},{"content":"If your help content is brief or specific enough to be displayed in-app, you should do so.","pos":[945,1035]},{"content":"Avoid directing users outside of the app for help unless it's necessary.","pos":[1036,1108]},{"pos":[1211,1241],"content":"Navigating external help pages"},{"content":"When a user is directed to an external help page, the experience should reflect one of two scenarios:","pos":[1243,1344]},{"content":"They are linked directly to the page that corresponds with their known issue.","pos":[1349,1426]},{"content":"This is contextual help, and should be used whenever possible.","pos":[1427,1489]},{"content":"They are linked to a general help page that provides a clear display of categories and subcategories to choose from.","pos":[1494,1610]},{"content":"Providing users with a way to search your help can be useful, but don't make this search the only way of navigating your help.","pos":[1612,1738]},{"content":"It can sometimes be difficult for users to describe their problems, which can make searching difficult.","pos":[1739,1842]},{"content":"Users should be able to quickly find pages relevant to their problems without needing to search.","pos":[1843,1939]},{"pos":[2052,2087],"content":"Tutorials and detailed walkthroughs"},{"content":"External help pages are the ideal place to provide users with tutorials and walkthroughs, whether video or textual.","pos":[2089,2204]},{"content":"Tutorials should focus on more complicated ideas and advanced functions.","pos":[2209,2281]},{"content":"Users shouldn't need a tutorial to use your app.","pos":[2282,2330]},{"content":"Make sure that these tutorials are displayed differently from standard help instructions.","pos":[2335,2424]},{"content":"Users who are looking for advanced instructions are more eager to search for them than users who want straightforward solutions to their problems.","pos":[2425,2571]},{"content":"Consider linking to tutorials from both a directory and from individual help pages that correspond to each tutorial.","pos":[2576,2692]},{"pos":[2730,2746],"content":"Related articles"},{"content":"Guidelines for app help","pos":[2751,2774]}],"content":"---\nauthor: QuinnRadich\nDescription: Design external help pages for detailed instructions and advice about your app.\ntitle: Guidelines for designing external help pages\nlabel: External help\ntemplate: detail.hbs\n---\n\n# External help pages\n\n\\[ Updated for Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps in Windows 10. For Windows 8.x articles, see the [archive](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132) \\]\n\nIf your app requires detailed help for complex content, consider hosting these instructions on a web page.\n\n## <span id=\"when_to_use_external_help_pages\"></span><span id=\"WHEN_TO_USE_EXTERNAL_HELP_PAGES\"></span>When to use external help pages\n\nExternal help pages are less convenient for general use or quick reference, but they are suitable for help content that is too extensive to be incorporated into the app itself, as well as for tutorials and instructions for advanced functions of an app that won't be used by its general audience.\n\nIf your help content is brief or specific enough to be displayed in-app, you should do so. Avoid directing users outside of the app for help unless it's necessary.\n\n## <span id=\"navigating_external_help_pages\"></span><span id=\"NAVIGATING_EXTERNAL_HELP_PAGES\"></span>Navigating external help pages\n\nWhen a user is directed to an external help page, the experience should reflect one of two scenarios:\n-   They are linked directly to the page that corresponds with their known issue. This is contextual help, and should be used whenever possible.\n-   They are linked to a general help page that provides a clear display of categories and subcategories to choose from.\n\nProviding users with a way to search your help can be useful, but don't make this search the only way of navigating your help. It can sometimes be difficult for users to describe their problems, which can make searching difficult. Users should be able to quickly find pages relevant to their problems without needing to search.\n\n## <span id=\"tutorials_and_detailed_walkthroughs\"></span><span id=\"TUTORIALS_AND_DETAILED_WALKTHROUGHS\"></span>Tutorials and detailed walkthroughs\n\nExternal help pages are the ideal place to provide users with tutorials and walkthroughs, whether video or textual.\n-   Tutorials should focus on more complicated ideas and advanced functions. Users shouldn't need a tutorial to use your app.\n-   Make sure that these tutorials are displayed differently from standard help instructions. Users who are looking for advanced instructions are more eager to search for them than users who want straightforward solutions to their problems.\n-   Consider linking to tutorials from both a directory and from individual help pages that correspond to each tutorial.\n\n## <span id=\"related_topics\"></span>Related articles\n\n* [Guidelines for app help](guidelines-for-app-help.md)\n"}