{"nodes":[{"content":"To view performance data for the ad units in your apps, use the app-level and account-level advertising performance reports on the Windows Dev Center dashboard.","pos":[30,190]},{"content":"Advertising performance report","pos":[198,228]},{"content":"Advertising performance report","pos":[285,315]},{"content":"To view performance data for the ad units in your apps, you can use the following reports on the Windows Dev Center dashboard:","pos":[318,444]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>App-level advertising performance report<ept id=\"p1\">](advertising-performance-report.md#app-level-advertising-performance-report)</ept>.","pos":[450,569]},{"content":"This report provides performance data for the Microsoft ad units in the currently selected app in the dashboard.","pos":[570,682]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Account-level advertising performance report<ept id=\"p1\">](advertising-performance-report.md#account-level-advertising-performance-report)</ept>.","pos":[687,814]},{"content":"This report provides detailed performance data for Microsoft ad units and community ads for all apps that are registered to your developer account.","pos":[815,962]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dashboard-level advertising performance report<ept id=\"p1\">](advertising-performance-report.md#dashboard-level-advertising-performance-report)</ept>.","pos":[967,1098]},{"content":"This report on your <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dashboard overview<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page provides a summary of performance data for Microsoft ad units in all apps that are registered to your developer account.","pos":[1099,1267]},{"content":"By default, the reports are filtered on performance from the last 30 days, on all devices.","pos":[1269,1359]},{"content":"To change these filters, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Page filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and choose a different time frame or an individual device type.","pos":[1360,1471]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> There may be differences between advertising performance reports in Dev Center and pubCenter.","pos":[1476,1578]},{"content":"Advertising performance data in Dev Center is aggregated based on UTC (not your particular time zone), while pubCenter reports are aggregated based on your particular time zone.","pos":[1579,1756]},{"content":"The following sections provide more details about these reports.","pos":[1758,1822]},{"content":"App-level advertising performance report","pos":[1827,1867]},{"content":"This page provides performance data in graph, world map, and table form for the Microsoft ad units in the currently selected app in the dashboard.","pos":[1869,2015]},{"content":"To view this report, select one of your apps in the dashboard and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Analytics<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Advertising performance<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> in the navigation pane.","pos":[2016,2158]},{"content":"The data is obtained from the following performance metrics we track for the ads in your app:","pos":[2160,2253]},{"pos":[2259,2358],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Estimated revenue<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The estimated amount of money you received from the ads running on your app."},{"pos":[2363,2413],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>eCPM<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Effective cost per thousand impressions."},{"pos":[2418,2489],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Requests<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of times an ad request was sent from your app."},{"pos":[2494,2559],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Impressions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of times an ad was shown in your app."},{"pos":[2564,2653],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Fill rate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The percentage of ad requests sent from your app in which an ad was shown."},{"pos":[2658,2727],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Clicks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of times someone clicked on an ad in your app."},{"pos":[2732,2845],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CTR<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Click-through rate, meaning the number of times an ad was clicked, divided by the number of impressions."},{"content":"To review all these performance metrics for the ad units in your app, refer to the table below the graph and map views.","pos":[2847,2966]},{"content":"To analyze the data for one of these metrics in a graph or world map view, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Graph<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Map<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2968,3070]},{"content":"Click the headers above the graph or map to switch between the different metrics.","pos":[3071,3152]},{"content":"By default, the graph and map views show performance data for all of the ad units in your app, but you can click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Choose ad units<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to select up to six individual ad units to compare.","pos":[3153,3337]},{"content":"In the map view, darker shades represent higher values and lighter shades represent lower values.","pos":[3339,3436]},{"content":"You can hover over a specific country or region on the map to analyze the value of the selected metric.","pos":[3437,3540]},{"content":"You can also zoom in on any area of the map to view data for smaller countries.","pos":[3541,3620]},{"content":"Account-level advertising performance report","pos":[3625,3669]},{"content":"This page provides performance data for Microsoft ad units and community ads used in apps that are registered to your developer account.","pos":[3671,3807]},{"content":"To view this report, go to your dashboard overview page and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Advertising performance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the navigation pane.","pos":[3808,3925]},{"content":"This page includes the following sections.","pos":[3927,3969]},{"content":"Microsoft Advertising","pos":[3975,3996]},{"content":"This report provides performance data for all the Microsoft ad units used in your apps.","pos":[3998,4085]},{"content":"This report also includes performance data for any pubCenter ad units that were not successfully mapped to your Dev Center apps.","pos":[4086,4214]},{"content":"This report shows the same seven performance metrics and views (graph, world map, and table) as the app-level advertising performance report described above.","pos":[4216,4373]},{"content":"You can apply the following filters to this report:","pos":[4374,4425]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All ad units<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4431,4448]},{"content":"When you select this filter, you can choose to display data from all ad units or from up to six specific ad units.","pos":[4449,4563]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All apps<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4568,4581]},{"content":"When you select this filter, you can choose to display data from all apps or from up to six specific apps.","pos":[4582,4688]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Individual app<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4693,4712]},{"content":"When you select an app, you can choose to display data from all ad units used by the app or from up to six specific ad units used by the app.","pos":[4713,4854]},{"content":"If you created ad units for an app using Microsoft pubCenter, it’s possible that not all of them were mapped successfully to your apps in Dev Center.","pos":[4856,5005]},{"content":"In this report, these ad units are associated with app names that you specified in pubCenter, with the string <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>(pubCenter)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> appended to the app name.","pos":[5006,5157]},{"content":"If you created ad units for an app using pubCenter, and you don’t see data for them in either report page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Link a pubCenter account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to link that account to your Dev Center account.","pos":[5159,5349]},{"content":"Enter the email address you associated with this pubCenter account and your account linking code.","pos":[5350,5447]},{"content":"You can find the account linking code by signing into this pubCenter account and going to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>My information<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[5448,5566]},{"pos":[5568,5714],"content":"For more information about migrating pubCenter accounts to Dev Center, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>pubCenter-DevCenter integration<ept id=\"p1\">](pubcenter-dev-center-integration.md)</ept>."},{"content":"Microsoft community ads","pos":[5720,5743]},{"content":"This section provides performance data in graph and world map form for community ads in the currently selected app in the dashboard.","pos":[5745,5877]},{"content":"For more information about community ads, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About community ads<ept id=\"p1\">](about-community-ads.md)</ept>.","pos":[5878,5970]},{"content":"The data is obtained from the following performance metrics we track for the ads in your app:","pos":[5972,6065]},{"pos":[6071,6151],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Requests<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of times a community ad request was sent from your app."},{"pos":[6156,6255],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Fill rate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The percentage of community ad requests sent from your app in which an ad was shown."},{"pos":[6260,6338],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Clicks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of times someone clicked on a community ad in your app."},{"pos":[6343,6465],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CTR<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Click-through rate, meaning the number of times a community ad was clicked, divided by the number of impressions."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Credits earned<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of community ad credits you have earned from this app.","pos":[6470,6555]},{"content":"For more details about how credits are earned, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About community ads<ept id=\"p1\">](about-community-ads.md)</ept>.","pos":[6556,6653]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Credits spent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of community ad credits you have spent for this app.","pos":[6658,6740]},{"content":"For more details about how credits are spent, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About community ads<ept id=\"p1\">](about-community-ads.md)</ept>.","pos":[6741,6837]},{"content":"To analyze the data for one of these metrics in a graph or world map view, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Graph<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Map<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[6839,6941]},{"content":"Click the headers above the graph or map to switch between the different metrics.","pos":[6942,7023]},{"content":"In the map view, darker shades represent higher values and lighter shades represent lower values.","pos":[7024,7121]},{"content":"You can hover over a specific country or region on the map to analyze the value of the selected metric.","pos":[7122,7225]},{"content":"You can also zoom in on any area of the map to view data for smaller countries.","pos":[7226,7305]},{"content":"Dashboard-level advertising performance report","pos":[7310,7356]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Advertising performance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section on your <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Dashboard overview<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page provides a summary of the performance data for all the Microsoft ad units used in your apps.","pos":[7358,7526]},{"content":"This report is similar to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Advertising<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section in the account-level advertising performance report, with the following differences:","pos":[7527,7675]},{"content":"It provides the data only in graph form.","pos":[7681,7721]},{"content":"For a table version of the data, use the account-level advertising performance report.","pos":[7722,7808]},{"content":"The only filters provided are for all apps or for individual apps.","pos":[7813,7879]},{"content":"To filter by ad units, use the account-level advertising performance report.","pos":[7880,7956]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: To view performance data for the ad units in your apps, use the app-level and account-level advertising performance reports on the Windows Dev Center dashboard.\ntitle: Advertising performance report\nms.assetid: 32E555C3-C34D-4503-82BB-4C3F5CAE4500\n---\n\n# Advertising performance report\n\n\nTo view performance data for the ad units in your apps, you can use the following reports on the Windows Dev Center dashboard:\n\n-   [App-level advertising performance report](advertising-performance-report.md#app-level-advertising-performance-report). This report provides performance data for the Microsoft ad units in the currently selected app in the dashboard.\n-   [Account-level advertising performance report](advertising-performance-report.md#account-level-advertising-performance-report). This report provides detailed performance data for Microsoft ad units and community ads for all apps that are registered to your developer account.\n-   [Dashboard-level advertising performance report](advertising-performance-report.md#dashboard-level-advertising-performance-report). This report on your **Dashboard overview** page provides a summary of performance data for Microsoft ad units in all apps that are registered to your developer account.\n\nBy default, the reports are filtered on performance from the last 30 days, on all devices. To change these filters, click **Page filters** and choose a different time frame or an individual device type. \n\n> **Note** There may be differences between advertising performance reports in Dev Center and pubCenter. Advertising performance data in Dev Center is aggregated based on UTC (not your particular time zone), while pubCenter reports are aggregated based on your particular time zone.\n\nThe following sections provide more details about these reports.\n\n## App-level advertising performance report\n\nThis page provides performance data in graph, world map, and table form for the Microsoft ad units in the currently selected app in the dashboard. To view this report, select one of your apps in the dashboard and click **Analytics** &gt; **Advertising performance** in the navigation pane.\n\nThe data is obtained from the following performance metrics we track for the ads in your app:\n\n-   **Estimated revenue**: The estimated amount of money you received from the ads running on your app.\n-   **eCPM**: Effective cost per thousand impressions.\n-   **Requests**: The number of times an ad request was sent from your app.\n-   **Impressions**: The number of times an ad was shown in your app.\n-   **Fill rate**: The percentage of ad requests sent from your app in which an ad was shown.\n-   **Clicks**: The number of times someone clicked on an ad in your app.\n-   **CTR**: Click-through rate, meaning the number of times an ad was clicked, divided by the number of impressions.\n\nTo review all these performance metrics for the ad units in your app, refer to the table below the graph and map views.\n\nTo analyze the data for one of these metrics in a graph or world map view, click **Graph** or **Map**. Click the headers above the graph or map to switch between the different metrics. By default, the graph and map views show performance data for all of the ad units in your app, but you can click **Choose ad units** to select up to six individual ad units to compare.\n\nIn the map view, darker shades represent higher values and lighter shades represent lower values. You can hover over a specific country or region on the map to analyze the value of the selected metric. You can also zoom in on any area of the map to view data for smaller countries.\n\n## Account-level advertising performance report\n\nThis page provides performance data for Microsoft ad units and community ads used in apps that are registered to your developer account. To view this report, go to your dashboard overview page and click **Advertising performance** in the navigation pane.\n\nThis page includes the following sections.\n\n### Microsoft Advertising\n\nThis report provides performance data for all the Microsoft ad units used in your apps. This report also includes performance data for any pubCenter ad units that were not successfully mapped to your Dev Center apps.\n\nThis report shows the same seven performance metrics and views (graph, world map, and table) as the app-level advertising performance report described above. You can apply the following filters to this report:\n\n-   **All ad units**. When you select this filter, you can choose to display data from all ad units or from up to six specific ad units.\n-   **All apps**. When you select this filter, you can choose to display data from all apps or from up to six specific apps.\n-   **Individual app**. When you select an app, you can choose to display data from all ad units used by the app or from up to six specific ad units used by the app.\n\nIf you created ad units for an app using Microsoft pubCenter, it’s possible that not all of them were mapped successfully to your apps in Dev Center. In this report, these ad units are associated with app names that you specified in pubCenter, with the string **(pubCenter)** appended to the app name.\n\nIf you created ad units for an app using pubCenter, and you don’t see data for them in either report page, click **Link a pubCenter account** to link that account to your Dev Center account. Enter the email address you associated with this pubCenter account and your account linking code. You can find the account linking code by signing into this pubCenter account and going to the **My information** page.\n\nFor more information about migrating pubCenter accounts to Dev Center, see [pubCenter-DevCenter integration](pubcenter-dev-center-integration.md).\n\n### Microsoft community ads\n\nThis section provides performance data in graph and world map form for community ads in the currently selected app in the dashboard. For more information about community ads, see [About community ads](about-community-ads.md).\n\nThe data is obtained from the following performance metrics we track for the ads in your app:\n\n-   **Requests**: The number of times a community ad request was sent from your app.\n-   **Fill rate**: The percentage of community ad requests sent from your app in which an ad was shown.\n-   **Clicks**: The number of times someone clicked on a community ad in your app.\n-   **CTR**: Click-through rate, meaning the number of times a community ad was clicked, divided by the number of impressions.\n-   **Credits earned**: The number of community ad credits you have earned from this app. For more details about how credits are earned, see [About community ads](about-community-ads.md).\n-   **Credits spent**: The number of community ad credits you have spent for this app. For more details about how credits are spent, see [About community ads](about-community-ads.md).\n\nTo analyze the data for one of these metrics in a graph or world map view, click **Graph** or **Map**. Click the headers above the graph or map to switch between the different metrics. In the map view, darker shades represent higher values and lighter shades represent lower values. You can hover over a specific country or region on the map to analyze the value of the selected metric. You can also zoom in on any area of the map to view data for smaller countries.\n\n## Dashboard-level advertising performance report\n\nThe **Advertising performance** section on your **Dashboard overview** page provides a summary of the performance data for all the Microsoft ad units used in your apps. This report is similar to the **Microsoft Advertising** section in the account-level advertising performance report, with the following differences:\n\n-   It provides the data only in graph form. For a table version of the data, use the account-level advertising performance report.\n-   The only filters provided are for all apps or for individual apps. To filter by ad units, use the account-level advertising performance report.\n\n\n \n\n \n"}