{"nodes":[{"content":"What's new for UWP on Xbox One","pos":[28,58]},{"content":"Highlights new features for UWP on Xbox One apps.","pos":[72,121]},{"content":"What's new in the June 2016 Developer Preview for UWP on Xbox One","pos":[140,205]},{"pos":[207,377],"content":"The June 2016 Developer Preview release of Universal Windows Platform (UWP) on Xbox One contains the following new features, updates to existing features, and bug fixes."},{"content":"Mouse mode is now enabled by default","pos":[382,418]},{"content":"Mouse mode is now enabled by default for all apps.","pos":[419,469]},{"content":"For more information about mouse mode, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Designing for Xbox and TV<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/input-and-devices/designing-for-tv?f=255&amp;MSPPError=-2147217396#mouse-mode)</ept>.","pos":[470,662]},{"content":"Extended UWP API surface area is now functional on the console","pos":[667,729]},{"content":"Additional UWP APIs are now functional on the Xbox console.","pos":[730,789]},{"content":"For more information about UWP API support, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>UWP features that aren't yet supported on Xbox<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=760755)</ept>.","pos":[790,935]},{"content":"Background music and audio capabilities","pos":[941,980]},{"content":"You can now play music and audio from an app that is running the background.","pos":[981,1057]},{"content":"XAML improvements","pos":[1062,1079]},{"content":"The following improvements have been made to the XAML platform:","pos":[1080,1143]},{"content":"The focus rectangle is now styled for a television 10-foot experience.","pos":[1148,1218]},{"content":"Xbox sounds are now embedded in the XAML platform.","pos":[1223,1273]},{"content":"XY focus navigation between UI elements has been improved.","pos":[1278,1336]},{"content":"See also","pos":[1342,1350]},{"content":"UWP on Xbox One","pos":[1354,1369]},{"content":"Known Issues","pos":[1384,1396]}],"content":"---\nauthor: v-angraf\ntitle: What's new for UWP on Xbox One\ndescription: Highlights new features for UWP on Xbox One apps.\narea: Xbox\n---\n\n# What's new in the June 2016 Developer Preview for UWP on Xbox One\n\nThe June 2016 Developer Preview release of Universal Windows Platform (UWP) on Xbox One contains the following new features, \nupdates to existing features, and bug fixes.\n\n## Mouse mode is now enabled by default\nMouse mode is now enabled by default for all apps. For more information about mouse mode, see \n[Designing for Xbox and TV](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/input-and-devices/designing-for-tv?f=255&MSPPError=-2147217396#mouse-mode).\n\n## Extended UWP API surface area is now functional on the console\nAdditional UWP APIs are now functional on the Xbox console. For more information about UWP API support, see \n[UWP features that aren't yet supported on Xbox](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=760755). \n\n## Background music and audio capabilities\nYou can now play music and audio from an app that is running the background.\n\n## XAML improvements\nThe following improvements have been made to the XAML platform:\n-   The focus rectangle is now styled for a television 10-foot experience.\n-   Xbox sounds are now embedded in the XAML platform.\n-   XY focus navigation between UI elements has been improved. \n\n## See also\n- [UWP on Xbox One](index.md)\n- [Known Issues](known-issues.md)\n"}