{"nodes":[{"content":"The IAP acquisitions report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you see how many IAPs you've sold, along with demographic and platform details.","pos":[30,178]},{"content":"IAP acquisitions report","pos":[186,209]},{"content":"IAP acquisitions report","pos":[266,289]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IAP acquisitions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you see how many IAPs you've sold, along with demographic and platform details.","pos":[292,444]},{"content":"You can view this data in your dashboard, or <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>download the report<ept id=\"p1\">](download-analytic-reports.md)</ept> to view offline.","pos":[445,558]},{"content":"Alternatively, you can programmatically retrieve this data by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Store analytics REST API<ept id=\"p1\">](../monetize/access-analytics-data-using-windows-store-services.md)</ept>.","pos":[559,733]},{"content":"In this report, an IAP acquisition means a customer has purchased an IAP from you.","pos":[735,817]},{"content":"Multiple purchases of the same consumable IAP by the same customer are counted as separate IAP acquisitions.","pos":[818,926]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  The <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>IAP acquisitions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> report does not include data about refunds, reversals, chargebacks, etc. To estimate your app proceeds, visit <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Payout summary<ept id=\"p3\">](payout-summary.md)</ept>.","pos":[930,1116]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reserved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, click the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Download reserved transactions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> link.","pos":[1117,1196]},{"content":"Apply filters","pos":[1201,1214]},{"content":"Near the top of the page, you can expand <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to filter all of the data on this page by date range and/or by device type.","pos":[1217,1351]},{"content":"You can also filter to show only data for a specific IAP.","pos":[1352,1409]},{"pos":[1415,1514],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default filter is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Last 30 days<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, but you can expand this up to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Last 12 months<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IAP<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default filter is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All IAPs<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[1519,1563]},{"content":"If you want to show acquisition data for only one of your IAPs, you can choose a specific one here.","pos":[1564,1663]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Device type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default setting is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All devices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[1668,1724]},{"content":"If you want to show data for IAP acquisitions from a certain device type only, you can choose a specific one here.","pos":[1725,1839]},{"pos":[1841,1951],"content":"The info in the charts listed below will reflect the period of time selected in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section."},{"content":"The info in all of the charts listed below will reflect the period of time selected in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section.","pos":[1953,2070]},{"content":"By default this will include data for all device types, unless you've used <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to choose only one.","pos":[2071,2183]},{"content":"IAP acquisitions","pos":[2188,2204]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IAP acquisitions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart shows the number of daily or weekly acquisitions of your IAPs over the selected period of time.","pos":[2207,2333]},{"content":"(When you use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to filter the data over a longer duration, the data will be grouped by week.)","pos":[2334,2443]},{"content":"You can also see the lifetime number of acquisitions for your IAPs.","pos":[2445,2512]},{"content":"This shows the cumulative total of all acquisitions, starting from when your app was first published.","pos":[2513,2614]},{"content":"The chart also shows the price that a customer paid to acquire the IAP.","pos":[2616,2687]},{"content":"You can optionally filter the results by market and/or by OS version.","pos":[2689,2758]},{"content":"Top IAPs","pos":[2763,2771]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Top IAPs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart shows the total number of acquisitions for each of your IAPs over the selected period of time by market.","pos":[2774,2901]},{"content":"By default, we show you the IAP which had the most acquisitions on top and continue downward from there.","pos":[2902,3006]},{"content":"You can reverse this order by toggling the arrow in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Acquisitions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column of this chart.","pos":[3007,3101]},{"content":"Markets","pos":[3106,3113]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Markets<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart shows the total number of IAP acquisitions over the selected period of time by market.","pos":[3116,3224]},{"content":"By default, we show you the market which had the most acquisitions on top and continue downward from there.","pos":[3225,3332]},{"content":"You can reverse this order by toggling the arrow in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Acquisitions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column of this chart.","pos":[3333,3427]},{"content":"Customer demographic","pos":[3432,3452]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customer demographic<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart shows demographic info about the people who acquired your app.","pos":[3455,3552]},{"content":"You can see how many acquisitions (over the selected period of time) were made by people in a certain age group and by which gender.","pos":[3553,3685]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Some customers have opted not to share this info.","pos":[3689,3748]},{"content":"If we were unable to determine the age group or gender, the acquisition is categorized as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Unknown<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[3749,3851]},{"content":"OS version","pos":[3856,3866]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OS version<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart shows the total number of acquisitions based on the customer's operating system (or via <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>volume acquisition by organizations<ept id=\"p2\">](organizational-licensing.md)</ept>).","pos":[3869,4050]},{"content":"In some cases we may not be able to determine this info.","pos":[4051,4107]},{"content":"In that case, the OS version will be listed as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Unknown<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4108,4167]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: The IAP acquisitions report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you see how many IAPs you've sold, along with demographic and platform details.\ntitle: IAP acquisitions report\nms.assetid: F2DF9188-0A98-4AC3-81C0-3E2C37B15582\n---\n\n# IAP acquisitions report\n\n\nThe **IAP acquisitions** report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you see how many IAPs you've sold, along with demographic and platform details. You can view this data in your dashboard, or [download the report](download-analytic-reports.md) to view offline. Alternatively, you can programmatically retrieve this data by using the [Windows Store analytics REST API](../monetize/access-analytics-data-using-windows-store-services.md).\n\nIn this report, an IAP acquisition means a customer has purchased an IAP from you. Multiple purchases of the same consumable IAP by the same customer are counted as separate IAP acquisitions.\n\n> **Important**  The **IAP acquisitions** report does not include data about refunds, reversals, chargebacks, etc. To estimate your app proceeds, visit [Payout summary](payout-summary.md). In the **Reserved** section, click the **Download reserved transactions** link.\n\n## Apply filters\n\n\nNear the top of the page, you can expand **Apply filters** to filter all of the data on this page by date range and/or by device type. You can also filter to show only data for a specific IAP.\n\n-   **Date**: The default filter is **Last 30 days**, but you can expand this up to **Last 12 months**.\n-   **IAP**: The default filter is **All IAPs**. If you want to show acquisition data for only one of your IAPs, you can choose a specific one here.\n-   **Device type**: The default setting is **All devices**. If you want to show data for IAP acquisitions from a certain device type only, you can choose a specific one here.\n\nThe info in the charts listed below will reflect the period of time selected in the **Apply filters** section.\n\nThe info in all of the charts listed below will reflect the period of time selected in the **Apply filters** section. By default this will include data for all device types, unless you've used **Apply filters** to choose only one.\n\n## IAP acquisitions\n\n\nThe **IAP acquisitions** chart shows the number of daily or weekly acquisitions of your IAPs over the selected period of time. (When you use **Apply filters** to filter the data over a longer duration, the data will be grouped by week.)\n\nYou can also see the lifetime number of acquisitions for your IAPs. This shows the cumulative total of all acquisitions, starting from when your app was first published.\n\nThe chart also shows the price that a customer paid to acquire the IAP.\n\nYou can optionally filter the results by market and/or by OS version.\n\n## Top IAPs\n\n\nThe **Top IAPs** chart shows the total number of acquisitions for each of your IAPs over the selected period of time by market. By default, we show you the IAP which had the most acquisitions on top and continue downward from there. You can reverse this order by toggling the arrow in the **Acquisitions** column of this chart.\n\n## Markets\n\n\nThe **Markets** chart shows the total number of IAP acquisitions over the selected period of time by market. By default, we show you the market which had the most acquisitions on top and continue downward from there. You can reverse this order by toggling the arrow in the **Acquisitions** column of this chart.\n\n## Customer demographic\n\n\nThe **Customer demographic** chart shows demographic info about the people who acquired your app. You can see how many acquisitions (over the selected period of time) were made by people in a certain age group and by which gender.\n\n> **Note**  Some customers have opted not to share this info. If we were unable to determine the age group or gender, the acquisition is categorized as **Unknown**.\n\n## OS version\n\n\nThe **OS version** chart shows the total number of acquisitions based on the customer's operating system (or via [volume acquisition by organizations](organizational-licensing.md)). In some cases we may not be able to determine this info. In that case, the OS version will be listed as **Unknown**.\n\n \n\n \n"}