{"nodes":[{"content":"Getting started with UWP for iOS developers","pos":[35,78]},{"content":"Getting started with UWP for iOS developers","pos":[86,129]},{"content":"Getting started with UWP for iOS developers","pos":[186,229]},{"content":"Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10.","pos":[234,269]},{"content":"For Windows 8.x articles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>archive<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132)</ept>","pos":[270,362]},{"content":"If you're an iOS developer considering developing for Windows 10, these docs are a great place to start.","pos":[367,471]},{"content":"They'll introduce you to some of the concepts you'll need to know as you get started writing apps, and they'll cover how you can publish your work on the Windows Store.","pos":[472,640]},{"content":"In this section, we'll start gradually, and examine how to use Microsoft Visual Studio and the C# programming language to create a trivial app, and in particular how the process might vary from the tools you currently use.","pos":[642,864]},{"content":"(Not a C# fan?","pos":[865,879]},{"content":"Don't worry, other programming languages and tools are available, and we'll touch on this in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting started: Choosing a programming language<ept id=\"p1\">](getting-started-choosing-a-programming-language.md)</ept>).","pos":[880,1077]},{"content":"Windows 10 introduces a new platform for creating engaging apps on desktop, laptop, tablet, phone devices and more.","pos":[1079,1194]},{"content":"As Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps provide many unique capabilities, a straight port of your iOS app will miss out on these features.","pos":[1195,1334]},{"content":"We therefore encourage you to try out the new controls and abilities to see how they will make your life as a developer easier, and new apps possible.","pos":[1335,1485]},{"content":"The bottom line is this: don't just port your app, but <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>reimagine<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> your app, and take advantage of new features and new devices.","pos":[1487,1617]},{"content":"Don't settle for the lowest common denominator, but create rich experiences that use unique Windows 10 features, such as live tiles, notifications, and interacting with Cortana.","pos":[1618,1795]},{"content":"To get started with these walkthroughs, you'll need a computer with both Windows 10 and Microsoft Visual Studio installed.","pos":[1797,1919]},{"content":"You can download these from the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Developer downloads for programming Windows Store apps<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=302144)</ept>.","pos":[1920,2058]},{"content":"Don't have a PC?","pos":[2059,2075]},{"content":"Don't worry, you can use your Mac: see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Installing Windows and the dev tools on your Mac<ept id=\"p1\">](setting-up-your-mac-with-windows-10.md)</ept>.","pos":[2076,2206]},{"content":"Topic","pos":[2210,2215]},{"content":"Description","pos":[2218,2229]},{"content":"Getting started: Creating a project","pos":[2259,2294]},{"content":"Visual Studio is to Windows as Xcode is to iOS and Mac OS.","pos":[2337,2395]},{"content":"In this walkthrough, we help you get comfortable using Visual Studio.","pos":[2396,2465]},{"content":"Getting started: Choosing a programming language","pos":[2471,2519]},{"content":"Before we go any further, you should know about the programming languages that you can choose from when you develop UWP apps.","pos":[2575,2700]},{"content":"Getting started: Getting around in Visual Studio","pos":[2706,2754]},{"content":"Let's now get back to the project that we created earlier, and look at how you might find your way around the Visual Studio integrated development environment (IDE).","pos":[2810,2975]},{"content":"Getting started: Common Controls","pos":[2981,3013]},{"content":"Here are some common controls you'll be using in your apps, and their iOS equivalents.","pos":[3053,3139]},{"content":"Getting started: Navigation","pos":[3145,3172]},{"content":"One of the ways to manage this navigation in a Windows 10 app is to use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Frame<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/br242682)</ept> class.","pos":[3207,3355]},{"content":"The following walkthrough shows you how to try this out.","pos":[3356,3412]},{"content":"Getting started: Animation","pos":[3418,3444]},{"content":"Animations in Windows apps can be created programmatically, but they can also be defined declaratively with Extensible Application Markup Language (XAML).","pos":[3478,3632]},{"content":"Getting started: What next?","pos":[3638,3665]},{"content":"With this basic information, you can now start writing more interesting Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps.","pos":[3699,3809]},{"content":"For your next steps, have a read through the following topics, and then fire up Visual Studio and start writing some code!","pos":[3810,3932]},{"content":"Windows app concept mapping","pos":[3938,3965]},{"content":"How to think of iOS concepts in terms of Windows (and Android) features","pos":[4038,4109]}],"content":"---\nauthor: mcleblanc\ndescription: Getting started with UWP for iOS developers\ntitle: Getting started with UWP for iOS developers\nms.assetid: 9F67068B-E578-4C70-B3E0-DFF150FA9BDD\n---\n\n# Getting started with UWP for iOS developers\n\n\\[ Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10. For Windows 8.x articles, see the [archive](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132) \\]\n\nIf you're an iOS developer considering developing for Windows 10, these docs are a great place to start. They'll introduce you to some of the concepts you'll need to know as you get started writing apps, and they'll cover how you can publish your work on the Windows Store.\n\nIn this section, we'll start gradually, and examine how to use Microsoft Visual Studio and the C# programming language to create a trivial app, and in particular how the process might vary from the tools you currently use. (Not a C# fan? Don't worry, other programming languages and tools are available, and we'll touch on this in [Getting started: Choosing a programming language](getting-started-choosing-a-programming-language.md)).\n\nWindows 10 introduces a new platform for creating engaging apps on desktop, laptop, tablet, phone devices and more. As Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps provide many unique capabilities, a straight port of your iOS app will miss out on these features. We therefore encourage you to try out the new controls and abilities to see how they will make your life as a developer easier, and new apps possible.\n\nThe bottom line is this: don't just port your app, but **reimagine** your app, and take advantage of new features and new devices. Don't settle for the lowest common denominator, but create rich experiences that use unique Windows 10 features, such as live tiles, notifications, and interacting with Cortana.\n\nTo get started with these walkthroughs, you'll need a computer with both Windows 10 and Microsoft Visual Studio installed. You can download these from the [Developer downloads for programming Windows Store apps](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=302144). Don't have a PC? Don't worry, you can use your Mac: see [Installing Windows and the dev tools on your Mac](setting-up-your-mac-with-windows-10.md).\n\n| Topic | Description |\n|-------|-------------|\n| [Getting started: Creating a project](getting-started-creating-a-project.md) | Visual Studio is to Windows as Xcode is to iOS and Mac OS. In this walkthrough, we help you get comfortable using Visual Studio. |\n| [Getting started: Choosing a programming language](getting-started-choosing-a-programming-language.md) | Before we go any further, you should know about the programming languages that you can choose from when you develop UWP apps. |\n| [Getting started: Getting around in Visual Studio](getting-started-getting-around-in-visual-studio.md) | Let's now get back to the project that we created earlier, and look at how you might find your way around the Visual Studio integrated development environment (IDE). |\n| [Getting started: Common Controls](getting-started-common-controls.md) | Here are some common controls you'll be using in your apps, and their iOS equivalents. |\n| [Getting started: Navigation](getting-started-navigation.md) | One of the ways to manage this navigation in a Windows 10 app is to use the [Frame](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/br242682) class. The following walkthrough shows you how to try this out. |\n| [Getting started: Animation](getting-started-animation.md) | Animations in Windows apps can be created programmatically, but they can also be defined declaratively with Extensible Application Markup Language (XAML). |\n| [Getting started: What next?](getting-started-what-next.md) | With this basic information, you can now start writing more interesting Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps. For your next steps, have a read through the following topics, and then fire up Visual Studio and start writing some code! |\n| [Windows app concept mapping](https://msdn.microsoft.com//windows/uwp/porting/android-ios-uwp-map) | How to think of iOS concepts in terms of Windows (and Android) features |\n\n \n\n \n\n \n"}