{"nodes":[{"content":"When submitting an IAP, the info you providewill be displayed to your app's customers.","pos":[30,116]},{"content":"Create IAP descriptions","pos":[124,147]},{"content":"Create IAP descriptions","pos":[204,227]},{"content":"When submitting an IAP, the info you provide in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Descriptions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> step will be displayed to your app's customers.","pos":[230,346]},{"content":"Make sure to consider the description carefully in order to represent your IAP accurately in a way that makes it appealing to customers.","pos":[347,483]},{"content":"You can provide customized descriptions for different languages.","pos":[484,548]},{"content":"Languages","pos":[553,562]},{"content":"Before you can enter description info, you need to specify one or more <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>languages<ept id=\"p1\">](supported-languages.md)</ept>.","pos":[565,672]},{"content":"We recommend providing descriptions for every language your app supports.","pos":[673,746]},{"content":"Under the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Descriptions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of your IAP’s submission, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Manage description languages<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, then click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Manage languages<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> on the next page.","pos":[748,898]},{"content":"Check the boxes for the languages that you’d like to add, then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Update<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[899,979]},{"content":"The languages that you’ve selected will be displayed in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Description languages<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of the page.","pos":[980,1086]},{"content":"To remove one or more of these languages, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Remove<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (or click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Manage languages<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and uncheck the box for languages you’d like to remove).","pos":[1087,1233]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> when you're happy with the list of languages.","pos":[1234,1294]},{"pos":[1298,1418],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tip<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> To add and remove additional languages, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Manage description languages<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> from the IAP submission overview."},{"content":"To edit a description, click the language name on the IAP submission overview.","pos":[1420,1498]},{"content":"The info you can enter for each language is described below.","pos":[1499,1559]},{"content":"Title","pos":[1564,1569]},{"content":"You must provide a title here, which is the name your customers will see for this IAP.","pos":[1571,1657]},{"content":"Your title can be up to 100 characters.","pos":[1658,1697]},{"content":"Description","pos":[1702,1713]},{"content":"If you'd like to display more info than just a title, you can enter up to 200 characters here.","pos":[1715,1809]},{"content":"This field is optional.","pos":[1810,1833]},{"content":"Icon","pos":[1838,1842]},{"content":"You also have the option to provide an image that may be displayed when the user buys the product.","pos":[1844,1942]},{"content":"This icon must be a .png file that measures exactly 300 x 300 pixels.","pos":[1943,2012]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: When submitting an IAP, the info you providewill be displayed to your app's customers.\ntitle: Create IAP descriptions\nms.assetid: 07178278-A18A-4F73-A660-0047DAAE49B5\n---\n\n# Create IAP descriptions\n\n\nWhen submitting an IAP, the info you provide in the **Descriptions** step will be displayed to your app's customers. Make sure to consider the description carefully in order to represent your IAP accurately in a way that makes it appealing to customers. You can provide customized descriptions for different languages.\n\n## Languages\n\n\nBefore you can enter description info, you need to specify one or more [languages](supported-languages.md). We recommend providing descriptions for every language your app supports.\n\nUnder the **Descriptions** section of your IAP’s submission, click **Manage description languages**, then click **Manage languages** on the next page. Check the boxes for the languages that you’d like to add, then click **Update**. The languages that you’ve selected will be displayed in the **Description languages** section of the page. To remove one or more of these languages, click **Remove** (or click **Manage languages** and uncheck the box for languages you’d like to remove). Click **Save** when you're happy with the list of languages.\n\n> **Tip** To add and remove additional languages, click **Manage description languages** from the IAP submission overview.\n\nTo edit a description, click the language name on the IAP submission overview. The info you can enter for each language is described below.\n\n## Title\n\nYou must provide a title here, which is the name your customers will see for this IAP. Your title can be up to 100 characters.\n\n## Description\n\nIf you'd like to display more info than just a title, you can enter up to 200 characters here. This field is optional.\n\n## Icon\n\nYou also have the option to provide an image that may be displayed when the user buys the product. This icon must be a .png file that measures exactly 300 x 300 pixels.\n\n \n\n \n\n\n\n\n"}