{"nodes":[{"content":"In order to receive money from app sales in the Windows Store, you need to set up your payout account and fill out the necessary tax forms.","pos":[30,169]},{"content":"Setting up your payout account and tax forms","pos":[177,221]},{"content":"Setting up your payout account and tax forms","pos":[278,322]},{"content":"In order to receive money from app sales in the Windows Store, you need to set up your payout account and fill out the necessary tax forms.","pos":[325,464]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  As of April 1st, 2016, your Microsoft Advertising earnings will be paid to the same payout account you've set up in Dev Center.","pos":[468,605]},{"content":"For more info, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>pubCenter-DevCenter payout account and tax profile consolidation<ept id=\"p1\">](pubcenter-devcenter-payout-account-and-tax-profile-consolidation.md)</ept>.","pos":[606,761]},{"content":"If you only plan to list free apps (and don't plan to offer in-app purchases or use Microsoft Advertising), you don't need to set up a payout account or fill out any tax forms.","pos":[763,939]},{"content":"If you change your mind later and decide you do want to sell apps (or in-app products), you can set up your payout account and fill out tax forms at that time.","pos":[940,1099]},{"content":"You won't be able to submit any paid apps or IAPs until your payout account and tax profile has been completed.","pos":[1100,1211]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  In <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>certain markets<ept id=\"p2\">](account-types-locations-and-fees.md#developer-account-and-app-submission-markets)</ept>, developers can only submit free apps.","pos":[1215,1366]},{"content":"If your account is registered in one of these markets, you will not have the option to set up a payout account.","pos":[1367,1478]},{"pos":[1481,1653],"content":"After you have <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>set up your developer account<ept id=\"p1\">](opening-a-developer-account.md)</ept>, there are two things you need to do before you can sell apps (or IAPs) in the Windows Store:"},{"content":"Set up your payout account","pos":[1660,1686]},{"content":"Fill out your tax forms","pos":[1726,1749]},{"pos":[1769,1898],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  For details about how and when you will be paid for the money your apps make, see <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Getting paid<ept id=\"p2\">](getting-paid-apps.md)</ept>."},{"content":"Payout account","pos":[1906,1920]},{"content":"A payout account is the bank account to which we send the proceeds from your sales.","pos":[1923,2006]},{"content":"This bank account must be located in the same country where you registered your developer account.","pos":[2007,2105]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  In some markets, PayPal can be used for your payout account.","pos":[2109,2179]},{"content":"See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Account types, locations, and fees<ept id=\"p1\">](account-types-locations-and-fees.md#developer-account-and-app-submission-markets)</ept> to find out if PayPal is supported for a specific market, and read the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>PayPal info<ept id=\"p2\">](#paypal)</ept> below for more details.","pos":[2180,2420]},{"content":"To set up your payout account","pos":[2426,2455]},{"pos":[2463,2559],"content":"In the Windows Dev Center dashboard, and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the left navigation menu."},{"pos":[2564,2651],"content":"In the left navigation menu of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Payout account<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."},{"pos":[2658,2737],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Because this is sensitive info, you may be prompted to sign in again."},{"content":"On the screen that appears, fill out the info for your account.","pos":[2743,2806]},{"pos":[2813,2907],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  The fields you use to provide your account info accept only alphanumeric characters."},{"content":"Save your info.","pos":[2913,2928]},{"content":"If you need to update or change your payout account, follow the same steps above, replacing the current info with the new info.","pos":[2930,3057]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Changing your payout account can delay your payments by up to one payment cycle.","pos":[3061,3156]},{"content":"This delay occurs because we need to verify the account change, just as we did when you first set up the payout account.","pos":[3157,3277]},{"content":"You'll still get paid for the full amount after your account has been verified; any payments due for the current payment cycle will be added to the next one.","pos":[3278,3435]},{"content":"See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting paid<ept id=\"p1\">](getting-paid-apps.md)</ept> for more info.","pos":[3436,3491]},{"content":"PayPal info","pos":[3500,3511]},{"content":"In select countries and regions, you can create a payment account by entering your PayPal info.","pos":[3513,3608]},{"content":"However, before choosing PayPal as a payment account option:","pos":[3609,3669]},{"pos":[3675,3828],"content":"Check <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Account types, locations, and fees<ept id=\"p1\">](account-types-locations-and-fees.md)</ept> to see if PayPal is a supported payment method in your country or region."},{"content":"Review the following FAQs.","pos":[3833,3859]},{"content":"Depending on your situation, PayPal may not be the best payment account option for you, and a bank account may be preferred.","pos":[3860,3984]},{"content":"Common questions about using PayPal as a payment method:","pos":[3986,4042]},{"content":"What PayPal settings do I need to have in order to receive payments?","pos":[4050,4118]},{"content":"You must ensure that your PayPal account does not block eCheck payments.","pos":[4121,4193]},{"content":"This setting is managed in PayPal’s Payment Receiving Preferences page.","pos":[4194,4265]},{"content":"See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>PayPal’s account setup page<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=513139)</ept> for more info.","pos":[4266,4363]},{"content":"Is my country/region supported?","pos":[4370,4401]},{"content":"See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Account types, locations, and fees<ept id=\"p1\">](account-types-locations-and-fees.md)</ept> to find out where PayPal is a supported payment method.","pos":[4404,4537]},{"content":"Is there a restriction on the size of payments that I can receive using PayPal?","pos":[4544,4623]},{"content":"Yes.","pos":[4626,4630]},{"content":"PayPal limits the amount of money that users can receive in a single transaction.","pos":[4631,4712]},{"content":"The limits vary by currency; see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>PayPal’s transaction limit page<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=513108)</ept> for each currency’s limit.","pos":[4713,4855]},{"content":"If you anticipate that you will receive a payment greater than your PayPal transaction limit, change your payment method to a bank account.","pos":[4856,4995]},{"content":"Does my PayPal account have to be registered in the same country/region as my Dev Center account?","pos":[5002,5099]},{"content":"No.","pos":[5102,5105]},{"content":"When you set up a PayPal account, you can accept the default configuration.","pos":[5106,5181]},{"content":"You shouldn’t have any issues with other countries/regions and currencies unless you have blocked payment in some currencies.","pos":[5182,5307]},{"content":"This setting is managed in PayPal’s Payment Receiving Preferences page.","pos":[5308,5379]},{"content":"Do I have to accept PayPal payments manually?","pos":[5386,5431]},{"content":"No.","pos":[5434,5437]},{"content":"PayPal accounts are set by default to require users to accept payments manually, which means if you don’t accept the payment within 30 days, it is returned.","pos":[5438,5594]},{"content":"You can change this setting by turning off “Ask Me” in PayPal’s More Settings page.","pos":[5595,5678]},{"content":"Specific requirements for certain countries/regions","pos":[5684,5735]},{"content":"In some countries and regions, additional requirements for payout accounts must be followed.","pos":[5737,5829]},{"content":"If you are a resident of Pakistan, Russia, or Ukraine, please note the following requirements.","pos":[5830,5924]},{"content":"Pakistan","pos":[5930,5938]},{"content":"Form-R is a Pakistan banking regulatory requirement.","pos":[5940,5992]},{"content":"It is used to indicate the purpose and reason for receipt of funds from abroad.","pos":[5993,6072]},{"content":"Therefore, anytime that you are eligible for a monthly payout from Microsoft, you will need to submit a Form-R to your bank before the payout can be released to your account.","pos":[6073,6247]},{"content":"Contact your local bank branch for instructions on how to obtain a copy of Form-R.","pos":[6248,6330]},{"content":"You will need to submit a Form-R to your bank each month that you are eligible for a payout.","pos":[6332,6424]},{"content":"For example, if you expect to receive a payout every month of the year, you will need to submit a Form-R 12 times (once each month).","pos":[6425,6557]},{"content":"Once the payout has been submitted to your bank, you have 30 days to submit a Form-R.","pos":[6559,6644]},{"content":"If it is not submitted within 30 days, the funds will be returned to Microsoft.","pos":[6645,6724]},{"content":"Russia","pos":[6730,6736]},{"content":"If you’re a developer who lives in Russia, you may need to provide documentation to your bank before your bank will deposit funds into your account.","pos":[6738,6886]},{"content":"When you’re eligible to be paid, we will provide you with the following documentation in an email message:","pos":[6887,6993]},{"content":"Certificate of Acceptance (CoA) – contains the amount of payout being transferred to your account.","pos":[6999,7097]},{"content":"App Developer Agreement (ADA) – a signed copy of the developer agreement that needs to be counter signed.","pos":[7102,7207]},{"content":"To ensure your payout is successful, please also keep in mind the following:","pos":[7209,7285]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account holder name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> entered for your payout account in the Windows Dev Center dashboard must be the exact same name associated with your bank account.","pos":[7291,7449]},{"content":"For example, if your bank account name contains a middle name, add a middle name to your <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account holder name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[7450,7563]},{"content":"Payouts are transferred directly from Microsoft to your bank account in Ruble (RUB) currency.","pos":[7568,7661]},{"content":"Bank information entered in Dev Center in Latin characters is translated to Cyrillic characters.","pos":[7666,7762]},{"content":"Payouts must be made to a bank account and not to a bank card.","pos":[7767,7829]},{"content":"Ukraine","pos":[7835,7842]},{"content":"If you’re a developer who lives in Ukraine, you may need to provide documentation to your bank before your bank will deposit funds into your account.","pos":[7844,7993]},{"content":"When you’re eligible to be paid, we will provide you with the following documentation in an email message:","pos":[7994,8100]},{"content":"Certificate of Acceptance (CoA) – contains the amount of payout being transferred to your account.","pos":[8106,8204]},{"content":"App Developer Agreement (ADA) – a signed copy of the developer agreement that needs to be counter signed.","pos":[8209,8314]},{"content":"Amendment Agreement (AA) – this document can be used by your bank to help identify your payout funds.","pos":[8319,8420]},{"content":"Microsoft provides all three documents when your first payout is attempted.","pos":[8422,8497]},{"content":"For any subsequent payouts, you will only receive the CoA document.","pos":[8498,8565]},{"content":"Please retain the ADA and AA documents in case you need them to receive future payouts from your bank.","pos":[8566,8668]},{"content":"To ensure your payout is successful, please also keep in mind the following:","pos":[8670,8746]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account holder name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> entered for your payout account in the Windows Dev Center dashboard must be the exact same name associated with your bank account.","pos":[8752,8910]},{"content":"For example, if your bank account name contains a middle name, add a middle name to your <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account holder name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[8911,9024]},{"content":"Payouts are transferred directly from Microsoft to your bank account in USD currency.","pos":[9029,9114]},{"content":"Bank information entered in Dev Center in Latin characters is translated to Cyrillic characters.","pos":[9119,9215]},{"content":"Tax forms","pos":[9220,9229]},{"pos":[9232,9461],"content":"After you have <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>registered for a developer account<ept id=\"p1\">](opening-a-developer-account.md)</ept> and set up your <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>payout account<ept id=\"p2\">](#receiving_payments)</ept>, you can create your <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>tax profile<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept> for the Windows Store by completing the following steps:"},{"content":"Specify your country of residence and citizenship.","pos":[9467,9517]},{"content":"Fill out the appropriate tax forms.","pos":[9522,9557]},{"content":"You can complete and submit your tax forms electronically in your dashboard; in most cases, you don't need to print and mail any forms.","pos":[9559,9694]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Different countries and regions have different tax requirements.","pos":[9698,9777]},{"content":"The exact amount that you must pay in taxes depends on the countries and regions where you sell your apps.","pos":[9778,9884]},{"content":"See the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>App Developer Agreement<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/hh694058)</ept> to find out for which countries Microsoft remits sales and use tax on your behalf.","pos":[9885,10059]},{"content":"In other countries, depending on where you are registered, you may need to remit sales and use tax for your app sales directly to the local taxing authority.","pos":[10060,10217]},{"content":"In addition, the app sales proceeds you receive may be taxable as income.","pos":[10218,10291]},{"content":"We strongly encourage you to contact the relevant authority for your country or region that can best help you determine the right tax info for your Windows Store developer activities.","pos":[10292,10475]},{"content":"To complete your tax profile","pos":[10481,10509]},{"pos":[10517,10609],"content":"In the Windows Dev Center dashboard, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the left navigation menu."},{"pos":[10614,10698],"content":"In the left navigation menu of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Tax profile<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."},{"pos":[10705,10784],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Because this is sensitive info, you may be prompted to sign in again."},{"pos":[10790,10879],"content":"Review your current tax profile status and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to complete the required forms."},{"pos":[10884,10972],"content":"Answer the questions about United States citizenship and residency, then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."},{"content":"If your name and address info are displayed, confirm them for the purposes of filing taxes.","pos":[10977,11068]},{"content":"Next, you will see electronic versions of the tax forms that you must complete.","pos":[11070,11149]},{"content":"Regardless of your country of residence or citizenship, you must fill out United States tax forms to sell any apps or in-app products through the Windows Store.","pos":[11150,11310]},{"content":"Developers who satisfy certain United States residency requirements must fill out an IRS W-9 form.","pos":[11311,11409]},{"content":"Other developers outside the United States must fill out an IRS W-8 form.","pos":[11410,11483]},{"content":"You can fill out these forms online as you complete your tax profile.","pos":[11484,11553]},{"content":"A United States Individual Taxpayer Identification Number (or ITIN) is not required to receive payments from Microsoft or to claim tax treaty benefits.","pos":[11555,11706]},{"content":"Withholding rates","pos":[11712,11729]},{"content":"The info you submit in your tax forms determines the appropriate tax withholding rate.","pos":[11731,11817]},{"content":"The withholding rate applies only to sales that you make into the United States; sales made into non-US locations are not subject to withholding.","pos":[11818,11963]},{"content":"The withholding rates vary, but for most developers registering outside the United States, the default rate is 30%.","pos":[11964,12079]},{"content":"You have the option of reducing this rate if your country has agreed to an income tax treaty with the United States.","pos":[12080,12196]},{"content":"Tax treaty benefits","pos":[12202,12221]},{"content":"If you are outside the United States, you may be able to take advantage of tax treaty benefits.","pos":[12223,12318]},{"content":"These benefits vary from country to country, and may allow you to reduce the amount of taxes that the Windows Store withholds.","pos":[12319,12445]},{"content":"You can claim tax treaty benefits by completing Part II of the W-8BEN form.","pos":[12446,12521]},{"content":"We recommend that you communicate with the appropriate resources in your country or region to determine whether these benefits apply to you.","pos":[12522,12662]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: In order to receive money from app sales in the Windows Store, you need to set up your payout account and fill out the necessary tax forms.\ntitle: Setting up your payout account and tax forms\nms.assetid: 690A2EBC-11B1-4547-B422-54F15A6C26A7\n---\n\n# Setting up your payout account and tax forms\n\n\nIn order to receive money from app sales in the Windows Store, you need to set up your payout account and fill out the necessary tax forms.\n\n> **Note**  As of April 1st, 2016, your Microsoft Advertising earnings will be paid to the same payout account you've set up in Dev Center. For more info, see [pubCenter-DevCenter payout account and tax profile consolidation](pubcenter-devcenter-payout-account-and-tax-profile-consolidation.md).\n\nIf you only plan to list free apps (and don't plan to offer in-app purchases or use Microsoft Advertising), you don't need to set up a payout account or fill out any tax forms. If you change your mind later and decide you do want to sell apps (or in-app products), you can set up your payout account and fill out tax forms at that time. You won't be able to submit any paid apps or IAPs until your payout account and tax profile has been completed.\n\n> **Note**  In [certain markets](account-types-locations-and-fees.md#developer-account-and-app-submission-markets), developers can only submit free apps. If your account is registered in one of these markets, you will not have the option to set up a payout account.\n\n\nAfter you have [set up your developer account](opening-a-developer-account.md), there are two things you need to do before you can sell apps (or IAPs) in the Windows Store:\n\n-   [Set up your payout account](#setting_up_your_payout_account)\n-   [Fill out your tax forms](#paying_taxes)\n\n> **Note**  For details about how and when you will be paid for the money your apps make, see [Getting paid](getting-paid-apps.md).\n\n \n\n## Payout account\n\n\nA payout account is the bank account to which we send the proceeds from your sales. This bank account must be located in the same country where you registered your developer account.\n\n> **Note**  In some markets, PayPal can be used for your payout account. See [Account types, locations, and fees](account-types-locations-and-fees.md#developer-account-and-app-submission-markets) to find out if PayPal is supported for a specific market, and read the [PayPal info](#paypal) below for more details.\n\n \n**To set up your payout account**\n\n1.  In the Windows Dev Center dashboard, and click **Account settings** in the left navigation menu.\n2.  In the left navigation menu of the **Account settings** page, click **Payout account**.\n\n   > **Note**  Because this is sensitive info, you may be prompted to sign in again.\n\n3.  On the screen that appears, fill out the info for your account.\n\n   > **Note**  The fields you use to provide your account info accept only alphanumeric characters.\n\n4.  Save your info.\n\nIf you need to update or change your payout account, follow the same steps above, replacing the current info with the new info.\n\n> **Important**  Changing your payout account can delay your payments by up to one payment cycle. This delay occurs because we need to verify the account change, just as we did when you first set up the payout account. You'll still get paid for the full amount after your account has been verified; any payments due for the current payment cycle will be added to the next one. See [Getting paid](getting-paid-apps.md) for more info.\n\n \n\n### PayPal info\n\nIn select countries and regions, you can create a payment account by entering your PayPal info. However, before choosing PayPal as a payment account option:\n\n-   Check [Account types, locations, and fees](account-types-locations-and-fees.md) to see if PayPal is a supported payment method in your country or region.\n-   Review the following FAQs. Depending on your situation, PayPal may not be the best payment account option for you, and a bank account may be preferred.\n\nCommon questions about using PayPal as a payment method:\n\n-   **What PayPal settings do I need to have in order to receive payments?** You must ensure that your PayPal account does not block eCheck payments. This setting is managed in PayPal’s Payment Receiving Preferences page. See [PayPal’s account setup page](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=513139) for more info.\n-   **Is my country/region supported?** See [Account types, locations, and fees](account-types-locations-and-fees.md) to find out where PayPal is a supported payment method.\n-   **Is there a restriction on the size of payments that I can receive using PayPal?** Yes. PayPal limits the amount of money that users can receive in a single transaction. The limits vary by currency; see [PayPal’s transaction limit page](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=513108) for each currency’s limit. If you anticipate that you will receive a payment greater than your PayPal transaction limit, change your payment method to a bank account.\n-   **Does my PayPal account have to be registered in the same country/region as my Dev Center account?** No. When you set up a PayPal account, you can accept the default configuration. You shouldn’t have any issues with other countries/regions and currencies unless you have blocked payment in some currencies. This setting is managed in PayPal’s Payment Receiving Preferences page.\n-   **Do I have to accept PayPal payments manually?** No. PayPal accounts are set by default to require users to accept payments manually, which means if you don’t accept the payment within 30 days, it is returned. You can change this setting by turning off “Ask Me” in PayPal’s More Settings page.\n\n### Specific requirements for certain countries/regions\n\nIn some countries and regions, additional requirements for payout accounts must be followed. If you are a resident of Pakistan, Russia, or Ukraine, please note the following requirements.\n\n### Pakistan\n\nForm-R is a Pakistan banking regulatory requirement. It is used to indicate the purpose and reason for receipt of funds from abroad. Therefore, anytime that you are eligible for a monthly payout from Microsoft, you will need to submit a Form-R to your bank before the payout can be released to your account. Contact your local bank branch for instructions on how to obtain a copy of Form-R.\n\nYou will need to submit a Form-R to your bank each month that you are eligible for a payout. For example, if you expect to receive a payout every month of the year, you will need to submit a Form-R 12 times (once each month).\n\nOnce the payout has been submitted to your bank, you have 30 days to submit a Form-R. If it is not submitted within 30 days, the funds will be returned to Microsoft.\n\n### Russia\n\nIf you’re a developer who lives in Russia, you may need to provide documentation to your bank before your bank will deposit funds into your account. When you’re eligible to be paid, we will provide you with the following documentation in an email message:\n\n1.  Certificate of Acceptance (CoA) – contains the amount of payout being transferred to your account.\n2.  App Developer Agreement (ADA) – a signed copy of the developer agreement that needs to be counter signed.\n\nTo ensure your payout is successful, please also keep in mind the following:\n\n-   The **Account holder name** entered for your payout account in the Windows Dev Center dashboard must be the exact same name associated with your bank account. For example, if your bank account name contains a middle name, add a middle name to your **Account holder name**.\n-   Payouts are transferred directly from Microsoft to your bank account in Ruble (RUB) currency.\n-   Bank information entered in Dev Center in Latin characters is translated to Cyrillic characters.\n-   Payouts must be made to a bank account and not to a bank card.\n\n### Ukraine\n\nIf you’re a developer who lives in Ukraine, you may need to provide documentation to your bank before your bank will deposit funds into your account. When you’re eligible to be paid, we will provide you with the following documentation in an email message:\n\n1.  Certificate of Acceptance (CoA) – contains the amount of payout being transferred to your account.\n2.  App Developer Agreement (ADA) – a signed copy of the developer agreement that needs to be counter signed.\n3.  Amendment Agreement (AA) – this document can be used by your bank to help identify your payout funds.\n\nMicrosoft provides all three documents when your first payout is attempted. For any subsequent payouts, you will only receive the CoA document. Please retain the ADA and AA documents in case you need them to receive future payouts from your bank.\n\nTo ensure your payout is successful, please also keep in mind the following:\n\n-   The **Account holder name** entered for your payout account in the Windows Dev Center dashboard must be the exact same name associated with your bank account. For example, if your bank account name contains a middle name, add a middle name to your **Account holder name**.\n-   Payouts are transferred directly from Microsoft to your bank account in USD currency.\n-   Bank information entered in Dev Center in Latin characters is translated to Cyrillic characters.\n\n## Tax forms\n\n\nAfter you have [registered for a developer account](opening-a-developer-account.md) and set up your [payout account](#receiving_payments), you can create your *tax profile* for the Windows Store by completing the following steps:\n\n-   Specify your country of residence and citizenship.\n-   Fill out the appropriate tax forms.\n\nYou can complete and submit your tax forms electronically in your dashboard; in most cases, you don't need to print and mail any forms.\n\n> **Important**  Different countries and regions have different tax requirements. The exact amount that you must pay in taxes depends on the countries and regions where you sell your apps. See the [App Developer Agreement](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/hh694058) to find out for which countries Microsoft remits sales and use tax on your behalf. In other countries, depending on where you are registered, you may need to remit sales and use tax for your app sales directly to the local taxing authority. In addition, the app sales proceeds you receive may be taxable as income. We strongly encourage you to contact the relevant authority for your country or region that can best help you determine the right tax info for your Windows Store developer activities.\n\n \n**To complete your tax profile**\n\n1.  In the Windows Dev Center dashboard, click **Account settings** in the left navigation menu.\n2.  In the left navigation menu of the **Account settings** page, click **Tax profile**.\n\n   > **Note**  Because this is sensitive info, you may be prompted to sign in again.\n\n3.  Review your current tax profile status and click **Edit** to complete the required forms.\n4.  Answer the questions about United States citizenship and residency, then click **Next**.\n5.  If your name and address info are displayed, confirm them for the purposes of filing taxes.\n\nNext, you will see electronic versions of the tax forms that you must complete. Regardless of your country of residence or citizenship, you must fill out United States tax forms to sell any apps or in-app products through the Windows Store. Developers who satisfy certain United States residency requirements must fill out an IRS W-9 form. Other developers outside the United States must fill out an IRS W-8 form. You can fill out these forms online as you complete your tax profile.\n\nA United States Individual Taxpayer Identification Number (or ITIN) is not required to receive payments from Microsoft or to claim tax treaty benefits.\n\n### Withholding rates\n\nThe info you submit in your tax forms determines the appropriate tax withholding rate. The withholding rate applies only to sales that you make into the United States; sales made into non-US locations are not subject to withholding. The withholding rates vary, but for most developers registering outside the United States, the default rate is 30%. You have the option of reducing this rate if your country has agreed to an income tax treaty with the United States.\n\n### Tax treaty benefits\n\nIf you are outside the United States, you may be able to take advantage of tax treaty benefits. These benefits vary from country to country, and may allow you to reduce the amount of taxes that the Windows Store withholds. You can claim tax treaty benefits by completing Part II of the W-8BEN form. We recommend that you communicate with the appropriate resources in your country or region to determine whether these benefits apply to you.\n\n \n\n \n\n\n\n\n"}