{"nodes":[{"content":"How to use contacts and calendar info in your UWP app.","pos":[32,86]},{"content":"Contacts and calendar","pos":[94,115]},{"content":"Contacts and calendar","pos":[172,193]},{"content":"Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10.","pos":[198,233]},{"content":"For Windows 8.x articles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>archive<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132)</ept>","pos":[234,326]},{"content":"You can let your users access their contacts and appointments so they can share content, email, calendar info, or messages with each other, or whatever functionality you design.","pos":[331,508]},{"content":"To see a few different ways in which your app can access contacts and appointments, see these topics:","pos":[510,611]},{"content":"Topic","pos":[615,620]},{"content":"Description","pos":[623,634]},{"content":"Select contacts","pos":[664,679]},{"content":"Through the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;strong&gt;</ph>Windows.ApplicationModel.Contacts<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ph><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225002)</ept> namespace, you have several options for selecting contacts.","pos":[706,888]},{"content":"Here, we'll show you how to select a single contact or multiple contacts, and we'll show you how to configure the contact picker to retrieve only the contact information that your app needs.","pos":[889,1079]},{"content":"Send email","pos":[1086,1096]},{"content":"Shows how to launch the compose email dialog to allow the user to send an email message.","pos":[1118,1206]},{"content":"You can pre-populate the fields of the email with data before showing the dialog.","pos":[1207,1288]},{"content":"The message will not be sent until the user taps the send button.","pos":[1289,1354]},{"content":"Send an SMS message","pos":[1360,1379]},{"content":"This topic shows you how to launch the compose SMS dialog to allow the user to send an SMS message.","pos":[1410,1509]},{"content":"You can pre-populate the fields of the SMS with data before showing the dialog.","pos":[1510,1589]},{"content":"The message will not be sent until the user taps the send button.","pos":[1590,1655]},{"content":"Manage appointments","pos":[1661,1680]},{"content":"Through the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;strong&gt;</ph>Windows.ApplicationModel.Appointments<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ph><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Dn263359)</ept> namespace, you can create and manage appointments in a user's calendar app.","pos":[1710,1912]},{"content":"Here, we'll show you how to create an appointment, add it to a calendar app, replace it in the calendar app, and remove it from the calendar app.","pos":[1913,2058]},{"content":"We'll also show how to display a time span for a calendar app and create an appointment-recurrence object.","pos":[2059,2165]},{"content":"Related topics","pos":[2175,2189]},{"content":"Appointments API sample","pos":[2194,2217]},{"content":"Contact manager API sample","pos":[2271,2297]},{"content":"Contact Picker app sample","pos":[2351,2376]},{"content":"Handling Contact Actions sample","pos":[2430,2461]}],"content":"---\nauthor: Xansky\ndescription: How to use contacts and calendar info in your UWP app.\ntitle: Contacts and calendar\nms.assetid: b7e53ab5-2828-4fb7-8656-2bec70b3467f\n---\n\n# Contacts and calendar\n\n\\[ Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10. For Windows 8.x articles, see the [archive](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132) \\]\n\nYou can let your users access their contacts and appointments so they can share content, email, calendar info, or messages with each other, or whatever functionality you design.\n\nTo see a few different ways in which your app can access contacts and appointments, see these topics:\n\n| Topic | Description |\n|-------|-------------|\n| [Select contacts](selecting-contacts.md) | Through the [<strong>Windows.ApplicationModel.Contacts</strong>](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225002) namespace, you have several options for selecting contacts. Here, we'll show you how to select a single contact or multiple contacts, and we'll show you how to configure the contact picker to retrieve only the contact information that your app needs. | \n| [Send email](sending-email.md) | Shows how to launch the compose email dialog to allow the user to send an email message. You can pre-populate the fields of the email with data before showing the dialog. The message will not be sent until the user taps the send button. |\n| [Send an SMS message](sending-an-sms-message.md) | This topic shows you how to launch the compose SMS dialog to allow the user to send an SMS message. You can pre-populate the fields of the SMS with data before showing the dialog. The message will not be sent until the user taps the send button. |\n| [Manage appointments](managing-appointments.md) | Through the [<strong>Windows.ApplicationModel.Appointments</strong>](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Dn263359) namespace, you can create and manage appointments in a user's calendar app. Here, we'll show you how to create an appointment, add it to a calendar app, replace it in the calendar app, and remove it from the calendar app. We'll also show how to display a time span for a calendar app and create an appointment-recurrence object. |\n\n \n\n## Related topics\n\n* [Appointments API sample](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=309836)\n* [Contact manager API sample](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=310079)\n* [Contact Picker app sample](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=231575)\n* [Handling Contact Actions sample](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=320151)\n\n\n\n"}