{"nodes":[{"content":"The Health report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you get data related to the performance and quality of your app, including crashes and unresponsive events.","pos":[30,196]},{"content":"Health report","pos":[204,217]},{"content":"Health report","pos":[274,287]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Health<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you get data related to the performance and quality of your app, including crashes and unresponsive events.","pos":[290,460]},{"content":"You can view this data in your dashboard, or <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>download the report<ept id=\"p1\">](download-analytic-reports.md)</ept> to view offline.","pos":[461,574]},{"content":"Where applicable, you can view stack traces for further debugging.","pos":[575,641]},{"content":"Alternatively, you can programmatically retrieve this data by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Store analytics REST API<ept id=\"p1\">](../monetize/access-analytics-data-using-windows-store-services.md)</ept>.","pos":[642,816]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  If you had previously published apps and viewed performance data in the earlier dashboards, you may notice an increased number of crashes and events reported here.","pos":[820,993]},{"content":"This is because we are able to include more data in this report to give you a more complete picture.","pos":[994,1094]},{"content":"Apply filters","pos":[1099,1112]},{"pos":[1115,1253],"content":"Near the top of the page, you can expand <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to filter all of the data on this page by date range and/or by package version."},{"pos":[1259,1358],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default filter is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Last 72 hours<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, but you can expand this up to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Last 6 months<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Package version<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default setting is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All versions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[1363,1424]},{"content":"If your app includes more than one package version, you can choose a specific one.","pos":[1425,1507]},{"content":"The info in all of the charts listed below will reflect the period of time selected in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section.","pos":[1509,1626]},{"content":"By default this will include data for all of your package versions, unless you've used the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to choose only one.","pos":[1627,1755]},{"content":"Total crashes and events","pos":[1760,1784]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Total crashes and events<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart shows the number of daily crashes and events that customers experienced when using your app during the selected period of time.","pos":[1787,1953]},{"content":"Each type of event that your app experienced is tracked separately: crashes, hangs, JavaScript exceptions, or memory failures.","pos":[1954,2080]},{"content":"You can optionally filter the results by market and/or by OS version.","pos":[2082,2151]},{"content":"Crash and event breakdown","pos":[2156,2181]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Crash and event breakdown<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart lets you see charts that track specific details related to the customers' configurations when a crash or unresponsive event occurred.","pos":[2184,2357]},{"content":"Click the section headings to see details about:","pos":[2358,2406]},{"content":"OS version","pos":[2412,2422]},{"content":"Device type","pos":[2427,2438]},{"content":"Memory (MB)","pos":[2443,2454]},{"content":"Mass storage (GB)","pos":[2459,2476]},{"content":"CPU speed (GHz)","pos":[2481,2496]},{"content":"You can optionally filter the results by <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Crash type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: crashes, hangs, JavaScript exceptions, or memory failures.","pos":[2498,2613]},{"content":"(The default setting is to show all crash types.)","pos":[2614,2663]},{"content":"Market","pos":[2668,2674]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Market<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart shows the total number of crashes and events over the selected period of time by market.","pos":[2677,2786]},{"content":"By default, we show you the market which had the most acquisitions on top and continue downward from there.","pos":[2787,2894]},{"content":"You can reverse this order by toggling the arrow in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Crashes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column of this chart.","pos":[2895,2984]},{"content":"Failure log","pos":[2989,3000]},{"pos":[3003,3219],"content":"If you have included PDB symbol files, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Failure log<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> chart will show details related to occurrences of specific symbols, including the total number of crashes and the average daily number of crashes per symbol."},{"content":"This info is based on a percentage of your total events.","pos":[3221,3277]},{"content":"Near the top of the chart, we'll indicate what percentage of events was sampled to provide this data.","pos":[3278,3379]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: The Health report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you get data related to the performance and quality of your app, including crashes and unresponsive events.\ntitle: Health report\nms.assetid: 4F671543-1E91-4E59-88A3-638E3E64539A\n---\n\n# Health report\n\n\nThe **Health** report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you get data related to the performance and quality of your app, including crashes and unresponsive events. You can view this data in your dashboard, or [download the report](download-analytic-reports.md) to view offline. Where applicable, you can view stack traces for further debugging. Alternatively, you can programmatically retrieve this data by using the [Windows Store analytics REST API](../monetize/access-analytics-data-using-windows-store-services.md).\n\n> **Note**  If you had previously published apps and viewed performance data in the earlier dashboards, you may notice an increased number of crashes and events reported here. This is because we are able to include more data in this report to give you a more complete picture.\n\n## Apply filters\n\n\nNear the top of the page, you can expand **Apply filters** to filter all of the data on this page by date range and/or by package version.\n\n-   **Date**: The default filter is **Last 72 hours**, but you can expand this up to **Last 6 months**.\n-   **Package version**: The default setting is **All versions**. If your app includes more than one package version, you can choose a specific one.\n\nThe info in all of the charts listed below will reflect the period of time selected in the **Apply filters** section. By default this will include data for all of your package versions, unless you've used the **Apply filters** to choose only one.\n\n## Total crashes and events\n\n\nThe **Total crashes and events** chart shows the number of daily crashes and events that customers experienced when using your app during the selected period of time. Each type of event that your app experienced is tracked separately: crashes, hangs, JavaScript exceptions, or memory failures.\n\nYou can optionally filter the results by market and/or by OS version.\n\n## Crash and event breakdown\n\n\nThe **Crash and event breakdown** chart lets you see charts that track specific details related to the customers' configurations when a crash or unresponsive event occurred. Click the section headings to see details about:\n\n-   OS version\n-   Device type\n-   Memory (MB)\n-   Mass storage (GB)\n-   CPU speed (GHz)\n\nYou can optionally filter the results by **Crash type**: crashes, hangs, JavaScript exceptions, or memory failures. (The default setting is to show all crash types.)\n\n## Market\n\n\nThe **Market** chart shows the total number of crashes and events over the selected period of time by market. By default, we show you the market which had the most acquisitions on top and continue downward from there. You can reverse this order by toggling the arrow in the **Crashes** column of this chart.\n\n## Failure log\n\n\nIf you have included PDB symbol files, the **Failure log** chart will show details related to occurrences of specific symbols, including the total number of crashes and the average daily number of crashes per symbol.\n\nThis info is based on a percentage of your total events. Near the top of the chart, we'll indicate what percentage of events was sampled to provide this data.\n\n \n\n \n"}