{"nodes":[{"content":"Device Portal for Desktop","pos":[78,103]},{"content":"Learn how the Windows Device Portal opens up diagnostics and automation on your Windows desktop.","pos":[117,213]},{"content":"Device Portal for Desktop","pos":[220,245]},{"content":"Starting in Windows 10, Version 1607, additional developer features are available for desktop.","pos":[247,341]},{"content":"These features are available only when Developer Mode is enabled.","pos":[342,407]},{"pos":[409,556],"content":"For information about how to enable Developer Mode, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Enable your device for development<ept id=\"p1\">](../get-started/enable-your-device-for-development.md)</ept>."},{"content":"Device Portal lets you view diagnostic information and interact with your desktop over HTTP from your browser.","pos":[558,668]},{"content":"You can use Device Portal to do the following:","pos":[669,715]},{"content":"See and manipulate a list of running processes","pos":[718,764]},{"content":"Install, delete, launch, and terminate apps","pos":[767,810]},{"content":"Change Wi-Fi profiles, view signal strength, and see ipconfig","pos":[813,874]},{"content":"View live graphs of CPU, memory, I/O, network, and GPU usage","pos":[877,937]},{"content":"Collect process dumps","pos":[940,961]},{"content":"Collect ETW traces","pos":[964,982]},{"content":"Manipulate the isolated storage of sideloaded apps","pos":[986,1036]},{"content":"Set up device portal on Windows Desktop","pos":[1041,1080]},{"content":"Turn on device portal","pos":[1086,1107]},{"pos":[1109,1203],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Developer Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, with Developer Mode enabled, you can enable Device Portal."},{"content":"When you enable Device Portal, you must also create a username and password for Device Portal.","pos":[1207,1301]},{"content":"Do not use your Microsoft account or other Windows credentials.","pos":[1302,1365]},{"content":"After Device Portal is enabled, you will see links to it at the bottom of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section.","pos":[1369,1468]},{"content":"Take note of the port number applied to the end of the URL: this port number is randomly generated when Device Portal is enabled, but should remain consistent between reboots of the desktop.","pos":[1469,1659]},{"content":"If you'd like to set the port numbers manually so they remain permanent, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Setting port numbers<ept id=\"p1\">](device-portal-desktop.md#setting-port-numbers)</ept>.","pos":[1660,1807]},{"content":"You can choose from two ways to connect to Device Portal: local host and over the local network (including VPN).","pos":[1809,1921]},{"content":"To connect to Device Portal","pos":[1925,1952]},{"content":"In your browser, enter the address shown here for the connection type you're using.","pos":[1959,2042]},{"pos":[2050,2087],"content":"Localhost: <ph id=\"ph1\">`http://127.0.0.1:PORT`</ph> or"},{"content":"Use this address to view Device Portal locally.","pos":[2117,2164]},{"pos":[2176,2190],"content":"Local Network:"},{"content":"Use this address to connect over a local network.","pos":[2243,2292]},{"content":"HTTPS is required for authentication and secure communication.","pos":[2294,2356]},{"content":"If you are using Device Portal in a protected environment, like a test lab, where you trust everyone on your local network, have no personal information on the device, and have unique requirements, you can disable authentication.","pos":[2358,2587]},{"content":"This enables unencrypted communication, and allows anyone with the IP address of your computer to control it.","pos":[2588,2697]},{"content":"Device Portal pages","pos":[2702,2721]},{"content":"Device Portal on desktop provides the standard set of pages.","pos":[2723,2783]},{"content":"For detailed descriptions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Device Portal overview<ept id=\"p1\">](device-portal.md)</ept>.","pos":[2784,2866]},{"content":"Apps","pos":[2870,2874]},{"content":"Processes","pos":[2877,2886]},{"content":"Performance","pos":[2889,2900]},{"content":"Debugging","pos":[2903,2912]},{"content":"Event Tracing for Windows (ETW)","pos":[2915,2946]},{"content":"Performance tracing","pos":[2949,2968]},{"content":"Devices","pos":[2971,2978]},{"content":"Networking","pos":[2981,2991]},{"content":"App File Explorer","pos":[2994,3011]},{"content":"Setting port numbers","pos":[3017,3037]},{"content":"If you would like to select port numbers for Device Portal (such as 80 and 443), you can set the following regkeys:","pos":[3039,3154]},{"content":"Under HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\WebManagement\\Service","pos":[3158,3246]},{"content":"UseDynamicPorts: A required DWORD.","pos":[3253,3287]},{"content":"Set this to 0 in order to retain the port numbers you've chosen.","pos":[3288,3352]},{"content":"HttpPort: A required DWORD.","pos":[3359,3386]},{"content":"Contains the port number that Device Portal will listen for HTTP connections on.","pos":[3387,3467]},{"content":"HttpsPort: A required DWORD.","pos":[3476,3504]},{"content":"Contains the port number that Device Portal will listen for HTTPS connections on.","pos":[3505,3586]},{"content":"Failure to install Developer Mode package","pos":[3591,3632]},{"content":"Sometimes, due to network or compatibility issues, Developer Mode won't install correctly.","pos":[3633,3723]},{"content":"The Developer Mode package is required for remote deployment -- Device Portal and SSH -- but not for local development.","pos":[3724,3843]},{"content":"Failed to locate the package","pos":[3851,3879]},{"content":"\"Developer Mode package couldn’t be located in Windows Update.","pos":[3881,3943]},{"content":"Error Code 0x001234 Learn more\"","pos":[3944,3975]},{"content":"This error may occur due to a network connectivity problem, Enterprise settings, or the package may be missing.","pos":[3980,4091]},{"content":"To fix this issue:","pos":[4094,4112]},{"content":"Ensure your computer is connected to the Internet.","pos":[4117,4167]},{"content":"If you are on a domain-joined computer, speak to your network administrator.","pos":[4172,4248]},{"pos":[4253,4365],"content":"Check for Windows updates in the Settings &gt; Updates and Security &gt; <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Updates<ept id=\"p1\">](ms-settings:windowsupdate)</ept>."},{"content":"Verify that the Windows Developer Mode package is present in Settings &gt; System &gt; Apps &amp; Features &gt; <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage optional features<ept id=\"p1\">](ms-settings:optionalfeatures)</ept> &gt; Add a feature.","pos":[4369,4541]},{"content":"If it is missing, Windows cannot find the correct package for your computer.","pos":[4542,4618]},{"content":"After doing any of the above steps, disable and then re-enable Developer Mode to verify the fix.","pos":[4621,4717]},{"content":"Failed to install the package","pos":[4725,4754]},{"content":"\"Developer Mode package failed to install.","pos":[4756,4798]},{"content":"Error code 0x001234  Learn more\"","pos":[4799,4831]},{"content":"This error may occur due to incompatibilities between your build of Windows and the Developer Mode package.","pos":[4833,4940]},{"content":"To fix this issue:","pos":[4943,4961]},{"pos":[4966,5078],"content":"Check for Windows updates in the Settings &gt; Updates and Security &gt; <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Updates<ept id=\"p1\">](ms-settings:windowsupdate)</ept>."},{"content":"Reboot your computer to ensure all updates are applied.","pos":[5082,5137]}],"content":"---\nauthor: mcleblanc\nms.assetid: 5c34c78e-9ff7-477b-87f6-a31367cd3f8b\ntitle: Device Portal for Desktop\ndescription: Learn how the Windows Device Portal opens up diagnostics and automation on your Windows desktop.\n---\n# Device Portal for Desktop\n\nStarting in Windows 10, Version 1607, additional developer features are available for desktop. These features are available only when Developer Mode is enabled.\n\nFor information about how to enable Developer Mode, see [Enable your device for development](../get-started/enable-your-device-for-development.md).\n\nDevice Portal lets you view diagnostic information and interact with your desktop over HTTP from your browser. You can use Device Portal to do the following:\n- See and manipulate a list of running processes\n- Install, delete, launch, and terminate apps\n- Change Wi-Fi profiles, view signal strength, and see ipconfig\n- View live graphs of CPU, memory, I/O, network, and GPU usage\n- Collect process dumps\n- Collect ETW traces \n- Manipulate the isolated storage of sideloaded apps\n\n## Set up device portal on Windows Desktop\n\n### Turn on device portal\n\nIn the **Developer Settings** menu, with Developer Mode enabled, you can enable Device Portal.  \n\nWhen you enable Device Portal, you must also create a username and password for Device Portal. Do not use your Microsoft account or other Windows credentials.  \n\nAfter Device Portal is enabled, you will see links to it at the bottom of the **Settings** section. Take note of the port number applied to the end of the URL: this port number is randomly generated when Device Portal is enabled, but should remain consistent between reboots of the desktop. If you'd like to set the port numbers manually so they remain permanent, see [Setting port numbers](device-portal-desktop.md#setting-port-numbers).\n\nYou can choose from two ways to connect to Device Portal: local host and over the local network (including VPN).\n\n**To connect to Device Portal**\n\n1. In your browser, enter the address shown here for the connection type you're using.\n\n    - Localhost: `http://127.0.0.1:PORT` or `http://localhost:PORT`\n\n    Use this address to view Device Portal locally.\n    \n    - Local Network: `https://<The IP address of the desktop>:PORT`\n\n    Use this address to connect over a local network.\n\nHTTPS is required for authentication and secure communication.\n\nIf you are using Device Portal in a protected environment, like a test lab, where you trust everyone on your local network, have no personal information on the device, and have unique requirements, you can disable authentication. This enables unencrypted communication, and allows anyone with the IP address of your computer to control it.\n\n## Device Portal pages\n\nDevice Portal on desktop provides the standard set of pages. For detailed descriptions, see [Windows Device Portal overview](device-portal.md).\n\n- Apps\n- Processes\n- Performance\n- Debugging\n- Event Tracing for Windows (ETW)\n- Performance tracing\n- Devices\n- Networking\n- App File Explorer \n\n## Setting port numbers\n\nIf you would like to select port numbers for Device Portal (such as 80 and 443), you can set the following regkeys:\n\n- Under HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\WebManagement\\Service\n    - UseDynamicPorts: A required DWORD. Set this to 0 in order to retain the port numbers you've chosen.\n    - HttpPort: A required DWORD. Contains the port number that Device Portal will listen for HTTP connections on.  \n    - HttpsPort: A required DWORD. Contains the port number that Device Portal will listen for HTTPS connections on.\n\n## Failure to install Developer Mode package\nSometimes, due to network or compatibility issues, Developer Mode won't install correctly. The Developer Mode package is required for remote deployment -- Device Portal and SSH -- but not for local development.  \n\n### Failed to locate the package\n\n\"Developer Mode package couldn’t be located in Windows Update. Error Code 0x001234 Learn more\"   \n\nThis error may occur due to a network connectivity problem, Enterprise settings, or the package may be missing. \n\nTo fix this issue:\n\n1. Ensure your computer is connected to the Internet. \n2. If you are on a domain-joined computer, speak to your network administrator. \n3. Check for Windows updates in the Settings > Updates and Security > [Windows Updates](ms-settings:windowsupdate).\n4. Verify that the Windows Developer Mode package is present in Settings > System > Apps & Features > [Manage optional features](ms-settings:optionalfeatures) > Add a feature. If it is missing, Windows cannot find the correct package for your computer. \n\nAfter doing any of the above steps, disable and then re-enable Developer Mode to verify the fix. \n\n\n### Failed to install the package\n\n\"Developer Mode package failed to install. Error code 0x001234  Learn more\"\n\nThis error may occur due to incompatibilities between your build of Windows and the Developer Mode package. \n\nTo fix this issue:\n\n1. Check for Windows updates in the Settings > Updates and Security > [Windows Updates](ms-settings:windowsupdate).\n2. Reboot your computer to ensure all updates are applied.\n"}