{"nodes":[{"content":"You can view detailed analytics for your apps in the Windows Dev Center dashboard.","pos":[30,112]},{"content":"Analytics","pos":[120,129]},{"content":"Analytics","pos":[186,195]},{"content":"You can view detailed analytics for your apps in the Windows Dev Center dashboard.","pos":[197,279]},{"content":"Statistics and charts let you know how your apps are doing—from how many customers you've reached to how they're using your app and what they have to say about it.","pos":[280,443]},{"content":"You can also find info on app health, ad usage, and more.","pos":[444,501]},{"content":"View the reports in the dashboard, or <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>download the reports you need<ept id=\"p1\">](download-analytic-reports.md)</ept> to analyze your data offline.","pos":[502,631]},{"content":"We also provide several ways for you to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>access your analytics data without using the dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">](#no-dashboard)</ept>.","pos":[632,744]},{"pos":[748,973],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>In addition to the dashboard reports, you can programmatically access some analytics data by using the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Windows Store analytics REST API<ept id=\"p2\">](../monetize/access-analytics-data-using-windows-store-services.md)</ept>."},{"content":"Analytics for all your apps","pos":[978,1005]},{"content":"Your dashboard overview page also includes a roll-up view to gather details about all your apps.","pos":[1008,1104]},{"content":"The stats shown on the overview page will vary, depending on your apps.","pos":[1105,1176]},{"content":"When you <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>download analytic reports<ept id=\"p1\">](download-analytic-reports.md)</ept>, you also have the option to download reports about all of your apps.","pos":[1178,1314]},{"content":"Note that you will need to access the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download reports<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Analytics<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> section for one of your apps, but you are not limited to downloading data only for that particular app.","pos":[1315,1503]},{"content":"Available reports for each app","pos":[1508,1538]},{"content":"In this section you'll find details about the info presented in each of the following reports:","pos":[1541,1635]},{"content":"Acquisitions report","pos":[1642,1661]},{"content":"Health report","pos":[1692,1705]},{"content":"Ratings report","pos":[1730,1744]},{"content":"Reviews report","pos":[1770,1784]},{"content":"Feedback report","pos":[1810,1825]},{"content":"Usage report","pos":[1852,1864]},{"content":"IAP acquisitions report","pos":[1888,1911]},{"content":"Ad mediation report","pos":[1946,1965]},{"content":"Advertising performance report","pos":[1996,2026]},{"content":"App install ads report","pos":[2068,2090]},{"content":"Channels and conversions report","pos":[2125,2156]},{"pos":[2197,2324],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>You may not see data in all of these reports, depending on your app's specific features and implementation."},{"content":"Page and section filters","pos":[2329,2353]},{"content":"Each report includes filters that you can use to drill down into your data.","pos":[2355,2430]},{"content":"Near the top of the page you'll see <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2431,2485]},{"content":"You can use these filters to limit or expand the scope of all of the charts and info on the page.","pos":[2486,2583]},{"content":"Within each particular chart, you may also see individual section filters.","pos":[2585,2659]},{"content":"These will limit the data shown only for that particular chart.","pos":[2660,2723]},{"content":"The specific filters vary by report.","pos":[2725,2761]},{"content":"The topics in this section will explain which filters are available and will describe the other data on the page for each report.","pos":[2762,2891]},{"content":"Access analytics data without using the Dev Center dashboard","pos":[2922,2982]},{"content":"In addition to the analytic reports on the dashboard, there are several other ways to access your analytics data.","pos":[2984,3097]},{"content":"Windows Store analytics API","pos":[3103,3130]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Store analytics API<ept id=\"p1\">](../monetize/access-analytics-data-using-windows-store-services.md)</ept> to programmatically retrieve analytics data for your apps.","pos":[3132,3295]},{"content":"This REST API enables you to retrieve data for app and IAP acquisitions, errors, app ratings and reviews.","pos":[3296,3401]},{"content":"This API uses Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) to authenticate the calls from your app or service.","pos":[3402,3501]},{"content":"Windows Dev Center content pack for Power BI","pos":[3507,3551]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Dev Center content pack for Power BI<ept id=\"p1\">](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/documentation/powerbi-content-pack-windows-dev-center/)</ept> to explore and monitor your Dev Center analytics data in Power BI.","pos":[3553,3760]},{"content":"Power BI is a cloud-based business analytics service that gives you a single view of your business data.","pos":[3761,3865]},{"content":"Use the following resources to get started using Power BI to access your analytics data.","pos":[3867,3955]},{"content":"Sign up for Power BI","pos":[3960,3980]},{"content":"Learn how to use Power BI","pos":[4080,4105]},{"content":"Learn how to use the Windows Dev Center content pack for Power BI to connect to your analytics data","pos":[4158,4257]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>To connect to the Windows Dev Center content pack for Power BI, we recommend that you specify credentials from an Azure AD directory that is associated with your Dev Center account.","pos":[4348,4549]},{"content":"If you use your Microsoft account credentials, your analytics data in Power BI does not refresh automatically, and you will need to log in to Power BI to refresh your data.","pos":[4550,4722]},{"content":"If your organization already uses Office 365 or other business services from Microsoft, you already have Azure AD.","pos":[4723,4837]},{"content":"Otherwise, you can <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>get it for free<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=703757)</ept>.","pos":[4838,4924]},{"content":"For more information about associating your Dev Center account with an Azure AD, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage account users<ept id=\"p1\">](manage-account-users.md)</ept>.","pos":[4925,5058]},{"content":"Dev Center app","pos":[5064,5078]},{"pos":[5080,5266],"content":"Install the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dev Center<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/dev-center/9nblggh4r5ws)</ept> app to quickly view details about the health and performance of your apps on any Windows 10 device."}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: You can view detailed analytics for your apps in the Windows Dev Center dashboard.\ntitle: Analytics\nms.assetid: 3A3C6F10-0DB1-416D-B632-CD388EA66759\n---\n\n# Analytics\n\nYou can view detailed analytics for your apps in the Windows Dev Center dashboard. Statistics and charts let you know how your apps are doing—from how many customers you've reached to how they're using your app and what they have to say about it. You can also find info on app health, ad usage, and more. View the reports in the dashboard, or [download the reports you need](download-analytic-reports.md) to analyze your data offline. We also provide several ways for you to [access your analytics data without using the dashboard](#no-dashboard).\n\n> **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;In addition to the dashboard reports, you can programmatically access some analytics data by using the [Windows Store analytics REST API](../monetize/access-analytics-data-using-windows-store-services.md).\n\n## Analytics for all your apps\n\n\nYour dashboard overview page also includes a roll-up view to gather details about all your apps. The stats shown on the overview page will vary, depending on your apps.\n\nWhen you [download analytic reports](download-analytic-reports.md), you also have the option to download reports about all of your apps. Note that you will need to access the **Download reports** page in the **Analytics** section for one of your apps, but you are not limited to downloading data only for that particular app.\n\n## Available reports for each app\n\n\nIn this section you'll find details about the info presented in each of the following reports:\n\n-   [Acquisitions report](acquisitions-report.md)\n-   [Health report](health-report.md)\n-   [Ratings report](ratings-report.md)\n-   [Reviews report](reviews-report.md)\n-   [Feedback report](feedback-report.md)\n-   [Usage report](usage-report.md)\n-   [IAP acquisitions report](iap-acquisitions-report.md)\n-   [Ad mediation report](ad-mediation-report.md)\n-   [Advertising performance report](advertising-performance-report.md)\n-   [App install ads report](app-install-ads-reports.md)\n-   [Channels and conversions report](channels-and-conversions-report.md)\n\n> **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;You may not see data in all of these reports, depending on your app's specific features and implementation.\n\n## Page and section filters\n\nEach report includes filters that you can use to drill down into your data. Near the top of the page you'll see **Apply filters**. You can use these filters to limit or expand the scope of all of the charts and info on the page.\n\nWithin each particular chart, you may also see individual section filters. These will limit the data shown only for that particular chart.\n\nThe specific filters vary by report. The topics in this section will explain which filters are available and will describe the other data on the page for each report.\n\n<span id=\"no-dashboard\"/>\n## Access analytics data without using the Dev Center dashboard\n\nIn addition to the analytic reports on the dashboard, there are several other ways to access your analytics data.\n\n### Windows Store analytics API\n\nUse the [Windows Store analytics API](../monetize/access-analytics-data-using-windows-store-services.md) to programmatically retrieve analytics data for your apps. This REST API enables you to retrieve data for app and IAP acquisitions, errors, app ratings and reviews. This API uses Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) to authenticate the calls from your app or service.\n\n### Windows Dev Center content pack for Power BI\n\nUse the [Windows Dev Center content pack for Power BI](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/documentation/powerbi-content-pack-windows-dev-center/) to explore and monitor your Dev Center analytics data in Power BI. Power BI is a cloud-based business analytics service that gives you a single view of your business data.\n\nUse the following resources to get started using Power BI to access your analytics data.\n\n* [Sign up for Power BI](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/documentation/powerbi-service-self-service-signup-for-power-bi/)\n* [Learn how to use Power BI](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/guided-learning/)\n* [Learn how to use the Windows Dev Center content pack for Power BI to connect to your analytics data](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/documentation/powerbi-content-pack-windows-dev-center/)\n\n> **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;To connect to the Windows Dev Center content pack for Power BI, we recommend that you specify credentials from an Azure AD directory that is associated with your Dev Center account. If you use your Microsoft account credentials, your analytics data in Power BI does not refresh automatically, and you will need to log in to Power BI to refresh your data. If your organization already uses Office 365 or other business services from Microsoft, you already have Azure AD. Otherwise, you can [get it for free](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=703757). For more information about associating your Dev Center account with an Azure AD, see [Manage account users](manage-account-users.md).\n\n### Dev Center app\n\nInstall the [Dev Center](https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/dev-center/9nblggh4r5ws) app to quickly view details about the health and performance of your apps on any Windows 10 device. \n"}