{"nodes":[{"content":"Dev Center Insider Program","pos":[11,37]},{"content":"Try out new Dev Center features before they become available to all developers and let us know what you think.","pos":[51,161]},{"content":"Dev Center Insider Program","pos":[182,208]},{"content":"As a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>registered developer<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=615100)</ept>, you can help influence the functionality we make available in the Dev Center dashboard by joining the Dev Center Insider Program.","pos":[210,415]},{"content":"This program allows you to try out new features before they become available to all developers.","pos":[416,511]},{"content":"We encourage you to give us your feedback on these features by using the Feedback link in the bottom right corner of Dev Center.","pos":[512,640]},{"content":"All of the feedback we receive from Dev Center Insiders will be read closely and given priority consideration.","pos":[641,751]},{"content":"To join the program, opt in on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in your Dev Center dashboard.","pos":[753,843]},{"content":"You can opt out at any time.","pos":[844,872]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The terms of the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>App Developer Agreement<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/windows/apps/hh694058.aspx)</ept> apply to your participation in the program.","pos":[876,1031]},{"content":"Please read them, particularly Exhibit I, before you join the program.","pos":[1032,1102]},{"content":"Keep in mind that the features made available exclusively to people in the Dev Center Insider Program may include experimental and early prerelease services.","pos":[1103,1260]},{"content":"This means that these features often don’t have documentation available yet, and you may experience unintended results when using them.","pos":[1261,1396]},{"content":"Here are some of the features that we’ve made available exclusively to members of the Dev Center Insider Program.","pos":[1399,1512]},{"content":"This list will change over time as new features are added (and as features introduced to the Insider Program are made available to everyone).","pos":[1513,1654]},{"content":"Dev Center Insider Program feature","pos":[1658,1692]},{"content":"How Dev Center Insiders can try it","pos":[1697,1731]},{"content":"Date added","pos":[1734,1744]},{"pos":[1839,2053],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Device family availability<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Manage device family availability for your app and see which packages will be offered to specific Windows 10 device families (and earlier OS versions, if applicable) in ranked order."},{"pos":[2054,2142],"content":"View this info and make your selections on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Packages<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page of an app’s submission."},{"content":"May 2016","pos":[2143,2151]},{"pos":[2154,2314],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>View your submitted feedback<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: View all of the feedback you’ve submitted to Dev Center, and get notifications when we’ve made changes based on your feedback."},{"pos":[2315,2388],"content":"Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Submitted feedback<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> in the left nav."},{"content":"April 2016","pos":[2389,2399]},{"pos":[2402,2510],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Life to date acquisition data<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Now you can see the cumulative total acquisitions for your apps and IAPs."},{"pos":[2511,2594],"content":"View this info in an app's <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Acquisitions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>IAP acquisitions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> report."},{"content":"April 2016","pos":[2595,2605]},{"pos":[2608,2756],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Page history for multi-user accounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Account owners can access detailed browsing history for any additional users they’ve added to the account."},{"pos":[2757,2887],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Manage users<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click the link shown under “Last activity” for the user whose browsing history you’d like to review."},{"content":"April 2016","pos":[2888,2898]},{"pos":[2901,2994],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New dashboard design<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Get an updated view of your apps and key metrics, all in one place."},{"content":"The new design will appear on your dashboard overview page.","pos":[2995,3054]},{"content":"March 2016","pos":[3055,3065]}],"content":"---\ntitle: Dev Center Insider Program\ndescription: Try out new Dev Center features before they become available to all developers and let us know what you think.\nauthor: JnHs\n---\n\n# Dev Center Insider Program\n\nAs a [registered developer](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=615100), you can help influence the functionality we make available in the Dev Center dashboard by joining the Dev Center Insider Program. This program allows you to try out new features before they become available to all developers. We encourage you to give us your feedback on these features by using the Feedback link in the bottom right corner of Dev Center. All of the feedback we receive from Dev Center Insiders will be read closely and given priority consideration.\n\nTo join the program, opt in on the **Account settings** page in your Dev Center dashboard. You can opt out at any time.\n\n> **Important** The terms of the [App Developer Agreement](https://msdn.microsoft.com/windows/apps/hh694058.aspx) apply to your participation in the program. Please read them, particularly Exhibit I, before you join the program. Keep in mind that the features made available exclusively to people in the Dev Center Insider Program may include experimental and early prerelease services. This means that these features often don’t have documentation available yet, and you may experience unintended results when using them. \n\nHere are some of the features that we’ve made available exclusively to members of the Dev Center Insider Program. This list will change over time as new features are added (and as features introduced to the Insider Program are made available to everyone).\n\n| Dev Center Insider Program feature   | How Dev Center Insiders can try it | Date added |\n|--------------------------------------|------------------------------------|------------|\n|**Device family availability**: Manage device family availability for your app and see which packages will be offered to specific Windows 10 device families (and earlier OS versions, if applicable) in ranked order.|View this info and make your selections on the **Packages** page of an app’s submission.|May 2016|\n|**View your submitted feedback**: View all of the feedback you’ve submitted to Dev Center, and get notifications when we’ve made changes based on your feedback.|Under **Account settings**, click **Submitted feedback** in the left nav.|April 2016|\n|**Life to date acquisition data**: Now you can see the cumulative total acquisitions for your apps and IAPs.|View this info in an app's **Acquisitions** report and **IAP acquisitions** report.|April 2016|\n|**Page history for multi-user accounts**: Account owners can access detailed browsing history for any additional users they’ve added to the account.|On the **Manage users** page, click the link shown under “Last activity” for the user whose browsing history you’d like to review.|April 2016|\n|**New dashboard design**: Get an updated view of your apps and key metrics, all in one place.|The new design will appear on your dashboard overview page.|March 2016|\n\n\n\n\n\n"}