{"nodes":[{"content":"Use the app-level and account-level affiliates performance reports on the Windows Dev Center dashboard to view performance data for affiliate ads in your apps.","pos":[30,189]},{"content":"Affiliates performance report","pos":[197,226]},{"content":"Affiliates performance report","pos":[283,312]},{"pos":[314,538],"content":"If you have <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>opted in to the Microsoft affiliate ads program<ept id=\"p1\">](about-affiliate-ads.md)</ept>, you can view performance data for the affiliate ads that appear in your app in the following reports on the Windows Dev Center dashboard:"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>App-level affiliates performance report<ept id=\"p1\">](affiliates-performance-report.md#app-level-affiliates-performance-report)</ept>.","pos":[544,660]},{"content":"This report provides performance data for affiliate ads in the currently selected app in the dashboard.","pos":[661,764]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dashboard-level affiliates performance report<ept id=\"p1\">](affiliates-performance-report.md#dashboard-level-affiliates-performance-report)</ept>.","pos":[769,897]},{"content":"This report provides a summary of performance data for affiliate ads in all apps that you have opted in to the Microsoft affiliate ads program.","pos":[898,1041]},{"content":"These reports are updated daily.","pos":[1043,1075]},{"content":"By default, the reports are filtered on performance from the last 30 days, on all devices.","pos":[1076,1166]},{"content":"To change these filters, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Page filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and choose a different time frame or an individual device type.","pos":[1167,1278]},{"content":"Note that all data is aggregated based using UTC, not your particular time zone.","pos":[1279,1359]},{"content":"The following sections provide more details about these reports.","pos":[1361,1425]},{"content":"App-level affiliate ads performance report","pos":[1430,1472]},{"content":"This report provides affiliate ads performance data in graph and table form for the currently selected app in the dashboard.","pos":[1474,1598]},{"content":"To view this report, select one of your apps in the dashboard and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Analytics<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Affiliates performance<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> in the navigation pane.","pos":[1599,1740]},{"content":"The data is obtained from the following seven performance metrics we track for the ads in your app:","pos":[1742,1841]},{"pos":[1847,2013],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Estimated earnings (approved)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The estimated amount of money you received as a commission for approved purchases made by users clicking affiliate ads in your app."},{"pos":[2018,2169],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Estimated earnings (pending approval)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The estimated amount of money you could receive as a commission for the purchases that are pending approval."},{"pos":[2174,2249],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Impressions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of times an affiliate ad was shown in your app."},{"pos":[2254,2333],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Clicks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of times someone clicked on an affiliate ad in your app."},{"pos":[2338,2474],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CTR<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Click-through rate, meaning the number of times an affiliate ad was clicked, divided by the number of affiliate ad impressions."},{"pos":[2479,2587],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Purchases (approved)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of approved purchases made by users clicking affiliate ads in your app."},{"pos":[2592,2726],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Purchases (pending approval)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The number of purchases pending approval that were made by users clicking affiliate ads in your app."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  After a user buys a product in the Store, there is a 45 day waiting period before the purchase can be approved for the affiliate ads program.","pos":[2730,2881]},{"content":"Because of this waiting period, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Estimated earnings (approved)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Estimated earnings (pending approval)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Purchases (approved)<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Purchases (pending approval)<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> data for a given day can change after purchases are approved or rejected.","pos":[2882,3131]},{"content":"Dashboard-level affiliate ads performance report","pos":[3136,3184]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Affiliates performance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section on your <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Dashboard overview<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page provides a summary of performance data for affiliate ads in all apps that you have opted in to the Microsoft affiliate ads program, in graph and table form.","pos":[3186,3417]},{"content":"This report shows the same performance metrics and filters as the app-level affiliates performance report described above.","pos":[3418,3540]},{"content":"Related topics","pos":[3545,3559]},{"content":"About affiliate ads","pos":[3564,3583]},{"content":"Monetize with ads","pos":[3612,3629]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: Use the app-level and account-level affiliates performance reports on the Windows Dev Center dashboard to view performance data for affiliate ads in your apps.\ntitle: Affiliates performance report\nms.assetid: 38AD494C-0F85-4FED-8732-9064D1FC503D\n---\n\n# Affiliates performance report\n\nIf you have [opted in to the Microsoft affiliate ads program](about-affiliate-ads.md), you can view performance data for the affiliate ads that appear in your app in the following reports on the Windows Dev Center dashboard:\n\n-   [App-level affiliates performance report](affiliates-performance-report.md#app-level-affiliates-performance-report). This report provides performance data for affiliate ads in the currently selected app in the dashboard.\n-   [Dashboard-level affiliates performance report](affiliates-performance-report.md#dashboard-level-affiliates-performance-report). This report provides a summary of performance data for affiliate ads in all apps that you have opted in to the Microsoft affiliate ads program.\n\nThese reports are updated daily. By default, the reports are filtered on performance from the last 30 days, on all devices. To change these filters, click **Page filters** and choose a different time frame or an individual device type. Note that all data is aggregated based using UTC, not your particular time zone.\n\nThe following sections provide more details about these reports.\n\n## App-level affiliate ads performance report\n\nThis report provides affiliate ads performance data in graph and table form for the currently selected app in the dashboard. To view this report, select one of your apps in the dashboard and click **Analytics** &gt; **Affiliates performance** in the navigation pane.\n\nThe data is obtained from the following seven performance metrics we track for the ads in your app:\n\n-   **Estimated earnings (approved)**: The estimated amount of money you received as a commission for approved purchases made by users clicking affiliate ads in your app.\n-   **Estimated earnings (pending approval)**: The estimated amount of money you could receive as a commission for the purchases that are pending approval.\n-   **Impressions**: The number of times an affiliate ad was shown in your app.\n-   **Clicks**: The number of times someone clicked on an affiliate ad in your app.\n-   **CTR**: Click-through rate, meaning the number of times an affiliate ad was clicked, divided by the number of affiliate ad impressions.\n-   **Purchases (approved)**: The number of approved purchases made by users clicking affiliate ads in your app.\n-   **Purchases (pending approval)**: The number of purchases pending approval that were made by users clicking affiliate ads in your app.\n\n> **Note**  After a user buys a product in the Store, there is a 45 day waiting period before the purchase can be approved for the affiliate ads program. Because of this waiting period, the **Estimated earnings (approved)**, **Estimated earnings (pending approval)**, **Purchases (approved)** and **Purchases (pending approval)** data for a given day can change after purchases are approved or rejected.\n\n## Dashboard-level affiliate ads performance report\n\nThe **Affiliates performance** section on your **Dashboard overview** page provides a summary of performance data for affiliate ads in all apps that you have opted in to the Microsoft affiliate ads program, in graph and table form. This report shows the same performance metrics and filters as the app-level affiliates performance report described above.\n\n## Related topics\n\n* [About affiliate ads](about-affiliate-ads.md)\n* [Monetize with ads](monetize-with-ads.md)\n \n\n \n"}