{"nodes":[{"content":"You can create an ad campaign using the Dev Center dashboard to help promote your app and grow your app's user base.","pos":[30,146]},{"content":"Create an ad campaign for your app","pos":[154,188]},{"content":"Create an ad campaign for your app","pos":[245,279]},{"content":"You can create an ad campaign using the Dev Center dashboard to help promote your app and grow your app's user base.","pos":[282,398]},{"content":"By default, we will choose the target audience for your ads based on the settings for your app in the Dev Center dashboard, but you can optionally define your own audience.","pos":[399,571]},{"content":"You can also use a default set of ad templates or upload your own ad designs.","pos":[572,649]},{"content":"For more details about ad campaigns, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Common questions about ad campaigns<ept id=\"p1\">](common-questions.md)</ept>.","pos":[650,750]},{"pos":[754,919],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  You can create ad campaigns only for apps that have passed the final publishing phase of the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>app certification process<ept id=\"p2\">](the-app-certification-process.md)</ept>."},{"content":"Here's how to create an ad campaign to promote your app.","pos":[921,977]},{"pos":[983,1110],"content":"From the left navigation menu on your app's page in the Dev Center dashboard, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Monetization<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Promote your app<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."},{"content":"Do one of the following:","pos":[1115,1139]},{"content":"If you have not yet created an ad campaign for this app, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Promote your app<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page displays information about the benefits of ad campaigns.","pos":[1149,1292]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get started<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Create an ad campaign<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[1293,1344]},{"content":"If you have already created an ad campaign for this app, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Promote your app<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page lists your existing ad campaigns.","pos":[1353,1473]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New campaign<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[1474,1497]},{"pos":[1503,1615],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New campaign<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, define the overall settings for this campaign in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Campaign details<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> section."},{"pos":[1624,1677],"content":"Name your ad campaign in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Campaign name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field."},{"pos":[1686,1739],"content":"Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Campaign type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, choose one of these options:"},{"pos":[1752,1836],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Paid<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: These ads will run in any app that matches your app’s device and category."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Community (free)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: These ads will run in apps published by other developers who also create community ad campaigns.","pos":[1849,1967]},{"content":"Before you can select this option, you must first check the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Show community ads in my app<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> box in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Monetize with ads<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page of the dashboard.","pos":[1968,2116]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About community ads<ept id=\"p1\">](about-community-ads.md)</ept>.","pos":[2117,2189]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>House (free)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: These ads will only run in your apps (that match the advertised app’s device).","pos":[2202,2298]},{"content":"House ads are free of charge.","pos":[2299,2328]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About house ads<ept id=\"p1\">](about-house-ads.md)</ept>.","pos":[2329,2393]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  If your app is not yet published, you will receive an error message on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New campaign<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2401,2508]},{"content":"You must wait for your app to be published before you can create an ad campaign for it.","pos":[2509,2596]},{"content":"By default, we will choose the audience for your ads, based on the settings you selected when creating the app in the Dev Center dashboard.","pos":[2602,2741]},{"content":"If you would rather choose the audience for your ads yourself, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Switch to manual targeting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to expand the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Audience<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> section.","pos":[2742,2878]},{"content":"If you want to go back to default targeting, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Switch to auto targeting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2879,2960]},{"pos":[2966,3061],"content":"If you select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Switch to manual targeting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you can edit the following targeting information:"},{"content":"Choose the countries or regions in which you want these ads to appear.","pos":[3071,3141]},{"content":"You can choose up to 5.","pos":[3142,3165]},{"content":"For a list of the supported countries or regions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Common questions<ept id=\"p1\">](common-questions.md)</ept>.","pos":[3166,3260]},{"content":"Choose the device types on which you want these ads to appear.","pos":[3269,3331]},{"content":"Only the device types supported by your app are shown.","pos":[3332,3386]},{"content":"Choose the operating system.","pos":[3395,3423]},{"content":"Only the operating systems supported by your app are shown.","pos":[3424,3483]},{"content":"Select the gender and age range of your desired audience.","pos":[3492,3549]},{"content":"This section also displays an <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Estimated Reach<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> graph.","pos":[3555,3611]},{"content":"This graph shows the audience you can reach with your current targeting selections as a percentage of all Windows ad-enabled app users in the selected markets.","pos":[3612,3771]},{"pos":[3777,3835],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Ad design<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, choose one of these options:"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use custom creatives<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[3844,3869]},{"content":"Choose this option to use your own ad designs.","pos":[3870,3916]},{"content":"You can upload different files for each of the available ad sizes.","pos":[3917,3983]},{"content":"The files must meet the following requirements and guidelines:","pos":[3984,4046]},{"content":"Each file must be a .png or .jpg that is less than 2 MB.","pos":[4059,4115]},{"pos":[4128,4273],"content":"Your ad designs must meet the requirements specified in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Creative Acceptance Policy<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink?LinkId=532595)</ept>."},{"content":"The content in your ad designs must be relevant to the app you are promoting.","pos":[4286,4363]},{"content":"Ad designs that are not related to the app will not be distributed to ads in other apps.","pos":[4364,4452]},{"content":"All content in your ad designs should be clearly legible.","pos":[4465,4522]},{"content":"For example, content should not be blurred, pixelated or stretched.","pos":[4523,4590]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use auto-generated creatives<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4599,4632]},{"content":"Choose this option to use ads from a list of default templates.","pos":[4633,4696]},{"content":"You have the following options to customize the content in the ads.","pos":[4697,4764]},{"content":"As you make selections, the previews of your ads will update automatically.","pos":[4765,4840]},{"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Show my app rating<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> checkbox if you want to show the app's rating.","pos":[4853,4933]},{"content":"If your app is free in all the selected markets, you will also have the option to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Show that my app is free<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4934,5045]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Language<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> drop-down, select the language of the ads.","pos":[5058,5120]},{"content":"The text for the Windows Store badge and your custom tag line text (if specified) will show in the language you select.","pos":[5121,5240]},{"pos":[5253,5342],"content":"To add an extra line of text to your ad, enter the text in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Custom tag line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  The text you enter must be localized into the selected language.","pos":[5357,5431]},{"content":"The custom tag line will be rejected if the text does not align with <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Bing Ads policies<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink?LinkId=398341)</ept>.","pos":[5432,5567]},{"content":"Consult this page for guidance on style and disallowed content.","pos":[5568,5631]},{"content":"To choose a background color and an image for your ads, expand <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customize ad design / See all ad sizes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[5645,5751]},{"content":"The available images are the images you have associated with your app in the Store.","pos":[5752,5835]},{"content":"If you are using Kochava or Tune to measure install analytics for your app, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Third-party install tracking URL (Kochava or Tune)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and enter your install tracking URL from Kochava or Tune.","pos":[5840,6034]},{"content":"When you save the campaign, the tracking URL is validated to make sure that it resolves to the listing page for your app in the Windows Store.","pos":[6035,6177]},{"content":"For more information about install tracking with Kochava and Tune, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Kochava<ept id=\"p1\">](http://support.kochava.com/)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Tune<ept id=\"p2\">](https://help.tune.com/)</ept> documentation.","pos":[6178,6341]},{"pos":[6347,6434],"content":"Now choose your ad campaign's financial settings in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budget and payment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section."},{"pos":[6440,6603],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  If you are creating a house campaign or community campaign, the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Budget and payment<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> section will not appear, since these campaigns are free of charge."},{"pos":[6613,6717],"content":"Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budget<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, use the slider to set the amount of money you want to spend each month to run this ad."},{"content":"The monthly budget is prorated for the month in which the ad campaign is created.","pos":[6727,6808]},{"content":"In other words, if you create an ad campaign halfway through a calendar month, you will be charged for half of your monthly budget for that month.","pos":[6809,6955]},{"pos":[6965,7087],"content":"Set a payment instrument for your ad campaign by clicking <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add new payment instrument<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and fill in your account details."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  The country/region of your payment instrument's billing address must match the country/region associated with your Dev Center account.","pos":[7098,7247]},{"content":"-   If you have received a coupon from a Microsoft representative to pay for an ad campaign, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use a coupon<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, enter the coupon code, and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Apply<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to apply the coupon to the campaign.","pos":[7248,7448]},{"content":"Finally, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Review<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to confirm your ad campaign's settings and, if it's a paid ad campaign, its budget and payment information.","pos":[7454,7587]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirm<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and your ads will typically start appearing on devices within a few hours.","pos":[7588,7680]},{"content":"Related topics","pos":[7685,7699]},{"content":"Managing your ad campaign","pos":[7704,7729]},{"content":"About house ads","pos":[7764,7779]},{"content":"App install ads report","pos":[7804,7826]},{"content":"Common questions about ad campaigns","pos":[7859,7894]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: You can create an ad campaign using the Dev Center dashboard to help promote your app and grow your app's user base.\ntitle: Create an ad campaign for your app\nms.assetid: 10D94929-92C4-4379-AA5F-6FEF879F2463\n---\n\n# Create an ad campaign for your app\n\n\nYou can create an ad campaign using the Dev Center dashboard to help promote your app and grow your app's user base. By default, we will choose the target audience for your ads based on the settings for your app in the Dev Center dashboard, but you can optionally define your own audience. You can also use a default set of ad templates or upload your own ad designs. For more details about ad campaigns, see [Common questions about ad campaigns](common-questions.md).\n\n> **Note**  You can create ad campaigns only for apps that have passed the final publishing phase of the [app certification process](the-app-certification-process.md).\n\nHere's how to create an ad campaign to promote your app.\n\n1.  From the left navigation menu on your app's page in the Dev Center dashboard, click **Monetization** &gt; **Promote your app**.\n2.  Do one of the following:\n\n    -   If you have not yet created an ad campaign for this app, the **Promote your app** page displays information about the benefits of ad campaigns. Click **Get started** or **Create an ad campaign**.\n    -   If you have already created an ad campaign for this app, the **Promote your app** page lists your existing ad campaigns. Click **New campaign**.\n\n3.  On the **New campaign** page, define the overall settings for this campaign in the **Campaign details** section.\n    -   Name your ad campaign in the **Campaign name** field.\n    -   Under **Campaign type**, choose one of these options:\n        -   **Paid**: These ads will run in any app that matches your app’s device and category.\n        -   **Community (free)**: These ads will run in apps published by other developers who also create community ad campaigns. Before you can select this option, you must first check the **Show community ads in my app** box in the **Monetize with ads** page of the dashboard. For more information, see [About community ads](about-community-ads.md).\n        -   **House (free)**: These ads will only run in your apps (that match the advertised app’s device). House ads are free of charge. For more information, see [About house ads](about-house-ads.md).\n\n    > **Note**  If your app is not yet published, you will receive an error message on the **New campaign** page. You must wait for your app to be published before you can create an ad campaign for it.\n\n4.  By default, we will choose the audience for your ads, based on the settings you selected when creating the app in the Dev Center dashboard. If you would rather choose the audience for your ads yourself, select **Switch to manual targeting** to expand the **Audience** section. If you want to go back to default targeting, select **Switch to auto targeting**.\n\n    If you select **Switch to manual targeting**, you can edit the following targeting information:\n\n    -   Choose the countries or regions in which you want these ads to appear. You can choose up to 5. For a list of the supported countries or regions, see [Common questions](common-questions.md).\n    -   Choose the device types on which you want these ads to appear. Only the device types supported by your app are shown.\n    -   Choose the operating system. Only the operating systems supported by your app are shown.\n    -   Select the gender and age range of your desired audience.\n\n    This section also displays an **Estimated Reach** graph. This graph shows the audience you can reach with your current targeting selections as a percentage of all Windows ad-enabled app users in the selected markets.\n\n5.  In the **Ad design** section, choose one of these options:\n    -   **Use custom creatives**. Choose this option to use your own ad designs. You can upload different files for each of the available ad sizes. The files must meet the following requirements and guidelines:\n        -   Each file must be a .png or .jpg that is less than 2 MB.\n        -   Your ad designs must meet the requirements specified in the [Microsoft Creative Acceptance Policy](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink?LinkId=532595).\n        -   The content in your ad designs must be relevant to the app you are promoting. Ad designs that are not related to the app will not be distributed to ads in other apps.\n        -   All content in your ad designs should be clearly legible. For example, content should not be blurred, pixelated or stretched.\n    -   **Use auto-generated creatives**. Choose this option to use ads from a list of default templates. You have the following options to customize the content in the ads. As you make selections, the previews of your ads will update automatically.\n        -   Select the **Show my app rating** checkbox if you want to show the app's rating. If your app is free in all the selected markets, you will also have the option to **Show that my app is free**.\n        -   In the **Language** drop-down, select the language of the ads. The text for the Windows Store badge and your custom tag line text (if specified) will show in the language you select.\n        -   To add an extra line of text to your ad, enter the text in the **Custom tag line** field.\n            > **Note**  The text you enter must be localized into the selected language. The custom tag line will be rejected if the text does not align with [Bing Ads policies](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink?LinkId=398341). Consult this page for guidance on style and disallowed content.\n\n        -   To choose a background color and an image for your ads, expand **Customize ad design / See all ad sizes**. The available images are the images you have associated with your app in the Store.\n\n6. If you are using Kochava or Tune to measure install analytics for your app, click **Third-party install tracking URL (Kochava or Tune)** and enter your install tracking URL from Kochava or Tune. When you save the campaign, the tracking URL is validated to make sure that it resolves to the listing page for your app in the Windows Store. For more information about install tracking with Kochava and Tune, see the [Kochava](http://support.kochava.com/) and [Tune](https://help.tune.com/) documentation.\n\n7.  Now choose your ad campaign's financial settings in the **Budget and payment** section.\n   > **Note**  If you are creating a house campaign or community campaign, the **Budget and payment** section will not appear, since these campaigns are free of charge.\n\n    -   Under **Budget**, use the slider to set the amount of money you want to spend each month to run this ad.\n\n        The monthly budget is prorated for the month in which the ad campaign is created. In other words, if you create an ad campaign halfway through a calendar month, you will be charged for half of your monthly budget for that month.\n\n    -   Set a payment instrument for your ad campaign by clicking **Add new payment instrument** and fill in your account details.\n        > **Important**  The country/region of your payment instrument's billing address must match the country/region associated with your Dev Center account.\n    -   If you have received a coupon from a Microsoft representative to pay for an ad campaign, click **Use a coupon**, enter the coupon code, and click **Apply** to apply the coupon to the campaign.\n\n8.  Finally, click **Review** to confirm your ad campaign's settings and, if it's a paid ad campaign, its budget and payment information. Click **Confirm** and your ads will typically start appearing on devices within a few hours.\n\n## Related topics\n\n* [Managing your ad campaign](managing-your-ad-campaign.md)\n* [About house ads](about-house-ads.md)\n* [App install ads report](app-install-ads-reports.md)\n* [Common questions about ad campaigns](common-questions.md)\n \n\n \n"}