{"nodes":[{"content":"The Feedback report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you see the problems, suggestions, and upvotes that your Windows 10 customers have submitted through Feedback Hub.","pos":[30,205]},{"content":"Feedback report","pos":[213,228]},{"content":"Feedback report","pos":[285,300]},{"content":"Encouraging your customers to give you feedback about your app is a great way to learn about the problems and features that are most important to them.","pos":[302,453]},{"content":"When your customers know they can send you feedback directly, they may be less likely to leave that feedback as a negative review.","pos":[454,584]},{"pos":[589,699],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The Feedback report that is described in this article is not yet available to all developer accounts."},{"content":"You can use the Feedback API in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk)</ept> to let customers <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>directly launch Feedback Hub from your app<ept id=\"p2\">](../monetize/launch-feedback-hub-from-your-app.md)</ept>.","pos":[701,927]},{"content":"Keep in mind that any customer who has downloaded your app on a Windows 10 device that supports Feedback Hub has the ability to leave feedback for it by using the Feedback Hub app.","pos":[928,1108]},{"content":"Because of this, you may see customer feedback in this report, even if you have not specifically asked for feedback from within your app.","pos":[1109,1246]},{"pos":[1250,1491],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tip<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Feedback becomes especially valuable if you are using <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>package flighting<ept id=\"p2\">](package-flights.md)</ept>, since the Feedback report will show you the specific package that each customer had installed on their device when they left the feedback."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Feedback<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you see the problems, suggestions, and upvotes that your Windows 10 customers have submitted through Feedback Hub.","pos":[1493,1672]},{"content":"You can view this data in your dashboard, or export the data to view offline.","pos":[1673,1750]},{"content":"Viewing feedback details","pos":[1756,1780]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of this report, you’ll find the individual feedback left by your customers.","pos":[1782,1884]},{"content":"To the left of the feedback text, you’ll see the number of times the feedback was upvoted by other customers in the Feedback Hub.","pos":[1885,2014]},{"content":"You can sort the feedback in three ways:","pos":[2015,2055]},{"pos":[2059,2198],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Upvoted<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (default): Shows feedback that has been upvoted by other customers, starting with the feedback which received the most upvotes."},{"pos":[2201,2370],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Trending<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Shows feedback that has been upvoted by other customers in the last seven days, starting with the feedback which has been getting the most recent activity."},{"pos":[2373,2456],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Most recent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Shows all feedback, starting with the feedback most recently left."},{"content":"Next to each comment you’ll see the date on which the feedback was left, and the type of feedback.","pos":[2459,2557]},{"content":"You’ll also see the customer’s market, the specific package of your app that was installed on the device they were using when they left the feedback, the type of that device, and <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Windows Insider<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> if the customer submitting the feedback is a member of the Windows Insider program.","pos":[2558,2840]},{"content":"Apply filters","pos":[2846,2859]},{"pos":[2861,2959],"content":"Near the top of the page, you can expand <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to filter all of the data on this page."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tip<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you don't see any feedback on the page, check to make sure your filters haven't excluded all of your feedback.","pos":[2963,3084]},{"content":"For example, if you filter by a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Device type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> that your app doesn't support, you won't see any feedback.","pos":[3085,3191]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default filter is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All time<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3195,3240]},{"content":"You can select shorter timeframes ranging from <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Last 30 days<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> up to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Last 12 months<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3241,3330]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Feedback type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default setting is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3333,3383]},{"content":"You can select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Problem<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Suggestion<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to show only that type of feedback.","pos":[3384,3464]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Device type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default setting is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All devices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3467,3523]},{"content":"You can select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Phone<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>PC<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Tablet<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> to show only feedback left from that type of device.","pos":[3524,3624]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Package version<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default setting is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All packages<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3627,3688]},{"content":"You can select one of your packages to show only feedback left from customers who were using that particular package when they left feedback.","pos":[3689,3830]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Market<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default setting is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All markets<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3833,3884]},{"content":"You can choose a specific to show only feedback from customers in that market.","pos":[3885,3963]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The default setting is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3966,4008]},{"content":"You can choose to view only feedback submitted by <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Insiders<ept id=\"p1\">](http://insider.windows.com)</ept>.","pos":[4009,4106]},{"content":"Translating feedback","pos":[4111,4131]},{"content":"By default, reviews that were not written in your preferred language are translated for you.","pos":[4133,4225]},{"content":"If you prefer, feedback translation can be disabled by unchecking the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Translate reviews<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> checkbox at the upper right, above the list of feedback.","pos":[4226,4374]},{"content":"Please note that feedback is translated by an automatic translation system, and the resulting translation may not always be accurate.","pos":[4376,4509]},{"content":"The original text is provided if you wish to compare it to the translation, or translate it through some other means.","pos":[4510,4627]},{"content":"Launching Feedback Hub directly from your app","pos":[4632,4677]},{"content":"As noted above, we recommend incorporating a link to Feedback Hub directly in your app to encourage customers to provide feedback.","pos":[4679,4809]},{"content":"For more info, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Launch Feedback Hub from your app<ept id=\"p1\">](../monetize/launch-feedback-hub-from-your-app.md)</ept>.","pos":[4810,4915]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: The Feedback report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you see the problems, suggestions, and upvotes that your Windows 10 customers have submitted through Feedback Hub.\ntitle: Feedback report\nms.assetid: 9EA8B456-CA57-40CE-A55B-7BFDC55CA8A8\n---\n\n# Feedback report\n\nEncouraging your customers to give you feedback about your app is a great way to learn about the problems and features that are most important to them. When your customers know they can send you feedback directly, they may be less likely to leave that feedback as a negative review. \n\n> **Note** The Feedback report that is described in this article is not yet available to all developer accounts.\n\nYou can use the Feedback API in the [Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk) to let customers [directly launch Feedback Hub from your app](../monetize/launch-feedback-hub-from-your-app.md). Keep in mind that any customer who has downloaded your app on a Windows 10 device that supports Feedback Hub has the ability to leave feedback for it by using the Feedback Hub app. Because of this, you may see customer feedback in this report, even if you have not specifically asked for feedback from within your app.\n\n> **Tip** Feedback becomes especially valuable if you are using [package flighting](package-flights.md), since the Feedback report will show you the specific package that each customer had installed on their device when they left the feedback.\n\nThe **Feedback** report in the Windows Dev Center dashboard lets you see the problems, suggestions, and upvotes that your Windows 10 customers have submitted through Feedback Hub. You can view this data in your dashboard, or export the data to view offline. \n\n## Viewing feedback details\n\nIn the **Details** section of this report, you’ll find the individual feedback left by your customers. To the left of the feedback text, you’ll see the number of times the feedback was upvoted by other customers in the Feedback Hub. You can sort the feedback in three ways:\n\n- **Upvoted** (default): Shows feedback that has been upvoted by other customers, starting with the feedback which received the most upvotes.\n- **Trending**: Shows feedback that has been upvoted by other customers in the last seven days, starting with the feedback which has been getting the most recent activity.\n- **Most recent**: Shows all feedback, starting with the feedback most recently left. \n\nNext to each comment you’ll see the date on which the feedback was left, and the type of feedback. You’ll also see the customer’s market, the specific package of your app that was installed on the device they were using when they left the feedback, the type of that device, and **Windows Insider** if the customer submitting the feedback is a member of the Windows Insider program.\n\n\n## Apply filters\n\nNear the top of the page, you can expand **Apply filters** to filter all of the data on this page.\n\n> **Tip** If you don't see any feedback on the page, check to make sure your filters haven't excluded all of your feedback. For example, if you filter by a **Device type** that your app doesn't support, you won't see any feedback.\n\n- **Date**: The default filter is **All time**. You can select shorter timeframes ranging from **Last 30 days** up to **Last 12 months**.\n- **Feedback type**: The default setting is **All**. You can select **Problem** or **Suggestion** to show only that type of feedback.\n- **Device type**: The default setting is **All devices**. You can select **Phone**, **PC**, or **Tablet** to show only feedback left from that type of device.\n- **Package version**: The default setting is **All packages**. You can select one of your packages to show only feedback left from customers who were using that particular package when they left feedback.\n- **Market**: The default setting is **All markets**. You can choose a specific to show only feedback from customers in that market.\n- **Group**: The default setting is **All**. You can choose to view only feedback submitted by [Windows Insiders](http://insider.windows.com).\n\n## Translating feedback\n\nBy default, reviews that were not written in your preferred language are translated for you. If you prefer, feedback translation can be disabled by unchecking the **Translate reviews** checkbox at the upper right, above the list of feedback.\n\nPlease note that feedback is translated by an automatic translation system, and the resulting translation may not always be accurate. The original text is provided if you wish to compare it to the translation, or translate it through some other means.\n\n## Launching Feedback Hub directly from your app\n\nAs noted above, we recommend incorporating a link to Feedback Hub directly in your app to encourage customers to provide feedback. For more info, see [Launch Feedback Hub from your app](../monetize/launch-feedback-hub-from-your-app.md).\n"}