{"nodes":[{"content":"Best practices for Xbox","pos":[26,49]},{"content":"How to optimize your application for Xbox.","pos":[63,105]},{"content":"Best practices for Xbox","pos":[124,147]},{"content":"If you want to build the best experience for Xbox or are working with code that you use on more than one TV platform, we recommend you take a look at the following information.","pos":[148,324]},{"content":"How to turn off mouse mode","pos":[331,357]},{"content":"Mouse mode is the default.","pos":[358,384]},{"content":"We strongly recommend you turn this off and optimize for directional controller navigation.","pos":[385,476]},{"content":"Learn more","pos":[479,489]},{"content":"How to draw to the edge of the screen","pos":[525,562]},{"content":"By default, there will be borders around your application.","pos":[563,621]},{"content":"To remove these borders and be able to use the full height and width of the screen, you can turn off automatic scaling.","pos":[622,741]},{"content":"Learn more","pos":[744,754]},{"content":"How to disable scaling","pos":[782,804]},{"content":"By default, your application will be scaled to 200% if you are using XAML or 150% for HTML.","pos":[805,896]},{"content":"It is possible to turn off automatic scaling.","pos":[897,942]},{"content":"Learn more","pos":[945,955]}],"content":"---\nauthor: payzer\ntitle: Best practices for Xbox\ndescription: How to optimize your application for Xbox.\narea: Xbox\n---\n\n# Best practices for Xbox\nIf you want to build the best experience for Xbox or are working with code that you use on more than one TV platform, we recommend you take a look at the following information.  \n\n## How to turn off mouse mode\nMouse mode is the default. We strongly recommend you turn this off and optimize for directional controller navigation.  [Learn more](how-to-disable-mouse-mode.md)\n\n## How to draw to the edge of the screen\nBy default, there will be borders around your application. To remove these borders and be able to use the full height and width of the screen, you can turn off automatic scaling.  [Learn more](turn-off-overscan.md)\n\n## How to disable scaling\nBy default, your application will be scaled to 200% if you are using XAML or 150% for HTML. It is possible to turn off automatic scaling.  [Learn more](disable-scaling.md)\n"}