{"nodes":[{"content":"Introduction to Xbox One tools","pos":[27,57]},{"content":"The Xbox One-specific tool Dev Home, using the Windows Device Portal.","pos":[71,140]},{"content":"Introduction to Xbox One tools","pos":[159,189]},{"pos":[191,282],"content":"This section covers the Xbox One-specific tool <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>Dev Home<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept>, using the Windows Device Portal."},{"content":"Dev Home","pos":[287,295]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>Dev Home<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> is a tools experience on the Xbox One Development Kit designed to aid developer productivity.","pos":[297,401]},{"content":"Dev Home offers functionality to manage and configure your dev kit.","pos":[402,469]},{"content":"To open Dev Home, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dev Home<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tile on the home screen.","pos":[471,537]},{"content":"If there is no tile present, the console is not in Developer Mode.","pos":[538,604]},{"content":"Windows Device Portal","pos":[610,631]},{"content":"User interface","pos":[672,686]},{"content":"The Dev Home user interface is divided into the areas described in the following sections.","pos":[687,777]},{"content":"Note the console IP address and friendly name are displayed here.","pos":[778,843]},{"content":"DevHome UI","pos":[849,859]},{"content":"Header","pos":[890,896]},{"content":"The header contains important “at a glance” information about the dev kit.","pos":[897,971]},{"content":"This includes the console name, its IP address, the Xbox Live sandbox it is in, and the version of the operating system it is running.","pos":[972,1106]},{"content":"On the right of the header, the current system time and date is shown for convenience.","pos":[1107,1193]},{"content":"Tool windows","pos":[1200,1212]},{"content":"Under the header is the main area of the app, which contains a set of configurable tool windows.","pos":[1213,1309]},{"content":"These are intended to allow developers to customize the app to provide access to various tools and sets of information.","pos":[1310,1429]},{"content":"For more details about the tools, see the following individual tool descriptions.","pos":[1430,1511]},{"content":"For information about how to configure the layout and appearance of the tool windows, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Customizing Dev Home<ept id=\"p1\">](#customizing-dev-home)</ept> section later on this page.","pos":[1512,1679]},{"content":"Main menu","pos":[1687,1696]},{"pos":[1697,1976],"content":"By pressing the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Menu<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button on your controller or navigating to the menu (“Hamburger”) button at the top left of the screen, you can access the main menu that allows you to configure the theme color and background image for the app workspace, and provide feedback on the app."},{"content":"Main menu","pos":[1982,1991]},{"content":"Snap mode","pos":[2028,2037]},{"content":"Tools in Dev Home can be snapped to the side while you are running your title so that you can have easy access to tools while you are testing.","pos":[2038,2180]},{"pos":[2182,2336],"content":"To access <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Snap<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> mode, select the title of the appropriate tool, press the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>View<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> button on your controller, and on the context menu, select <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Snap<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."},{"content":"Snap mode","pos":[2342,2351]},{"content":"Dev Home will snap right.","pos":[2383,2408]},{"content":"You can switch context by double tapping the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Nexus<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button as usual.","pos":[2409,2480]},{"content":"Nexus","pos":[2486,2491]},{"content":"Tool descriptions","pos":[2526,2543]},{"content":"Tool","pos":[2546,2550]},{"content":"Capabilities","pos":[2554,2566]},{"content":"Games &amp; Apps","pos":[2596,2608]},{"content":"Lists the titles and apps installed on the dev kit and the ability to quickly open them.","pos":[2612,2700]},{"content":"You can also view the process lifetime management (PLM) state of games and apps, and change PLM states from a context menu.","pos":[2701,2824]},{"content":"Users","pos":[2829,2834]},{"content":"Lists the users currently registered on the console.","pos":[2837,2889]},{"content":"Enables one-click user sign in/out, adding users and guests, and viewing details of users and guests.","pos":[2890,2991]},{"content":"Console settings","pos":[2997,3013]},{"content":"Provides an “at a glance” view and editing options of console settings and information.","pos":[3036,3123]},{"content":"Visual Studio","pos":[3128,3141]},{"content":"Enables you to pair the console with an instance of Visual Studio to allow deployment.","pos":[3144,3230]},{"content":"If necessary, clear any existing paired VS instances to prevent UWP app deployment to a kit.","pos":[3231,3323]},{"content":"Windows Device Portal","pos":[3329,3350]},{"content":"Enables WDP (a browser-based device management tool) on the kit.","pos":[3378,3442]},{"content":"Xbox Live status","pos":[3447,3463]},{"content":"Provides the current status of the Xbox Live service.","pos":[3466,3519]},{"content":"Customizing Dev Home","pos":[3527,3547]},{"content":"Dev Home has been designed to be customizable and personal.","pos":[3549,3608]},{"content":"You can choose a background image and theme color to personalize your Dev Home experience.","pos":[3609,3699]},{"content":"These options are found on the main menu.","pos":[3700,3741]},{"content":"Resizing and reordering tools","pos":[3748,3777]},{"content":"To change the size or position of a tool, use the context menu button (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>View<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button on your controller) while the title has focus.","pos":[3778,3911]},{"content":"On the context menu, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Move<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Resize<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3912,3963]},{"content":"Move or resize","pos":[3969,3983]},{"content":"Changing theme color and background image","pos":[4016,4057]},{"content":"On the main menu, you can select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change theme color<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4058,4114]},{"content":"To update the theme color used for focus highlighting, select a new color and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4115,4213]},{"content":"Change theme color","pos":[4219,4237]},{"content":"Providing feedback","pos":[4271,4289]},{"pos":[4290,4410],"content":"To provide feedback on Dev Home, or any of the tools processes, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Provide feedback<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option on the main menu."},{"content":"Provide feedback","pos":[4416,4432]},{"content":"Console settings","pos":[4467,4483]},{"content":"The Console settings tool provides quick access to the settings of the dev kit.","pos":[4484,4563]},{"content":"Setting a hostname for the console","pos":[4569,4603]},{"content":"When communicating with the console from your development PC, you can set a friendly name (called a <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>hostname<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept>) for the Xbox One dev kit to use as an alternative to the console IP address.","pos":[4604,4792]},{"content":"Your development PC and the dev kit must be on the same subnet for hostname connectivity to work.","pos":[4793,4890]},{"pos":[4894,5008],"content":"To define a hostname for a dev kit, go to the Console settings tool and type the hostname in the <bpt id=\"p1\">__</bpt>Hostname<ept id=\"p1\">__</ept> box."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>Name uniqueness is not enforced when the hostname is created.","pos":[5016,5097]},{"content":"Be careful to avoid name duplication.","pos":[5098,5135]},{"content":"One way to do this is to derive the hostname from the name of your development computer, which is usually unique within an organization.","pos":[5136,5272]},{"content":"Windows Device Portal","pos":[5277,5298]},{"content":"Windows Device Portal (WDP) is a OneCore device management tool that allows a browser-based device management experience.","pos":[5299,5420]},{"content":"To enable WDP on your Xbox One console:","pos":[5422,5461]},{"content":"Select the Dev Home tile on the home screen.","pos":[5466,5510]},{"content":"Select Dev Home tile","pos":[5516,5536]},{"pos":[5576,5636],"content":"Within Dev Home, navigate to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Remote management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tool."},{"content":"Remote management tool","pos":[5642,5664]},{"pos":[5704,5766],"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">__</bpt>Manage Windows Device Portal<ept id=\"p1\">__</ept>, and then press <bpt id=\"p2\">__</bpt>A<ept id=\"p2\">__</ept>."},{"pos":[5770,5824],"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">__</bpt>Enable Windows Device Portal<ept id=\"p1\">__</ept> check box."},{"content":"Enter a <bpt id=\"p1\">__</bpt>Username<ept id=\"p1\">__</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">__</bpt>Password<ept id=\"p2\">__</ept>, and save them.","pos":[5828,5881]},{"content":"These are used to authenticate access to your dev kit from a browser.","pos":[5882,5951]},{"pos":[5955,6051],"content":"Close the <bpt id=\"p1\">__</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">__</ept> page, and note the URL listed on the <bpt id=\"p2\">_</bpt>Remote Management<ept id=\"p2\">_</ept> tool to connect."},{"content":"Enter the URL in your browser, and then sign in with the credentials you configured.","pos":[6055,6139]},{"content":"You will receive a warning about the certificate that was provided, similar to the following screenshot, because the security certificate signed by your Xbox One console is not considered a well-known trusted publisher.","pos":[6143,6362]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Continue to this website<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to access the Windows Device Portal.","pos":[6363,6434]},{"content":"Security certificate warning","pos":[6440,6468]},{"content":"See also","pos":[6508,6516]},{"content":"Microsoft Developer technologies: Windows Device Portal","pos":[6520,6575]},{"content":"UWP on Xbox One","pos":[6649,6664]}],"content":"---\nauthor: Mtoepke\ntitle: Introduction to Xbox One tools\ndescription: The Xbox One-specific tool Dev Home, using the Windows Device Portal.\narea: Xbox\n---\n\n# Introduction to Xbox One tools\n\nThis section covers the Xbox One-specific tool _Dev Home_, using the Windows Device Portal.\n\n## Dev Home\n\n_Dev Home_ is a tools experience on the Xbox One Development Kit designed to aid developer productivity. Dev Home offers functionality to manage and configure your dev kit.\n\nTo open Dev Home, select the **Dev Home** tile on the home screen. If there is no tile present, the console is not in Developer Mode.\n\n  ![Windows Device Portal](images/windowsdeviceportal_1.png)\n\n### User interface\nThe Dev Home user interface is divided into the areas described in the following sections. Note the console IP address and friendly name are displayed here.\n\n  ![DevHome UI](images/devhome_ui.png)\n\n#### Header\nThe header contains important “at a glance” information about the dev kit. This includes the console name, its IP address, the Xbox Live sandbox it is in, and the version of the operating system it is running. On the right of the header, the current system time and date is shown for convenience.\n\n#### Tool windows\nUnder the header is the main area of the app, which contains a set of configurable tool windows. These are intended to allow developers to customize the app to provide access to various tools and sets of information. For more details about the tools, see the following individual tool descriptions. For information about how to configure the layout and appearance of the tool windows, see the [Customizing Dev Home](#customizing-dev-home) section later on this page.\n\n##### Main menu\nBy pressing the **Menu** button on your controller or navigating to the menu (“Hamburger”) button at the top left of the screen, you can access the main menu that allows you to configure the theme color and background image for the app workspace, and provide feedback on the app.\n\n  ![Main menu](images/devhome_mainmenu.png)\n\n#### Snap mode\nTools in Dev Home can be snapped to the side while you are running your title so that you can have easy access to tools while you are testing.\n\nTo access **Snap** mode, select the title of the appropriate tool, press the **View** button on your controller, and on the context menu, select **Snap**.\n\n  ![Snap mode](images/devhome_snapmode.png)\n\nDev Home will snap right. You can switch context by double tapping the **Nexus** button as usual.\n\n  ![Nexus](images/devhome_nexus.png)\n\n##### Tool descriptions\n| Tool  | Capabilities |\n|-------|--------------|\n| Games & Apps  | Lists the titles and apps installed on the dev kit and the ability to quickly open them. You can also view the process lifetime management (PLM) state of games and apps, and change PLM states from a context menu. |\n| Users | Lists the users currently registered on the console. Enables one-click user sign in/out, adding users and guests, and viewing details of users and guests. |\n| [Console settings](#console-settings) | Provides an “at a glance” view and editing options of console settings and information. |\n| Visual Studio | Enables you to pair the console with an instance of Visual Studio to allow deployment. If necessary, clear any existing paired VS instances to prevent UWP app deployment to a kit. |\n| [Windows Device Portal](#windows-device-portal) | Enables WDP (a browser-based device management tool) on the kit. |\n| Xbox Live status | Provides the current status of the Xbox Live service. |\n\n### Customizing Dev Home\n\nDev Home has been designed to be customizable and personal. You can choose a background image and theme color to personalize your Dev Home experience. These options are found on the main menu.\n\n#### Resizing and reordering tools\nTo change the size or position of a tool, use the context menu button (**View** button on your controller) while the title has focus. On the context menu, select **Move** or **Resize**.\n\n  ![Move or resize](images/devhome_move.png)\n\n#### Changing theme color and background image\nOn the main menu, you can select **Change theme color**. To update the theme color used for focus highlighting, select a new color and then click **Save**.\n\n  ![Change theme color](images/devhome_colors.png)\n\n### Providing feedback\nTo provide feedback on Dev Home, or any of the tools processes, select the **Provide feedback** option on the main menu.\n\n  ![Provide feedback](images/devhome_feedback.png)\n\n## Console settings\nThe Console settings tool provides quick access to the settings of the dev kit.\n\n### Setting a hostname for the console\nWhen communicating with the console from your development PC, you can set a friendly name (called a _hostname_) for the Xbox One dev kit to use as an alternative to the console IP address. Your development PC and the dev kit must be on the same subnet for hostname connectivity to work.  \n\nTo define a hostname for a dev kit, go to the Console settings tool and type the hostname in the __Hostname__ box.  \n\n  > **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;Name uniqueness is not enforced when the hostname is created. Be careful to avoid name duplication. One way to do this is to derive the hostname from the name of your development computer, which is usually unique within an organization.\n\n## Windows Device Portal\nWindows Device Portal (WDP) is a OneCore device management tool that allows a browser-based device management experience.\n\nTo enable WDP on your Xbox One console:\n\n1. Select the Dev Home tile on the home screen.\n\n  ![Select Dev Home tile](images/windowsdeviceportal_1.png)\n\n2. Within Dev Home, navigate to the **Remote management** tool.\n\n  ![Remote management tool](images/windowsdeviceportal_2.png)\n\n3. Select __Manage Windows Device Portal__, and then press __A__.\n4. Select the __Enable Windows Device Portal__ check box.\n5. Enter a __Username__ and __Password__, and save them. These are used to authenticate access to your dev kit from a browser.\n6. Close the __Settings__ page, and note the URL listed on the _Remote Management_ tool to connect.\n7. Enter the URL in your browser, and then sign in with the credentials you configured.\n8. You will receive a warning about the certificate that was provided, similar to the following screenshot, because the security certificate signed by your Xbox One console is not considered a well-known trusted publisher. Click **Continue to this website** to access the Windows Device Portal.\n\n  ![Security certificate warning](images/security_cert_warning.jpg)\n\n## See also\n- [Microsoft Developer technologies: Windows Device Portal](https://ms-iot.github.io/content/en-US/win10/tools/DevicePortal.htm)\n- [UWP on Xbox One](index.md)\n\n\n\n----\n"}