{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Troubleshoot Hyper-V on Windows 10",
      "pos": [
        2,
        36
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I updated to Windows 10 and now I can't connect to my downlevel (Windows 8.1 or Server 2012 R2) host",
      "pos": [
        41,
        141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Windows 10, Hyper-V manager moved to WinRM for remote management.",
      "pos": [
        142,
        210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What that means is now Remote Management has to be enabled on the remote host in order to use Hyper-V manager to manage it.",
      "pos": [
        212,
        335
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        337,
        420
      ],
      "content": "For more information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Managing Remote Hyper-V Hosts<ept id=\"p1\">](remote_host_management.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "I changed the checkpoint type, but it is still taking the wrong type of checkpoint",
      "pos": [
        425,
        507
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are taking the checkpoint from VMConnect and you change the checkpoint type in Hyper-V manager the checkpoint taken be whatever checkpoint type was specified when VMConnect was opened.",
      "pos": [
        508,
        699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Close VMConnect and reopen it to make it take the correct type of checkpoint.",
      "pos": [
        701,
        778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When I try to create a virtual hard disk on a flash drive, an error message is displayed",
      "pos": [
        783,
        871
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V does not support FAT/FAT32 formatted disk drives since these file systems do not provide access control lists (ACLs) and do not support files larger than 4GB.",
      "pos": [
        872,
        1038
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ExFAT formatted disks only provide limited ACL functionality and are therefore also not supported for security reasons.",
      "pos": [
        1039,
        1158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The error message displayed in PowerShell is \"The system failed to create '\\[path to VHD\\]': The requested operation could not be completed due to a file system limitation (0x80070299).\"",
      "pos": [
        1159,
        1345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use a NTFS formatted drive instead.",
      "pos": [
        1347,
        1382
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I get this message when I try to install: \"Hyper-V cannot be installed: The processor does not support second level address translation (SLAT).\"",
      "pos": [
        1388,
        1532
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V requires SLAT in order to run virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        1533,
        1588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you computer does not support SLAT, then it cannot be a host for virtual mahchines.",
      "pos": [
        1589,
        1675
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1677,
        1830
      ],
      "content": "If you are only trying to install the management tools, unselect <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Hyper-V Platform<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Programs and Features<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Turn Windows features on or off<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "# Troubleshoot Hyper-V on Windows 10\n\n## I updated to Windows 10 and now I can't connect to my downlevel (Windows 8.1 or Server 2012 R2) host\nIn Windows 10, Hyper-V manager moved to WinRM for remote management.  What that means is now Remote Management has to be enabled on the remote host in order to use Hyper-V manager to manage it.\n\nFor more information see [Managing Remote Hyper-V Hosts](remote_host_management.md)\n\n## I changed the checkpoint type, but it is still taking the wrong type of checkpoint\nIf you are taking the checkpoint from VMConnect and you change the checkpoint type in Hyper-V manager the checkpoint taken be whatever checkpoint type was specified when VMConnect was opened.\n\nClose VMConnect and reopen it to make it take the correct type of checkpoint.\n\n## When I try to create a virtual hard disk on a flash drive, an error message is displayed\nHyper-V does not support FAT/FAT32 formatted disk drives since these file systems do not provide access control lists (ACLs) and do not support files larger than 4GB. ExFAT formatted disks only provide limited ACL functionality and are therefore also not supported for security reasons.\nThe error message displayed in PowerShell is \"The system failed to create '\\[path to VHD\\]': The requested operation could not be completed due to a file system limitation (0x80070299).\"\n\nUse a NTFS formatted drive instead. \n\n## I get this message when I try to install: \"Hyper-V cannot be installed: The processor does not support second level address translation (SLAT).\"\nHyper-V requires SLAT in order to run virtual machines. If you computer does not support SLAT, then it cannot be a host for virtual mahchines.\n\nIf you are only trying to install the management tools, unselect **Hyper-V Platform** in **Programs and Features** > **Turn Windows features on or off**.\n"
}