{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Policy-based VPN type:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Policy-based VPNs were previously called static routing gateways in the classic deployment model.",
      "pos": [
        2,
        126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policy-based VPNs encrypt and direct packets through IPsec tunnels based on the IPsec policies configured with the combinations of address prefixes between your on premises network and the Azure VNet.",
      "pos": [
        127,
        327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The policy (or traffic selector) is usually defined as an access list in the VPN device configuration.",
      "pos": [
        328,
        430
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The value for a policy-based VPN type is <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>PolicyBased<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        431,
        486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Route-based VPN type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Route-based VPNs were previously called dynamic routing gateways in the classic deployment model.",
      "pos": [
        490,
        613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Route-based VPNs use \"routes\" in the IP forwarding or routing table to direct packets into their corresponding tunnel interfaces.",
      "pos": [
        614,
        743
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The tunnel interfaces then encrypt or decrypt the packets in and out of the tunnels.",
      "pos": [
        744,
        828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The policy (or traffic selector) for route-based VPNs are configured as any-to-any (or wild cards).",
      "pos": [
        829,
        928
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The value for a route-based VPN type is <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>RouteBased<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        929,
        982
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "- **Policy-based VPN type:** Policy-based VPNs were previously called static routing gateways in the classic deployment model. Policy-based VPNs encrypt and direct packets through IPsec tunnels based on the IPsec policies configured with the combinations of address prefixes between your on premises network and the Azure VNet. The policy (or traffic selector) is usually defined as an access list in the VPN device configuration. The value for a policy-based VPN type is *PolicyBased*.\n\n- **Route-based VPN type**: Route-based VPNs were previously called dynamic routing gateways in the classic deployment model. Route-based VPNs use \"routes\" in the IP forwarding or routing table to direct packets into their corresponding tunnel interfaces. The tunnel interfaces then encrypt or decrypt the packets in and out of the tunnels. The policy (or traffic selector) for route-based VPNs are configured as any-to-any (or wild cards). The value for a route-based VPN type is *RouteBased*."
}