{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Using Azure AD Connect Health with sync | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        29,
        86
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is the Azure AD Connect Health page that will discuss how to monitor Azure AD Connect sync.",
      "pos": [
        106,
        202
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Azure AD Connect Health for sync",
      "pos": [
        545,
        583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following documentation is specific to monitoring Azure AD Connect sync with Azure AD Connect Health.",
      "pos": [
        584,
        689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information on monitoring AD FS with Azure AD Connect Health see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using Azure AD Connect Health with AD FS<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-health-adfs.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        691,
        847
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health for Sync",
      "pos": [
        851,
        883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Alerts for Azure AD Connect Health for sync",
      "pos": [
        947,
        990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure AD Connect Health Alerts for sync section provides you the list of active alerts.",
      "pos": [
        991,
        1082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each alert includes relevant information, resolution steps, and links to related documentation.",
      "pos": [
        1083,
        1178
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By selecting an active or resolved alert you will see a new blade with additional information, as well as steps you can take to resolve the alert, and links to additional documentation.",
      "pos": [
        1179,
        1364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also view historical data on alerts that were resolved in the past.",
      "pos": [
        1365,
        1440
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By selecting an alert you will be provided with additional information as well as steps you can take to resolve the alert and links to additional documentation.",
      "pos": [
        1442,
        1602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect sync error",
      "pos": [
        1606,
        1633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync Insight",
      "pos": [
        1698,
        1710
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With the latest release of Azure AD Connect Health for sync the following new capabilities have been added:",
      "pos": [
        1711,
        1818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Latency of sync operations",
      "pos": [
        1822,
        1848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Object Change trend",
      "pos": [
        1851,
        1870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync Latency",
      "pos": [
        1876,
        1888
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This feature provides a graphical trend of latency of the sync operations (import, export, etc.) for connectors.",
      "pos": [
        1889,
        2001
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This provides a quick and easy way to understand not only the latency of your operations (great if you have a large set of changes occurring) but also a way to detect anomalies in the latency that may require further investigation.",
      "pos": [
        2003,
        2234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync Latency",
      "pos": [
        2238,
        2250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default, only the latency of the 'Export' operation for the Azure AD connector is shown.",
      "pos": [
        2318,
        2409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see more operations on the connector or to view operations from other connectors, right-click on the chart and choose the specific operation and connector.",
      "pos": [
        2411,
        2569
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync Object Changes",
      "pos": [
        2575,
        2594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This feature provides a graphical trend of the number of changes that are being evaluated and exported to Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        2595,
        2710
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Today, trying to gather this information from the sync logs is difficult.",
      "pos": [
        2712,
        2785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The chart gives you, not only a simpler way of monitoring the number of changes that are occurring in your environment, but also a visual view of the failures that are occurring.",
      "pos": [
        2787,
        2965
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sync Latency",
      "pos": [
        2972,
        2984
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Related links",
      "pos": [
        3061,
        3074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health",
      "pos": [
        3079,
        3102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health Agent Installation",
      "pos": [
        3146,
        3188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health Operations",
      "pos": [
        3246,
        3280
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Azure AD Connect Health with AD FS",
      "pos": [
        3335,
        3375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health FAQ",
      "pos": [
        3424,
        3451
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "\n<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Using Azure AD Connect Health with sync | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"This is the Azure AD Connect Health page that will discuss how to monitor Azure AD Connect sync.\" \n    services=\"active-directory\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"billmath\" \n    manager=\"stevenpo\" \n    editor=\"curtand\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"active-directory\" \n    ms.workload=\"identity\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"get-started-article\" \n    ms.date=\"12/16/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"billmath\"/>\n\n# Using Azure AD Connect Health for sync\nThe following documentation is specific to monitoring Azure AD Connect sync with Azure AD Connect Health.  For information on monitoring AD FS with Azure AD Connect Health see [Using Azure AD Connect Health with AD FS](active-directory-aadconnect-health-adfs.md).\n\n![Azure AD Connect Health for Sync](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-health-sync/sync.png)\n\n## Alerts for Azure AD Connect Health for sync\nThe Azure AD Connect Health Alerts for sync section provides you the list of active alerts. Each alert includes relevant information, resolution steps, and links to related documentation. By selecting an active or resolved alert you will see a new blade with additional information, as well as steps you can take to resolve the alert, and links to additional documentation. You can also view historical data on alerts that were resolved in the past.\n\nBy selecting an alert you will be provided with additional information as well as steps you can take to resolve the alert and links to additional documentation.\n\n![Azure AD Connect sync error](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-health-sync/alert.png)\n\n## Sync Insight\nWith the latest release of Azure AD Connect Health for sync the following new capabilities have been added:\n\n- Latency of sync operations\n- Object Change trend\n\n### Sync Latency\nThis feature provides a graphical trend of latency of the sync operations (import, export, etc.) for connectors.  This provides a quick and easy way to understand not only the latency of your operations (great if you have a large set of changes occurring) but also a way to detect anomalies in the latency that may require further investigation.\n\n![Sync Latency](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-health-sync/synclatency.png)\n\nBy default, only the latency of the 'Export' operation for the Azure AD connector is shown.  To see more operations on the connector or to view operations from other connectors, right-click on the chart and choose the specific operation and connector.\n\n### Sync Object Changes\nThis feature provides a graphical trend of the number of changes that are being evaluated and exported to Azure AD.  Today, trying to gather this information from the sync logs is difficult.  The chart gives you, not only a simpler way of monitoring the number of changes that are occurring in your environment, but also a visual view of the failures that are occurring.   \n\n![Sync Latency](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-health-sync/syncobjectchanges.png)\n\n## Related links\n\n* [Azure AD Connect Health](active-directory-aadconnect-health.md)\n* [Azure AD Connect Health Agent Installation](active-directory-aadconnect-health-agent-install.md)\n* [Azure AD Connect Health Operations](active-directory-aadconnect-health-operations.md)\n* [Using Azure AD Connect Health with AD FS](active-directory-aadconnect-health-adfs.md)\n* [Azure AD Connect Health FAQ](active-directory-aadconnect-health-faq.md)\n\n"
}