{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect: Prerequisites and hardware | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        88
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Article description that will be displayed on landing pages and in most search results",
      "pos": [
        106,
        192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Prerequisites for Azure AD Connect",
      "pos": [
        508,
        542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic describes the pre-requisites and the hardware requirements for Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        543,
        634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you install Azure AD Connect",
      "pos": [
        639,
        674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you install Azure AD Connect, there are a few things that you will need.",
      "pos": [
        675,
        754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD",
      "pos": [
        758,
        766
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure subscription or an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure trial subscription<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        772,
        875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is only required for accessing the Azure portal and not for using Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        876,
        964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using PowerShell or Office 365 you do not need an Azure subscription to use Azure AD Connect.",
      "pos": [
        966,
        1070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have an Office 365 license you can also use the Office 365 portal.",
      "pos": [
        1071,
        1144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With a paid Office 365 license you can also get into the Azure portal from the Office 365 portal.",
      "pos": [
        1145,
        1242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Add and verify the domain<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-add-domain.md)</ept> you plan to use in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        1245,
        1333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example if you plan to use contoso.com for your users then make sure this domain has been verified and you are not only using the contoso.onmicrosoft.com default domain.",
      "pos": [
        1334,
        1507
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure AD directory will by default allow 50k objects.",
      "pos": [
        1510,
        1566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you verify the domain the limit will be increased to 300k objects.",
      "pos": [
        1567,
        1638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need even more objects in Azure AD you need to open a support case to have the limit increased even further.",
      "pos": [
        1639,
        1754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need more than 500k objects, you will need a license such as Office 365, Azure AD Basic, Azure AD Premium, or Enterprise Mobility Suite.",
      "pos": [
        1755,
        1898
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On-premises servers and environment",
      "pos": [
        1902,
        1937
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The AD schema version and forest functional level must be Windows Server 2003 or later.",
      "pos": [
        1943,
        2030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The domain controllers can run any version as long as the schema and forest level requirements are met.",
      "pos": [
        2031,
        2134
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2137,
        2271
      ],
      "content": "If you plan to use the feature <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>password writeback<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> the Domain Controllers must be on Windows Server 2008 (with latest SP) or later."
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect cannot be installed on Small Business Server or Windows Server Essentials.",
      "pos": [
        2274,
        2365
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The server must be using Windows Server standard or better.",
      "pos": [
        2366,
        2425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect must be installed on Windows Server 2008 or later.",
      "pos": [
        2428,
        2495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This server may be a domain controller or a member server if using express settings.",
      "pos": [
        2497,
        2581
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you use custom settings, the server can also be stand-alone and does not have to be joined to a domain.",
      "pos": [
        2582,
        2688
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you install Azure AD Connect on Windows Server 2008, make sure to apply the latest hotfixes from Windows Update.",
      "pos": [
        2691,
        2806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The installation will not be able to start with an unpatched server.",
      "pos": [
        2807,
        2875
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2878,
        3014
      ],
      "content": "If you plan to use the feature <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>password synchronization<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, the Azure AD Connect server must be on Windows Server 2008 R2 SP1 or later."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3017,
        3169
      ],
      "content": "The Azure AD Connect server must have <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>.Net 4.5.1<ept id=\"p1\">](#component-prerequisites)</ept> or later and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>PowerShell 3.0<ept id=\"p2\">](#component-prerequisites)</ept> or later installed."
    },
    {
      "content": "If Active Directory Federation Services is being deployed, the servers where AD FS or Web Application Proxy will be installed must be Windows Server 2012 R2 or later.",
      "pos": [
        3172,
        3338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows remote management<ept id=\"p1\">](#windows-remote-management)</ept> must be enabled on these servers for remote installation.",
      "pos": [
        3339,
        3452
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3455,
        3573
      ],
      "content": "If Active Directory Federation Services is being deployed, you need <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SSL Certificates<ept id=\"p1\">](#ssl-certificate-requirements)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect requires a SQL Server database to store identity data.",
      "pos": [
        3576,
        3647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default a SQL Server 2012 Express LocalDB (a light version of SQL Server Express) is installed and the service account for the service is created on the local machine.",
      "pos": [
        3648,
        3818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server Express has a 10GB size limit that enables you to manage approximately 100.000 objects.",
      "pos": [
        3819,
        3917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need to manage a higher volume of directory objects, you need to point the installation process to a different version of SQL Server.",
      "pos": [
        3918,
        4058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect supports all flavors of Microsoft SQL Server from SQL Server 2008 (with SP4) to SQL Server 2014.",
      "pos": [
        4059,
        4172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Accounts",
      "pos": [
        4176,
        4184
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure AD Global Administrator account for the Azure AD directory you wish to integrate with.",
      "pos": [
        4190,
        4285
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Enterprise Administrator account for your local Active Directory if you use express settings or upgrade from DirSync.",
      "pos": [
        4288,
        4408
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4411,
        4544
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Accounts is Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md)</ept> if you use the custom settings installation path."
    },
    {
      "content": "Connectivity",
      "pos": [
        4548,
        4560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using an outbound proxy for connecting to the Internet, the following setting in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>C:\\Windows\\Microsoft.NET\\Framework64\\v4.0.30319\\Config\\machine.config<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> file must be added for the installation wizard and Azure AD sync to be able to connect to the Internet and Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        4566,
        4852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This text must be entered at the bottom of the file.",
      "pos": [
        4853,
        4905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this code, &amp;lt;PROXYADRESS&amp;gt; represents the actual proxy IP address or host name.",
      "pos": [
        4907,
        4993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If your proxy server requires authentication, then the section should look like this instead.",
      "pos": [
        5250,
        5343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With this change in machine.config the installation wizard and sync engine will respond to authentication requests from the proxy server.",
      "pos": [
        5644,
        5781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In all installation wizard pages, excluding the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, the signed in user's credentials are used.",
      "pos": [
        5782,
        5892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page at the end of the installation wizard, the context is switched to the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>service account<ept id=\"p2\">](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md#azure-ad-connect-sync-service-accounts)</ept> which was created.",
      "pos": [
        5893,
        6117
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6119,
        6233
      ],
      "content": "See MSDN for more information about the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>default proxy Element<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/kd3cf2ex.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6237,
        6499
      ],
      "content": "If your proxy limits which URLs which can be accessed then the URLs documented in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Office 365 URLs and IP address ranges <ept id=\"p1\">](https://support.office.com/article/Office-365-URLs-and-IP-address-ranges-8548a211-3fe7-47cb-abb1-355ea5aa88a2)</ept> must be opened in the proxy."
    },
    {
      "content": "Other",
      "pos": [
        6503,
        6508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Optional:  A test user account to verify synchronization.",
      "pos": [
        6514,
        6571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Component prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        6576,
        6599
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect depends on PowerShell and .Net 4.5.1.",
      "pos": [
        6601,
        6655
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Depending on your Windows Server version, do the following:",
      "pos": [
        6656,
        6715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2012R2",
      "pos": [
        6719,
        6740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell is installed by default, no action is required.",
      "pos": [
        6745,
        6803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ".Net 4.5.1 and later releases are offered through Windows Update.",
      "pos": [
        6808,
        6873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure you have installed the latest updates to Windows Server in the Control Panel.",
      "pos": [
        6874,
        6961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2008R2 and Windows Server 2012",
      "pos": [
        6964,
        7009
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7014,
        7178
      ],
      "content": "The latest version of PowerShell is available in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Windows Management Framework 4.0<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, available on <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Microsoft Download Center<ept id=\"p2\">](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7183,
        7294
      ],
      "content": ".Net 4.5.1 and later releases are available on <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Download Center<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2008",
      "pos": [
        7297,
        7316
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7321,
        7495
      ],
      "content": "The latest supported version of PowerShell is available in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Windows Management Framework 3.0<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, available on <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Microsoft Download Center<ept id=\"p2\">](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7499,
        7610
      ],
      "content": ".Net 4.5.1 and later releases are available on <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Download Center<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Remote Management",
      "pos": [
        7615,
        7640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using Azure AD Connect to deploy Active Directory Federation Services or the Web Application Proxy, check the requirements below to ensure connectivity and configuration will succeed:",
      "pos": [
        7643,
        7831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the target server is domain joined, ensure that Windows Remote Managed is enabled",
      "pos": [
        7836,
        7920
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7927,
        8000
      ],
      "content": "In an elevated PSH command window, use command <ph id=\"ph1\">`Enable-PSRemoting –force`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "content": "If the target server is a non-domain joined WAP machine, there are a couple of additional requirements",
      "pos": [
        8004,
        8106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the target machine (WAP machine):",
      "pos": [
        8113,
        8149
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure the winrm (Windows Remote Management / WS-Management) service is running via the Services snap-in",
      "pos": [
        8161,
        8265
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8277,
        8350
      ],
      "content": "In an elevated PSH command window, use command <ph id=\"ph1\">`Enable-PSRemoting –force`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "content": "On the machine on which the wizard is running (if the target machine is non-domain joined or untrusted domain):",
      "pos": [
        8357,
        8468
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8479,
        8620
      ],
      "content": "In an elevated PSH command window, use the command <ph id=\"ph1\">`Set-Item WSMan:\\localhost\\Client\\TrustedHosts –Value &lt;DMZServerFQDN&gt; -Force –Concatenate`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "content": "In Server Manager:",
      "pos": [
        8631,
        8649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "add DMZ WAP host to machine pool (server manager -&gt; Manage -&gt; Add Servers...use DNS tab)",
      "pos": [
        8665,
        8753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server Manager All Servers tab: right click WAP server and choose Manage As..., enter local (not domain) creds for the WAP machine",
      "pos": [
        8769,
        8899
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To validate remote PSH connectivity, in the Server Manager All Servers tab: right click WAP server and choose Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        8915,
        9044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A remote PSH session should open to ensure remote PowerShell sessions can be established.",
      "pos": [
        9046,
        9135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SSL Certificate Requirements",
      "pos": [
        9140,
        9168
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9170,
        9324
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> it’s strongly recommended to use the same SSL certificate across all nodes of your AD FS farm as well as all Web Application proxy servers."
    },
    {
      "content": "The certificate must be an X509 certificate.",
      "pos": [
        9328,
        9372
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use a self-signed certificate on federation servers in a test lab environment.",
      "pos": [
        9375,
        9461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, for a production environment, we recommend that you obtain the certificate from a public CA.",
      "pos": [
        9462,
        9563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If using a certificate that is not publicly trusted, ensure that the certificate installed on each Web Application Proxy server is trusted on both the local server and on all federation servers",
      "pos": [
        9570,
        9763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The identity of the certificate must match the federation service name (for example, fs.contoso.com).",
      "pos": [
        9766,
        9867
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The identity is either a subject alternative name (SAN) extension of type dNSName or, if there are no SAN entries, the subject name specified as a common name.",
      "pos": [
        9874,
        10033
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Multiple SAN entries can be present in the certificate, provided one of them matches the federation service name.",
      "pos": [
        10042,
        10155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are planning to use Workplace Join, an additional SAN is required with the value <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>enterpriseregistration.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        10162,
        10277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "followed by the User Principal Name (UPN) suffix of your organization, for example, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>enterpriseregistration.contoso.com<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10278,
        10401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Certificates based on CryptoAPI next generation (CNG) keys and key storage providers are not supported.",
      "pos": [
        10404,
        10507
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means you must use a certificate based on a CSP (cryptographic service provider) and not a KSP (key storage provider).",
      "pos": [
        10508,
        10631
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Wild card certificates are supported.",
      "pos": [
        10634,
        10671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect supporting components",
      "pos": [
        10676,
        10714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following is a list of components that Azure AD Connect will install on the server where Azure AD Connect is installed.",
      "pos": [
        10716,
        10839
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This list is for a basic Express installation.",
      "pos": [
        10840,
        10886
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you choose to use a different SQL Server on the Install synchronization services page then SQL Express LocalDB is not installed locally.",
      "pos": [
        10888,
        11027
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Command Line Utilities",
      "pos": [
        11031,
        11079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Native Client",
      "pos": [
        11082,
        11121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Express LocalDB",
      "pos": [
        11124,
        11165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Module for Windows PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        11168,
        11220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Online Services Sign-In Assistant for IT Professionals",
      "pos": [
        11223,
        11287
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Visual C++ 2013 Redistribution Package",
      "pos": [
        11290,
        11338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hardware requirements for Azure AD Connect",
      "pos": [
        11344,
        11386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The table below shows the minimum requirements for the Azure AD Connect sync computer.",
      "pos": [
        11387,
        11473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Number of objects in Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        11477,
        11514
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CPU",
      "pos": [
        11517,
        11520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Memory",
      "pos": [
        11523,
        11529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hard drive size",
      "pos": [
        11532,
        11547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Fewer than 10,000",
      "pos": [
        11627,
        11644
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1.6 GHz",
      "pos": [
        11647,
        11654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4 GB",
      "pos": [
        11657,
        11661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "70 GB",
      "pos": [
        11664,
        11669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "10,000–50,000",
      "pos": [
        11674,
        11687
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1.6 GHz",
      "pos": [
        11690,
        11697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4 GB",
      "pos": [
        11700,
        11704
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "70 GB",
      "pos": [
        11707,
        11712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "50,000–100,000",
      "pos": [
        11717,
        11731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1.6 GHz",
      "pos": [
        11734,
        11741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "16 GB",
      "pos": [
        11744,
        11749
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100 GB",
      "pos": [
        11752,
        11758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For 100,000 or more objects the full version of SQL Server is required",
      "pos": [
        11763,
        11833
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100,000–300,000",
      "pos": [
        11846,
        11861
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1.6 GHz",
      "pos": [
        11864,
        11871
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "32 GB",
      "pos": [
        11874,
        11879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "300 GB",
      "pos": [
        11882,
        11888
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "300,000–600,000",
      "pos": [
        11893,
        11908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1.6 GHz",
      "pos": [
        11911,
        11918
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "32 GB",
      "pos": [
        11921,
        11926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "450 GB",
      "pos": [
        11929,
        11935
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "More than 600,000",
      "pos": [
        11940,
        11957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1.6 GHz",
      "pos": [
        11960,
        11967
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "32 GB",
      "pos": [
        11970,
        11975
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "500 GB",
      "pos": [
        11978,
        11984
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The minimum requirements for computers running AD FS or Web Application Servers is the following:",
      "pos": [
        11988,
        12085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CPU: Dual core 1.6 GHz or higher",
      "pos": [
        12089,
        12121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MEMORY: 2GB or higher",
      "pos": [
        12124,
        12145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure VM: A2 configuration or higher",
      "pos": [
        12148,
        12184
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        12190,
        12200
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12201,
        12320
      ],
      "content": "Learn more about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Azure AD Connect: Prerequisites and hardware | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Article description that will be displayed on landing pages and in most search results\"\n   services=\"active-directory\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"andkjell\"\n   manager=\"stevenpo\"\n   editor=\"curtand\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n   ms.workload=\"identity\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.date=\"11/16/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"andkjell;billmath\"/>\n\n# Prerequisites for Azure AD Connect\nThis topic describes the pre-requisites and the hardware requirements for Azure AD Connect.\n\n## Before you install Azure AD Connect\nBefore you install Azure AD Connect, there are a few things that you will need.\n\n**Azure AD**\n\n- An Azure subscription or an [Azure trial subscription](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/). This is only required for accessing the Azure portal and not for using Azure AD Connect.  If you are using PowerShell or Office 365 you do not need an Azure subscription to use Azure AD Connect. If you have an Office 365 license you can also use the Office 365 portal. With a paid Office 365 license you can also get into the Azure portal from the Office 365 portal.\n- [Add and verify the domain](active-directory-add-domain.md) you plan to use in Azure AD. For example if you plan to use contoso.com for your users then make sure this domain has been verified and you are not only using the contoso.onmicrosoft.com default domain.\n- An Azure AD directory will by default allow 50k objects. When you verify the domain the limit will be increased to 300k objects. If you need even more objects in Azure AD you need to open a support case to have the limit increased even further. If you need more than 500k objects, you will need a license such as Office 365, Azure AD Basic, Azure AD Premium, or Enterprise Mobility Suite.\n\n**On-premises servers and environment**\n\n- The AD schema version and forest functional level must be Windows Server 2003 or later. The domain controllers can run any version as long as the schema and forest level requirements are met.\n- If you plan to use the feature **password writeback** the Domain Controllers must be on Windows Server 2008 (with latest SP) or later.\n- Azure AD Connect cannot be installed on Small Business Server or Windows Server Essentials. The server must be using Windows Server standard or better.\n- Azure AD Connect must be installed on Windows Server 2008 or later.  This server may be a domain controller or a member server if using express settings. If you use custom settings, the server can also be stand-alone and does not have to be joined to a domain.\n- If you install Azure AD Connect on Windows Server 2008, make sure to apply the latest hotfixes from Windows Update. The installation will not be able to start with an unpatched server.\n- If you plan to use the feature **password synchronization**, the Azure AD Connect server must be on Windows Server 2008 R2 SP1 or later.\n- The Azure AD Connect server must have [.Net 4.5.1](#component-prerequisites) or later and [PowerShell 3.0](#component-prerequisites) or later installed.\n- If Active Directory Federation Services is being deployed, the servers where AD FS or Web Application Proxy will be installed must be Windows Server 2012 R2 or later. [Windows remote management](#windows-remote-management) must be enabled on these servers for remote installation.\n- If Active Directory Federation Services is being deployed, you need [SSL Certificates](#ssl-certificate-requirements).\n- Azure AD Connect requires a SQL Server database to store identity data. By default a SQL Server 2012 Express LocalDB (a light version of SQL Server Express) is installed and the service account for the service is created on the local machine. SQL Server Express has a 10GB size limit that enables you to manage approximately 100.000 objects. If you need to manage a higher volume of directory objects, you need to point the installation process to a different version of SQL Server. Azure AD Connect supports all flavors of Microsoft SQL Server from SQL Server 2008 (with SP4) to SQL Server 2014.\n\n**Accounts**\n\n- An Azure AD Global Administrator account for the Azure AD directory you wish to integrate with.\n- An Enterprise Administrator account for your local Active Directory if you use express settings or upgrade from DirSync.\n- [Accounts is Active Directory](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md) if you use the custom settings installation path.\n\n**Connectivity**\n\n- If you are using an outbound proxy for connecting to the Internet, the following setting in the **C:\\Windows\\Microsoft.NET\\Framework64\\v4.0.30319\\Config\\machine.config** file must be added for the installation wizard and Azure AD sync to be able to connect to the Internet and Azure AD. This text must be entered at the bottom of the file.  In this code, &lt;PROXYADRESS&gt; represents the actual proxy IP address or host name.\n\n```\n    <system.net>\n        <defaultProxy>\n            <proxy\n            usesystemdefault=\"true\"\n            proxyaddress=\"http://<PROXYADDRESS>:<PROXYPORT>\"\n            bypassonlocal=\"true\"\n            />\n        </defaultProxy>\n    </system.net>\n```\n\nIf your proxy server requires authentication, then the section should look like this instead.\n\n```\n    <system.net>\n        <defaultProxy enabled=\"true\" useDefaultCredentials=\"true\">\n            <proxy\n            usesystemdefault=\"true\"\n            proxyaddress=\"http://<PROXYADDRESS>:<PROXYPORT>\"\n            bypassonlocal=\"true\"\n            />\n        </defaultProxy>\n    </system.net>\n```\n\nWith this change in machine.config the installation wizard and sync engine will respond to authentication requests from the proxy server. In all installation wizard pages, excluding the **Configure** page, the signed in user's credentials are used. On the **Configure** page at the end of the installation wizard, the context is switched to the [service account](active-directory-aadconnect-accounts-permissions.md#azure-ad-connect-sync-service-accounts) which was created.\n\nSee MSDN for more information about the [default proxy Element](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/kd3cf2ex.aspx).\n\n- If your proxy limits which URLs which can be accessed then the URLs documented in [Office 365 URLs and IP address ranges ](https://support.office.com/article/Office-365-URLs-and-IP-address-ranges-8548a211-3fe7-47cb-abb1-355ea5aa88a2) must be opened in the proxy.\n\n**Other**\n\n- Optional:  A test user account to verify synchronization.\n\n## Component prerequisites\n\nAzure AD Connect depends on PowerShell and .Net 4.5.1. Depending on your Windows Server version, do the following:\n\n- Windows Server 2012R2\n  - PowerShell is installed by default, no action is required.\n  - .Net 4.5.1 and later releases are offered through Windows Update. Make sure you have installed the latest updates to Windows Server in the Control Panel.\n- Windows Server 2008R2 and Windows Server 2012\n  - The latest version of PowerShell is available in **Windows Management Framework 4.0**, available on [Microsoft Download Center](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads).\n  - .Net 4.5.1 and later releases are available on [Microsoft Download Center](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads).\n- Windows Server 2008\n  - The latest supported version of PowerShell is available in **Windows Management Framework 3.0**, available on [Microsoft Download Center](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads).\n - .Net 4.5.1 and later releases are available on [Microsoft Download Center](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads).\n\n## Windows Remote Management\n\n When using Azure AD Connect to deploy Active Directory Federation Services or the Web Application Proxy, check the requirements below to ensure connectivity and configuration will succeed:\n\n - If the target server is domain joined, ensure that Windows Remote Managed is enabled\n    - In an elevated PSH command window, use command `Enable-PSRemoting –force`\n - If the target server is a non-domain joined WAP machine, there are a couple of additional requirements\n    - On the target machine (WAP machine):\n         - Ensure the winrm (Windows Remote Management / WS-Management) service is running via the Services snap-in\n         - In an elevated PSH command window, use command `Enable-PSRemoting –force`\n    - On the machine on which the wizard is running (if the target machine is non-domain joined or untrusted domain):\n        - In an elevated PSH command window, use the command `Set-Item WSMan:\\localhost\\Client\\TrustedHosts –Value <DMZServerFQDN> -Force –Concatenate`\n        - In Server Manager:\n             - add DMZ WAP host to machine pool (server manager -> Manage -> Add Servers...use DNS tab)\n             - Server Manager All Servers tab: right click WAP server and choose Manage As..., enter local (not domain) creds for the WAP machine\n             - To validate remote PSH connectivity, in the Server Manager All Servers tab: right click WAP server and choose Windows PowerShell.  A remote PSH session should open to ensure remote PowerShell sessions can be established.\n\n## SSL Certificate Requirements\n\n**Important:** it’s strongly recommended to use the same SSL certificate across all nodes of your AD FS farm as well as all Web Application proxy servers.\n\n- The certificate must be an X509 certificate.\n- You can use a self-signed certificate on federation servers in a test lab environment. However, for a production environment, we recommend that you obtain the certificate from a public CA.\n    - If using a certificate that is not publicly trusted, ensure that the certificate installed on each Web Application Proxy server is trusted on both the local server and on all federation servers\n- The identity of the certificate must match the federation service name (for example, fs.contoso.com).\n    - The identity is either a subject alternative name (SAN) extension of type dNSName or, if there are no SAN entries, the subject name specified as a common name.  \n    - Multiple SAN entries can be present in the certificate, provided one of them matches the federation service name.\n    - If you are planning to use Workplace Join, an additional SAN is required with the value **enterpriseregistration.** followed by the User Principal Name (UPN) suffix of your organization, for example, **enterpriseregistration.contoso.com**.\n- Certificates based on CryptoAPI next generation (CNG) keys and key storage providers are not supported. This means you must use a certificate based on a CSP (cryptographic service provider) and not a KSP (key storage provider).\n- Wild card certificates are supported.\n\n## Azure AD Connect supporting components\n\nThe following is a list of components that Azure AD Connect will install on the server where Azure AD Connect is installed. This list is for a basic Express installation.  If you choose to use a different SQL Server on the Install synchronization services page then SQL Express LocalDB is not installed locally.\n\n- Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Command Line Utilities\n- Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Native Client\n- Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Express LocalDB\n- Azure Active Directory Module for Windows PowerShell\n- Microsoft Online Services Sign-In Assistant for IT Professionals\n- Microsoft Visual C++ 2013 Redistribution Package\n\n\n## Hardware requirements for Azure AD Connect\nThe table below shows the minimum requirements for the Azure AD Connect sync computer.\n\n| Number of objects in Active Directory | CPU | Memory | Hard drive size |\n| ------------------------------------- | --- | ------ | --------------- |\n| Fewer than 10,000 | 1.6 GHz | 4 GB | 70 GB |\n| 10,000–50,000 | 1.6 GHz | 4 GB | 70 GB |\n| 50,000–100,000 | 1.6 GHz | 16 GB | 100 GB |\n| For 100,000 or more objects the full version of SQL Server is required|  |  |  |\n| 100,000–300,000 | 1.6 GHz | 32 GB | 300 GB |\n| 300,000–600,000 | 1.6 GHz | 32 GB | 450 GB |\n| More than 600,000 | 1.6 GHz | 32 GB | 500 GB |\n\nThe minimum requirements for computers running AD FS or Web Application Servers is the following:\n\n- CPU: Dual core 1.6 GHz or higher\n- MEMORY: 2GB or higher\n- Azure VM: A2 configuration or higher\n\n\n## Next steps\nLearn more about [Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory](active-directory-aadconnect.md).\n\n\n"
}