{"nodes":[{"content":"Introduction to multi-user applications","pos":[27,66]},{"content":"Introduction to multi-user applications","pos":[99,138]},{"content":"This topic is intended to be a simple high-level introduction to the Xbox multi-user model.","pos":[140,231]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>In this initial developer preview, multi-user applications are not enabled.","pos":[235,330]},{"content":"In a future developer preview, multi-user applications will be enabled, and at that time we will publish more detailed documentation, guidelines, and samples.","pos":[331,489]},{"content":"The Xbox One user model is tuned to the requirements of a gaming console that supports multiple users playing games cooperatively on a single device.","pos":[492,641]},{"content":"It enables multiple users, each with their own controller, to be signed in and using the console at the same time in a single interactive session.","pos":[642,789]},{"content":"This is different from other Windows devices.","pos":[790,836]},{"content":"For example:","pos":[837,849]},{"pos":[852,1048],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Windows desktop PCs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> allow multiple users to use the same device, but each user has their own interactive session and each session is completely independent of the other sessions on the device."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Windows phones<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> allow only a single user to use the device.","pos":[1051,1113]},{"content":"That single user is determined during the OOBE (out-of-box-experience) and the user cannot sign out after they are signed in.","pos":[1114,1239]},{"content":"In effect, if a different user wants to use the device, the device has to be reset.","pos":[1240,1323]},{"pos":[1327,1446],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Xbox One<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> allows multiple users to be signed in and use the device at the same time in a single interactive session."},{"content":"Each user in the Xbox One user model is backed by a local user account.","pos":[1448,1519]},{"content":"This local user account is associated with an Xbox Live account (and therefore a Microsoft account).","pos":[1520,1621]},{"content":"This means that there is a strict one-to-one mapping of an Xbox user account to an Xbox Live account and to a Microsoft account.","pos":[1622,1751]},{"content":"Single user applications","pos":[1756,1780]},{"content":"By default, UWP apps run in the context of the user that launched the application.","pos":[1781,1863]},{"content":"These “single user applications” (SUAs) are only aware of that single user, and run in a mode that is compatible with the user model on other Windows devices.","pos":[1864,2023]},{"content":"The Xbox user model manages which user is associated with the app and guarantees that a user is signed in when the app is launched.","pos":[2024,2156]},{"content":"In this model, UWP app and games authors do not have to do anything special to run on Xbox.","pos":[2157,2249]},{"content":"Multi-user applications","pos":[2255,2278]},{"content":"UWP games can choose to opt into the Xbox One multi-user model.","pos":[2279,2342]},{"content":"These “multi-user applications” (MUAs) run in the context of a system account (called the Default Account) and can take full advantage of the flexibility and power of the Xbox One user model.","pos":[2343,2535]},{"content":"For these games, the Xbox user model does not manage which user is associated with the game and does not even require that a user is signed in for the game to run.","pos":[2536,2700]},{"content":"This means that they have to be written to be explicitly aware of, and manage their user requirements: whether they require a signed-in user or not, whether they implement the concept of a current user, whether they allow simultaneous input from multiple users, and so on.","pos":[2701,2974]},{"content":"To opt into the multi-user model:","pos":[2979,3012]},{"content":"Open your project in Visual Studio.","pos":[3019,3054]},{"content":"Select the package.appxmanifest.xml file.","pos":[3061,3102]},{"content":"Right click and select View Code.","pos":[3109,3142]},{"pos":[3149,3215],"content":"Add the following line in the <ph id=\"ph1\">`&lt;Properties&gt;&lt;/Properties&gt;`</ph> section:"},{"content":"Guidance on which model to choose","pos":[3272,3305]},{"content":"All UWP apps and the majority of single user games can be written to be SUA.","pos":[3306,3382]},{"content":"We recommend that only cooperative multi-player games consider opting into the Xbox One multi-user model.","pos":[3383,3489]},{"content":"We will provide more detailed documentation, guidance and samples in a future developer preview.","pos":[3490,3587]},{"content":"See also","pos":[3592,3600]},{"content":"UWP on Xbox One","pos":[3604,3619]}],"content":"---\nauthor: Mtoepke\ntitle: Introduction to multi-user applications\ndescription: \narea: Xbox\n---\n\n# Introduction to multi-user applications\n\nThis topic is intended to be a simple high-level introduction to the Xbox multi-user model.\n\n> **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;In this initial developer preview, multi-user applications are not enabled. In a future developer preview, multi-user applications will be enabled, and at that time we will publish more detailed documentation, guidelines, and samples. \n\nThe Xbox One user model is tuned to the requirements of a gaming console that supports multiple users playing games cooperatively on a single device. \nIt enables multiple users, each with their own controller, to be signed in and using the console at the same time in a single interactive session. \nThis is different from other Windows devices. For example:\n* **Windows desktop PCs** allow multiple users to use the same device, but each user has their own interactive session and each session is completely independent of the other sessions on the device.\n* **Windows phones** allow only a single user to use the device. That single user is determined during the OOBE (out-of-box-experience) and the user cannot sign out after they are signed in. In effect, if a different user wants to use the device, the device has to be reset. \n* **Xbox One** allows multiple users to be signed in and use the device at the same time in a single interactive session.\n\nEach user in the Xbox One user model is backed by a local user account. \nThis local user account is associated with an Xbox Live account (and therefore a Microsoft account). \nThis means that there is a strict one-to-one mapping of an Xbox user account to an Xbox Live account and to a Microsoft account.\n\n## Single user applications\nBy default, UWP apps run in the context of the user that launched the application. \nThese “single user applications” (SUAs) are only aware of that single user, and run in a mode that is compatible with the user model on other Windows devices. \nThe Xbox user model manages which user is associated with the app and guarantees that a user is signed in when the app is launched. \nIn this model, UWP app and games authors do not have to do anything special to run on Xbox. \n\n## Multi-user applications\nUWP games can choose to opt into the Xbox One multi-user model. \nThese “multi-user applications” (MUAs) run in the context of a system account (called the Default Account) and can take full advantage of the flexibility and power of the Xbox One user model. \nFor these games, the Xbox user model does not manage which user is associated with the game and does not even require that a user is signed in for the game to run. \nThis means that they have to be written to be explicitly aware of, and manage their user requirements: whether they require a signed-in user or not, whether they implement the concept of a current user, whether they allow simultaneous input from multiple users, and so on.\n   \nTo opt into the multi-user model:   \n1. Open your project in Visual Studio.   \n2. Select the package.appxmanifest.xml file.   \n3. Right click and select View Code.   \n4. Add the following line in the `<Properties></Properties>` section:\n\n`<uap:SupportedUsers>multiple</uap:SupportedUsers>`\n\n##Guidance on which model to choose\nAll UWP apps and the majority of single user games can be written to be SUA. \nWe recommend that only cooperative multi-player games consider opting into the Xbox One multi-user model. \nWe will provide more detailed documentation, guidance and samples in a future developer preview.\n\n## See also\n- [UWP on Xbox One](index.md)\n"}