{"nodes":[{"content":"A pattern with a content area and a command area for single-view apps or modal experiences, such as photo viewers/editors, document viewers, maps, painting, or other apps that make use of a free-scrolling view.","pos":[32,242]},{"content":"Guidelines for the active canvas pattern","pos":[250,290]},{"content":"Active canvas pattern","pos":[377,398]},{"content":"An active canvas is a pattern with a content area and a command area.","pos":[400,469]},{"content":"It's for single-view apps or modal experiences, such as photo viewers/editors, document viewers, maps, painting, or other apps that make use of a free-scrolling view.","pos":[470,636]},{"content":"For taking actions, an active canvas can be paired with a command bar or just buttons, depending on the number and types of actions you need.","pos":[637,778]},{"content":"Examples","pos":[783,791]},{"content":"This design of a photo editing app features an active canvas pattern, with a mobile example on the left, and a desktop example on the right.","pos":[793,933]},{"content":"The image editing surface is a canvas, and the command bar at the bottom contains all of the contextual actions for the app.","pos":[934,1058]},{"content":"Example of a photo editor using active canvas pattern","pos":[1062,1115]},{"content":"This design of a subway map app makes use of an active canvas with a simple UI strip at the top that has only two actions and a search box.","pos":[1153,1292]},{"content":"Contextual actions are shown in the context menu, as seen on the right image.","pos":[1293,1370]},{"content":"Example of a maps app using active canvas pattern","pos":[1374,1423]},{"content":"Implementing this pattern","pos":[1466,1491]},{"content":"The active canvas pattern consists of a content area and a command area.","pos":[1493,1565]},{"content":"Content area.","pos":[1569,1582]},{"content":"The content area is usually a free-scrolling canvas.","pos":[1586,1638]},{"content":"Multiple content areas can exist within an app.","pos":[1639,1686]},{"content":"Command area.","pos":[1690,1703]},{"content":"If you're placing a lot of commands, then a command bar, which responds based on screen size, could be the way to go.","pos":[1707,1824]},{"content":"If you're not placing that many commands and aren't as concerned with a responsive UI, space-saving buttons work well.","pos":[1825,1943]},{"content":"Related articles","pos":[1950,1966]},{"content":"App bar and command bar","pos":[1975,1998]}],"content":"---\nauthor: Jwmsft\nDescription: A pattern with a content area and a command area for single-view apps or modal experiences, such as photo viewers/editors, document viewers, maps, painting, or other apps that make use of a free-scrolling view.\ntitle: Guidelines for the active canvas pattern\nms.assetid: 4D768472-64D6-406C-9E87-F750F6B981A0\nlabel: TBD\ntemplate: detail.hbs\n---\n#Active canvas pattern\n\nAn active canvas is a pattern with a content area and a command area. It's for single-view apps or modal experiences, such as photo viewers/editors, document viewers, maps, painting, or other apps that make use of a free-scrolling view. For taking actions, an active canvas can be paired with a command bar or just buttons, depending on the number and types of actions you need.\n\n## Examples\n\nThis design of a photo editing app features an active canvas pattern, with a mobile example on the left, and a desktop example on the right. The image editing surface is a canvas, and the command bar at the bottom contains all of the contextual actions for the app.\n\n![Example of a photo editor using active canvas pattern](images/uap-photo-pc-phone-700.png)\n\nThis design of a subway map app makes use of an active canvas with a simple UI strip at the top that has only two actions and a search box. Contextual actions are shown in the context menu, as seen on the right image.\n\n![Example of a maps app using active canvas pattern](images/uap-subway-pc-phone-700.png)\n\n\n## Implementing this pattern\n\nThe active canvas pattern consists of a content area and a command area.\n\n**Content area.**  The content area is usually a free-scrolling canvas. Multiple content areas can exist within an app.\n\n**Command area.**  If you're placing a lot of commands, then a command bar, which responds based on screen size, could be the way to go. If you're not placing that many commands and aren't as concerned with a responsive UI, space-saving buttons work well.\n\n\n\n## Related articles\n\n-   [**App bar and command bar**](app-bars.md)\n"}