{"nodes":[{"content":"This section includes topics that explain programming concepts that are generally applicable to any app that you write.","pos":[81,200]},{"content":"XAML platform","pos":[208,221]},{"content":"XAML platform","pos":[229,242]},{"content":"Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10.","pos":[247,282]},{"content":"For Windows 8.x articles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>archive<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132)</ept>","pos":[283,375]},{"content":"This section includes topics that explain programming concepts that are generally applicable to any app that you write, if you are using C#, Microsoft Visual Basic, or Visual C++ component extensions (C++/CX) as your programming language and XAML for your UI definition.","pos":[380,650]},{"content":"This includes basic programming concepts such as using properties and events, and how these apply to Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app programming.","pos":[651,801]},{"content":"The Universal Windows Platform (UWP) extends C#, Visual Basic, or C++/CX concepts of properties and their values by adding the dependency property system.","pos":[802,956]},{"content":"Topics in this section also document the XAML language as it is used by the UWP, and cover basic scenarios and advanced topics explaining how to use XAML to define the UI for your UWP app.","pos":[957,1145]},{"content":"Topic","pos":[1150,1155]},{"content":"Description","pos":[1158,1169]},{"content":"XAML overview","pos":[1199,1212]},{"content":"We introduce the XAML language and XAML concepts to the Windows Runtime app developer audience, and describe the different ways to declare objects and set attributes in XAML as it is used for creating a Windows Runtime app.","pos":[1234,1457]},{"content":"Dependency properties overview","pos":[1463,1493]},{"content":"This topic explains the dependency property system that is available when you write a Windows Runtime app using C++, C#, or Visual Basic along with XAML definitions for UI.","pos":[1532,1704]},{"content":"Custom dependency properties","pos":[1710,1738]},{"content":"Explains how to define and implement custom dependency properties for a Windows Runtime app using C++, C#, or Visual Basic.","pos":[1775,1898]},{"content":"Attached properties overview","pos":[1904,1932]},{"content":"Explains the concept of an attached property in XAML, and provides some examples.","pos":[1969,2050]},{"content":"Custom attached properties","pos":[2056,2082]},{"content":"Explains how to implement a XAML attached property as a dependency property and how to define the accessor convention that is necessary for your attached property to be usable in XAML.","pos":[2117,2301]},{"content":"Events and routed events overview","pos":[2307,2340]},{"content":"We describe the programming concept of events in a Windows Runtime app, when using C#, Visual Basic or C++/CX as your programming language, and XAML for your UI definition.","pos":[2382,2554]},{"content":"You can assign handlers for events as part of the declarations for UI elements in XAML, or you can add the handlers in code.","pos":[2555,2679]},{"content":"Windows Runtime supports <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>routed events<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: certain input events and data events can be handled by objects beyond the object that fired the event.","pos":[2680,2826]},{"content":"Routed events are useful when you define control templates, or use pages or layout containers.","pos":[2827,2921]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jwmsft\nms.assetid: b632a6cc-3503-4ab8-bfd1-dde731bd89ab\ndescription: This section includes topics that explain programming concepts that are generally applicable to any app that you write.\ntitle: XAML platform\n---\n\n# XAML platform\n\n\\[ Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10. For Windows 8.x articles, see the [archive](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132) \\]\n\nThis section includes topics that explain programming concepts that are generally applicable to any app that you write, if you are using C#, Microsoft Visual Basic, or Visual C++ component extensions (C++/CX) as your programming language and XAML for your UI definition. This includes basic programming concepts such as using properties and events, and how these apply to Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app programming. The Universal Windows Platform (UWP) extends C#, Visual Basic, or C++/CX concepts of properties and their values by adding the dependency property system. Topics in this section also document the XAML language as it is used by the UWP, and cover basic scenarios and advanced topics explaining how to use XAML to define the UI for your UWP app.\n \n| Topic | Description |\n|-------|-------------|\n| [XAML overview](xaml-overview.md) | We introduce the XAML language and XAML concepts to the Windows Runtime app developer audience, and describe the different ways to declare objects and set attributes in XAML as it is used for creating a Windows Runtime app. |\n| [Dependency properties overview](dependency-properties-overview.md) | This topic explains the dependency property system that is available when you write a Windows Runtime app using C++, C#, or Visual Basic along with XAML definitions for UI. |\n| [Custom dependency properties](custom-dependency-properties.md) | Explains how to define and implement custom dependency properties for a Windows Runtime app using C++, C#, or Visual Basic. |\n| [Attached properties overview](attached-properties-overview.md) | Explains the concept of an attached property in XAML, and provides some examples. |\n| [Custom attached properties](custom-attached-properties.md) | Explains how to implement a XAML attached property as a dependency property and how to define the accessor convention that is necessary for your attached property to be usable in XAML. |\n| [Events and routed events overview](events-and-routed-events-overview.md) | We describe the programming concept of events in a Windows Runtime app, when using C#, Visual Basic or C++/CX as your programming language, and XAML for your UI definition. You can assign handlers for events as part of the declarations for UI elements in XAML, or you can add the handlers in code. Windows Runtime supports **routed events**: certain input events and data events can be handled by objects beyond the object that fired the event. Routed events are useful when you define control templates, or use pages or layout containers. |\n\n \n"}