{"nodes":[{"content":"The Windows SDK, Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK, and the Windows Store provide many features that enable you to make more money from your apps and gain customers from engaging with your users.","pos":[86,295]},{"content":"Monetize your app","pos":[303,320]},{"content":"Monetize your app and engage customers","pos":[328,366]},{"content":"Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10.","pos":[372,407]},{"content":"For Windows 8.x articles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>archive<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132)</ept>","pos":[408,500]},{"content":"The Windows SDK, the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK, and the Windows Store provide features that enable you to make more money from your apps and gain customers by engaging with your users.","pos":[505,711]},{"content":"The topics in this section show you how to build these features into your app.","pos":[712,790]},{"pos":[792,976],"content":"For details about the fees charged by the Windows Store and how you get paid for the money your app makes, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting paid<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/mt148536)</ept>."},{"content":"In this section","pos":[981,996]},{"content":"Topic","pos":[1001,1006]},{"content":"Description","pos":[1111,1122]},{"content":"Exclude or limit features in a trial version","pos":[1286,1330]},{"content":"If you enable customers to use your app for free during a trial period, you can entice your customers to upgrade to the full version of your app by excluding or limiting some features during the trial period by using APIs in the Windows SDK.","pos":[1395,1636]},{"content":"Determine which features should be limited before you begin coding, then make sure that your app only allows them to work when a full license has been purchased.","pos":[1637,1798]},{"content":"You can also enable features, such as banners or watermarks, that are shown only during the trial, before a customer buys your app.","pos":[1799,1930]},{"content":"Enable in-app product purchases","pos":[1936,1967]},{"content":"Whether your app is free or not, you can sell content, other apps, or new app functionality (such as unlocking the next level of a game) from right within the app.","pos":[2045,2208]},{"content":"Here we show you how to enable these products in your app by using APIs in the Windows SDK.","pos":[2209,2300]},{"content":"Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK","pos":[2309,2356]},{"content":"The Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK provides libraries and tools that you can use to add features to your apps that help you make more money and engage with your customers.","pos":[2444,2632]},{"content":"Run experiments with A/B testing","pos":[2640,2672]},{"content":"Run A/B tests in your Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps to measure the effectiveness of features on some customers before you release the features to everyone.","pos":[2724,2887]},{"content":"This feature requires the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.","pos":[2888,2962]},{"content":"Display ads in your app","pos":[2969,2992]},{"content":"Increase your revenue by displaying banner ads or video interstitial ads in your app.","pos":[3031,3116]},{"content":"This feature requires the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.","pos":[3117,3191]},{"content":"Launch Feedback Hub from your app","pos":[3199,3232]},{"content":"Add code to your UWP apps to direct your Windows 10 customers to Feedback Hub, where they can submit problems, suggestions, and upvotes.","pos":[3281,3417]},{"content":"Then, manage this feedback in the Dev Center dashboard.","pos":[3418,3473]},{"content":"This feature requires the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.","pos":[3474,3548]},{"content":"Use Windows Store services","pos":[3556,3582]},{"content":"The Windows Store exposes several services that you can call via REST APIs to programmatically access certain types of data for apps that are registered to your or your organization's Windows Dev Center account.","pos":[3654,3865]}],"content":"---\nauthor: mcleanbyron\nms.assetid: 4e8cc0c0-b14c-472c-9e1c-4601d10289d2\ndescription: The Windows SDK, Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK, and the Windows Store provide many features that enable you to make more money from your apps and gain customers from engaging with your users.\ntitle: Monetize your app\n---\n\n# Monetize your app and engage customers\n\n\n\\[ Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10. For Windows 8.x articles, see the [archive](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132) \\]\n\nThe Windows SDK, the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK, and the Windows Store provide features that enable you to make more money from your apps and gain customers by engaging with your users. The topics in this section show you how to build these features into your app.\n\nFor details about the fees charged by the Windows Store and how you get paid for the money your app makes, see [Getting paid](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/mt148536).\n\n## In this section\n\n\n| Topic                                                                                                       | Description                 |\n|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-----------------------------|\n| [Exclude or limit features in a trial version](exclude-or-limit-features-in-a-trial-version-of-your-app.md) | If you enable customers to use your app for free during a trial period, you can entice your customers to upgrade to the full version of your app by excluding or limiting some features during the trial period by using APIs in the Windows SDK. Determine which features should be limited before you begin coding, then make sure that your app only allows them to work when a full license has been purchased. You can also enable features, such as banners or watermarks, that are shown only during the trial, before a customer buys your app. |\n| [Enable in-app product purchases](enable-in-app-product-purchases.md)                                       | Whether your app is free or not, you can sell content, other apps, or new app functionality (such as unlocking the next level of a game) from right within the app. Here we show you how to enable these products in your app by using APIs in the Windows SDK.    |\n| [Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK](monetize-your-app-with-the-microsoft-store-engagement-and-monetization-sdk.md)      | The Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK provides libraries and tools that you can use to add features to your apps that help you make more money and engage with your customers.   |\n| [Run experiments with A/B testing](run-app-experiments-with-a-b-testing.md)      |   Run A/B tests in your Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps to measure the effectiveness of features on some customers before you release the features to everyone. This feature requires the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.  |\n| [Display ads in your app](display-ads-in-your-app.md)      |   Increase your revenue by displaying banner ads or video interstitial ads in your app. This feature requires the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.   |\n| [Launch Feedback Hub from your app](launch-feedback-hub-from-your-app.md)      |   Add code to your UWP apps to direct your Windows 10 customers to Feedback Hub, where they can submit problems, suggestions, and upvotes. Then, manage this feedback in the Dev Center dashboard. This feature requires the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.   |\n| [Use Windows Store services](using-windows-store-services.md)                                    | The Windows Store exposes several services that you can call via REST APIs to programmatically access certain types of data for apps that are registered to your or your organization's Windows Dev Center account.    |\n"}