{"nodes":[{"content":"Configures XAML compilation to join partial classes between markup and code-behind.","pos":[32,115]},{"content":"The code partial class is defined in a separate code file, and the markup partial class is created by code generation during XAML compilation.","pos":[116,258]},{"content":"xClass attribute","pos":[266,282]},{"content":"x:Class attribute","pos":[339,356]},{"content":"Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10.","pos":[361,396]},{"content":"For Windows 8.x articles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>archive<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132)</ept>","pos":[397,489]},{"content":"Configures XAML compilation to join partial classes between markup and code-behind.","pos":[494,577]},{"content":"The code partial class is defined in a separate code file, and the markup partial class is created by code generation during XAML compilation.","pos":[578,720]},{"content":"XAML attribute usage","pos":[725,745]},{"content":"XAML values","pos":[825,836]},{"content":"Term","pos":[840,844]},{"content":"Description","pos":[847,858]},{"content":"namespace","pos":[886,895]},{"content":"Optional.","pos":[898,907]},{"content":"Specifies a namespace that contains the partial class identified by <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>classname<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept>.","pos":[908,988]},{"content":"If <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>namespace<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> is specified, a dot (.) separates <bpt id=\"p2\">_</bpt>namespace<ept id=\"p2\">_</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">_</bpt>classname<ept id=\"p3\">_</ept>.","pos":[989,1066]},{"content":"If <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>namespace<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> is omitted, <bpt id=\"p2\">_</bpt>classname<ept id=\"p2\">_</ept> is assumed to have no namespace.","pos":[1067,1138]},{"content":"classname","pos":[1143,1152]},{"content":"Required.","pos":[1155,1164]},{"content":"Specifies the name of the partial class that connects the loaded XAML and your code-behind for that XAML.","pos":[1165,1270]},{"content":"Remarks","pos":[1278,1285]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x:Class<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> can be declared as an attribute for any element that is the root of a XAML file/object tree and is being compiled by build actions, or for the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Application<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept><ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/br242324)</ept> root in the application definition of a compiled application.","pos":[1287,1579]},{"content":"Declaring <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x:Class<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on any element other than a page root or application root, and under any circumstances for a XAML file that is not compiled with the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Page<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> build action, results in a compile-time error.","pos":[1580,1790]},{"pos":[1792,1847],"content":"The class used as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x:Class<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cannot be a nested class."},{"content":"The value of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x:Class<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> attribute must be a string that specifies the fully qualified name of a class.","pos":[1849,1956]},{"content":"You can omit namespace information so long as that is how the code-behind is structured also (your class definition starts at the class level).","pos":[1957,2100]},{"content":"The code-behind file for a page or application definition must be within a code file that is included as part of the project.","pos":[2101,2226]},{"content":"The code-behind class must be public.","pos":[2227,2264]},{"content":"The code-behind class must be partial.","pos":[2265,2303]},{"content":"CLR language rules","pos":[2308,2326]},{"content":"Although your code-behind file can be a C++ file, there are certain conventions that still follow the CLR language form, so that there is no difference in the XAML syntax.","pos":[2328,2499]},{"content":"In particular, the separator between the namespace and classname components of any <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x:Class<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value is always a dot (\".\"), even though the separator between namespace and classname in the C++ code file associated with the XAML is \"::\".","pos":[2500,2736]},{"content":"If you declare nested namespaces in C++, then the separator between the successive nested namespace strings should also be \".\" rather than \"::\" when you specify the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>namespace<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>x:Class<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> value.","pos":[2737,2944]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jwmsft\ndescription: Configures XAML compilation to join partial classes between markup and code-behind. The code partial class is defined in a separate code file, and the markup partial class is created by code generation during XAML compilation.\ntitle: xClass attribute\nms.assetid: 40A7C036-133A-44DF-9D11-0D39232C948F\n---\n\n# x:Class attribute\n\n\\[ Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10. For Windows 8.x articles, see the [archive](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132) \\]\n\nConfigures XAML compilation to join partial classes between markup and code-behind. The code partial class is defined in a separate code file, and the markup partial class is created by code generation during XAML compilation.\n\n## XAML attribute usage\n\n\n``` syntax\n<object x:Class=\"namespace.classname\"...>\n  ...\n</object>\n```\n\n## XAML values\n\n| Term | Description |\n|------|-------------|\n| namespace | Optional. Specifies a namespace that contains the partial class identified by _classname_. If _namespace_ is specified, a dot (.) separates _namespace_ and _classname_. If _namespace_ is omitted, _classname_ is assumed to have no namespace. |\n| classname | Required. Specifies the name of the partial class that connects the loaded XAML and your code-behind for that XAML. | \n\n## Remarks\n\n**x:Class** can be declared as an attribute for any element that is the root of a XAML file/object tree and is being compiled by build actions, or for the [**Application**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/br242324) root in the application definition of a compiled application. Declaring **x:Class** on any element other than a page root or application root, and under any circumstances for a XAML file that is not compiled with the **Page** build action, results in a compile-time error.\n\nThe class used as **x:Class** cannot be a nested class.\n\nThe value of the **x:Class** attribute must be a string that specifies the fully qualified name of a class. You can omit namespace information so long as that is how the code-behind is structured also (your class definition starts at the class level). The code-behind file for a page or application definition must be within a code file that is included as part of the project. The code-behind class must be public. The code-behind class must be partial.\n\n## CLR language rules\n\nAlthough your code-behind file can be a C++ file, there are certain conventions that still follow the CLR language form, so that there is no difference in the XAML syntax. In particular, the separator between the namespace and classname components of any **x:Class** value is always a dot (\".\"), even though the separator between namespace and classname in the C++ code file associated with the XAML is \"::\". If you declare nested namespaces in C++, then the separator between the successive nested namespace strings should also be \".\" rather than \"::\" when you specify the *namespace* part of the **x:Class** value.\n\n"}