{"nodes":[{"content":"If you had previously set up a pubCenter payout account for your Microsoft Advertising earnings, that account will no longer be used for payments as of April 1st, 2016.","pos":[30,198]},{"content":"Your payments will now be made through your Dev Center payout account.","pos":[199,269]},{"content":"pubCenter-DevCenter payout account and tax profile consolidation","pos":[277,341]},{"content":"pubCenter-DevCenter payout account and tax profile consolidation","pos":[398,462]},{"content":"If you had previously set up a pubCenter payout account for your Microsoft Advertising earnings, that account will no longer be used for payments as of April 1st, 2016.","pos":[465,633]},{"content":"Payments are now made through your Dev Center payout account.","pos":[634,695]},{"pos":[697,935],"content":"To ensure any payments due are submitted on time, please sign in to your Dev Center dashboard and confirm that your <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>payout account and tax profile<ept id=\"p1\">](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md)</ept> are set up correctly and are up to date."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  If you have never set up your payout account or tax profile in Dev Center, you’ll need to do that now.","pos":[939,1056]},{"content":"For more info, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Setting up your payout account and tax forms<ept id=\"p1\">](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md)</ept>.","pos":[1057,1172]},{"content":"For more info about payments in Dev Center, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Payout summary<ept id=\"p1\">](payout-summary.md)</ept>.","pos":[1174,1258]},{"content":"For info about currencies used for payouts in different countries and regions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Developer account and app-submission markets<ept id=\"p1\">](account-types-locations-and-fees.md#account_markets)</ept>.","pos":[1259,1442]},{"content":"We also suggest reviewing the FAQ below for more info about specific scenarios.","pos":[1444,1523]},{"content":"Frequently asked questions","pos":[1528,1554]},{"content":"I have my pubCenter and DevCenter accounts registered with the same Microsoft account in the same region/country.","pos":[1560,1673]},{"content":"How will I receive my money?","pos":[1674,1702]},{"content":"Your Microsoft Advertising earnings will be paid to your the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center.","pos":[1704,1835]},{"content":"I have my pubCenter and DevCenter accounts registered with the same Microsoft Account but in different regions/countries.","pos":[1841,1962]},{"content":"How will I receive my money?","pos":[1963,1991]},{"content":"Your Microsoft Advertising earnings will be paid to the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center.","pos":[1993,2119]},{"content":"The payout amount will be converted to the currency of your Dev Center account country or region.","pos":[2120,2217]},{"content":"I have manually linked my pubCenter accounts to my DevCenter accounts.","pos":[2223,2293]},{"content":"Where will I receive my Microsoft Advertising earnings?","pos":[2294,2349]},{"content":"You will receive a single payout for the Microsoft Advertising earnings from all your linked pubCenter accounts in the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center.","pos":[2351,2540]},{"content":"The payout amount will be converted to the currency of your Dev Center account country or region.","pos":[2541,2638]},{"content":"I had multiple pubCenter accounts registered with the same publisher.","pos":[2644,2713]},{"content":"How will I receive my earnings for all these accounts?","pos":[2714,2768]},{"content":"You will receive a single payout for the Microsoft Advertising earnings from all your linked pubCenter accounts in the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center.","pos":[2770,2959]},{"content":"The payout amount will be converted to the currency of your Dev Center account country or region.","pos":[2960,3057]},{"content":"I had multiple pubCenter accounts registered with different tax profiles in pubCenter.","pos":[3063,3149]},{"content":"Why do I only see one tax profile in DevCenter?","pos":[3150,3197]},{"content":"Your DevCenter account has a single tax profile that will be used for all your payouts.","pos":[3199,3286]},{"content":"Visit <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Setting up your payout account and tax forms<ept id=\"p1\">](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md)</ept> to learn about setting up and managing your payment and tax information in Dev Center.","pos":[3287,3475]},{"content":"Why was my payout converted to a different currency?","pos":[3481,3533]},{"content":"Your Microsoft Advertising earnings will be converted and paid to the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center .","pos":[3535,3676]},{"content":"If your pubCenter account country did not match your Dev Center account country, you will be paid in the currency associated with your Dev Center account country.","pos":[3677,3839]},{"content":"Why was my payout sent to a different PayPal or bank account?","pos":[3845,3906]},{"content":"This can happen if you had set up different payout accounts (PayPal or bank accounts) in Dev Center and pubCenter.","pos":[3908,4022]},{"content":"As of April 1st, 2016, all Microsoft Advertising payouts will be made to the payout account that you set up in Dev Center.","pos":[4023,4145]},{"content":"Why didn’t I receive my Microsoft Advertising payout this month?","pos":[4151,4215]},{"content":"This is usually due to one or more of the following reasons:","pos":[4217,4277]},{"pos":[4283,4418],"content":"Your <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>payout account and tax profile details<ept id=\"p1\">](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md)</ept> were not set up correctly in Dev Center."},{"pos":[4423,4532],"content":"Your pubCenter account has not been <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>linked to your Dev Center account<ept id=\"p1\">](pubcenter-dev-center-integration.md)</ept>."},{"content":"How can I check the payout account and tax profile that will be used for payout in DevCenter?","pos":[4538,4631]},{"pos":[4633,4827],"content":"Visit <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Setting up your payout account and tax forms<ept id=\"p1\">](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md)</ept> to learn how to view (and edit if necessary) your payment and tax information in Dev Center."},{"content":"I still see my tax profile and payout account information in pubCenter.","pos":[4833,4904]},{"content":"Will these be used for my payout?","pos":[4905,4938]},{"content":"No, your pubCenter payout account and tax profile information will no longer be used for payments starting April 1st, 2016.","pos":[4940,5063]},{"content":"Visit <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Setting up your payout account and tax forms<ept id=\"p1\">](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md)</ept> to learn how to set up and manage your payment and tax information in Dev Center.","pos":[5064,5247]},{"content":"Can I still manage my tax profile and payout account information in pubCenter?","pos":[5253,5331]},{"content":"No, your pubCenter payout account and tax profile information will no longer be used for payments as of April 1st, 2016.","pos":[5333,5453]},{"content":"Visit <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Setting up your payout account and tax forms<ept id=\"p1\">](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md)</ept> to learn how to set up and manage your payment and tax information in Dev Center.","pos":[5454,5637]},{"content":"If I need help with my payouts, whom do I contact?","pos":[5643,5693]},{"pos":[5695,5807],"content":"For any questions or inquiries, please open a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>support ticket<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=733342)</ept>."}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: If you had previously set up a pubCenter payout account for your Microsoft Advertising earnings, that account will no longer be used for payments as of April 1st, 2016. Your payments will now be made through your Dev Center payout account.\ntitle: pubCenter-DevCenter payout account and tax profile consolidation\nms.assetid: 1EC55E2F-2BC5-4982-A569-A59082A808EC\n---\n\n# pubCenter-DevCenter payout account and tax profile consolidation\n\n\nIf you had previously set up a pubCenter payout account for your Microsoft Advertising earnings, that account will no longer be used for payments as of April 1st, 2016. Payments are now made through your Dev Center payout account.\n\nTo ensure any payments due are submitted on time, please sign in to your Dev Center dashboard and confirm that your [payout account and tax profile](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md) are set up correctly and are up to date.\n\n> **Important**  If you have never set up your payout account or tax profile in Dev Center, you’ll need to do that now. For more info, see [Setting up your payout account and tax forms](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md).\n\nFor more info about payments in Dev Center, see [Payout summary](payout-summary.md). For info about currencies used for payouts in different countries and regions, see [Developer account and app-submission markets](account-types-locations-and-fees.md#account_markets).\n\nWe also suggest reviewing the FAQ below for more info about specific scenarios.\n\n## Frequently asked questions\n\n### I have my pubCenter and DevCenter accounts registered with the same Microsoft account in the same region/country. How will I receive my money?\n\nYour Microsoft Advertising earnings will be paid to your the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center.\n\n### I have my pubCenter and DevCenter accounts registered with the same Microsoft Account but in different regions/countries. How will I receive my money?\n\nYour Microsoft Advertising earnings will be paid to the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center. The payout amount will be converted to the currency of your Dev Center account country or region.\n\n### I have manually linked my pubCenter accounts to my DevCenter accounts. Where will I receive my Microsoft Advertising earnings?\n\nYou will receive a single payout for the Microsoft Advertising earnings from all your linked pubCenter accounts in the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center. The payout amount will be converted to the currency of your Dev Center account country or region.\n\n### I had multiple pubCenter accounts registered with the same publisher. How will I receive my earnings for all these accounts?\n\nYou will receive a single payout for the Microsoft Advertising earnings from all your linked pubCenter accounts in the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center. The payout amount will be converted to the currency of your Dev Center account country or region.\n\n### I had multiple pubCenter accounts registered with different tax profiles in pubCenter. Why do I only see one tax profile in DevCenter?\n\nYour DevCenter account has a single tax profile that will be used for all your payouts. Visit [Setting up your payout account and tax forms](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md) to learn about setting up and managing your payment and tax information in Dev Center.\n\n### Why was my payout converted to a different currency?\n\nYour Microsoft Advertising earnings will be converted and paid to the payout account (PayPal or bank account) that you set up in Dev Center . If your pubCenter account country did not match your Dev Center account country, you will be paid in the currency associated with your Dev Center account country.\n\n### Why was my payout sent to a different PayPal or bank account?\n\nThis can happen if you had set up different payout accounts (PayPal or bank accounts) in Dev Center and pubCenter. As of April 1st, 2016, all Microsoft Advertising payouts will be made to the payout account that you set up in Dev Center.\n\n### Why didn’t I receive my Microsoft Advertising payout this month?\n\nThis is usually due to one or more of the following reasons:\n\n-   Your [payout account and tax profile details](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md) were not set up correctly in Dev Center.\n-   Your pubCenter account has not been [linked to your Dev Center account](pubcenter-dev-center-integration.md).\n\n### How can I check the payout account and tax profile that will be used for payout in DevCenter?\n\nVisit [Setting up your payout account and tax forms](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md) to learn how to view (and edit if necessary) your payment and tax information in Dev Center.\n\n### I still see my tax profile and payout account information in pubCenter. Will these be used for my payout?\n\nNo, your pubCenter payout account and tax profile information will no longer be used for payments starting April 1st, 2016. Visit [Setting up your payout account and tax forms](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md) to learn how to set up and manage your payment and tax information in Dev Center.\n\n### Can I still manage my tax profile and payout account information in pubCenter?\n\nNo, your pubCenter payout account and tax profile information will no longer be used for payments as of April 1st, 2016. Visit [Setting up your payout account and tax forms](setting-up-your-payout-account-and-tax-forms.md) to learn how to set up and manage your payment and tax information in Dev Center.\n\n### If I need help with my payouts, whom do I contact?\n\nFor any questions or inquiries, please open a [support ticket](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=733342).\n\n \n\n \n\n\n\n\n"}