{"nodes":[{"content":"Xbox One Developer Mode activation","pos":[27,61]},{"content":"How to activate Developer Mode so you can switch between Retail Mode and Developer Mode.","pos":[75,163]},{"content":"Xbox One Developer Mode activation","pos":[182,216]},{"content":"How Developer Mode works","pos":[221,245]},{"content":"Activate Developer Mode on your retail Xbox One console","pos":[277,332]},{"content":"Switch between Retail and Developer Mode","pos":[397,437]},{"content":"How Developer Mode works","pos":[486,510]},{"content":"Xbox One has two modes, <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> Mode (1) and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Developer<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> Mode (2).","pos":[511,578]},{"content":"In Retail Mode, the console is in the state that any customer or user of an Xbox One console would use: you can play games and run apps as a user.","pos":[579,725]},{"content":"In Developer Mode, you can develop software for the console, but you cannot play retail games or run retail apps.","pos":[726,839]},{"content":"Developer Mode can be enabled on any retail Xbox One console.","pos":[840,901]},{"content":"After Developer Mode is enabled, you can switch back and forth between Retail (2a) and Developer Modes (2b).","pos":[902,1010]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>When you activate Developer Mode on Xbox One, you are opting into Xbox system updates for a developer preview release that includes experimental and early pre-release software.","pos":[1014,1215]},{"content":"This means that some popular games and apps will not work as expected, and you may experience occasional crashes and data loss.","pos":[1216,1343]},{"content":"If you leave the developer preview, your console will factory reset and you will have to reinstall all of your games, apps, and content.","pos":[1344,1480]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>You cannot activate Developer Mode on Xbox One if you are part of an existing preview program such as the Xbox One Beta program.","pos":[1485,1633]},{"content":"You can leave an existing preview program by using the Xbox Preview Dashboard app.","pos":[1634,1716]},{"content":"Xbox One modes","pos":[1721,1735]},{"content":"Activate Developer Mode on your retail Xbox One console","pos":[1767,1822]},{"content":"Start your Xbox One console.","pos":[1828,1856]},{"pos":[1862,1983],"content":"Search for and install the Dev Mode Activation app from the Xbox One store.  \n![](images/activation-store-search.png)","leadings":["","    "],"nodes":[{"content":"Search for and install the Dev Mode Activation app from the Xbox One store.","pos":[0,75]}]},{"pos":[1989,2032],"content":"Navigate to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>My games &amp; apps<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> &gt; </ph><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Apps<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."},{"content":"Dev Mode Activation app","pos":[2040,2063]},{"content":"Open the Dev Mode Activation app.","pos":[2098,2131]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>Please make sure that you read the disclaimers carefully.","pos":[2147,2224]},{"content":"As part of activating Xbox for development, you will be getting early pre-release builds.","pos":[2225,2314]},{"content":"To play games and apps, you will need to switch to Retail Mode.","pos":[2315,2378]},{"content":"Sideloaded apps will only work in Developer Mode.","pos":[2379,2428]},{"content":"Note the code displayed in the Dev Mode Activation app.","pos":[2434,2489]},{"content":"Activation Step 5","pos":[2499,2516]},{"pos":[2559,2650],"content":"Go to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>developer.microsoft.com/xboxactivate<ept id=\"p1\">](https://developer.microsoft.com/xboxactivate)</ept>."},{"content":"Sign in to Dev Center with your Dev Center account.","pos":[2655,2706]},{"content":"Enter the activation code displayed in the Dev Mode Activation app.","pos":[2713,2780]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>You have a limited number of activations associated with your account.","pos":[2795,2885]},{"content":"After Developer Mode has been activated, Dev Center will indicate you have used one of the activations associated with your account.","pos":[2886,3018]},{"content":"Activation Step 8","pos":[3031,3048]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Agree and activate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[3093,3122]},{"content":"This will cause the page to reload, and you will see your device populate in the table.","pos":[3123,3210]},{"pos":[3222,3376],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</ph>Terms for the Xbox One Developer Mode Activation Program agreement can be found <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p2\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=760399)</ept>."},{"content":"After you’ve entered your activation code, your console will display a progress screen for the activation process.","pos":[3382,3496]},{"content":"After activation completes, you will have to wait for your console to update to the required preview build.","pos":[3503,3610]},{"content":"This may take several hours; please be patient.","pos":[3611,3658]},{"content":"Activation Step 11","pos":[3668,3686]},{"content":"After activation has completed, open the Dev Mode Activation app and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Switch and restart<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to go to Developer Mode.","pos":[3732,3854]},{"content":"Note that this will take longer than usual.","pos":[3855,3898]},{"content":"Activation Step 12","pos":[3908,3926]},{"content":"Switch between Retail and Developer Mode","pos":[3976,4016]},{"content":"After Developer Mode has been enabled on your console, use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dev Home<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to switch between Retail Mode and Developer Mode.","pos":[4017,4138]},{"content":"To learn more about starting and using <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dev Home<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, see <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Introduction to Xbox One tools<ept id=\"p2\">](introduction-to-xbox-tools.md)</ept>.","pos":[4139,4260]},{"content":"To switch to Retail Mode, use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dev Home<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Leave developer mode<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[4264,4342]},{"content":"This will restart your console in Retail Mode.","pos":[4343,4389]},{"content":"Activation Step 13","pos":[4399,4417]},{"content":"To switch to Developer Mode, use the Dev Mode Activation app.","pos":[4457,4518]},{"content":"Open the app and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Switch and restart<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4519,4565]},{"content":"This will restart your console in Developer Mode.","pos":[4566,4615]},{"content":"Activation Step 14","pos":[4623,4641]},{"content":"See also","pos":[4680,4688]},{"content":"Xbox One Developer Mode deactivation","pos":[4692,4728]},{"content":"UWP on Xbox One","pos":[4757,4772]}],"content":"---\nauthor: Mtoepke\ntitle: Xbox One Developer Mode activation\ndescription: How to activate Developer Mode so you can switch between Retail Mode and Developer Mode.\narea: Xbox\n---\n\n# Xbox One Developer Mode activation\n\n* [How Developer Mode works](#how-developer-mode-works)\n* [Activate Developer Mode on your retail Xbox One console](#activate-developer-mode-on-your-retail-xbox-one-console)  \n* [Switch between Retail and Developer Mode](#switch-between-retail-and-developer-mode)\n\n## How Developer Mode works\nXbox One has two modes, *Retail* Mode (1) and *Developer* Mode (2). In Retail Mode, the console is in the state that any customer or user of an Xbox One console would use: you can play games and run apps as a user. In Developer Mode, you can develop software for the console, but you cannot play retail games or run retail apps.\nDeveloper Mode can be enabled on any retail Xbox One console. After Developer Mode is enabled, you can switch back and forth between Retail (2a) and Developer Modes (2b).\n\n> **Important**&nbsp;&nbsp;When you activate Developer Mode on Xbox One, you are opting into Xbox system updates for a developer preview release that includes experimental and early pre-release software. This means that some popular games and apps will not work as expected, and you may experience occasional crashes and data loss. If you leave the developer preview, your console will factory reset and you will have to reinstall all of your games, apps, and content. \n\n> **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;You cannot activate Developer Mode on Xbox One if you are part of an existing preview program such as the Xbox One Beta program. You can leave an existing preview program by using the Xbox Preview Dashboard app. \n\n![Xbox One modes](images/dev-mode-flow.png)\n\n## Activate Developer Mode on your retail Xbox One console\n\n1.  Start your Xbox One console.\n\n2.  Search for and install the Dev Mode Activation app from the Xbox One store.  \n    ![](images/activation-store-search.png)\n\n3.  Navigate to **My games & apps** > **Apps**.\n\n    ![Dev Mode Activation app](images/activation-step-3.png)\n4. Open the Dev Mode Activation app.    \n    \n    > **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;Please make sure that you read the disclaimers carefully. As part of activating Xbox for development, you will be getting early pre-release builds. To play games and apps, you will need to switch to Retail Mode. Sideloaded apps will only work in Developer Mode.\n\n5.  Note the code displayed in the Dev Mode Activation app.  \n\n    ![Activation Step 5](images/activation-step-5.png)  \n    \n6.  Go to [developer.microsoft.com/xboxactivate](https://developer.microsoft.com/xboxactivate).\n7.  Sign in to Dev Center with your Dev Center account.  \n8.  Enter the activation code displayed in the Dev Mode Activation app.   \n   \n     > **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;You have a limited number of activations associated with your account. After Developer Mode has been activated, Dev Center will indicate you have used one of the activations associated with your account. \n    \n    ![Activation Step 8](images/activation-step-8.png)    \n    \n9.  Click **Agree and activate**. This will cause the page to reload, and you will see your device populate in the table.\n    \n    > **Note**&nbsp;&nbsp;Terms for the Xbox One Developer Mode Activation Program agreement can be found [here](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=760399).\n\n10. After you’ve entered your activation code, your console will display a progress screen for the activation process.  \n11. After activation completes, you will have to wait for your console to update to the required preview build. This may take several hours; please be patient.  \n\n    ![Activation Step 11](images/activation-step-11.png)    \n    \n12. After activation has completed, open the Dev Mode Activation app and click **Switch and restart** to go to Developer Mode. Note that this will take longer than usual.  \n\n    ![Activation Step 12](images/activation-step-12.png)   \n    \n\n    \n## Switch between Retail and Developer Mode\nAfter Developer Mode has been enabled on your console, use **Dev Home** to switch between Retail Mode and Developer Mode. To learn more about starting and using **Dev Home**, see [Introduction to Xbox One tools](introduction-to-xbox-tools.md).\n\n* To switch to Retail Mode, use **Dev Home** and click **Leave developer mode**. This will restart your console in Retail Mode.    \n\n  ![Activation Step 13](images/activation-step-13.png)  \n  \n* To switch to Developer Mode, use the Dev Mode Activation app. Open the app and click **Switch and restart**. This will restart your console in Developer Mode.  \n\n  ![Activation Step 14](images/activation-step-12.png)  \n\n## See also\n- [Xbox One Developer Mode deactivation](devkit-deactivation.md)\n- [UWP on Xbox One](index.md)\n"}