{"nodes":[{"content":"Pair devices","pos":[77,89]},{"content":"Some devices need to be paired before they can be used.","pos":[103,158]},{"content":"The Windows.Devices.Enumeration namespace supports three different ways to pair devices.","pos":[159,247]},{"content":"Pair devices","pos":[254,266]},{"content":"Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10.","pos":[271,306]},{"content":"For Windows 8.x articles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>archive<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132)</ept>","pos":[307,399]},{"content":"Important APIs","pos":[408,422]},{"content":"Windows.Devices.Enumeration","pos":[434,461]},{"content":"Some devices need to be paired before they can be used.","pos":[524,579]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Windows.Devices.Enumeration<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225459)</ept> namespace supports three different ways to pair devices.","pos":[580,732]},{"content":"Automatic pairing","pos":[738,755]},{"content":"Basic pairing","pos":[760,773]},{"content":"Custom pairing","pos":[778,792]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tip<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Some devices do not need to be paired in order to be used.","pos":[794,861]},{"content":"This is covered under the section on automatic pairing.","pos":[862,917]},{"content":"Automatic pairing","pos":[925,942]},{"content":"Sometimes you want to use a device in your application, but do not care whether or not the device is paired.","pos":[945,1053]},{"content":"You simply want to be able to use the functionality associated with a device.","pos":[1054,1131]},{"content":"For example, if your app wants to simply capture an image from a webcam, you are not necessarily interested in the device itself, just the image capture.","pos":[1132,1285]},{"content":"If there are device APIs available for the device you are interested in, this scenario would fall under automatic pairing.","pos":[1286,1408]},{"content":"In this case, you simply use the APIs associated with the device, making the calls as necessary and trusting the system to handle any pairing that might be necessary.","pos":[1410,1576]},{"content":"Some devices do not need to be paired in order for you to use their functionality.","pos":[1577,1659]},{"content":"If the device does need to be paired, then the device APIs will handle the pairing action behind the scenes so you do not need to integrate that functionality into your app.","pos":[1660,1833]},{"content":"Your app will have no knowledge about whether or not a given device is paired or needs to be, but you will still be able to access the device and use its functionality.","pos":[1834,2002]},{"content":"Basic pairing","pos":[2007,2020]},{"content":"Basic pairing is when your application uses the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Windows.Devices.Enumeration<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225459)</ept> APIs in order to attempt to pair the device.","pos":[2023,2207]},{"content":"In this scenario, you are letting Windows attempt the pairing process and handle it.","pos":[2208,2292]},{"content":"If any user interaction is necessary, it will be handled by Windows.","pos":[2293,2361]},{"content":"You would use basic pairing if you need to pair with a device and there is not a relevant device API that will attempt automatic pairing.","pos":[2362,2499]},{"content":"You just want to be able to use the device and need to pair with it first.","pos":[2500,2574]},{"content":"In order to attempt basic pairing, you first need to obtain the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393)</ept> object for the device you are interested in.","pos":[2576,2766]},{"content":"Once you receive that object, you will interact with the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformation.Pairing<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx)</ept> property, which is a <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>DeviceInformationPairing<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept><ept id=\"p3\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx)</ept> object.","pos":[2767,3143]},{"content":"To attempt to pair, simply call <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformationPairing.PairAsync<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/mt608800)</ept>.","pos":[3144,3275]},{"content":"You will need to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>await<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> the result in order to give your app time to attempt to complete the pairing action.","pos":[3276,3387]},{"content":"The result of the pairing action will be returned, and as long as no errors are returned, the device will be paired.","pos":[3388,3504]},{"content":"If you are using basic pairing, you also have access to additional information about the pairing status of the device.","pos":[3506,3624]},{"content":"For example you know the pairing status (<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>IsPaired<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx_ispaired)</ept>) and whether the device can pair (<bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>CanPair<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept><ept id=\"p3\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx_canpair)</ept>).","pos":[3625,3975]},{"content":"Both of these are properties of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformationPairing<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx)</ept> object.","pos":[3976,4164]},{"content":"If you are using automatic pairing, you might not have access to this information unless you obtain the relevant <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393)</ept> objects.","pos":[4165,4368]},{"content":"Custom pairing","pos":[4373,4387]},{"content":"Custom pairing enables your app to participate in the pairing process.","pos":[4390,4460]},{"content":"This allows your app to specify the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Mt608808)</ept> that are supported for the pairing process.","pos":[4461,4623]},{"content":"You will also be responsible for creating your own user interface to interact with the user as needed.","pos":[4624,4726]},{"content":"Use custom pairing when you want your app to have a little more influence over how the pairing process proceeds or to display your own pairing user interface.","pos":[4727,4885]},{"content":"In order to implement custom pairing, you will need to obtain the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393)</ept> object for the device you are interested in, just like with basic pairing.","pos":[4887,5109]},{"content":"However, the specific property your are interested in is <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformation.Pairing.Custom<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx_custom)</ept>.","pos":[5110,5327]},{"content":"This will give you a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformationCustomPairing<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393custompairing)</ept> object.","pos":[5328,5464]},{"content":"All of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformationCustomPairing.PairAsync<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393custompairing_pairasync)</ept> methods require you to include a <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept><ept id=\"p3\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Mt608808)</ept> parameter.","pos":[5465,5730]},{"content":"This indicates the actions that the user will need to take in order to attempt to pair the device.","pos":[5731,5829]},{"content":"See the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> reference page for more information about the different kinds and what actions the user will need to take.","pos":[5830,5967]},{"content":"Just like with basic pairing, you will need to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>await<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> the result in order to give your app time to attempt to complete the pairing action.","pos":[5968,6109]},{"content":"The result of the pairing action will be returned, and as long as no errors are returned, the device will be paired.","pos":[6110,6226]},{"content":"To support custom pairing, you will need to create a handler for the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>PairingRequested<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393custompairing_pairingrequested)</ept> event.","pos":[6228,6414]},{"content":"This handler needs to make sure to account for all the different <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Mt608808)</ept> that might be used in a custom pairing scenario.","pos":[6415,6611]},{"content":"The appropriate action to take will depend on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> provided as part of the event arguments.","pos":[6612,6725]},{"content":"It is important to be aware that custom pairing is always a system-level operation.","pos":[6727,6810]},{"content":"Because of this, when you are operating on Desktop or Windows Phone, a system dialog will always be shown to the user when pairing is going to happen.","pos":[6811,6961]},{"content":"This is because both of those platforms posses a user experience that requires user consent.","pos":[6962,7054]},{"content":"Since that dialog is automatically generated, you will not need to create your own dialog when you are opting for a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Mt608808)</ept> of <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>ConfirmOnly<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> when operating on these platforms.","pos":[7055,7307]},{"content":"For the other <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you will need to perform some special handling depending on the specific <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> value.","pos":[7308,7448]},{"content":"See the sample for examples of how to handle custom pairing for different <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DevicePairingKinds<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> values.","pos":[7449,7553]},{"content":"Unpairing","pos":[7558,7567]},{"content":"Unpairing a device is only relevant in the basic or custom pairing scenarios described above.","pos":[7570,7663]},{"content":"If you are using automatic pairing, your app remains oblivious to the pairing status of the device and there is no need to unpair it.","pos":[7664,7797]},{"content":"If you do choose to unpair a device, the process is identical whether you implement basic or custom pairing.","pos":[7798,7906]},{"content":"This is because there is no need to provide additional information or interact in the unpairing process.","pos":[7907,8011]},{"content":"The first step to unpairing a device is obtaining the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393)</ept> object for the device that you want to unpair.","pos":[8013,8195]},{"content":"Then you need to retrieve the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeviceInformation.Pairing<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx)</ept> property and call <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>DeviceInformationPairing.UnpairAsync<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept><ept id=\"p3\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformationpairing.unpairasync)</ept>.","pos":[8196,8547]},{"content":"Just like with pairing, you will want to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>await<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> the result.","pos":[8548,8610]},{"content":"The result of the unpairing action will be returned, and as long as no errors are returned, the device will be unpaired.","pos":[8611,8731]},{"content":"Sample","pos":[8736,8742]},{"pos":[8745,8947],"content":"To download a sample showing how to use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Windows.Devices.Enumeration<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225459)</ept> APIs, click <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p3\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=620536)</ept>."}],"content":"---\nauthor: DBirtolo\nms.assetid: F8A741B4-7A6A-4160-8C5D-6B92E267E6EA\ntitle: Pair devices\ndescription: Some devices need to be paired before they can be used. The Windows.Devices.Enumeration namespace supports three different ways to pair devices.\n---\n# Pair devices\n\n\\[ Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10. For Windows 8.x articles, see the [archive](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132) \\]\n\n\n** Important APIs **\n\n-   [**Windows.Devices.Enumeration**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225459)\n\nSome devices need to be paired before they can be used. The [**Windows.Devices.Enumeration**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225459) namespace supports three different ways to pair devices.\n\n-   Automatic pairing\n-   Basic pairing\n-   Custom pairing\n\n**Tip**  Some devices do not need to be paired in order to be used. This is covered under the section on automatic pairing.\n\n \n\n## Automatic pairing\n\n\nSometimes you want to use a device in your application, but do not care whether or not the device is paired. You simply want to be able to use the functionality associated with a device. For example, if your app wants to simply capture an image from a webcam, you are not necessarily interested in the device itself, just the image capture. If there are device APIs available for the device you are interested in, this scenario would fall under automatic pairing.\n\nIn this case, you simply use the APIs associated with the device, making the calls as necessary and trusting the system to handle any pairing that might be necessary. Some devices do not need to be paired in order for you to use their functionality. If the device does need to be paired, then the device APIs will handle the pairing action behind the scenes so you do not need to integrate that functionality into your app. Your app will have no knowledge about whether or not a given device is paired or needs to be, but you will still be able to access the device and use its functionality.\n\n## Basic pairing\n\n\nBasic pairing is when your application uses the [**Windows.Devices.Enumeration**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225459) APIs in order to attempt to pair the device. In this scenario, you are letting Windows attempt the pairing process and handle it. If any user interaction is necessary, it will be handled by Windows. You would use basic pairing if you need to pair with a device and there is not a relevant device API that will attempt automatic pairing. You just want to be able to use the device and need to pair with it first.\n\nIn order to attempt basic pairing, you first need to obtain the [**DeviceInformation**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393) object for the device you are interested in. Once you receive that object, you will interact with the [**DeviceInformation.Pairing**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx) property, which is a [**DeviceInformationPairing**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx) object. To attempt to pair, simply call [**DeviceInformationPairing.PairAsync**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/mt608800). You will need to **await** the result in order to give your app time to attempt to complete the pairing action. The result of the pairing action will be returned, and as long as no errors are returned, the device will be paired.\n\nIf you are using basic pairing, you also have access to additional information about the pairing status of the device. For example you know the pairing status ([**IsPaired**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx_ispaired)) and whether the device can pair ([**CanPair**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx_canpair)). Both of these are properties of the [**DeviceInformationPairing**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx) object. If you are using automatic pairing, you might not have access to this information unless you obtain the relevant [**DeviceInformation**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393) objects.\n\n## Custom pairing\n\n\nCustom pairing enables your app to participate in the pairing process. This allows your app to specify the [**DevicePairingKinds**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Mt608808) that are supported for the pairing process. You will also be responsible for creating your own user interface to interact with the user as needed. Use custom pairing when you want your app to have a little more influence over how the pairing process proceeds or to display your own pairing user interface.\n\nIn order to implement custom pairing, you will need to obtain the [**DeviceInformation**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393) object for the device you are interested in, just like with basic pairing. However, the specific property your are interested in is [**DeviceInformation.Pairing.Custom**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx_custom). This will give you a [**DeviceInformationCustomPairing**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393custompairing) object. All of the [**DeviceInformationCustomPairing.PairAsync**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393custompairing_pairasync) methods require you to include a [**DevicePairingKinds**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Mt608808) parameter. This indicates the actions that the user will need to take in order to attempt to pair the device. See the **DevicePairingKinds** reference page for more information about the different kinds and what actions the user will need to take. Just like with basic pairing, you will need to **await** the result in order to give your app time to attempt to complete the pairing action. The result of the pairing action will be returned, and as long as no errors are returned, the device will be paired.\n\nTo support custom pairing, you will need to create a handler for the [**PairingRequested**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393custompairing_pairingrequested) event. This handler needs to make sure to account for all the different [**DevicePairingKinds**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Mt608808) that might be used in a custom pairing scenario. The appropriate action to take will depend on the **DevicePairingKinds** provided as part of the event arguments.\n\nIt is important to be aware that custom pairing is always a system-level operation. Because of this, when you are operating on Desktop or Windows Phone, a system dialog will always be shown to the user when pairing is going to happen. This is because both of those platforms posses a user experience that requires user consent. Since that dialog is automatically generated, you will not need to create your own dialog when you are opting for a [**DevicePairingKinds**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/Mt608808) of **ConfirmOnly** when operating on these platforms. For the other **DevicePairingKinds**, you will need to perform some special handling depending on the specific **DevicePairingKinds** value. See the sample for examples of how to handle custom pairing for different **DevicePairingKinds** values.\n\n## Unpairing\n\n\nUnpairing a device is only relevant in the basic or custom pairing scenarios described above. If you are using automatic pairing, your app remains oblivious to the pairing status of the device and there is no need to unpair it. If you do choose to unpair a device, the process is identical whether you implement basic or custom pairing. This is because there is no need to provide additional information or interact in the unpairing process.\n\nThe first step to unpairing a device is obtaining the [**DeviceInformation**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225393) object for the device that you want to unpair. Then you need to retrieve the [**DeviceInformation.Pairing**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformation.pairing.aspx) property and call [**DeviceInformationPairing.UnpairAsync**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.devices.enumeration.deviceinformationpairing.unpairasync). Just like with pairing, you will want to **await** the result. The result of the unpairing action will be returned, and as long as no errors are returned, the device will be unpaired.\n\n## Sample\n\n\nTo download a sample showing how to use the [**Windows.Devices.Enumeration**](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR225459) APIs, click [here](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=620536).\n\n \n\n \n\n\n\n\n"}