{"nodes":[{"content":"You can encourage your customers to leave feedback by launching Feedback Hub from your app.","pos":[37,128]},{"content":"Launch Feedback Hub from your app","pos":[136,169]},{"content":"Launch Feedback Hub from your app","pos":[226,259]},{"content":"You can encourage your customers to leave feedback by adding a control (such as a button) to your Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app that launches Feedback Hub.","pos":[261,423]},{"content":"Feedback Hub is a preinstalled app that provides a single place to gather feedback on Windows and installed apps.","pos":[424,537]},{"content":"All customer feedback that is submitted for your app through Feedback Hub is collected and presented to you in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Feedback report<ept id=\"p1\">](../publish/feedback-report.md)</ept> in the Windows Dev Center dashboard, so you can see the problems, suggestions, and upvotes that your customers have submitted in one report.","pos":[538,842]},{"pos":[845,1020],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Feedback<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> report is currently available only to developer accounts that have joined the <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Dev Center Insider Program<ept id=\"p3\">](../publish/dev-center-insider-program.md)</ept>."},{"content":"To launch Feedback Hub from your app, use an API that is provided by the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk)</ept>.","pos":[1023,1174]},{"content":"We recommend that you use this API to launch Feedback Hub from a UI element in your app that follows our design guidelines.","pos":[1175,1298]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Feedback Hub is available only on devices that are running Windows 10 version 10.0.14271 or later.","pos":[1301,1408]},{"content":"We recommend that you show a feedback control in your app only if the Feedback Hub is available on the user's device.","pos":[1409,1526]},{"content":"The code in this topic demonstrates how to do this.","pos":[1527,1578]},{"content":"How to launch Feedback Hub from your app","pos":[1583,1623]},{"content":"To launch Feedback Hub from your app:","pos":[1625,1662]},{"content":"Install the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk)</ept>.","pos":[1667,1757]},{"content":"In addition to the API for launching Feedback Hub, this SDK also provides APIs for other features such as running experiments in your apps with A/B testing and displaying ads.","pos":[1758,1933]},{"content":"For more information about this SDK, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Monetize your app and engage customers with the Store Engagement and Monetization SDK<ept id=\"p1\">](monetize-your-app-with-the-microsoft-store-engagement-and-monetization-sdk.md)</ept>.","pos":[1934,2142]},{"content":"Open your project in Visual Studio.","pos":[2146,2181]},{"pos":[2185,2288],"content":"In Solution Explorer, right-click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>References<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> node for your project and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add Reference<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."},{"pos":[2292,2372],"content":"In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reference Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, expand <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Universal Windows<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Extensions<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."},{"pos":[2376,2477],"content":"In the list of SDKs, click the check box next to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Store Engagement SDK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."},{"content":"In your project, add the control that you want to show to users to launch Feedback Hub, such as a button.","pos":[2481,2586]},{"content":"We recommend that you configure the control as follows:","pos":[2587,2642]},{"pos":[2647,2721],"content":"Set the font of the content shown in the control to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Segoe MDL2 Assets<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."},{"content":"Set the text in the control to the hexadecimal Unicode character code E939.","pos":[2726,2801]},{"content":"This is the character code for the recommended feedback icon in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Segoe MDL2 Assets<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> font.","pos":[2802,2897]},{"content":"Set the visibility of the control to hidden.","pos":[2902,2946]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Feedback Hub is available only on devices that are running Windows 10 version 10.0.14271 or later.","pos":[2954,3062]},{"content":"We recommend that you hide your feedback control by default and show it in your initialization code only if the Feedback Hub is available on the user's device.","pos":[3063,3222]},{"content":"The next step demonstrates how to do this.","pos":[3223,3265]},{"pos":[3269,3459],"content":"The following code demonstrates the XAML definition of a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Button<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.ui.xaml.controls.button.aspx)</ept> that is configured as described above."},{"content":"In your initialization code for the app page that hosts your feedback control, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>IsSupported<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.services.store.engagement.feedback.issupported.aspx)</ept> property of the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Feedback<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.services.store.engagement.feedback.aspx)</ept> class to determine whether the Feedback Hub is available on the user's device.","pos":[3689,4105]},{"content":"If this property returns <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>true<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, make the control visible.","pos":[4106,4166]},{"content":"The following code demonstrates how to do this for a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Button<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.ui.xaml.controls.button.aspx)</ept>.","pos":[4167,4315]},{"content":"In the event handler that runs when the user clicks the control, call the static <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>LaunchFeedbackAsync<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.services.store.engagement.feedback.launchfeedbackasync.aspx)</ept> method of the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Feedback<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.services.store.engagement.feedback.aspx)</ept> class to launch the Feedback Hub app.","pos":[4460,4843]},{"content":"There are two overloads for this method: one without parameters, and another one that accepts a dictionary of key and value pairs that contain metadata that you want to associate with the feedback.","pos":[4844,5041]},{"content":"The following example demonstrates how to launch Feedback Hub in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Click<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.ui.xaml.controls.primitives.buttonbase.click.aspx)</ept> event handler for a <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Button<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.ui.xaml.controls.button.aspx)</ept>.","pos":[5042,5341]},{"content":"Design recommendations for your feedback UI","pos":[5520,5563]},{"content":"To launch Feedback Hub, we recommend that you add a UI element in your app (such as a button) that displays the following standard feedback icon from the Segoe MDL2 Assets font and the character code E939.","pos":[5565,5770]},{"content":"![]Feedback icon](images/feedback_icon.PNG)","pos":[5772,5815]},{"content":"We also recommend that you use one or more of the following placement options for linking to Feedback Hub in your app.","pos":[5817,5935]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Directly in the app bar<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[5938,5966]},{"content":"Depending on your implementation, you may wish to use the icon only or add text (as shown below).","pos":[5967,6064]},{"content":"![]Feedback icon](images/feedback_appbar_placement.png)","pos":[6068,6123]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>In your app's settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[6127,6154]},{"content":"This is a more subtle way to provide access to Feedback Hub.","pos":[6155,6215]},{"content":"In the example below, the Feedback link appears as one of the links under App.","pos":[6216,6294]},{"content":"![]Feedback icon](images/feedback_settings_placement.png)","pos":[6298,6355]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>In an event-driven flyout<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[6359,6389]},{"content":"This is useful when you want to query your customers about a specific question before launching into the Windows Feedback Hub.","pos":[6390,6516]},{"content":"For example, after your app uses a certain feature, you might prompt the customer with a specific question about their satisfaction with that feature.","pos":[6517,6667]},{"content":"If the customer chooses to respond, your app launches Feedback Hub.","pos":[6668,6735]},{"content":"Related topics","pos":[6741,6755]},{"content":"Feedback report","pos":[6760,6775]}],"content":"---\nauthor: mcleanbyron\nDescription: You can encourage your customers to leave feedback by launching Feedback Hub from your app.\ntitle: Launch Feedback Hub from your app\nms.assetid: 070B9CA4-6D70-4116-9B18-FBF246716EF0\n---\n\n# Launch Feedback Hub from your app\n\nYou can encourage your customers to leave feedback by adding a control (such as a button) to your Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app that launches Feedback Hub. Feedback Hub is a preinstalled app that provides a single place to gather feedback on Windows and installed apps. All customer feedback that is submitted for your app through Feedback Hub is collected and presented to you in the [Feedback report](../publish/feedback-report.md) in the Windows Dev Center dashboard, so you can see the problems, suggestions, and upvotes that your customers have submitted in one report.\n\n>**Note** The **Feedback** report is currently available only to developer accounts that have joined the [Dev Center Insider Program](../publish/dev-center-insider-program.md). \n\nTo launch Feedback Hub from your app, use an API that is provided by the [Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk). We recommend that you use this API to launch Feedback Hub from a UI element in your app that follows our design guidelines.\n\n>**Note** Feedback Hub is available only on devices that are running Windows 10 version 10.0.14271 or later. We recommend that you show a feedback control in your app only if the Feedback Hub is available on the user's device. The code in this topic demonstrates how to do this.\n\n## How to launch Feedback Hub from your app\n\nTo launch Feedback Hub from your app:\n\n1. Install the [Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk). In addition to the API for launching Feedback Hub, this SDK also provides APIs for other features such as running experiments in your apps with A/B testing and displaying ads. For more information about this SDK, see [Monetize your app and engage customers with the Store Engagement and Monetization SDK](monetize-your-app-with-the-microsoft-store-engagement-and-monetization-sdk.md).\n2. Open your project in Visual Studio.\n3. In Solution Explorer, right-click the **References** node for your project and click **Add Reference**.\n4. In **Reference Manager**, expand **Universal Windows** and click **Extensions**.\n5. In the list of SDKs, click the check box next to **Microsoft Store Engagement SDK** and click **OK**.\n6. In your project, add the control that you want to show to users to launch Feedback Hub, such as a button. We recommend that you configure the control as follows:\n  * Set the font of the content shown in the control to **Segoe MDL2 Assets**.\n  * Set the text in the control to the hexadecimal Unicode character code E939. This is the character code for the recommended feedback icon in the **Segoe MDL2 Assets** font.\n  * Set the visibility of the control to hidden.\n\n    > **Note**  Feedback Hub is available only on devices that are running Windows 10 version 10.0.14271 or later. We recommend that you hide your feedback control by default and show it in your initialization code only if the Feedback Hub is available on the user's device. The next step demonstrates how to do this.\n\n  The following code demonstrates the XAML definition of a [Button](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.ui.xaml.controls.button.aspx) that is configured as described above.\n  ```xml\n  <Button x:Name=\"feedbackButton\" FontFamily=\"Segoe MDL2 Assets\" Content=\"&#xE939;\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Left\" Margin=\"138,352,0,0\" VerticalAlignment=\"Top\" Visibility=\"Collapsed\"  Click=\"feedbackButton_Click\"/>\n  ```\n7. In your initialization code for the app page that hosts your feedback control, use the [IsSupported](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.services.store.engagement.feedback.issupported.aspx) property of the [Feedback](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.services.store.engagement.feedback.aspx) class to determine whether the Feedback Hub is available on the user's device. If this property returns **true**, make the control visible. The following code demonstrates how to do this for a [Button](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.ui.xaml.controls.button.aspx).\n```CSharp\nif (Microsoft.Services.Store.Engagement.Feedback.IsSupported)\n{\n        this.feedbackButton.Visibility = Visibility.Visible;\n}\n```\n8. In the event handler that runs when the user clicks the control, call the static [LaunchFeedbackAsync](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.services.store.engagement.feedback.launchfeedbackasync.aspx) method of the [Feedback](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.services.store.engagement.feedback.aspx) class to launch the Feedback Hub app. There are two overloads for this method: one without parameters, and another one that accepts a dictionary of key and value pairs that contain metadata that you want to associate with the feedback. The following example demonstrates how to launch Feedback Hub in the [Click](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.ui.xaml.controls.primitives.buttonbase.click.aspx) event handler for a [Button](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/windows.ui.xaml.controls.button.aspx).\n```CSharp\nprivate async void feedbackButton_Click(object sender, RoutedEventArgs e)\n{\n        await Microsoft.Services.Store.Engagement.Feedback.LaunchFeedbackAsync();\n}\n```\n\n## Design recommendations for your feedback UI\n\nTo launch Feedback Hub, we recommend that you add a UI element in your app (such as a button) that displays the following standard feedback icon from the Segoe MDL2 Assets font and the character code E939.\n\n![]Feedback icon](images/feedback_icon.PNG)\n\nWe also recommend that you use one or more of the following placement options for linking to Feedback Hub in your app.\n* **Directly in the app bar**. Depending on your implementation, you may wish to use the icon only or add text (as shown below).\n\n  ![]Feedback icon](images/feedback_appbar_placement.png)\n\n* **In your app's settings**. This is a more subtle way to provide access to Feedback Hub. In the example below, the Feedback link appears as one of the links under App.\n\n  ![]Feedback icon](images/feedback_settings_placement.png)\n\n* **In an event-driven flyout**. This is useful when you want to query your customers about a specific question before launching into the Windows Feedback Hub. For example, after your app uses a certain feature, you might prompt the customer with a specific question about their satisfaction with that feature. If the customer chooses to respond, your app launches Feedback Hub.\n\n\n## Related topics\n\n* [Feedback report](../publish/feedback-report.md)\n"}