{"nodes":[{"content":"Learn about known issues for the current release of the Microsoft advertising libraries in the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.","pos":[86,229]},{"content":"Known issues for the Microsoft advertising libraries","pos":[237,289]},{"content":"Known issues for the Microsoft advertising libraries","pos":[297,349]},{"content":"Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10.","pos":[355,390]},{"content":"For Windows 8.x articles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>archive<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132)</ept>","pos":[391,483]},{"content":"This topic lists the known issues with the current release of the Microsoft advertising libraries in the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.","pos":[488,641]},{"content":"Installation requires Visual Studio Tools for Universal Windows Apps","pos":[646,714]},{"content":"To install the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk)</ept> with Visual Studio 2015, you must have version 1.1 or later of the Visual Studio Tools for Universal Windows Apps installed.","pos":[716,933]},{"content":"For more information, see the Visual Studio <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>release notes<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=624516)</ept>.","pos":[934,1041]},{"content":"Windows Phone 8.x Silverlight projects","pos":[1046,1084]},{"content":"To get the Microsoft advertising assemblies for Windows Phone 8.x Silverlight projects, install the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk)</ept>, open your project in Visual Studio, and then go to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Project<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> &gt; </ph><bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Add Connected Service<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph2\"> &gt; </ph><bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Ad Mediator<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> to automatically download the assemblies.","pos":[1086,1415]},{"content":"After doing this, you can remove the ad mediator references from your project if you do not want to use ad mediation.","pos":[1416,1533]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>AdControl in Windows Phone Silverlight<ept id=\"p1\">](adcontrol-in-windows-phone-silverlight.md)</ept>.","pos":[1534,1644]},{"content":"AdControl interface unknown in XAML","pos":[1649,1684]},{"content":"The XAML markup for an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>AdControl<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.advertising.winrt.ui.adcontrol.aspx)</ept> may incorrectly show a blue curvy line implying that the interface is unknown.","pos":[1686,1894]},{"content":"This occurs only when targeting x86, and it may be ignored.","pos":[1895,1954]},{"content":"lastError from previous ad request","pos":[1959,1993]},{"content":"If there is a leftover <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>lastError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> from the previous ad request, the event may be fired twice during the next ad call.","pos":[1995,2115]},{"content":"While the new ad request will still be made and may yield a valid ad, this behavior may cause confusion.","pos":[2116,2220]},{"content":"Interstitial ads and navigation buttons on phones","pos":[2225,2274]},{"pos":[2276,2482],"content":"On phones (or emulators) that have software <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Back<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Start<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Search<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> buttons instead of hardware buttons, the countdown timer and click through buttons for video interstitial ads may be obscured."},{"content":"Recently created ads are not being served to your app","pos":[2487,2540]},{"content":"If you have created an ad recently (less than a day), it might not be available immediately.","pos":[2542,2634]},{"content":"If the ad has been approved for editorial content, it will be served once the advertising server has processed it and the ad is available as inventory.","pos":[2635,2786]},{"content":"No ads are shown in your app","pos":[2791,2819]},{"content":"There are many reasons you may see no ads, including network errors.","pos":[2821,2889]},{"content":"Other reasons might include:","pos":[2890,2918]},{"pos":[2922,3055],"content":"Selecting an ad unit in Windows Dev Center with a size that is greater or less than the size of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AdControl<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in your app's code."},{"pos":[3059,3180],"content":"Ads will not appear if you're using a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>test mode value<ept id=\"p1\">](test-mode-values.md)</ept> for your ad unit ID when running a live app."},{"content":"If you created a new ad unit ID in the past half-hour, you might not see an ad until the servers propagate new data through the system.","pos":[3184,3319]},{"content":"Existing IDs that have shown ads before should show ads immediately.","pos":[3320,3388]},{"content":"If you can see test ads in the app, your code is working and is able to display ads.","pos":[3390,3474]},{"content":"If you encounter issues, contact <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>product support<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=331508)</ept>.","pos":[3475,3576]},{"content":"On that page, choose <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>In-App Advertising<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[3577,3621]},{"pos":[3623,3716],"content":"You can also post a question in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>forum<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=401266)</ept>."},{"content":"Test ads are showing in your app instead of live ads","pos":[3721,3773]},{"content":"Test ads can be shown, even when you are expecting live ads.","pos":[3775,3835]},{"content":"This can happen in the following scenarios:","pos":[3836,3879]},{"content":"Microsoft advertising cannot verify or find the live application ID used in the app store.","pos":[3883,3973]},{"content":"In this case, when an ad unit is created by a user, its status can start as live (non-test) but will move to test status within 6 hours after the first ad request.","pos":[3974,4137]},{"content":"It will change back to live if there are no requests from test apps for 10 days.","pos":[4138,4218]},{"content":"Side-loaded apps or apps that are running in the emulator will not show live ads.","pos":[4222,4303]},{"content":"When a live ad unit is serving test ads, the ad unit’s status shows <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active and serving test ads<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in Windows Dev Center.","pos":[4305,4427]},{"content":"This does not currently apply to phone apps.","pos":[4428,4472]},{"content":"Obsolete test values for ad unit ID and application ID no longer working","pos":[4477,4549]},{"content":"The following test values for Windows Phone Silverlight apps are obsolete, and will no longer work.","pos":[4551,4650]},{"content":"If you have an existing project that uses these test values, update your project to use the values provided in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Test mode values<ept id=\"p1\">](test-mode-values.md)</ept>.","pos":[4651,4802]},{"content":"Application ID","pos":[4806,4820]},{"content":"Ad unit ID","pos":[4825,4835]},{"content":"test_client","pos":[4880,4891]},{"content":"Image320_50","pos":[4899,4910]},{"content":"test_client","pos":[4917,4928]},{"content":"Image300_50","pos":[4936,4947]},{"content":"test_client","pos":[4954,4965]},{"content":"TextAd","pos":[4973,4979]},{"content":"test_client","pos":[4986,4997]},{"content":"Image480_80","pos":[5005,5016]},{"content":"Reference errors caused by targeting Any CPU in your project","pos":[5055,5115]},{"content":"When using the Microsoft advertising libraries, you cannot target <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Any CPU<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in your project.","pos":[5117,5211]},{"content":"If your project targets the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Any CPU<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> platform, you may see a warning after adding the reference similar to this one.","pos":[5212,5331]},{"content":"referenceerror<ph id=\"ph1\">\\-</ph>solutionexplorer","pos":[5335,5367]},{"content":"To remove this warning, update your project to use an architecture-specific build output (for example, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x86<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>).","pos":[5422,5534]},{"content":"Use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configuration Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to set the platform targets for debug and release configurations.","pos":[5535,5630]},{"content":"configurationmanagerwin10","pos":[5634,5659]},{"content":"When you create your app packages for store submission (as shown in the following images), be sure to include the architectures you intend to target.","pos":[5714,5863]},{"content":"You may opt to skip x64 if you intend to run x86 builds on the x64 OS.","pos":[5864,5934]},{"content":"projectstorecreateapppackages","pos":[5938,5967]},{"content":"createapppackages","pos":[6024,6041]},{"content":"Z-order in JavaScript/HTML apps","pos":[6099,6130]},{"content":"JavaScript/HTML apps must not place elements into the reserved MAX-10 range of z-order.","pos":[6132,6219]},{"content":"The sole exception is an interrupt overlay, such as an inbound call notification for a Skype app.","pos":[6220,6317]},{"content":"Do not use borders","pos":[6343,6361]},{"pos":[6363,6490],"content":"Setting border-related properties inherited by the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AdControl<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> from its parent class will cause the ad placement to be wrong."},{"content":"More Information","pos":[6495,6511]},{"pos":[6514,6702],"content":"For more information about the latest known issues and to post questions related to the Microsoft advertising libraries, visit the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>forum<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=401266)</ept>."},{"content":"Support","pos":[6707,6714]},{"pos":[6717,6906],"content":"To contact product support for issues with the Microsoft advertising libraries, visit the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>support page<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=331508)</ept> and choose <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>In-App Advertising<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."}],"content":"---\nauthor: mcleanbyron\nms.assetid: 9ca1f880-2ced-46b4-8ea7-aba43d2ff863\ndescription: Learn about known issues for the current release of the Microsoft advertising libraries in the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.\ntitle: Known issues for the Microsoft advertising libraries\n---\n\n# Known issues for the Microsoft advertising libraries\n\n\n\\[ Updated for UWP apps on Windows 10. For Windows 8.x articles, see the [archive](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=619132) \\]\n\nThis topic lists the known issues with the current release of the Microsoft advertising libraries in the Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK.\n\n## Installation requires Visual Studio Tools for Universal Windows Apps\n\nTo install the [Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk) with Visual Studio 2015, you must have version 1.1 or later of the Visual Studio Tools for Universal Windows Apps installed. For more information, see the Visual Studio [release notes](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=624516).\n\n## Windows Phone 8.x Silverlight projects\n\nTo get the Microsoft advertising assemblies for Windows Phone 8.x Silverlight projects, install the [Microsoft Store Engagement and Monetization SDK](http://aka.ms/store-em-sdk), open your project in Visual Studio, and then go to **Project** > **Add Connected Service** > **Ad Mediator** to automatically download the assemblies. After doing this, you can remove the ad mediator references from your project if you do not want to use ad mediation. For more information, see [AdControl in Windows Phone Silverlight](adcontrol-in-windows-phone-silverlight.md).\n\n## AdControl interface unknown in XAML\n\nThe XAML markup for an [AdControl](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/microsoft.advertising.winrt.ui.adcontrol.aspx) may incorrectly show a blue curvy line implying that the interface is unknown. This occurs only when targeting x86, and it may be ignored.\n\n## lastError from previous ad request\n\nIf there is a leftover **lastError** from the previous ad request, the event may be fired twice during the next ad call. While the new ad request will still be made and may yield a valid ad, this behavior may cause confusion.\n\n## Interstitial ads and navigation buttons on phones\n\nOn phones (or emulators) that have software **Back**, **Start**, and **Search** buttons instead of hardware buttons, the countdown timer and click through buttons for video interstitial ads may be obscured.\n\n## Recently created ads are not being served to your app\n\nIf you have created an ad recently (less than a day), it might not be available immediately. If the ad has been approved for editorial content, it will be served once the advertising server has processed it and the ad is available as inventory.\n\n## No ads are shown in your app\n\nThere are many reasons you may see no ads, including network errors. Other reasons might include:\n\n* Selecting an ad unit in Windows Dev Center with a size that is greater or less than the size of the **AdControl** in your app's code.\n\n* Ads will not appear if you're using a [test mode value](test-mode-values.md) for your ad unit ID when running a live app.\n\n* If you created a new ad unit ID in the past half-hour, you might not see an ad until the servers propagate new data through the system. Existing IDs that have shown ads before should show ads immediately.\n\nIf you can see test ads in the app, your code is working and is able to display ads. If you encounter issues, contact [product support](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=331508). On that page, choose **In-App Advertising**.\n\nYou can also post a question in the [forum](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=401266).\n\n## Test ads are showing in your app instead of live ads\n\nTest ads can be shown, even when you are expecting live ads. This can happen in the following scenarios:\n\n* Microsoft advertising cannot verify or find the live application ID used in the app store. In this case, when an ad unit is created by a user, its status can start as live (non-test) but will move to test status within 6 hours after the first ad request. It will change back to live if there are no requests from test apps for 10 days.\n\n* Side-loaded apps or apps that are running in the emulator will not show live ads.\n\nWhen a live ad unit is serving test ads, the ad unit’s status shows **Active and serving test ads** in Windows Dev Center. This does not currently apply to phone apps.\n\n## Obsolete test values for ad unit ID and application ID no longer working\n\nThe following test values for Windows Phone Silverlight apps are obsolete, and will no longer work. If you have an existing project that uses these test values, update your project to use the values provided in [Test mode values](test-mode-values.md).\n\n| Application ID  |  Ad unit ID    |\n|-----------------|----------------|\n| test_client     |  Image320_50   |\n| test_client     |  Image300_50   |\n| test_client     |  TextAd   |\n| test_client     |  Image480_80   |\n\n<span id=\"reference_errors\"/>\n## Reference errors caused by targeting Any CPU in your project\n\nWhen using the Microsoft advertising libraries, you cannot target **Any CPU** in your project. If your project targets the **Any CPU** platform, you may see a warning after adding the reference similar to this one.\n\n![referenceerror\\-solutionexplorer](images/13-19629921-023c-42ec-b8f5-bc0b63d5a191.jpg)\n\nTo remove this warning, update your project to use an architecture-specific build output (for example, **x86**). Use **Configuration Manager** to set the platform targets for debug and release configurations.\n\n![configurationmanagerwin10](images/13-87074274-c10d-4dbd-9a06-453b7184f8de.png)\n\nWhen you create your app packages for store submission (as shown in the following images), be sure to include the architectures you intend to target. You may opt to skip x64 if you intend to run x86 builds on the x64 OS.\n\n![projectstorecreateapppackages](images/13-a99b05a4-8917-4c53-822e-2548fadf828a.png)\n\n![createapppackages](images/13-16280cb1-a838-42b9-9256-eac7f33f5603.png)\n\n## Z-order in JavaScript/HTML apps\n\nJavaScript/HTML apps must not place elements into the reserved MAX-10 range of z-order. The sole exception is an interrupt overlay, such as an inbound call notification for a Skype app.\n\n<span id=\"bkmk-ui\"/>\n## Do not use borders\n\nSetting border-related properties inherited by the **AdControl** from its parent class will cause the ad placement to be wrong.\n\n## More Information\n\n\nFor more information about the latest known issues and to post questions related to the Microsoft advertising libraries, visit the [forum](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=401266).\n\n## Support\n\n\nTo contact product support for issues with the Microsoft advertising libraries, visit the [support page](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=331508) and choose **In-App Advertising**.\n\n \n\n \n"}