{"nodes":[{"content":"Notifications Visualizer is a new Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app in the Store that helps developers design adaptive live tiles for Windows 10.","pos":[34,182]},{"content":"Notifications Visualizer","pos":[190,214]},{"content":"Notifications Visualizer","pos":[303,327]},{"pos":[333,559],"content":"Notifications Visualizer is a new Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>the Store<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/notifications-visualizer/9nblggh5xsl1)</ept> that helps developers design adaptive live tiles for Windows 10."},{"pos":[645,653],"content":"Overview"},{"content":"The Notifications Visualizer app provides instant visual previews of your tile as you edit, similar to Visual Studio's XAML editor/design view.","pos":[656,799]},{"content":"The app also checks for errors, which ensures that you create a valid tile payload.","pos":[800,883]},{"content":"This screenshot from the app shows the XML payload and how tile sizes appear on a selected device:","pos":[885,983]},{"content":"screenshot of notifications visualizer app editor with code and tiles","pos":[987,1056]},{"content":"With Notifications Visualizer, you can create and test adaptive tile payloads without having to edit and deploy the app itself.","pos":[1095,1222]},{"content":"Once you've created a payload with ideal visual results you can integrate that into your app.","pos":[1223,1316]},{"content":"See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Send a local tile notification<ept id=\"p1\">](tiles-and-notifications-sending-a-local-tile-notification.md)</ept> to learn more.","pos":[1317,1430]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>   Notifications Visualizer's simulation of the Windows Start menu isn't always completely accurate, and it doesn't support some payload properties like <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>baseUri<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/br208712)</ept>.","pos":[1432,1661]},{"content":"When you have the tile design you want, test it by pinning the tile to the actual Start menu to verify that it appears as you intend.","pos":[1662,1795]},{"pos":[1884,1892],"content":"Features"},{"content":"Notifications Visualizer comes with a number of sample payloads to showcase what's possible with adaptive live tiles and to help you get started.","pos":[1895,2040]},{"content":"You can experiment with all the different text options, groups/subgroups, background images, and you can see how the tile adapts to different devices and screens.","pos":[2041,2203]},{"content":"Once you've made changes, you can save your updated payload to a file for future use.","pos":[2204,2289]},{"content":"The editor provides real-time errors and warnings.","pos":[2291,2341]},{"content":"For example, if your app payload is limited to less than 5 KB (a platform limitation), Notifications Visualizer warns you if your payload exceeds that limit.","pos":[2342,2499]},{"content":"It gives you warnings for incorrect attribute names or values, which helps you debug visual issues.","pos":[2500,2599]},{"content":"You can control tile properties like display name, color, logos, ShowName, badge value.","pos":[2601,2688]},{"content":"These options help you instantly understand how your tile properties and tile notification payloads interact, and the results they produce.","pos":[2689,2828]},{"content":"This screenshot from the app shows the tile editor:","pos":[2830,2881]},{"content":"screenshot of notifications visualizer editor with tiles","pos":[2885,2941]},{"pos":[3016,3030],"content":"Related topics"},{"content":"Get Notifications Visualizer in the Store","pos":[3036,3077]},{"content":"Create adaptive tiles","pos":[3158,3179]},{"content":"Adaptive tile templates: schema and documentation","pos":[3234,3283]},{"content":"Tiles and toasts (MSDN blog)","pos":[3338,3366]},{"content":"NotificationsExtensions library (MSDN blog)","pos":[3414,3457]}],"content":"---\nauthor: mijacobs\nDescription: Notifications Visualizer is a new Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app in the Store that helps developers design adaptive live tiles for Windows 10.\ntitle: Notifications Visualizer\nms.assetid: FCBB7BB1-2C79-484B-8FFC-26FE1934EC1C\nlabel: TBD\ntemplate: detail.hbs\n---\n\n# Notifications Visualizer\n\n\n\n\n\nNotifications Visualizer is a new Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app in [the Store](https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/notifications-visualizer/9nblggh5xsl1) that helps developers design adaptive live tiles for Windows 10.\n\n## <span id=\"Overview\"></span><span id=\"overview\"></span><span id=\"OVERVIEW\"></span>Overview\n\n\nThe Notifications Visualizer app provides instant visual previews of your tile as you edit, similar to Visual Studio's XAML editor/design view. The app also checks for errors, which ensures that you create a valid tile payload.\n\nThis screenshot from the app shows the XML payload and how tile sizes appear on a selected device:\n\n![screenshot of notifications visualizer app editor with code and tiles](images/notif-visualizer-001.png)\n\n \n\nWith Notifications Visualizer, you can create and test adaptive tile payloads without having to edit and deploy the app itself. Once you've created a payload with ideal visual results you can integrate that into your app. See [Send a local tile notification](tiles-and-notifications-sending-a-local-tile-notification.md) to learn more.\n\n**Note**   Notifications Visualizer's simulation of the Windows Start menu isn't always completely accurate, and it doesn't support some payload properties like [baseUri](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/br208712). When you have the tile design you want, test it by pinning the tile to the actual Start menu to verify that it appears as you intend.\n\n \n\n## <span id=\"Features\"></span><span id=\"features\"></span><span id=\"FEATURES\"></span>Features\n\n\nNotifications Visualizer comes with a number of sample payloads to showcase what's possible with adaptive live tiles and to help you get started. You can experiment with all the different text options, groups/subgroups, background images, and you can see how the tile adapts to different devices and screens. Once you've made changes, you can save your updated payload to a file for future use.\n\nThe editor provides real-time errors and warnings. For example, if your app payload is limited to less than 5 KB (a platform limitation), Notifications Visualizer warns you if your payload exceeds that limit. It gives you warnings for incorrect attribute names or values, which helps you debug visual issues.\n\nYou can control tile properties like display name, color, logos, ShowName, badge value. These options help you instantly understand how your tile properties and tile notification payloads interact, and the results they produce.\n\nThis screenshot from the app shows the tile editor:\n\n![screenshot of notifications visualizer editor with tiles](images/notif-visualizer-004.png)\n\n \n\n## <span id=\"related_topics\"></span>Related topics\n\n\n* [Get Notifications Visualizer in the Store](https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/notifications-visualizer/9nblggh5xsl1)\n* [Create adaptive tiles](tiles-and-notifications-create-adaptive-tiles.md)\n* [Adaptive tile templates: schema and documentation](tiles-and-notifications-adaptive-tiles-schema.md)\n* [Tiles and toasts (MSDN blog)](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/tiles_and_toasts/)\n* [NotificationsExtensions library (MSDN blog)](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/tiles_and_toasts/archive/2015/08/20/introducing-notificationsextensions-for-windows-10.aspx)\n \n\n \n\n\n\n\n"}