{"nodes":[{"content":"You can indicate whether and how your app can be offered for volume purchases through the Windows Store for Business in the Organizational licensing section of the Pricing and availability page of an app submission.","pos":[30,245]},{"content":"Organizational licensing options","pos":[253,285]},{"content":"Organizational licensing options","pos":[342,374]},{"pos":[377,660],"content":"You can indicate whether and how your app can be offered for volume purchases through the Windows Store for Business in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Organizational licensing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Pricing and availability<ept id=\"p2\">](set-app-pricing-and-availability.md#organizational-licensing)</ept> page of an app submission."},{"content":"Through these settings, you can opt to allow your app to be made available to organizations who acquire and deploy multiple licenses for their users, providing an opportunity to increase your reach to Windows 10 organizations across device types, including PCs, tablets and phones.","pos":[662,943]},{"content":"You will also need to allow organizational licensing for <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>line-of-business (LOB) apps<ept id=\"p1\">](distribute-lob-apps-to-enterprises.md)</ept> that you publish directly to enterprises.","pos":[944,1111]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Selections for each of your apps are configured independently from each other.","pos":[1115,1203]},{"content":"You may change your preferences for an app at any time by creating a new submission, and your changes will take effect after the submission completes the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>certification process<ept id=\"p1\">](the-app-certification-process.md)</ept>.","pos":[1204,1416]},{"content":"Allowing your app to be offered to organizations","pos":[1421,1469]},{"content":"By default, the box labeled <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Make my app available to organizations with Store-managed (online) volume licensing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is checked.","pos":[1471,1598]},{"content":"This means that you wish your app to be available for inclusion in catalogs of apps that will be made available to organizations for volume acquisition, with app licenses managed through the Store's online licensing system.","pos":[1599,1822]},{"pos":[1826,1918],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  This does not guarantee that your app will be made available to all organizations."},{"content":"If you prefer not to allow us to offer your app to organizations for volume acquisition, uncheck this box.","pos":[1920,2026]},{"content":"Note that this change will only take place after the app completes the certification process.","pos":[2027,2120]},{"content":"If any organizations had previously acquired licenses to your app, those licenses will still be valid, and the people who have the app already can continue to use it.","pos":[2121,2287]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tip<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  To publish line-of-business (LOB) apps exclusively to a specific organization, you can set up an enterprise association and allow the organization to add the apps directly their private store.","pos":[2291,2492]},{"content":"For more info, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Distribute LOB apps to enterprises<ept id=\"p1\">](distribute-lob-apps-to-enterprises.md)</ept>.","pos":[2493,2588]},{"content":"Allowing disconnected (offline) licensing","pos":[2593,2634]},{"content":"Many organizations need apps enabled for offline licensing.","pos":[2637,2696]},{"content":"For example, some organizations need to deploy apps to devices which rarely or never connect to the internet.","pos":[2697,2806]},{"content":"If you want to allow your app to be made available to these customers, check the box labeled <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Allow disconnected (offline) licensing for organizations<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2807,2961]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  This box is unchecked by default; you must check the box to allow us to make your app available to verified organizations who will install it using disconnected licensing.","pos":[2965,3146]},{"content":"Organizations must go through additional validation in order to install paid apps to their end users in this way.","pos":[3147,3260]},{"content":"Offline licensing allows organizations to acquire your app on a volume basis, and then install the app without requiring each device to contact the Store's licensing system.","pos":[3262,3435]},{"content":"The organization is able to download your app's package along with a license which lets them install it to devices (via their own management tools or by preloading apps on OS images) without notifying the Store when a particular license has been used.","pos":[3436,3687]},{"content":"Enabling this scenario greatly increases deployment flexibility, and it may substantially increase the attractiveness of your app with these customers.","pos":[3688,3839]},{"pos":[3843,3910],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Offline licensing is not supported for .xap packages."},{"content":"Paid app support","pos":[3919,3935]},{"content":"Currently, developer accounts in certain markets are able to offer paid apps for volume acquisition through the Windows Store for Business.","pos":[3937,4076]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> In some markets, the price shown for an app in the Windows Store for Business may be different than the price shown to retail customers in the Windows Store for the same price tier.","pos":[4081,4271]},{"content":"Payout of proceeds from organizational purchases works just the same as it does for consumer purchases of your app.","pos":[4272,4387]},{"content":"For more info, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting paid<ept id=\"p1\">](getting-paid-apps.md)</ept> and the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>App Developer Agreement<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/hh694058)</ept>.","pos":[4388,4536]},{"content":"If your country or region is not listed below, your paid apps currently will not be offered in the Windows Store for Business.","pos":[4538,4664]},{"content":"If so, the organizational licensing selections you make for your paid apps may be applied at a later time, as the Windows Store for Business continues to add support for paid app submissions from additional developer account markets.","pos":[4665,4898]},{"content":"At this time, developers in the following countries and regions can distribute paid apps to organizational customers via the Windows Store for Business:","pos":[4900,5052]},{"content":"Austria","pos":[5056,5063]},{"content":"Belgium","pos":[5066,5073]},{"content":"Bulgaria","pos":[5076,5084]},{"content":"Canada","pos":[5087,5093]},{"content":"Croatia","pos":[5096,5103]},{"content":"Cyprus","pos":[5106,5112]},{"content":"Czech Republic","pos":[5115,5129]},{"content":"Denmark","pos":[5132,5139]},{"content":"Estonia","pos":[5142,5149]},{"content":"Finland","pos":[5152,5159]},{"content":"France","pos":[5162,5168]},{"content":"Germany","pos":[5171,5178]},{"content":"Greece","pos":[5181,5187]},{"content":"Hungary","pos":[5190,5197]},{"content":"Ireland","pos":[5200,5207]},{"content":"Isle of Man","pos":[5210,5221]},{"content":"Italy","pos":[5224,5229]},{"content":"Latvia","pos":[5232,5238]},{"content":"Liechtenstein","pos":[5241,5254]},{"content":"Lithuania","pos":[5257,5266]},{"content":"Luxembourg","pos":[5269,5279]},{"content":"Malta","pos":[5282,5287]},{"content":"Monaco","pos":[5290,5296]},{"content":"Netherlands","pos":[5299,5310]},{"content":"Norway","pos":[5313,5319]},{"content":"Poland","pos":[5322,5328]},{"content":"Portugal","pos":[5331,5339]},{"content":"Romania","pos":[5342,5349]},{"content":"Slovakia","pos":[5352,5360]},{"content":"Slovenia","pos":[5363,5371]},{"content":"Spain","pos":[5374,5379]},{"content":"Sweden","pos":[5382,5388]},{"content":"Switzerland","pos":[5391,5402]},{"content":"United Kingdom","pos":[5405,5419]},{"content":"United States","pos":[5422,5435]}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: You can indicate whether and how your app can be offered for volume purchases through the Windows Store for Business in the Organizational licensing section of the Pricing and availability page of an app submission.\ntitle: Organizational licensing options\nms.assetid: 1EB139B0-67E7-4F66-AAEF-491B1E52E96F\n---\n\n# Organizational licensing options\n\n\nYou can indicate whether and how your app can be offered for volume purchases through the Windows Store for Business in the **Organizational licensing** section of the [Pricing and availability](set-app-pricing-and-availability.md#organizational-licensing) page of an app submission.\n\nThrough these settings, you can opt to allow your app to be made available to organizations who acquire and deploy multiple licenses for their users, providing an opportunity to increase your reach to Windows 10 organizations across device types, including PCs, tablets and phones. You will also need to allow organizational licensing for [line-of-business (LOB) apps](distribute-lob-apps-to-enterprises.md) that you publish directly to enterprises.\n\n> **Note**  Selections for each of your apps are configured independently from each other. You may change your preferences for an app at any time by creating a new submission, and your changes will take effect after the submission completes the [certification process](the-app-certification-process.md).\n\n## Allowing your app to be offered to organizations\n\nBy default, the box labeled **Make my app available to organizations with Store-managed (online) volume licensing** is checked. This means that you wish your app to be available for inclusion in catalogs of apps that will be made available to organizations for volume acquisition, with app licenses managed through the Store's online licensing system.\n\n> **Note**  This does not guarantee that your app will be made available to all organizations.\n\nIf you prefer not to allow us to offer your app to organizations for volume acquisition, uncheck this box. Note that this change will only take place after the app completes the certification process. If any organizations had previously acquired licenses to your app, those licenses will still be valid, and the people who have the app already can continue to use it.\n\n> **Tip**  To publish line-of-business (LOB) apps exclusively to a specific organization, you can set up an enterprise association and allow the organization to add the apps directly their private store. For more info, see [Distribute LOB apps to enterprises](distribute-lob-apps-to-enterprises.md).\n\n## Allowing disconnected (offline) licensing\n\n\nMany organizations need apps enabled for offline licensing. For example, some organizations need to deploy apps to devices which rarely or never connect to the internet. If you want to allow your app to be made available to these customers, check the box labeled **Allow disconnected (offline) licensing for organizations**.\n\n> **Note**  This box is unchecked by default; you must check the box to allow us to make your app available to verified organizations who will install it using disconnected licensing. Organizations must go through additional validation in order to install paid apps to their end users in this way.\n\nOffline licensing allows organizations to acquire your app on a volume basis, and then install the app without requiring each device to contact the Store's licensing system. The organization is able to download your app's package along with a license which lets them install it to devices (via their own management tools or by preloading apps on OS images) without notifying the Store when a particular license has been used. Enabling this scenario greatly increases deployment flexibility, and it may substantially increase the attractiveness of your app with these customers.\n\n> **Important** Offline licensing is not supported for .xap packages.  \n\n \n## Paid app support\n\nCurrently, developer accounts in certain markets are able to offer paid apps for volume acquisition through the Windows Store for Business. \n\n> **Note** In some markets, the price shown for an app in the Windows Store for Business may be different than the price shown to retail customers in the Windows Store for the same price tier. Payout of proceeds from organizational purchases works just the same as it does for consumer purchases of your app. For more info, see [Getting paid](getting-paid-apps.md) and the [App Developer Agreement](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/hh694058).\n\nIf your country or region is not listed below, your paid apps currently will not be offered in the Windows Store for Business. If so, the organizational licensing selections you make for your paid apps may be applied at a later time, as the Windows Store for Business continues to add support for paid app submissions from additional developer account markets.\n\nAt this time, developers in the following countries and regions can distribute paid apps to organizational customers via the Windows Store for Business:\n\n- Austria\n- Belgium\n- Bulgaria\n- Canada\n- Croatia\n- Cyprus\n- Czech Republic\n- Denmark\n- Estonia\n- Finland\n- France\n- Germany\n- Greece\n- Hungary\n- Ireland\n- Isle of Man\n- Italy\n- Latvia\n- Liechtenstein\n- Lithuania\n- Luxembourg\n- Malta\n- Monaco\n- Netherlands\n- Norway\n- Poland\n- Portugal\n- Romania\n- Slovakia\n- Slovenia\n- Spain\n- Sweden\n- Switzerland\n- United Kingdom\n- United States\n"}