{"nodes":[{"content":"When submitting an IAP, the options on the Properties page help determine the behavior of your IAP when offered to customers.","pos":[30,155]},{"content":"Enter IAP properties","pos":[163,183]},{"content":"Enter IAP properties","pos":[240,260]},{"pos":[263,392],"content":"When submitting an IAP, the options on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page help determine the behavior of your IAP when offered to customers."},{"content":"Product type","pos":[397,409]},{"content":"Your product type is selected when you first create the IAP.","pos":[411,471]},{"content":"The product type you selected is displayed here, but you can't change it.","pos":[472,545]},{"pos":[549,686],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  If you haven't published the IAP, you can delete the submission and start again if you need to choose a different product type."},{"content":"If you selected Durable for your product type, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product lifetime<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is shown here.","pos":[689,775]},{"content":"The default <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product lifetime<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for a durable IAP is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Forever<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, which means the IAP never expires.","pos":[776,877]},{"content":"If you prefer, you can set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product lifetime<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> so that the IAP expires after a set duration (with options from 1-365 days).","pos":[878,1006]},{"content":"Content type","pos":[1012,1024]},{"content":"Regardless of your IAP's product type, you'll also need to indicate the type of content you're offering.","pos":[1026,1130]},{"content":"For most IAPs, the content type should be <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Electronic software download<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[1131,1206]},{"content":"If another option from the list seems to describe your IAP better (for example, if you are offering a music download or an e-book), select that option instead.","pos":[1207,1366]},{"content":"These are the possible options for an IAP's content type:","pos":[1369,1426]},{"content":"Electronic software download","pos":[1432,1460]},{"content":"Electronic books","pos":[1465,1481]},{"content":"Electronic magazine single issue","pos":[1486,1518]},{"content":"Electronic newspaper single issue","pos":[1523,1556]},{"content":"Music download","pos":[1561,1575]},{"content":"Music streaming","pos":[1580,1595]},{"content":"Online data storage/services","pos":[1600,1628]},{"content":"Video download","pos":[1633,1647]},{"content":"Video streaming","pos":[1652,1667]},{"content":"Software as a service","pos":[1672,1693]},{"content":"Keywords","pos":[1698,1706]},{"content":"You have the option to provide up to ten keywords of up to 30 characters each for each IAP you submit.","pos":[1708,1810]},{"content":"Your app can then query for products that match these words.","pos":[1811,1871]},{"content":"This feature lets you build screens in your app that can load IAPs without you having to directly specify the product ID in your app's code.","pos":[1872,2012]},{"content":"You can then change the IAP's keywords anytime, without having to make code changes in your app or submit the app again.","pos":[2013,2133]},{"pos":[2137,2230],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Keywords are not available for use in packages targeting Windows 8 and Windows 8.1."},{"content":"Tag","pos":[2235,2238]},{"pos":[2240,2348],"content":"You can enter up to 3000 characters into the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tag<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field to provide extra context for your in-app product."},{"content":"For example, let’s say you have a game, and you’re selling a bag of gold coins as an IAP.","pos":[2350,2439]},{"content":"Using the Tags field, the app can query for this bag of gold.","pos":[2440,2501]},{"content":"You can adjust the value at any time (in this case, the number of coins in your bag) by updating the info in the IAP's <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tag<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, without having to make code changes in your app or submit the app again.","pos":[2502,2708]},{"pos":[2712,2813],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  The <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Tag<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field is not available for use in packages targeting Windows 8 and Windows 8.1."}],"content":"---\nauthor: jnHs\nDescription: When submitting an IAP, the options on the Properties page help determine the behavior of your IAP when offered to customers.\ntitle: Enter IAP properties\nms.assetid: 26D2139F-66FD-479E-940B-7491238ADCAE\n---\n\n# Enter IAP properties\n\n\nWhen submitting an IAP, the options on the **Properties** page help determine the behavior of your IAP when offered to customers.\n\n## Product type\n\nYour product type is selected when you first create the IAP. The product type you selected is displayed here, but you can't change it.\n\n> **Note**  If you haven't published the IAP, you can delete the submission and start again if you need to choose a different product type. \n\nIf you selected Durable for your product type, the **Product lifetime** is shown here. The default **Product lifetime** for a durable IAP is **Forever**, which means the IAP never expires. If you prefer, you can set the **Product lifetime** so that the IAP expires after a set duration (with options from 1-365 days). \n\n## Content type\n\nRegardless of your IAP's product type, you'll also need to indicate the type of content you're offering. For most IAPs, the content type should be **Electronic software download**. If another option from the list seems to describe your IAP better (for example, if you are offering a music download or an e-book), select that option instead. \n\nThese are the possible options for an IAP's content type:\n\n-   Electronic software download\n-   Electronic books\n-   Electronic magazine single issue\n-   Electronic newspaper single issue\n-   Music download\n-   Music streaming\n-   Online data storage/services\n-   Video download\n-   Video streaming\n-   Software as a service\n\n## Keywords\n\nYou have the option to provide up to ten keywords of up to 30 characters each for each IAP you submit. Your app can then query for products that match these words. This feature lets you build screens in your app that can load IAPs without you having to directly specify the product ID in your app's code. You can then change the IAP's keywords anytime, without having to make code changes in your app or submit the app again.\n\n> **Note**  Keywords are not available for use in packages targeting Windows 8 and Windows 8.1.\n\n## Tag\n\nYou can enter up to 3000 characters into the **Tag** field to provide extra context for your in-app product.\n\nFor example, let’s say you have a game, and you’re selling a bag of gold coins as an IAP. Using the Tags field, the app can query for this bag of gold. You can adjust the value at any time (in this case, the number of coins in your bag) by updating the info in the IAP's **Tag** field, without having to make code changes in your app or submit the app again.\n\n> **Note**  The **Tag** field is not available for use in packages targeting Windows 8 and Windows 8.1.\n\n \n\n \n\n \n\n\n\n\n"}