{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        27,
        82
      ],
      "content": "Deploy a Machine Learning web service | Microsoft Azure"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        101,
        249
      ],
      "content": "How to convert a training experiment to a predictive experiment, prepare it for deployment, then deploy it as an Azure Machine Learning web service."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        574,
        618
      ],
      "content": "Deploy an Azure Machine Learning web service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        620,
        713
      ],
      "content": "Azure Machine Learning enables you to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        715,
        776
      ],
      "content": "From a high-level point-of-view, this is done in three steps:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        780,
        993
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p2\">Create a training experiment]</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph2\"/> - Azure Machine Learning Studio is a collaborative visual development environment that you use to train and test a predictive analytics model using training data that you supply."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        996,
        1195
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p4\">Convert it to a predictive experiment]</ept><ept id=\"p3\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph3\"/> - Once your model has been trained with existing data and you're ready to use it to score new data, you prepare and streamline your experiment for scoring."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1198,
        1387
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p6\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p6\">Deploy it as a web service]</ept><ept id=\"p5\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph4\"/> - With just a click, you can deploy your scoring experiment as an Azure web service. Users can send data to your model and receive your model's predictions.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p6\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p6\">Deploy it as a web service]</ept><ept id=\"p5\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph4\"/> - With just a click, you can deploy your scoring experiment as an Azure web service.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            207
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Users can send data to your model and receive your model's predictions.",
          "pos": [
            208,
            279
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1483,
        1529
      ],
      "content": "Once you've deployed the web service, you can:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1533,
        1576
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p8\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p8\">Access]</ept><ept id=\"p7\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph6\"/> it through the web service API"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1579,
        1632
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p9\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p10\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p10\">Manage]</ept><ept id=\"p9\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph7\"/> it through the Azure Classic Portal, and"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1635,
        1672
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p11\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p12\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p12\">Update]</ept><ept id=\"p11\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph8\"/> it if your model changes"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2056,
        2084
      ],
      "content": "Create a training experiment"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2086,
        2459
      ],
      "content": "To train a predictive analytics model, you use Azure Machine Learning Studio to create a training experiment where you include various modules to load training data, prepare the data as necessary, apply machine learning algorithms, and evaluate the results. You can iterate on an experiment and try different machine learning algorithms to compare and evaluate the results.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "To train a predictive analytics model, you use Azure Machine Learning Studio to create a training experiment where you include various modules to load training data, prepare the data as necessary, apply machine learning algorithms, and evaluate the results.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            257
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can iterate on an experiment and try different machine learning algorithms to compare and evaluate the results.",
          "pos": [
            258,
            373
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2461,
        2611
      ],
      "content": "The process of creating and managing training experiments is covered more thoroughly elsewhere - see these articles for more information and examples:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2615,
        2715
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p13\">[</bpt>Create a simple experiment in Azure Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p13\">](machine-learning-create-experiment.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2718,
        2838
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p14\">[</bpt>Develop a predictive solution with Azure Machine Learning<ept id=\"p14\">](machine-learning-walkthrough-develop-predictive-solution.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2841,
        2949
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p15\">[</bpt>Import your training data into Azure Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p15\">](machine-learning-data-science-import-data.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2952,
        3065
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p16\">[</bpt>Manage experiment iterations in Azure Machine Learning Studio<ept id=\"p16\">](machine-learning-manage-experiment-iterations.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3070,
        3128
      ],
      "content": "Convert the training experiment to a predictive experiment"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3130,
        3283
      ],
      "content": "Once you've trained your model, you're ready to use it to score new data. To do this, you convert your training experiment into a predictive experiment.\n",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Once you've trained your model, you're ready to use it to score new data.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            73
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "To do this, you convert your training experiment into a predictive experiment.",
          "pos": [
            74,
            152
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "\n",
          "pos": [
            152,
            153
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3283,
        3642
      ],
      "content": "By converting to a predictive experiment, you're getting your trained model ready to be deployed as a scoring web service. Users of the web service will send input data to your model and your model will send back the prediction results. So as you convert to a predictive experiment you will want to keep in mind how you expect your model to be used by others.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "By converting to a predictive experiment, you're getting your trained model ready to be deployed as a scoring web service.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            122
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Users of the web service will send input data to your model and your model will send back the prediction results.",
          "pos": [
            123,
            236
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "So as you convert to a predictive experiment you will want to keep in mind how you expect your model to be used by others.",
          "pos": [
            237,
            359
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3644,
        3831
      ],
      "content": "To convert your training experiment to a predictive experiment, click <bpt id=\"p17\">**</bpt>Run<ept id=\"p17\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> at the bottom of the experiment canvas, click <bpt id=\"p18\">**</bpt>Set Up Web Service<ept id=\"p18\">**</ept>, then select <bpt id=\"p19\">**</bpt>Predictive Web Service<ept id=\"p19\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3833,
        3943
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph10\">![</ph>Convert to scoring experiment<ph id=\"ph11\">](./media/machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service/figure-1.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3945,
        4142
      ],
      "content": "For more details on how to do this conversion, see <bpt id=\"p20\">[</bpt>Convert a Machine Learning training experiment to a predictive experiment<ept id=\"p20\">](machine-learning-convert-training-experiment-to-scoring-experiment.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4148,
        4197
      ],
      "content": "Deploy the predictive experiment as a web service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4199,
        4408
      ],
      "content": "Now that the predictive experiment has been sufficiently prepared, you can deploy it as an Azure web service. Using the web service, users can send data to your model and the model will return its predictions.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Now that the predictive experiment has been sufficiently prepared, you can deploy it as an Azure web service.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            109
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Using the web service, users can send data to your model and the model will return its predictions.",
          "pos": [
            110,
            209
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4410,
        4614
      ],
      "content": "To deploy your predictive experiment, click <bpt id=\"p21\">**</bpt>Run<ept id=\"p21\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph12\"/> at the bottom of the experiment canvas and then click <bpt id=\"p22\">**</bpt>Deploy Web Service<ept id=\"p22\">**</ept>. The web service is set up and you are placed in the web service dashboard.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "To deploy your predictive experiment, click <bpt id=\"p21\">**</bpt>Run<ept id=\"p21\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph12\"/> at the bottom of the experiment canvas and then click <bpt id=\"p22\">**</bpt>Deploy Web Service<ept id=\"p22\">**</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            224
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The web service is set up and you are placed in the web service dashboard.",
          "pos": [
            225,
            299
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4616,
        4719
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph13\">![</ph>Deploy the web service<ph id=\"ph14\">](./media/machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service/figure-2.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4721,
        5051
      ],
      "content": "To test the web service, click the <bpt id=\"p23\">**</bpt>Test<ept id=\"p23\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph15\"/> link in the web service dashboard. A dialog pops up to ask you for the input data for the service. These are the columns expected by the scoring experiment. Enter a set of data and then click <bpt id=\"p24\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p24\">**</ept>. The results generated by the web service are displayed at the bottom of the dashboard.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "To test the web service, click the <bpt id=\"p23\">**</bpt>Test<ept id=\"p23\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph15\"/> link in the web service dashboard.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            133
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "A dialog pops up to ask you for the input data for the service.",
          "pos": [
            134,
            197
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "These are the columns expected by the scoring experiment.",
          "pos": [
            198,
            255
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Enter a set of data and then click <bpt id=\"p24\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p24\">**</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            256,
            338
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The results generated by the web service are displayed at the bottom of the dashboard.",
          "pos": [
            339,
            425
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5053,
        5154
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph16\">![</ph>Test the web service<ph id=\"ph17\">](./media/machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service/figure-3.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5156,
        5760
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p25\">**</bpt>CONFIGURATION<ept id=\"p25\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph18\"/> tab you can change the display name of the service and give it a description. The name and description is displayed in the Azure Classic Portal where you manage your web services.\nYou can provide a description for your input data, output data, and web service parameters by entering a string for each column under <bpt id=\"p26\">**</bpt>INPUT SCHEMA<ept id=\"p26\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p27\">**</bpt>OUTPUT SCHEMA<ept id=\"p27\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p28\">**</bpt>WEB SERVICE PARAMETER<ept id=\"p28\">**</ept>. These descriptions are used in the sample code documentation provided for the web service.\nYou can also enable logging to diagnose any failures that you're seeing when your web service is accessed.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p25\">**</bpt>CONFIGURATION<ept id=\"p25\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph18\"/> tab you can change the display name of the service and give it a description.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            157
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "The name and description is displayed in the Azure Classic Portal where you manage your web services.",
          "pos": [
            158,
            259
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can provide a description for your input data, output data, and web service parameters by entering a string for each column under <bpt id=\"p26\">**</bpt>INPUT SCHEMA<ept id=\"p26\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p27\">**</bpt>OUTPUT SCHEMA<ept id=\"p27\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p28\">**</bpt>WEB SERVICE PARAMETER<ept id=\"p28\">**</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            260,
            581
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "These descriptions are used in the sample code documentation provided for the web service.",
          "pos": [
            582,
            672
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can also enable logging to diagnose any failures that you're seeing when your web service is accessed.",
          "pos": [
            673,
            779
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5762,
        5881
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p29\">[</bpt>Enable logging for Machine Learning web services<ept id=\"p29\">](machine-learning-web-services-logging.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5883,
        5989
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph19\">![</ph>Configure the web service<ph id=\"ph20\">](./media/machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service/figure-4.png)</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5995,
        6017
      ],
      "content": "Access the web service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6019,
        6154
      ],
      "content": "Once you deploy your web service from Machine Learning Studio, you can send data to the service and receive responses programmatically."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6156,
        6390
      ],
      "content": "The dashboard provides all the information you need to access your web service. For example, the API key is provided to allow authorized access to the service, and API help pages are provided to help you get started writing your code.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The dashboard provides all the information you need to access your web service.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            79
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For example, the API key is provided to allow authorized access to the service, and API help pages are provided to help you get started writing your code.",
          "pos": [
            80,
            234
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6392,
        6570
      ],
      "content": "For more information about accessing a Machine Learning web service, see <bpt id=\"p30\">[</bpt>How to consume a deployed Azure Machine Learning web service<ept id=\"p30\">](machine-learning-consume-web-services.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6576,
        6626
      ],
      "content": "Manage the web service in the Azure Classic Portal"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6628,
        7042
      ],
      "content": "In the Azure Classic Portal, you can manage your web services by clicking the <bpt id=\"p31\">**</bpt>Machine Learning<ept id=\"p31\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph21\"/> service, opening your Machine Learning workspace, and then opening the web service from the <bpt id=\"p32\">**</bpt>WEB SERVICES<ept id=\"p32\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph22\"/> tab. From this page you can monitor the web service, update it, and delete it. You can also add a second endpoint for your web service in addition to the default endpoint that is created when you deploy it.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "In the Azure Classic Portal, you can manage your web services by clicking the <bpt id=\"p31\">**</bpt>Machine Learning<ept id=\"p31\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph21\"/> service, opening your Machine Learning workspace, and then opening the web service from the <bpt id=\"p32\">**</bpt>WEB SERVICES<ept id=\"p32\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph22\"/> tab.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            322
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "From this page you can monitor the web service, update it, and delete it.",
          "pos": [
            323,
            396
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can also add a second endpoint for your web service in addition to the default endpoint that is created when you deploy it.",
          "pos": [
            397,
            524
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7044,
        7153
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p33\">[</bpt>Manage an Azure Machine Learning workspace<ept id=\"p33\">](machine-learning-manage-workspace.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7386,
        7408
      ],
      "content": "Update the web service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7410,
        7568
      ],
      "content": "You can make changes to your web service, such as updating the model with additional training data, and deploy it again, overwriting the original web service."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7570,
        8041
      ],
      "content": "To update the web service, open the original predictive experiment you used to deploy the  web service and make an editable copy by clicking <bpt id=\"p34\">**</bpt>SAVE AS<ept id=\"p34\">**</ept>. Make your changes and then click <bpt id=\"p35\">**</bpt>Deploy Web Service<ept id=\"p35\">**</ept>. Because you've deployed this experiment before, Machine Learning Studio prompts you to ask if you want to overwrite the existing service. If you click <bpt id=\"p36\">**</bpt>YES<ept id=\"p36\">**</ept>, then the existing web service is stopped and the new predictive experiment is deployed in its place.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "To update the web service, open the original predictive experiment you used to deploy the  web service and make an editable copy by clicking <bpt id=\"p34\">**</bpt>SAVE AS<ept id=\"p34\">**</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            193
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Make your changes and then click <bpt id=\"p35\">**</bpt>Deploy Web Service<ept id=\"p35\">**</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            194,
            290
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Because you've deployed this experiment before, Machine Learning Studio prompts you to ask if you want to overwrite the existing service.",
          "pos": [
            291,
            428
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "If you click <bpt id=\"p36\">**</bpt>YES<ept id=\"p36\">**</ept>, then the existing web service is stopped and the new predictive experiment is deployed in its place.",
          "pos": [
            429,
            591
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8045,
        8220
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph24\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph25\"/> If you made configuration changes in the original web service, for example, entering a new display name or description, you will need to enter those values again."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8222,
        8435
      ],
      "content": "One option for updating your web service is to retrain the model programmatically. For more information, see <bpt id=\"p37\">[</bpt>Retrain Machine Learning models programmatically<ept id=\"p37\">](machine-learning-retrain-models-programmatically.md)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "One option for updating your web service is to retrain the model programmatically.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            82
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p37\">[</bpt>Retrain Machine Learning models programmatically<ept id=\"p37\">](machine-learning-retrain-models-programmatically.md)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            83,
            253
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Deploy a Machine Learning web service | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"How to convert a training experiment to a predictive experiment, prepare it for deployment, then deploy it as an Azure Machine Learning web service.\"\n    services=\"machine-learning\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"garyericson\"\n    manager=\"paulettm\"\n    editor=\"cgronlun\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\"\n    ms.workload=\"data-services\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"02/01/2016\"\n    ms.author=\"garye\"/>\n\n# Deploy an Azure Machine Learning web service\n\nAzure Machine Learning enables you to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions.\n\nFrom a high-level point-of-view, this is done in three steps:\n\n- **[Create a training experiment]** - Azure Machine Learning Studio is a collaborative visual development environment that you use to train and test a predictive analytics model using training data that you supply.\n- **[Convert it to a predictive experiment]** - Once your model has been trained with existing data and you're ready to use it to score new data, you prepare and streamline your experiment for scoring.\n- **[Deploy it as a web service]** - With just a click, you can deploy your scoring experiment as an Azure web service. Users can send data to your model and receive your model's predictions.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [machine-learning-free-trial](../../includes/machine-learning-free-trial.md)]\n\nOnce you've deployed the web service, you can:\n\n- **[Access]** it through the web service API\n- **[Manage]** it through the Azure Classic Portal, and\n- **[Update]** it if your model changes\n\n[Create a training experiment]: #create-a-training-experiment\n[Convert it to a predictive experiment]: #convert-the-training-experiment-to-a-predictive-experiment\n[Deploy it as a web service]: #deploy-the-predictive-experiment-as-a-web-service\n[Access]: #access-the-web-service\n[Manage]: #manage-the-web-service-in-the-azure-management-portal\n[Update]: #update-the-web-service\n\n\n## Create a training experiment\n\nTo train a predictive analytics model, you use Azure Machine Learning Studio to create a training experiment where you include various modules to load training data, prepare the data as necessary, apply machine learning algorithms, and evaluate the results. You can iterate on an experiment and try different machine learning algorithms to compare and evaluate the results.\n\nThe process of creating and managing training experiments is covered more thoroughly elsewhere - see these articles for more information and examples:\n\n- [Create a simple experiment in Azure Machine Learning Studio](machine-learning-create-experiment.md)\n- [Develop a predictive solution with Azure Machine Learning](machine-learning-walkthrough-develop-predictive-solution.md)\n- [Import your training data into Azure Machine Learning Studio](machine-learning-data-science-import-data.md)\n- [Manage experiment iterations in Azure Machine Learning Studio](machine-learning-manage-experiment-iterations.md)\n\n## Convert the training experiment to a predictive experiment\n\nOnce you've trained your model, you're ready to use it to score new data. To do this, you convert your training experiment into a predictive experiment.\nBy converting to a predictive experiment, you're getting your trained model ready to be deployed as a scoring web service. Users of the web service will send input data to your model and your model will send back the prediction results. So as you convert to a predictive experiment you will want to keep in mind how you expect your model to be used by others.\n\nTo convert your training experiment to a predictive experiment, click **Run** at the bottom of the experiment canvas, click **Set Up Web Service**, then select **Predictive Web Service**.\n\n![Convert to scoring experiment](./media/machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service/figure-1.png)\n\nFor more details on how to do this conversion, see [Convert a Machine Learning training experiment to a predictive experiment](machine-learning-convert-training-experiment-to-scoring-experiment.md)\n\n\n## Deploy the predictive experiment as a web service\n\nNow that the predictive experiment has been sufficiently prepared, you can deploy it as an Azure web service. Using the web service, users can send data to your model and the model will return its predictions.\n\nTo deploy your predictive experiment, click **Run** at the bottom of the experiment canvas and then click **Deploy Web Service**. The web service is set up and you are placed in the web service dashboard.\n\n![Deploy the web service](./media/machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service/figure-2.png)\n\nTo test the web service, click the **Test** link in the web service dashboard. A dialog pops up to ask you for the input data for the service. These are the columns expected by the scoring experiment. Enter a set of data and then click **OK**. The results generated by the web service are displayed at the bottom of the dashboard.\n\n![Test the web service](./media/machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service/figure-3.png)\n\nOn the **CONFIGURATION** tab you can change the display name of the service and give it a description. The name and description is displayed in the Azure Classic Portal where you manage your web services.\nYou can provide a description for your input data, output data, and web service parameters by entering a string for each column under **INPUT SCHEMA**, **OUTPUT SCHEMA**, and **WEB SERVICE PARAMETER**. These descriptions are used in the sample code documentation provided for the web service.\nYou can also enable logging to diagnose any failures that you're seeing when your web service is accessed.\n\nFor more information, see [Enable logging for Machine Learning web services](machine-learning-web-services-logging.md).\n\n![Configure the web service](./media/machine-learning-publish-a-machine-learning-web-service/figure-4.png)\n\n\n## Access the web service\n\nOnce you deploy your web service from Machine Learning Studio, you can send data to the service and receive responses programmatically.\n\nThe dashboard provides all the information you need to access your web service. For example, the API key is provided to allow authorized access to the service, and API help pages are provided to help you get started writing your code.\n\nFor more information about accessing a Machine Learning web service, see [How to consume a deployed Azure Machine Learning web service](machine-learning-consume-web-services.md).\n\n\n## Manage the web service in the Azure Classic Portal\n\nIn the Azure Classic Portal, you can manage your web services by clicking the **Machine Learning** service, opening your Machine Learning workspace, and then opening the web service from the **WEB SERVICES** tab. From this page you can monitor the web service, update it, and delete it. You can also add a second endpoint for your web service in addition to the default endpoint that is created when you deploy it.\n\nFor more information, see [Manage an Azure Machine Learning workspace](machine-learning-manage-workspace.md).\n<!-- When this article gets published, fix the link and uncomment\nFor more information on how to manage Azure Machine Learning web service endpoints using the REST API, see **Azure machine learning web service endpoints**.\n-->\n\n\n## Update the web service\n\nYou can make changes to your web service, such as updating the model with additional training data, and deploy it again, overwriting the original web service.\n\nTo update the web service, open the original predictive experiment you used to deploy the  web service and make an editable copy by clicking **SAVE AS**. Make your changes and then click **Deploy Web Service**. Because you've deployed this experiment before, Machine Learning Studio prompts you to ask if you want to overwrite the existing service. If you click **YES**, then the existing web service is stopped and the new predictive experiment is deployed in its place.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] If you made configuration changes in the original web service, for example, entering a new display name or description, you will need to enter those values again.\n\nOne option for updating your web service is to retrain the model programmatically. For more information, see [Retrain Machine Learning models programmatically](machine-learning-retrain-models-programmatically.md).\n"
}