{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        28,
        91
      ],
      "content": "Vehicle telemetry analytics solution playbook | Microsoft Azure"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        111,
        232
      ],
      "content": "Use the capabilities of Cortana Analytics to gain real-time and predictive insights on vehicle health and driving habits."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        570,
        615
      ],
      "content": "Vehicle telemetry analytics solution playbook"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        617,
        670
      ],
      "content": "This <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>menu<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph2\"/> links to the chapters in this playbook."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        794,
        802
      ],
      "content": "Overview"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        803,
        1273
      ],
      "content": "Super computers have moved out of the lab and are now parked in our garage! These cutting-edge automobiles contain a myriad of sensors, giving them the ability to track and monitor millions of events every second. We expect that by 2020, most of these cars will be connected to the internet. Imagine tapping into this wealth of data to provide best in class safety, reliability and driving experience. Microsoft has made this imagination a reality via Cortana Analytics.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Super computers have moved out of the lab and are now parked in our garage!",
          "pos": [
            0,
            75
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "These cutting-edge automobiles contain a myriad of sensors, giving them the ability to track and monitor millions of events every second.",
          "pos": [
            76,
            213
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "We expect that by 2020, most of these cars will be connected to the internet.",
          "pos": [
            214,
            291
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Imagine tapping into this wealth of data to provide best in class safety, reliability and driving experience.",
          "pos": [
            292,
            401
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Microsoft has made this imagination a reality via Cortana Analytics.",
          "pos": [
            402,
            470
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1275,
        1746
      ],
      "content": "Microsoft’s Cortana Analytics is a fully managed big data and advanced analytics suite that enables you to transform your data into intelligent action. We want to introduce you to the Cortana Analytics Vehicle Telemetry Analytics Solution Template. This solution demonstrates how car dealerships, automobile manufacturers and insurance companies can use the capabilities of Cortana Analytics to gain real-time and predictive insights on vehicle health and driving habits.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Microsoft’s Cortana Analytics is a fully managed big data and advanced analytics suite that enables you to transform your data into intelligent action.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            151
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "We want to introduce you to the Cortana Analytics Vehicle Telemetry Analytics Solution Template.",
          "pos": [
            152,
            248
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "This solution demonstrates how car dealerships, automobile manufacturers and insurance companies can use the capabilities of Cortana Analytics to gain real-time and predictive insights on vehicle health and driving habits.",
          "pos": [
            249,
            471
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1749,
        2658
      ],
      "content": "The solution is implemented as a <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>lambda architecture pattern<ept id=\"p2\">](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lambda_architecture)</ept><ph id=\"ph4\"/> showing the full potential of the Cortana Analytics platform for real-time and batch processing. It includes a Vehicle Telematics simulator, leverages Event Hubs for ingesting millions of simulated vehicle telemetry events into Azure, then uses Stream Analytics for gaining real-time insights on vehicle health and persists that data into long-term storage for richer batch analytics. It takes advantage of Machine Learning for anomaly detection in real-time and batch processing to gain predictive insights. HDInsight is leveraged to transform data at scale, and Data Factory handles orchestration, scheduling, resource management and monitoring of the batch processing pipeline. Finally, Power BI gives this solution a rich dashboard for real-time data and predictive analytics visualizations.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The solution is implemented as a <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>lambda architecture pattern<ept id=\"p2\">](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lambda_architecture)</ept><ph id=\"ph4\"/> showing the full potential of the Cortana Analytics platform for real-time and batch processing.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            262
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "It includes a Vehicle Telematics simulator, leverages Event Hubs for ingesting millions of simulated vehicle telemetry events into Azure, then uses Stream Analytics for gaining real-time insights on vehicle health and persists that data into long-term storage for richer batch analytics.",
          "pos": [
            263,
            550
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "It takes advantage of Machine Learning for anomaly detection in real-time and batch processing to gain predictive insights.",
          "pos": [
            551,
            674
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "HDInsight is leveraged to transform data at scale, and Data Factory handles orchestration, scheduling, resource management and monitoring of the batch processing pipeline.",
          "pos": [
            675,
            846
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Finally, Power BI gives this solution a rich dashboard for real-time data and predictive analytics visualizations.",
          "pos": [
            847,
            961
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2664,
        2676
      ],
      "content": "Architecture"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2678,
        2858
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph5\">![](./media/cortana-analytics-playbook-vehicle-telemetry/fig1-vehicle-telemetry-annalytics-solution-architecture.png)</ph><bpt id=\"p3\">\n*</bpt>Figure 1 – Vehicle Telemetry Analytics Solution Architecture<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2860,
        2972
      ],
      "content": "This solution includes the following <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Cortana Analytics components<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph6\"/> and showcases their end to end integration"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2977,
        3054
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Event Hubs<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph7\"/> for ingesting millions of vehicle telemetry events into Azure."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3057,
        3200
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Stream Analytics<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph8\"/> for gaining real-time insights on vehicle health and persists that data into long-term storage for richer batch analytics."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3203,
        3308
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>Machine Learning<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> for anomaly detection in real-time and batch processing to gain predictive insights."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3311,
        3364
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p8\">**</bpt>HDInsight<ept id=\"p8\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph10\"/> is leveraged to transform data at scale"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3367,
        3487
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p9\">**</bpt>Data Factory<ept id=\"p9\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph11\"/> handles orchestration, scheduling, resource management and monitoring of the batch processing pipeline."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3490,
        3599
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p10\">**</bpt>Power BI<ept id=\"p10\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph12\"/> gives this solution a rich dashboard for real-time data and predictive analytics visualizations."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3601,
        3655
      ],
      "content": "This solution accesses two different <bpt id=\"p11\">**</bpt>data sources<ept id=\"p11\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3660,
        3872
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p12\">**</bpt>Simulated vehicle signals and diagnostics<ept id=\"p12\">**</ept>: A vehicle telematics simulator emits diagnostic information and signals that correspond to the state of the vehicle and the driving pattern at a given point in time."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3876,
        3951
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p13\">**</bpt>Vehicle catalog<ept id=\"p13\">**</ept>: A reference dataset containing a VIN to model mapping."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Vehicle telemetry analytics solution playbook | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"Use the capabilities of Cortana Analytics to gain real-time and predictive insights on vehicle health and driving habits.\" \n    services=\"machine-learning\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"bradsev\" \n    manager=\"paulettm\" \n    editor=\"cgronlun\" />\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\" \n    ms.workload=\"data-services\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"12/02/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"bradsev\" />\n\n\n# Vehicle telemetry analytics solution playbook\n\nThis **menu** links to the chapters in this playbook. \n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [cap-vehicle-telemetry-playbook-selector](../../includes/cap-vehicle-telemetry-playbook-selector.md)]\n\n## Overview\nSuper computers have moved out of the lab and are now parked in our garage! These cutting-edge automobiles contain a myriad of sensors, giving them the ability to track and monitor millions of events every second. We expect that by 2020, most of these cars will be connected to the internet. Imagine tapping into this wealth of data to provide best in class safety, reliability and driving experience. Microsoft has made this imagination a reality via Cortana Analytics.\n\nMicrosoft’s Cortana Analytics is a fully managed big data and advanced analytics suite that enables you to transform your data into intelligent action. We want to introduce you to the Cortana Analytics Vehicle Telemetry Analytics Solution Template. This solution demonstrates how car dealerships, automobile manufacturers and insurance companies can use the capabilities of Cortana Analytics to gain real-time and predictive insights on vehicle health and driving habits. \n\nThe solution is implemented as a [lambda architecture pattern](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lambda_architecture) showing the full potential of the Cortana Analytics platform for real-time and batch processing. It includes a Vehicle Telematics simulator, leverages Event Hubs for ingesting millions of simulated vehicle telemetry events into Azure, then uses Stream Analytics for gaining real-time insights on vehicle health and persists that data into long-term storage for richer batch analytics. It takes advantage of Machine Learning for anomaly detection in real-time and batch processing to gain predictive insights. HDInsight is leveraged to transform data at scale, and Data Factory handles orchestration, scheduling, resource management and monitoring of the batch processing pipeline. Finally, Power BI gives this solution a rich dashboard for real-time data and predictive analytics visualizations. \n\n## Architecture\n\n![](./media/cortana-analytics-playbook-vehicle-telemetry/fig1-vehicle-telemetry-annalytics-solution-architecture.png)\n*Figure 1 – Vehicle Telemetry Analytics Solution Architecture*\n\nThis solution includes the following **Cortana Analytics components** and showcases their end to end integration\n\n\n- **Event Hubs** for ingesting millions of vehicle telemetry events into Azure.\n- **Stream Analytics** for gaining real-time insights on vehicle health and persists that data into long-term storage for richer batch analytics.\n- **Machine Learning** for anomaly detection in real-time and batch processing to gain predictive insights.\n- **HDInsight** is leveraged to transform data at scale\n- **Data Factory** handles orchestration, scheduling, resource management and monitoring of the batch processing pipeline.\n- **Power BI** gives this solution a rich dashboard for real-time data and predictive analytics visualizations.\n\nThis solution accesses two different **data sources**: \n\n- **Simulated vehicle signals and diagnostics**: A vehicle telematics simulator emits diagnostic information and signals that correspond to the state of the vehicle and the driving pattern at a given point in time. \n- **Vehicle catalog**: A reference dataset containing a VIN to model mapping.\n"
}