{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        26,
        114
      ],
      "content": "Monitor and manage HDInsight clusters using the Apache Ambari REST API | Microsoft Azure"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        132,
        307
      ],
      "content": "Learn how to use Ambari to monitor and manage Linux-based HDInsight clusters. In this document, you will learn how to use the Ambari REST API included with HDInsight clusters.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Learn how to use Ambari to monitor and manage Linux-based HDInsight clusters.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            77
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "In this document, you will learn how to use the Ambari REST API included with HDInsight clusters.",
          "pos": [
            78,
            175
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        624,
        678
      ],
      "content": "Manage HDInsight clusters by using the Ambari REST API"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        760,
        1240
      ],
      "content": "Apache Ambari simplifies the management and monitoring of a Hadoop cluster by providing an easy to use web UI and REST API. Ambari is included on Linux-based HDInsight clusters, and is used to monitor the cluster and make configuration changes. In this document, you will learn the basics of working with the Ambari REST API by performing common tasks such as finding the fully qualified domain name of the cluster nodes or finding the default storage account used by the cluster.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Apache Ambari simplifies the management and monitoring of a Hadoop cluster by providing an easy to use web UI and REST API.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            123
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Ambari is included on Linux-based HDInsight clusters, and is used to monitor the cluster and make configuration changes.",
          "pos": [
            124,
            244
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "In this document, you will learn the basics of working with the Ambari REST API by performing common tasks such as finding the fully qualified domain name of the cluster nodes or finding the default storage account used by the cluster.",
          "pos": [
            245,
            480
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1244,
        1566
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph3\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph4\"/> The information in this article applies only to Linux-based HDInsight clusters. For Windows-based HDInsight clusters, only a sub-set of monitoring functionality is available through the Ambari REST API. See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Monitor Windows-based Hadoop on HDInsight using the Ambari API<ept id=\"p1\">](hdinsight-monitor-use-ambari-api.md)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph3\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph4\"/> The information in this article applies only to Linux-based HDInsight clusters.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            124
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For Windows-based HDInsight clusters, only a sub-set of monitoring functionality is available through the Ambari REST API.",
          "pos": [
            125,
            247
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Monitor Windows-based Hadoop on HDInsight using the Ambari API<ept id=\"p1\">](hdinsight-monitor-use-ambari-api.md)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            248,
            392
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1570,
        1583
      ],
      "content": "Prerequisites"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1587,
        1782
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>cURL<ept id=\"p2\">](http://curl.haxx.se/)</ept>: cURL is a cross-platform utility that can be used to work with REST APIs from the command-line. In this document, it is used to communicate with the Ambari REST API.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>cURL<ept id=\"p2\">](http://curl.haxx.se/)</ept>: cURL is a cross-platform utility that can be used to work with REST APIs from the command-line.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            163
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "In this document, it is used to communicate with the Ambari REST API.",
          "pos": [
            164,
            233
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1785,
        1991
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>jq<ept id=\"p3\">](https://stedolan.github.io/jq/)</ept>: jq is a cross-platform command-line utility for working with JSON documents. In this document, it is used to parse the JSON documents returned from the Ambari REST API.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>jq<ept id=\"p3\">](https://stedolan.github.io/jq/)</ept>: jq is a cross-platform command-line utility for working with JSON documents.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            152
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "In this document, it is used to parse the JSON documents returned from the Ambari REST API.",
          "pos": [
            153,
            244
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1993,
        1995
      ],
      "content": "##"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2014,
        2029
      ],
      "content": "What is Ambari?"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2082,
        2095
      ],
      "content": "Apache Ambari"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2100,
        2315
      ],
      "content": "makes Hadoop management simpler by providing an easy-to-use web UI that can be used to provision, manage, and monitor Hadoop clusters. Developers can integrate these capabilities into their applications by using the",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "makes Hadoop management simpler by providing an easy-to-use web UI that can be used to provision, manage, and monitor Hadoop clusters.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            134
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Developers can integrate these capabilities into their applications by using the",
          "pos": [
            135,
            215
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2421,
        2437
      ],
      "content": "Ambari REST APIs"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2441,
        2442
      ],
      "content": "."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2444,
        2510
      ],
      "content": "Ambari is provided by default with Linux-based HDInsight clusters."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2514,
        2522
      ],
      "content": "REST API"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2524,
        2695
      ],
      "content": "The base URI for the Ambari REST API on HDInsight is https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME, where <bpt id=\"p4\">__</bpt>CLUSTERNAME<ept id=\"p4\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph5\"/> is the name of your cluster."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2700,
        2917
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph6\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph><ph id=\"ph7\"/> Connecting to Ambari on HDInsight requires HTTPS. You must also authenticate to Ambari using the admin account name (the default is <bpt id=\"p5\">__</bpt>admin<ept id=\"p5\">__</ept>,) and password you provided when the cluster was created.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph6\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph><ph id=\"ph7\"/> Connecting to Ambari on HDInsight requires HTTPS.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            99
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You must also authenticate to Ambari using the admin account name (the default is <bpt id=\"p5\">__</bpt>admin<ept id=\"p5\">__</ept>,) and password you provided when the cluster was created.",
          "pos": [
            100,
            287
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2919,
        3007
      ],
      "content": "The following is an example of using cURL to perform a GET request against the REST API:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3113,
        3325
      ],
      "content": "If you run this, replacing <bpt id=\"p6\">__</bpt>PASSWORD<ept id=\"p6\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph8\"/> with the admin password for your cluster, and <bpt id=\"p7\">__</bpt>CLUSTERNAME<ept id=\"p7\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph9\"/> with the cluster name, you will receive a JSON document that begins with information similar to the following:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3905,
        4152
      ],
      "content": "Since this is JSON, it is usually easier to use a JSON parser to retrieve data. For example, if you want to retrieve a count of alerts (contained in the <bpt id=\"p8\">__</bpt>\"Host/host_status/ALERT\"<ept id=\"p8\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph10\"/> element,) you can use the following to directly access the value:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Since this is JSON, it is usually easier to use a JSON parser to retrieve data.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            79
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For example, if you want to retrieve a count of alerts (contained in the <bpt id=\"p8\">__</bpt>\"Host/host_status/ALERT\"<ept id=\"p8\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph10\"/> element,) you can use the following to directly access the value:",
          "pos": [
            80,
            300
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4314,
        4503
      ],
      "content": "This retrieves the JSON document, then pipes the output to jq. <ph id=\"ph11\">`'.Clusters.health_report.\"Host/host_status/ALERT\"'`</ph><ph id=\"ph12\"/> indicates the element within the JSON document that you want to retrieve.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "This retrieves the JSON document, then pipes the output to jq.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            62
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph11\">`'.Clusters.health_report.\"Host/host_status/ALERT\"'`</ph><ph id=\"ph12\"/> indicates the element within the JSON document that you want to retrieve.",
          "pos": [
            63,
            223
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4507,
        4718
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph13\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph14\"/> The <bpt id=\"p9\">__</bpt>Host/host_status/ALERT<ept id=\"p9\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph15\"/> element is enclosed in quotes to indicate that '/' is part of the element name. For more information on using jq, see the <bpt id=\"p10\">[</bpt>jq website<ept id=\"p10\">](https://stedolan.github.io/jq/)</ept>.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph13\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph14\"/> The <bpt id=\"p9\">__</bpt>Host/host_status/ALERT<ept id=\"p9\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph15\"/> element is enclosed in quotes to indicate that '/' is part of the element name.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            210
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For more information on using jq, see the <bpt id=\"p10\">[</bpt>jq website<ept id=\"p10\">](https://stedolan.github.io/jq/)</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            211,
            338
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4722,
        4760
      ],
      "content": "Example: Get the FQDN of cluster nodes"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4762,
        4960
      ],
      "content": "When working with HDInsight, you may need to know the fully qualified domain name (FQDN) of a cluster node. You can easily retrieve the FQDN for the various nodes in the cluster using the following:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "When working with HDInsight, you may need to know the fully qualified domain name (FQDN) of a cluster node.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            107
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can easily retrieve the FQDN for the various nodes in the cluster using the following:",
          "pos": [
            108,
            198
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4964,
        5156
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p11\">__</bpt>Head nodes<ept id=\"p11\">__</ept>: <ph id=\"ph16\">`curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME/services/HDFS/components/NAMENODE\" | jq '.host_components[].HostRoles.host_name'`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5159,
        5353
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p12\">__</bpt>Worker nodes<ept id=\"p12\">__</ept>: <ph id=\"ph17\">`curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME/services/HDFS/components/DATANODE\" | jq '.host_components[].HostRoles.host_name'`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5356,
        5566
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p13\">__</bpt>Zookeeper nodes<ept id=\"p13\">__</ept>: <ph id=\"ph18\">`curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME/services/ZOOKEEPER/components/ZOOKEEPER_SERVER\" | jq '.host_components[].HostRoles.host_name'`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5568,
        5755
      ],
      "content": "Note that each of these follow the same pattern of querying a component that we know runs on those nodes, then retrieving the <ph id=\"ph19\">`host_name`</ph><ph id=\"ph20\"/> elements, which contain the FQDN for these nodes."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5757,
        6116
      ],
      "content": "The <ph id=\"ph21\">`host_components`</ph><ph id=\"ph22\"/> element of the return document contains multiple items. Using <ph id=\"ph23\">`.host_components[]`</ph>, and then specifying a path within the element will loop through each item and pull out the value from the specific path. If you only want one value, such as the first FQDN entry, you can return the items as a collection and then select a specific entry:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "The <ph id=\"ph21\">`host_components`</ph><ph id=\"ph22\"/> element of the return document contains multiple items.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            111
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Using <ph id=\"ph23\">`.host_components[]`</ph>, and then specifying a path within the element will loop through each item and pull out the value from the specific path.",
          "pos": [
            112,
            279
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "If you only want one value, such as the first FQDN entry, you can return the items as a collection and then select a specific entry:",
          "pos": [
            280,
            412
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6172,
        6224
      ],
      "content": "This will return the first FQDN from the collection."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6228,
        6282
      ],
      "content": "Example: Get the default storage account and container"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6284,
        6587
      ],
      "content": "When you create an HDInsight cluster, you must use an Azure Storage Account and a blob container as the default storage for the cluster. You can use Ambari to retrieve this information after the cluster has been created. For example, if you want to programmatically write data directly to the container.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "When you create an HDInsight cluster, you must use an Azure Storage Account and a blob container as the default storage for the cluster.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            136
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "You can use Ambari to retrieve this information after the cluster has been created.",
          "pos": [
            137,
            220
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For example, if you want to programmatically write data directly to the container.",
          "pos": [
            221,
            303
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6589,
        6662
      ],
      "content": "The following will retrieve the WASB URI of the clusters default storage:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6932,
        7228
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph24\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph25\"/> This will return the first configuration applied to the server (<ph id=\"ph26\">`service_config_version=1`</ph>,) which will contain this information. If you are retrieving a value that has been modified after cluster creation, you may need to list the configuration versions and retrieve the latest one.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph24\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph25\"/> This will return the first configuration applied to the server (<ph id=\"ph26\">`service_config_version=1`</ph>,) which will contain this information.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            195
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "If you are retrieving a value that has been modified after cluster creation, you may need to list the configuration versions and retrieve the latest one.",
          "pos": [
            196,
            349
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7230,
        7380
      ],
      "content": "This will return a value similar to the following, where <bpt id=\"p14\">__</bpt>CONTAINER<ept id=\"p14\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph27\"/> is the default container and <bpt id=\"p15\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTNAME<ept id=\"p15\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph28\"/> is the Azure Storage Account name:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7438,
        7577
      ],
      "content": "You can then use this information with the <bpt id=\"p16\">[</bpt>Azure CLI<ept id=\"p16\">](../xplat-cli-install.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph29\"/> to upload or download data from the container. For example:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "You can then use this information with the <bpt id=\"p16\">[</bpt>Azure CLI<ept id=\"p16\">](../xplat-cli-install.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph29\"/> to upload or download data from the container.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            181
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "For example:",
          "pos": [
            182,
            194
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7582,
        7706
      ],
      "content": "Get the resource group for the Storage Account. Replace <bpt id=\"p17\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTNAME<ept id=\"p17\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph30\"/> with the Storage Account name retrieved from Ambari:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Get the resource group for the Storage Account.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            47
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Replace <bpt id=\"p17\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTNAME<ept id=\"p17\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph30\"/> with the Storage Account name retrieved from Ambari:",
          "pos": [
            48,
            179
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7815,
        7872
      ],
      "content": "This will return the resource group name for the account."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7884,
        8102
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph31\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph32\"/> If nothing is returned from this command, you may need to change the Azure CLI to Azure Resource Manager mode and run the command again. To switch to Azure Resource Manager mode, use the following command.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph31\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph32\"/> If nothing is returned from this command, you may need to change the Azure CLI to Azure Resource Manager mode and run the command again.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            183
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "To switch to Azure Resource Manager mode, use the following command.",
          "pos": [
            184,
            252
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8147,
        8308
      ],
      "content": "Get the key for the Storage account. Replace <bpt id=\"p18\">__</bpt>GROUPNAME<ept id=\"p18\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph34\"/> with the Resource Group from the previous step. Replace <bpt id=\"p19\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTNAME<ept id=\"p19\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph35\"/> with the Storage Account name:",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Get the key for the Storage account.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            36
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Replace <bpt id=\"p18\">__</bpt>GROUPNAME<ept id=\"p18\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph34\"/> with the Resource Group from the previous step.",
          "pos": [
            37,
            161
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Replace <bpt id=\"p19\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTNAME<ept id=\"p19\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph35\"/> with the Storage Account name:",
          "pos": [
            162,
            271
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8419,
        8468
      ],
      "content": "This will return the primary key for the account."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8477,
        8533
      ],
      "content": "Use the upload command to store a file in the container:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8661,
        8879
      ],
      "content": "Replace <bpt id=\"p20\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTNAME<ept id=\"p20\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph36\"/> with the Storage Account name. Replace <bpt id=\"p21\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTKEY<ept id=\"p21\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph37\"/> with the key retrieved previously. <bpt id=\"p22\">__</bpt>FILEPATH<ept id=\"p22\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph38\"/> is the path to the file you want to upload, while <bpt id=\"p23\">__</bpt>BLOBPATH<ept id=\"p23\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph39\"/> is the path in the container.",
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Replace <bpt id=\"p20\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTNAME<ept id=\"p20\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph36\"/> with the Storage Account name.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            109
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Replace <bpt id=\"p21\">__</bpt>ACCOUNTKEY<ept id=\"p21\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph37\"/> with the key retrieved previously.",
          "pos": [
            110,
            222
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<bpt id=\"p22\">__</bpt>FILEPATH<ept id=\"p22\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph38\"/> is the path to the file you want to upload, while <bpt id=\"p23\">__</bpt>BLOBPATH<ept id=\"p23\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph39\"/> is the path in the container.",
          "pos": [
            223,
            438
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8885,
        9034
      ],
      "content": "For example, if you want the file to appear in HDInsight at wasb://example/data/filename.txt, then <bpt id=\"p24\">__</bpt>BLOBPATH<ept id=\"p24\">__</ept><ph id=\"ph40\"/> would be <ph id=\"ph41\">`example/data/filename.txt`</ph>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9038,
        9048
      ],
      "content": "Next steps"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9050,
        9202
      ],
      "content": "For a complete reference of the REST API, see <bpt id=\"p25\">[</bpt>Ambari API Reference V1<ept id=\"p25\">](https://github.com/apache/ambari/blob/trunk/ambari-server/docs/api/v1/index.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9206,
        9385
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph42\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph><ph id=\"ph43\"/> Some Ambari functionality is disabled, as it is managed by the HDInsight cloud service; for example, adding or removing hosts from the cluster or adding new services."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Monitor and manage HDInsight clusters using the Apache Ambari REST API | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Learn how to use Ambari to monitor and manage Linux-based HDInsight clusters. In this document, you will learn how to use the Ambari REST API included with HDInsight clusters.\"\n   services=\"hdinsight\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"Blackmist\"\n   manager=\"paulettm\"\n   editor=\"cgronlun\"\n    tags=\"azure-portal\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"hdinsight\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"big-data\"\n   ms.date=\"01/08/2016\"\n   ms.author=\"larryfr\"/>\n\n#Manage HDInsight clusters by using the Ambari REST API\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [ambari-selector](../../includes/hdinsight-ambari-selector.md)]\n\nApache Ambari simplifies the management and monitoring of a Hadoop cluster by providing an easy to use web UI and REST API. Ambari is included on Linux-based HDInsight clusters, and is used to monitor the cluster and make configuration changes. In this document, you will learn the basics of working with the Ambari REST API by performing common tasks such as finding the fully qualified domain name of the cluster nodes or finding the default storage account used by the cluster.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] The information in this article applies only to Linux-based HDInsight clusters. For Windows-based HDInsight clusters, only a sub-set of monitoring functionality is available through the Ambari REST API. See [Monitor Windows-based Hadoop on HDInsight using the Ambari API](hdinsight-monitor-use-ambari-api.md).\n\n##Prerequisites\n\n* [cURL](http://curl.haxx.se/): cURL is a cross-platform utility that can be used to work with REST APIs from the command-line. In this document, it is used to communicate with the Ambari REST API.\n* [jq](https://stedolan.github.io/jq/): jq is a cross-platform command-line utility for working with JSON documents. In this document, it is used to parse the JSON documents returned from the Ambari REST API.\n\n##<a id=\"whatis\"></a>What is Ambari?\n\n<a href=\"http://ambari.apache.org\" target=\"_blank\">Apache Ambari</a> makes Hadoop management simpler by providing an easy-to-use web UI that can be used to provision, manage, and monitor Hadoop clusters. Developers can integrate these capabilities into their applications by using the <a href=\"https://github.com/apache/ambari/blob/trunk/ambari-server/docs/api/v1/index.md\" target=\"_blank\">Ambari REST APIs</a>.\n\nAmbari is provided by default with Linux-based HDInsight clusters.\n\n##REST API\n\nThe base URI for the Ambari REST API on HDInsight is https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME, where __CLUSTERNAME__ is the name of your cluster. \n\n> [AZURE.IMPORTANT] Connecting to Ambari on HDInsight requires HTTPS. You must also authenticate to Ambari using the admin account name (the default is __admin__,) and password you provided when the cluster was created.\n\nThe following is an example of using cURL to perform a GET request against the REST API:\n\n    curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME\"\n    \nIf you run this, replacing __PASSWORD__ with the admin password for your cluster, and __CLUSTERNAME__ with the cluster name, you will receive a JSON document that begins with information similar to the following:\n\n    {\n    \"href\" : \"http://10.0.0.10:8080/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME\",\n    \"Clusters\" : {\n        \"cluster_id\" : 2,\n        \"cluster_name\" : \"CLUSTERNAME\",\n        \"health_report\" : {\n        \"Host/stale_config\" : 0,\n        \"Host/maintenance_state\" : 0,\n        \"Host/host_state/HEALTHY\" : 7,\n        \"Host/host_state/UNHEALTHY\" : 0,\n        \"Host/host_state/HEARTBEAT_LOST\" : 0,\n        \"Host/host_state/INIT\" : 0,\n        \"Host/host_status/HEALTHY\" : 7,\n        \"Host/host_status/UNHEALTHY\" : 0,\n        \"Host/host_status/UNKNOWN\" : 0,\n        \"Host/host_status/ALERT\" : 0\n\nSince this is JSON, it is usually easier to use a JSON parser to retrieve data. For example, if you want to retrieve a count of alerts (contained in the __\"Host/host_status/ALERT\"__ element,) you can use the following to directly access the value:\n\n    curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME\" | jq '.Clusters.health_report.\"Host/host_status/ALERT\"'\n    \nThis retrieves the JSON document, then pipes the output to jq. `'.Clusters.health_report.\"Host/host_status/ALERT\"'` indicates the element within the JSON document that you want to retrieve.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] The __Host/host_status/ALERT__ element is enclosed in quotes to indicate that '/' is part of the element name. For more information on using jq, see the [jq website](https://stedolan.github.io/jq/).\n\n##Example: Get the FQDN of cluster nodes\n\nWhen working with HDInsight, you may need to know the fully qualified domain name (FQDN) of a cluster node. You can easily retrieve the FQDN for the various nodes in the cluster using the following:\n\n* __Head nodes__: `curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME/services/HDFS/components/NAMENODE\" | jq '.host_components[].HostRoles.host_name'`\n* __Worker nodes__: `curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME/services/HDFS/components/DATANODE\" | jq '.host_components[].HostRoles.host_name'`\n* __Zookeeper nodes__: `curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME/services/ZOOKEEPER/components/ZOOKEEPER_SERVER\" | jq '.host_components[].HostRoles.host_name'`\n\nNote that each of these follow the same pattern of querying a component that we know runs on those nodes, then retrieving the `host_name` elements, which contain the FQDN for these nodes.\n\nThe `host_components` element of the return document contains multiple items. Using `.host_components[]`, and then specifying a path within the element will loop through each item and pull out the value from the specific path. If you only want one value, such as the first FQDN entry, you can return the items as a collection and then select a specific entry:\n\n    jq '[.host_components[].HostRoles.host_name][0]'\n\nThis will return the first FQDN from the collection.\n\n##Example: Get the default storage account and container\n\nWhen you create an HDInsight cluster, you must use an Azure Storage Account and a blob container as the default storage for the cluster. You can use Ambari to retrieve this information after the cluster has been created. For example, if you want to programmatically write data directly to the container.\n\nThe following will retrieve the WASB URI of the clusters default storage:\n\n    curl -u admin:PASSWORD -G \"https://CLUSTERNAME.azurehdinsight.net/api/v1/clusters/CLUSTERNAME/configurations/service_config_versions?service_name=HDFS&service_config_version=1\" | jq '.items[].configurations[].properties[\"fs.defaultFS\"] | select(. != null)'\n    \n> [AZURE.NOTE] This will return the first configuration applied to the server (`service_config_version=1`,) which will contain this information. If you are retrieving a value that has been modified after cluster creation, you may need to list the configuration versions and retrieve the latest one.\n\nThis will return a value similar to the following, where __CONTAINER__ is the default container and __ACCOUNTNAME__ is the Azure Storage Account name:\n\n    wasb://CONTAINER@ACCOUNTNAME.blob.core.windows.net\n\nYou can then use this information with the [Azure CLI](../xplat-cli-install.md) to upload or download data from the container. For example:\n\n1. Get the resource group for the Storage Account. Replace __ACCOUNTNAME__ with the Storage Account name retrieved from Ambari:\n\n        azure storage account list --json | jq '.[] | select(.name==\"ACCOUNTNAME\").resourceGroup'\n    \n    This will return the resource group name for the account.\n    \n    > [AZURE.NOTE] If nothing is returned from this command, you may need to change the Azure CLI to Azure Resource Manager mode and run the command again. To switch to Azure Resource Manager mode, use the following command.\n    >\n    > `azure config mode arm`\n    \n2. Get the key for the Storage account. Replace __GROUPNAME__ with the Resource Group from the previous step. Replace __ACCOUNTNAME__ with the Storage Account name:\n\n        azure storage account keys list -g GROUPNAME ACCOUNTNAME --json | jq '.storageAccountKeys.key1'\n\n    This will return the primary key for the account.\n    \n3. Use the upload command to store a file in the container:\n\n        azure storage blob upload -a ACCOUNTNAME -k ACCOUNTKEY -f FILEPATH --container __CONTAINER__ -b BLOBPATH\n        \n    Replace __ACCOUNTNAME__ with the Storage Account name. Replace __ACCOUNTKEY__ with the key retrieved previously. __FILEPATH__ is the path to the file you want to upload, while __BLOBPATH__ is the path in the container.\n\n    For example, if you want the file to appear in HDInsight at wasb://example/data/filename.txt, then __BLOBPATH__ would be `example/data/filename.txt`.\n\n##Next steps\n\nFor a complete reference of the REST API, see [Ambari API Reference V1](https://github.com/apache/ambari/blob/trunk/ambari-server/docs/api/v1/index.md).\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Some Ambari functionality is disabled, as it is managed by the HDInsight cloud service; for example, adding or removing hosts from the cluster or adding new services."
}