{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "1. How will customers be notified of the retiring SDK?",
      "pos": [
        2,
        56
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft will provide 12 month advance notification to the end of support of the retiring SDK in order to facilitate a smooth transition to a supported SDK.",
      "pos": [
        60,
        217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Further, customers will be notified through various communication channels – Azure Management Portal, Developer Center, blog post, and direct communication to assigned service administrators.",
      "pos": [
        218,
        409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2. Can customers author applications using a \"to-be\" retired DocumentDB SDK during the 12 month period?",
      "pos": [
        413,
        516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes, customers will have full access to author, deploy and modify applications using the \"to-be\" retired DocumentDB SDK during the 12 month grace period.",
      "pos": [
        521,
        674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During the 12 month grace period, customers are advised to migrate to a newer supported version of DocumentDB SDK as appropriate.",
      "pos": [
        675,
        804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3. Can customers author and modify applications using a retired DocumentDB SDK after the 12 month notification period?",
      "pos": [
        808,
        926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the 12 month notification period, the SDK will be retired.",
      "pos": [
        930,
        994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any access to DocumentDB by an applications using a retired SDK will not be permitted by the DocumentDB platform.",
      "pos": [
        995,
        1108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Further, Microsoft will not provide customer support on the retired SDK.",
      "pos": [
        1109,
        1181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4. What happens to Customer’s running applications that are using unsupported DocumentDB SDK version?",
      "pos": [
        1185,
        1286
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any attempts made to connect to the DocumentDB service with a retired SDK version will be rejected.",
      "pos": [
        1290,
        1389
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "5. Will new features and functionality be applied to all non-retired SDKs",
      "pos": [
        1394,
        1467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "New features and functionality will only be added to new versions.",
      "pos": [
        1471,
        1537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using an old, non-retired, version of the SDK your requests to DocumentDB will still function as previous but you will not have access to any new capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        1538,
        1708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "6. What should I do if I cannot update my application before a cut-off date",
      "pos": [
        1714,
        1789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend that you upgrade to the latest SDK as early as possible.",
      "pos": [
        1793,
        1862
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once an SDK has been tagged for retirement you will have 12 months to update your application.",
      "pos": [
        1863,
        1957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If, for whatever reason, you cannot complete your application update within this timeframe then please contact the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>DocumentDB Team<ept id=\"p1\">](mailto:askdocdb@microsoft.com)</ept> and request their assistance before the cutoff date.",
      "pos": [
        1958,
        2174
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "**1. How will customers be notified of the retiring SDK?**\n\nMicrosoft will provide 12 month advance notification to the end of support of the retiring SDK in order to facilitate a smooth transition to a supported SDK. Further, customers will be notified through various communication channels – Azure Management Portal, Developer Center, blog post, and direct communication to assigned service administrators.\n\n**2. Can customers author applications using a \"to-be\" retired DocumentDB SDK during the 12 month period?** \n\nYes, customers will have full access to author, deploy and modify applications using the \"to-be\" retired DocumentDB SDK during the 12 month grace period. During the 12 month grace period, customers are advised to migrate to a newer supported version of DocumentDB SDK as appropriate.\n\n**3. Can customers author and modify applications using a retired DocumentDB SDK after the 12 month notification period?**\n\nAfter the 12 month notification period, the SDK will be retired. Any access to DocumentDB by an applications using a retired SDK will not be permitted by the DocumentDB platform. Further, Microsoft will not provide customer support on the retired SDK.\n\n**4. What happens to Customer’s running applications that are using unsupported DocumentDB SDK version?**\n\nAny attempts made to connect to the DocumentDB service with a retired SDK version will be rejected. \n\n**5. Will new features and functionality be applied to all non-retired SDKs**\n\nNew features and functionality will only be added to new versions. If you are using an old, non-retired, version of the SDK your requests to DocumentDB will still function as previous but you will not have access to any new capabilities.  \n\n**6. What should I do if I cannot update my application before a cut-off date**\n\nWe recommend that you upgrade to the latest SDK as early as possible. Once an SDK has been tagged for retirement you will have 12 months to update your application. If, for whatever reason, you cannot complete your application update within this timeframe then please contact the [DocumentDB Team](mailto:askdocdb@microsoft.com) and request their assistance before the cutoff date.\n"
}