{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Azure PowerShell is currently available in two releases - 1.0 and 0.9.8.",
      "pos": [
        2,
        87
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have existing scripts and do not want to change them right now, you can continue using the 0.9.8 release.",
      "pos": [
        88,
        200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using the 1.0 release, you should carefully test your scripts in pre-production environments before using them in production to avoid unexpected impacts.",
      "pos": [
        201,
        359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1.0 cmdlets follow the naming pattern {verb}-AzureRm{noun}; whereas, the 0.9.8 names do not include <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Rm<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (for example, New-AzureRmResourceGroup instead of New-AzureResourceGroup).",
      "pos": [
        364,
        545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using Azure PowerShell 0.9.8, you must first enable the Resource Manager mode by running the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command.",
      "pos": [
        546,
        694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command is not necessary in 1.0.",
      "pos": [
        695,
        732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "New features will be added to only the 1.0 release.",
      "pos": [
        737,
        788
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information about the 1.0 release, including how to install and uninstall the release, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure PowerShell 1.0<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/azps-1-0/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        789,
        951
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "> [AZURE.NOTE] Azure PowerShell is currently available in two releases - 1.0 and 0.9.8. If you have existing scripts and do not want to change them right now, you can continue using the 0.9.8 release. When using the 1.0 release, you should carefully test your scripts in pre-production environments before using them in production to avoid unexpected impacts.\n>\n> 1.0 cmdlets follow the naming pattern {verb}-AzureRm{noun}; whereas, the 0.9.8 names do not include **Rm** (for example, New-AzureRmResourceGroup instead of New-AzureResourceGroup). When using Azure PowerShell 0.9.8, you must first enable the Resource Manager mode by running the **Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager** command. This command is not necessary in 1.0.\n>\n> New features will be added to only the 1.0 release. For information about the 1.0 release, including how to install and uninstall the release, see [Azure PowerShell 1.0](https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/azps-1-0/).\n\n\n"
}