{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "How Azure App Service Works",
      "pos": [
        28,
        55
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how App Service work",
      "pos": [
        75,
        101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How App Service Works",
      "pos": [
        509,
        530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure App Service is a cloud services designed to solve the practical problems facing engineers today.",
      "pos": [
        532,
        634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service is focused on providing superior developer productivity without compromising on the need to deliver applications at cloud scale.",
      "pos": [
        636,
        776
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service also provides the set of features and frameworks necessary to compose enterprise Line-of-Business applications while meeting developers where they are with support for most popular development languages (.NET, Java, PHP, Node.JS and Python).",
      "pos": [
        778,
        1031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With App Service developers can:",
      "pos": [
        1032,
        1064
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Build truly scalable Web Apps",
      "pos": [
        1068,
        1097
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Quickly build Mobile App back-ends with a set of easy to use mobile capabilities such as data back-ends, user authentication and push notifications with Mobile Apps.",
      "pos": [
        1100,
        1265
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Implement, deploy and publish APIs with API Apps.",
      "pos": [
        1269,
        1318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tie business applications together in workflows and transform data with Logic Apps.",
      "pos": [
        1321,
        1404
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All App types rely on the scalable and flexible Web App platform which allows developers an optimized full lifecycle experience from App design to App maintenance.",
      "pos": [
        1406,
        1569
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The lifecycle capabilities allow developers to:",
      "pos": [
        1570,
        1617
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Quick App Creation - start from scratch or pick an OSS package from the Azure Marketplace.",
      "pos": [
        1621,
        1711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Continuous Deployment - automatically deploy new code from popular source control solutions such as TFS, GitHub and BitBucket and sync content from online storage services such as OneDrive and DropBox.",
      "pos": [
        1715,
        1916
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test in Production - smoothly create pre-production environments and manage the portion of traffic going to them.",
      "pos": [
        1919,
        2032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Debug in the cloud when needed and roll back if issues are found.",
      "pos": [
        2033,
        2098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run asynchronous tasks and batch jobs - execute code in a background process or activate your code based on events (such as messages landing in an Azure Storage Queue) and scheduled times (CRON).",
      "pos": [
        2101,
        2296
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scale the app - use one of many options to scale your service horizontally and vertically automatically based on traffic and resource utilization.",
      "pos": [
        2299,
        2445
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure private environments dedicated to your Apps",
      "pos": [
        2446,
        2499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Maintain the app - leverage many of the debugging and diagnostics features to stay ahead of problems and to efficiently resolve them either in real time (with features such as auto-healing and live debugging) or after the fact by analyzing logs and memory dumps",
      "pos": [
        2505,
        2766
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Put together, the App Service capabilities allow developers to focus on their code and reach a stable, highly scalable production state quickly.",
      "pos": [
        2769,
        2913
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With the API and Logic App features, developers can build real-world enterprise applications bridging barriers between business solutions as well as on premise to cloud integration.",
      "pos": [
        2914,
        3095
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"How Azure App Service Works\" \n    description=\"Learn how App Service work\" \n    keywords=\"app service, azure app service, scale, scalable, app service plan, app service cost\"\n    services=\"app-service\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"yochay\" \n    manager=\"wpickett\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"app-service\" \n    ms.workload=\"na\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"hero-article\" \n    ms.date=\"02/10/2016\" \n    ms.author=\"yochay\"/>\n\n# How App Service Works\n\nAzure App Service is a cloud services designed to solve the practical problems facing engineers today. \nApp Service is focused on providing superior developer productivity without compromising on the need to deliver applications at cloud scale. \nApp Service also provides the set of features and frameworks necessary to compose enterprise Line-of-Business applications while meeting developers where they are with support for most popular development languages (.NET, Java, PHP, Node.JS and Python).\nWith App Service developers can:\n\n* Build truly scalable Web Apps\n* Quickly build Mobile App back-ends with a set of easy to use mobile capabilities such as data back-ends, user authentication and push notifications with Mobile Apps. \n* Implement, deploy and publish APIs with API Apps.\n* Tie business applications together in workflows and transform data with Logic Apps.\n\nAll App types rely on the scalable and flexible Web App platform which allows developers an optimized full lifecycle experience from App design to App maintenance. The lifecycle capabilities allow developers to:\n\n* Quick App Creation - start from scratch or pick an OSS package from the Azure Marketplace. \n* Continuous Deployment - automatically deploy new code from popular source control solutions such as TFS, GitHub and BitBucket and sync content from online storage services such as OneDrive and DropBox.\n* Test in Production - smoothly create pre-production environments and manage the portion of traffic going to them. Debug in the cloud when needed and roll back if issues are found.\n* Run asynchronous tasks and batch jobs - execute code in a background process or activate your code based on events (such as messages landing in an Azure Storage Queue) and scheduled times (CRON).\n* Scale the app - use one of many options to scale your service horizontally and vertically automatically based on traffic and resource utilization. Configure private environments dedicated to your Apps   \n* Maintain the app - leverage many of the debugging and diagnostics features to stay ahead of problems and to efficiently resolve them either in real time (with features such as auto-healing and live debugging) or after the fact by analyzing logs and memory dumps\n \nPut together, the App Service capabilities allow developers to focus on their code and reach a stable, highly scalable production state quickly. With the API and Logic App features, developers can build real-world enterprise applications bridging barriers between business solutions as well as on premise to cloud integration.  \n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [app-service-blueprint-how-app-service-works](../../includes/app-service-blueprint-how-app-service-works.md)]\n"
}