{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect sync: Understanding Declarative Provisioning Expressions | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Explains the declarative provisioning expressions.",
      "pos": [
        137,
        187
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect sync: Understanding Declarative Provisioning Expressions",
      "pos": [
        509,
        582
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect sync builds on declarative provisioning first introduced in Forefront Identity Manager 2010 to allow you to implement your complete identity integration business logic without the need to write compiled code.",
      "pos": [
        584,
        809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An essential part of declarative provisioning is the expression language used in attribute flows.",
      "pos": [
        811,
        908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The language used is a subset of Microsoft® Visual Basic® for Applications (VBA).",
      "pos": [
        909,
        990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This language is used in Microsoft Office and users with experience of VBScript will also recognize it.",
      "pos": [
        991,
        1094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Declarative Provisioning Expression Language is only using functions and is not a structured language; there are no methods or statements.",
      "pos": [
        1095,
        1237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Functions will instead be nested to express program flow.",
      "pos": [
        1238,
        1295
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1297,
        1451
      ],
      "content": "For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Welcome to the Visual Basic for Applications language reference for Office 2013<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/gg264383.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "The attributes are strongly typed.",
      "pos": [
        1453,
        1487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A function which expects a single-value string attribute will not accept multi-valued or attributes of a different type.",
      "pos": [
        1488,
        1608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is also case sensitive.",
      "pos": [
        1609,
        1635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both function names and attribute names must have proper casing or an error will be thrown",
      "pos": [
        1636,
        1726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Language definitions and Identifiers",
      "pos": [
        1731,
        1767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Functions have a name followed by arguments in brackets: FunctionName(argument 1,argument N).",
      "pos": [
        1771,
        1864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Attributes are identified by square brackets: [attributeName]",
      "pos": [
        1867,
        1928
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Parameters are identified by percent signs: %ParameterName%",
      "pos": [
        1931,
        1990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "String constants are surrounded by quotes: E.g.",
      "pos": [
        1993,
        2040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"Contoso\" (Note: must use straight quotes \"\" and not smart quotes  “”)",
      "pos": [
        2041,
        2111
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Numeric values are expressed without quotes and expected to be decimal.",
      "pos": [
        2114,
        2185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hexadecimal values are prefixed with &amp;H.",
      "pos": [
        2186,
        2226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "E.g.",
      "pos": [
        2227,
        2231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "98052, &amp;HFF",
      "pos": [
        2232,
        2243
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Boolean values are expressed with constants: True, False.",
      "pos": [
        2246,
        2303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Built-in constants are expressed with only their name: NULL, CRLF, IgnoreThisFlow",
      "pos": [
        2306,
        2387
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Functions",
      "pos": [
        2393,
        2402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Declarative provisioning use many functions to enable the possibility to transform attribute values.",
      "pos": [
        2403,
        2503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These can be nested so the result from one function is passed in to another function.",
      "pos": [
        2504,
        2589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Functions can also operate over a multi-valued attribute.",
      "pos": [
        2591,
        2648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case the function will operate over every individual value and apply the same function to every value.",
      "pos": [
        2649,
        2759
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example <ph id=\"ph1\">`Trim([proxyAddresses])`</ph> would do a Trim of every value in the proxyAddress attribute.",
      "pos": [
        2760,
        2858
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2860,
        2988
      ],
      "content": "The complete list of functions can be found in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>function reference<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-functions-reference.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Parameters",
      "pos": [
        2994,
        3004
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A parameter is defined either by a Connector or by an administrator using PowerShell to set these.",
      "pos": [
        3006,
        3104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Parameters will usually contain values which will be different from system to system, e.g. the name of the domain the user is located in.",
      "pos": [
        3105,
        3242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These can be used in attribute flows.",
      "pos": [
        3243,
        3280
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Active Directory Connector provided the following parameters for inbound Synchronization Rules:",
      "pos": [
        3282,
        3381
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Parameter Name",
      "pos": [
        3385,
        3399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Comment",
      "pos": [
        3402,
        3409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Domain.Netbios",
      "pos": [
        3428,
        3442
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Netbios format of the domain currently being imported, e.g. FABRIKAMSALES",
      "pos": [
        3445,
        3518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Domain.FQDN",
      "pos": [
        3523,
        3534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "FQDN format of the domain currently being imported, e.g. sales.fabrikam.com",
      "pos": [
        3537,
        3612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Domain.LDAP",
      "pos": [
        3617,
        3628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "LDAP format of the domain currently being imported, e.g. DC=sales,DC=fabrikam,DC=com",
      "pos": [
        3631,
        3715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Forest.Netbios",
      "pos": [
        3720,
        3734
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Netbios format of the forest name currently being imported, e.g. FABRIKAMCORP",
      "pos": [
        3737,
        3814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Forest.FQDN",
      "pos": [
        3819,
        3830
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "FQDN format of the forest name currently being imported, e.g. fabrikam.com",
      "pos": [
        3833,
        3907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Forest.LDAP",
      "pos": [
        3912,
        3923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "LDAP format of the forest name currently being imported, e.g. DC=fabrikam,DC=com",
      "pos": [
        3926,
        4006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The system provides the following parameter, which is used to get the identifier of the Connector currently running:",
      "pos": [
        4010,
        4126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An example which will populate the metaverse attribute domain with the netbios name of the domain where the user is located:",
      "pos": [
        4144,
        4268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operators",
      "pos": [
        4304,
        4313
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following operators can be used:",
      "pos": [
        4315,
        4351
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4355,
        4390
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Comparison<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: &lt;, &lt;=, &lt;&gt;, =, &gt;, &gt;="
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4393,
        4420
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Mathematics<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: +, -, *, -"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4423,
        4450
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>String<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: &amp; (concatenate)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4453,
        4483
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Logical<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: &amp;&amp; (and), || (or)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4486,
        4511
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Evaluation order<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: ( )"
    },
    {
      "content": "Operators are evaluated left to right and have the same evaluation priority.",
      "pos": [
        4513,
        4589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I.e.",
      "pos": [
        4590,
        4594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "the \\* (multiplier) is not evaluated before - (subtraction).",
      "pos": [
        4595,
        4655
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2\\*(5+3) is not the same as 2\\*5+3.",
      "pos": [
        4656,
        4691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The brackets ( ) are used to change the evaluation order when a left to right evaluation order isn't appropriate.",
      "pos": [
        4692,
        4805
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Common scenarios",
      "pos": [
        4810,
        4826
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Length of attributes",
      "pos": [
        4832,
        4852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "String attributes are by default set to be indexable and the maximum length is 448 characters.",
      "pos": [
        4854,
        4948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are working with string attributes which might contain more, then make sure to include the following in the attribute flow:",
      "pos": [
        4949,
        5079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Changing the userPrincipalSuffix",
      "pos": [
        5131,
        5163
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The userPrincipalName attribute in Active Directory is not always known by the users and might not be suitable as the login ID.",
      "pos": [
        5165,
        5292
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure AD Connect sync installation wizard allows picking a different attribute, e.g. mail.",
      "pos": [
        5293,
        5387
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "But in some cases the attribute must be calculated.",
      "pos": [
        5388,
        5439
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example the company Contoso has two Azure AD directories, one for production and one for testing.",
      "pos": [
        5440,
        5541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They want the users in their test tenant to just change the suffix in the login ID.",
      "pos": [
        5542,
        5625
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this expression we take everything left of the first @-sign (Word) and concatenate with a fixed string.",
      "pos": [
        5704,
        5810
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Convert a multi-value to a single-value",
      "pos": [
        5816,
        5855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some attributes in Active Directory are multi-valued in the schema even though they look single valued in Active Directory Users and Computers.",
      "pos": [
        5857,
        6000
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An example is the description attribute.",
      "pos": [
        6001,
        6041
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this expression in case the attribute has a value, we take the first item (Item) in the attribute, remove leading and trailing spaces (Trim), and then keep the first 448 characters (Left) in the string.",
      "pos": [
        6138,
        6343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Advanced concept",
      "pos": [
        6348,
        6364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "NULL vs IgnoreThisFlow",
      "pos": [
        6370,
        6392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For inbound Synchronization Rules, the constant <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>NULL<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> should always be used.",
      "pos": [
        6394,
        6473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This indicates that the flow has no value to contribute and another rule can contribute a value.",
      "pos": [
        6474,
        6570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If no rule contributed a value, then the metaverse attribute is removed.",
      "pos": [
        6571,
        6643
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For outbound Synchronization Rules there are two different constants to use: NULL and IgnoreThisFlow.",
      "pos": [
        6645,
        6746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both indicates that the attribute flow has nothing to contribute, but the difference is what happens when no other rule has anything to contribute either.",
      "pos": [
        6747,
        6901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If there is an existing value in the connected directory, a NULL will stage a delete on the attribute removing it while IgnoreThisFlow will keep the existing value.",
      "pos": [
        6902,
        7066
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ImportedValue",
      "pos": [
        7073,
        7086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The function ImportedValues is different than all other functions since the attribute name must be enclosed in quotes rather than square brackets: ImportedValue(“proxyAddresses”).",
      "pos": [
        7088,
        7267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Usually during synchronization an attribute will use the expected value, even if it hasn’t been exported yet or an error was received during export (“top of the tower”).",
      "pos": [
        7269,
        7438
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An inbound synchronization will assume that an attribute which hasn’t yet reached a connected directory will eventually reach it.",
      "pos": [
        7439,
        7568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In some cases it is important to only synchronize a value which has been confirmed by the connected directory and in this case the function ImportedValue is used (“hologram and delta import tower”).",
      "pos": [
        7569,
        7767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An example of this can be found in the out-of-box Synchronization Rule In from AD – User Common from Exchange where in Hybrid Exchange the value added by Exchange online should only be synchronized if it has been confirmed the value was exported successfully:",
      "pos": [
        7769,
        8028
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8108,
        8246
      ],
      "content": "For a complete list of functions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure AD Connect sync: Functions Reference<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnectsync-functions-reference.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional Resources",
      "pos": [
        8252,
        8272
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Sync: Customizing Synchronization options",
      "pos": [
        8277,
        8335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        8383,
        8450
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Azure AD Connect sync: Understanding Declarative Provisioning Expressions | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Explains the declarative provisioning expressions.\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"markusvi\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"11/10/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"markusvi;andkjell\"/>\n\n\n# Azure AD Connect sync: Understanding Declarative Provisioning Expressions\n\nAzure AD Connect sync builds on declarative provisioning first introduced in Forefront Identity Manager 2010 to allow you to implement your complete identity integration business logic without the need to write compiled code.\n\nAn essential part of declarative provisioning is the expression language used in attribute flows. The language used is a subset of Microsoft® Visual Basic® for Applications (VBA). This language is used in Microsoft Office and users with experience of VBScript will also recognize it. The Declarative Provisioning Expression Language is only using functions and is not a structured language; there are no methods or statements. Functions will instead be nested to express program flow.\n\nFor more details, see [Welcome to the Visual Basic for Applications language reference for Office 2013](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/gg264383.aspx).\n\nThe attributes are strongly typed. A function which expects a single-value string attribute will not accept multi-valued or attributes of a different type. It is also case sensitive. Both function names and attribute names must have proper casing or an error will be thrown\n\n## Language definitions and Identifiers\n\n- Functions have a name followed by arguments in brackets: FunctionName(argument 1,argument N).\n- Attributes are identified by square brackets: [attributeName]\n- Parameters are identified by percent signs: %ParameterName%\n- String constants are surrounded by quotes: E.g. \"Contoso\" (Note: must use straight quotes \"\" and not smart quotes  “”)\n- Numeric values are expressed without quotes and expected to be decimal. Hexadecimal values are prefixed with &H. E.g. 98052, &HFF\n- Boolean values are expressed with constants: True, False.\n- Built-in constants are expressed with only their name: NULL, CRLF, IgnoreThisFlow\n\n### Functions\nDeclarative provisioning use many functions to enable the possibility to transform attribute values. These can be nested so the result from one function is passed in to another function.\n\nFunctions can also operate over a multi-valued attribute. In this case the function will operate over every individual value and apply the same function to every value. For example `Trim([proxyAddresses])` would do a Trim of every value in the proxyAddress attribute.\n\nThe complete list of functions can be found in the [function reference](active-directory-aadconnectsync-functions-reference.md).\n\n### Parameters\n\nA parameter is defined either by a Connector or by an administrator using PowerShell to set these. Parameters will usually contain values which will be different from system to system, e.g. the name of the domain the user is located in. These can be used in attribute flows.\n\nThe Active Directory Connector provided the following parameters for inbound Synchronization Rules:\n\n| Parameter Name | Comment |\n| --- | --- |\n| Domain.Netbios | Netbios format of the domain currently being imported, e.g. FABRIKAMSALES |\n| Domain.FQDN | FQDN format of the domain currently being imported, e.g. sales.fabrikam.com |\n| Domain.LDAP | LDAP format of the domain currently being imported, e.g. DC=sales,DC=fabrikam,DC=com |\n| Forest.Netbios | Netbios format of the forest name currently being imported, e.g. FABRIKAMCORP |\n| Forest.FQDN | FQDN format of the forest name currently being imported, e.g. fabrikam.com |\n| Forest.LDAP | LDAP format of the forest name currently being imported, e.g. DC=fabrikam,DC=com |\n\nThe system provides the following parameter, which is used to get the identifier of the Connector currently running:\n\n`Connector.ID`\n\nAn example which will populate the metaverse attribute domain with the netbios name of the domain where the user is located:\n\n`domain <- %Domain.Netbios%`\n\n### Operators\n\nThe following operators can be used:\n\n- **Comparison**: <, <=, <>, =, >, >=\n- **Mathematics**: +, -, *, -\n- **String**: & (concatenate)\n- **Logical**: && (and), || (or)\n- **Evaluation order**: ( )\n\nOperators are evaluated left to right and have the same evaluation priority. I.e. the \\* (multiplier) is not evaluated before - (subtraction). 2\\*(5+3) is not the same as 2\\*5+3. The brackets ( ) are used to change the evaluation order when a left to right evaluation order isn't appropriate.\n\n## Common scenarios\n\n### Length of attributes\n\nString attributes are by default set to be indexable and the maximum length is 448 characters. If you are working with string attributes which might contain more, then make sure to include the following in the attribute flow:\n\n`attributeName <- Left([attributeName],448)`\n\n### Changing the userPrincipalSuffix\n\nThe userPrincipalName attribute in Active Directory is not always known by the users and might not be suitable as the login ID. The Azure AD Connect sync installation wizard allows picking a different attribute, e.g. mail. But in some cases the attribute must be calculated. For example the company Contoso has two Azure AD directories, one for production and one for testing. They want the users in their test tenant to just change the suffix in the login ID.\n\n`userPrincipalName <- Word([userPrincipalName],1,\"@\") & \"@contosotest.com\"`\n\nIn this expression we take everything left of the first @-sign (Word) and concatenate with a fixed string.\n\n### Convert a multi-value to a single-value\n\nSome attributes in Active Directory are multi-valued in the schema even though they look single valued in Active Directory Users and Computers. An example is the description attribute.\n\n`description <- IIF(IsNullOrEmpty([description]),NULL,Left(Trim(Item([description],1)),448))`\n\nIn this expression in case the attribute has a value, we take the first item (Item) in the attribute, remove leading and trailing spaces (Trim), and then keep the first 448 characters (Left) in the string.\n\n## Advanced concept\n\n### NULL vs IgnoreThisFlow\n\nFor inbound Synchronization Rules, the constant **NULL** should always be used. This indicates that the flow has no value to contribute and another rule can contribute a value. If no rule contributed a value, then the metaverse attribute is removed.\n\nFor outbound Synchronization Rules there are two different constants to use: NULL and IgnoreThisFlow. Both indicates that the attribute flow has nothing to contribute, but the difference is what happens when no other rule has anything to contribute either. If there is an existing value in the connected directory, a NULL will stage a delete on the attribute removing it while IgnoreThisFlow will keep the existing value.\n\n#### ImportedValue\n\nThe function ImportedValues is different than all other functions since the attribute name must be enclosed in quotes rather than square brackets: ImportedValue(“proxyAddresses”).\n\nUsually during synchronization an attribute will use the expected value, even if it hasn’t been exported yet or an error was received during export (“top of the tower”). An inbound synchronization will assume that an attribute which hasn’t yet reached a connected directory will eventually reach it. In some cases it is important to only synchronize a value which has been confirmed by the connected directory and in this case the function ImportedValue is used (“hologram and delta import tower”).\n\nAn example of this can be found in the out-of-box Synchronization Rule In from AD – User Common from Exchange where in Hybrid Exchange the value added by Exchange online should only be synchronized if it has been confirmed the value was exported successfully:\n\n`proxyAddresses <- RemoveDuplicates(Trim(ImportedValues(\"proxyAddresses\")))`\n\nFor a complete list of functions, see [Azure AD Connect sync: Functions Reference](active-directory-aadconnectsync-functions-reference.md)\n\n\n## Additional Resources\n\n* [Azure AD Connect Sync: Customizing Synchronization options](active-directory-aadconnectsync-whatis.md)\n* [Integrating your on-premises identities with Azure Active Directory](active-directory-aadconnect.md)\n\n<!--Image references-->\n\n\n"
}