{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "You can use a load balancer to provide high availability for your workloads in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        0,
        85
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure load balancer is a Layer-4 (TCP, UDP) type load balancer that distributes incoming traffic among healthy service instances in cloud services or virtual machines defined in a load balancer set.",
      "pos": [
        86,
        287
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can configure a load balancer to.",
      "pos": [
        290,
        327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Load balance incoming Internet traffic to virtual machines (VMs).",
      "pos": [
        331,
        396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We refer to a load balancer in this scenario as an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Internet facing load balancer<ept id=\"p1\">](load-balancer-internet-overview.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        397,
        516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Load balance traffic between VMs in a virtual network (VNet), VMs in cloud services, or between on-premises computers and VMs in a cross-premises virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        519,
        681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We refer to a load balancer in this scenario as an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>internal load balancer (ILB)<ept id=\"p1\">](load-balancer-internal-overview.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        682,
        800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Forward external traffic to a specific VM instance.",
      "pos": [
        805,
        856
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "You can use a load balancer to provide high availability for your workloads in Azure. An Azure load balancer is a Layer-4 (TCP, UDP) type load balancer that distributes incoming traffic among healthy service instances in cloud services or virtual machines defined in a load balancer set.\n \nYou can configure a load balancer to.\n\n- Load balance incoming Internet traffic to virtual machines (VMs). We refer to a load balancer in this scenario as an [Internet facing load balancer](load-balancer-internet-overview.md).\n- Load balance traffic between VMs in a virtual network (VNet), VMs in cloud services, or between on-premises computers and VMs in a cross-premises virtual network. We refer to a load balancer in this scenario as an [internal load balancer (ILB)](load-balancer-internal-overview.md).\n-   Forward external traffic to a specific VM instance.\n\n\n"
}